import{_ as k,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as p,p as c,e as f,f as j,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},A={class:"poem-container"},z={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},T={class:"review-content"};function x(e,a,s,g,t,u){return i(),o("div",A,[n("div",z,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",T,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const S=k(q,[["render",x],["__scopeId","data-v-9c65044f"]]),I=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"╨в╨░╨╝╨░╨║ ╨╢╙й╨╜╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╨╝╨░╨║╨░╨╗ ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨╡╤Б╨╕╨╖╨▒╨╕?","answer":"╨в╨░╨╝╨░╨║ ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨░╤Б╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╨║╤Г╤И ╤В╨╛╤А╨│╨╛ ╤В╥п╤И╥п╨┐╤В╥п╤А."},{"question":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╢╗р╖Кр╢║р╖Ър╖Вр╢лр╖Пр╢Ьр╖Пр╢╗р╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Щр╢п?","answer":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╢╗р╖Кр╢║р╖Ър╖Вр╢лр╖Пр╢Ьр╖Пр╢╗р╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ъ р╢╜р╖Фр╢лр╖Фр╖Ар╖Тр╢╜ р╢▒р╢Ьр╢╗р╢║р╖Щр╖Др╖Тр╢║."},{"question":"р╢Ър╖Тр╢нр╖Ф р╢пр╖Др╢╕р╖Ъ р╢Ср╢▒  р╢╕р╖Цр╢╜ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╢║ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"тАЬр╢╕р╖Цр╢╜ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╢║тАЭ р╢║р╢▒ р╢┤р╢пр╢║ р╖Др╖Ьр╢│ р╖Гр╖Д р╢▒р╢╗р╢Ъ р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Шр╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Ср╢╕ р╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢Ър╖Ьр╢зр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Жр╢пр╢╕р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ър╖Ур╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢Ър╢╕ р╢▒р╢╕р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╢║ р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Ф р╢Ър╖Ьр╢зр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢╕р╖Фр╢╜р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Др╢нр╖К р╢╕р╢▒р╖Фр╖Вр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╢║р╖Пр╢зр╢╕ р╢Зр╢нр╖Тр╖Ар╖Ц р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕ р╢Ър╖Щр╢╗р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢Ър╢зр╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Цр╢╜ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╢║ р╢Ер╢┤р╢з р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢о р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╖Ъ тАЬр╢Тр╢пр╢▒р╖К р╢Лр╢║р╢▒р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢Жр╢пр╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Ф р╢Ър╖Е р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╢║р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Шр╢вр╖Ф р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖Тр╢╡р╢╜р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ър╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╖Др╢╕р╖Цр╖Др╢║р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢Ер╢┤р╢з р╢Ер╢║р╖Тр╢нр╖Тр╖А р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╢║ р╖Гр╖Д р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╖Ар╢╗р╢пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║тАЭ р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╢║р╖Т. р╢Ер╢┤ р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╖А р╢┤р╖Ар╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢нр╖Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╢║р╖Гр╢Ър╢з р╢┤р╢нр╖К р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢зр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢ор╢╕р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К, р╢╕р╖Цр╢╜ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╢║ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢╕р╢нр╖Ар╖Пр╢пр╢║ р╢Ер╢┤р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╢║р╢з р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕ р╖Гр╖Д р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ер╢┤р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╖Ар╢╗р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╢║ р╢Ър╖Щр╢╗р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Ър╖Вр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢╕ р╢║р╖Ьр╢╕р╖Фр╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Ср╢╕ р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕ р╢Ър╖Щр╢╗р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢Ър╢зр╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢╕р╢нр╢║р╢▒р╖К 3 р╢Ър╖К (р╢нр╖Фр╢▒р╢Ър╖К) р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Ъ."},{"question":"Hallo, ik ben Anna, de virtuele chatbot van uw energiebedrijf. Vertel me uw vraag, en ik help u zo snel mogelijk verder","answer":"O nee he, niet zo'n stomme prutchatbot. Ik wil een mens spreken. Nu meteen. "},{"question":"╨Р╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ ╤Б╤Л╨╝╨░╨╗╨┤╤Г╤Г╨╗╨░╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ...","answer":"╨Р╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ ╤Б╤Л╨╝╨░╨╗╨┤╤Г╤Г╨╗╨░╤А тАФ ╨Ъ╤Г╨╖╨╜╨╡╤З╨╕╨║╨╛╨▓╤Л╨╡ ╤З╨╡╨│╨╕╤А╤В╨║╨╡╨╗╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╤З╨╛╥г ╤В╤Г╨║╤Г╨╝╤Г, ╨▒╤Г╨╗╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╨╜╨░╨║╤В╨░ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А ╤В╤Г╨║╤Г╨╝╤Г (╨╗╨░╤В. Tettigoniidea), ╨▒╤Г╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨║╤Л╨╣╨╗╨░ ╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г╤Б╤Г ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╤В╥п╤А╥п ╨▒╨░╤А: ╤Г╨╖╤Г╨╜ ╨▒╤Г╤В ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ (Pinegia longipes), ╤З╨╛╥г ╨▒╨░╤И ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜, ╨╢╨░╤И╤Л╨╗ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ (Tettigonia viridissima), ╨╢╨░╨╗╨▒╤Л╤А╨░╨║╤Б╤Л╨╝╨░╨║ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ (Tanusia corrupta), ╨Ь╨░╨╗╨░╨╣╤П ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╤Л (Leptoderes ornatipennis), ╨║╨╡╤А╨╕╨║╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜, ╨╛╤А╨░╨╜╨╢╨╡╤А╨╡╤П ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╤Л (Tachycines asynamorus), ╤З╨╡╨║╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╡╨║ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ (Tettigonia cantans), ╤Н╤Н╤А╤З╨╡╨║ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ (Ephippiger ephippiger), ╨▒╨╛╨╖ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ (Decticus verrucivorus), ╨б╤Г╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╤Л (Eurycorypha fallax), ╨г╤Б╤Б╤Г╤А╨╕ ╨╢╨░╤И╤Л╨╗ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╤Л (Tettigonia ussuriana), ╨║╤Г╨╣╤А╤Г╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ (╨в. caudata), ╨╢╨░╤И╤Л╨╗ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А (╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г) (Tettigonia), ╨▒╨╛╨╖ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А (╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г) (Decticus), ╤Б╨╡╨║╨╕╤А╤З╤Н╤Н╨║ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А (╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г) (Platycleis)."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa gobalka uu ku dhashay Maxamed Gacal Xaayow? ","answer":"Gobalka uu kudhashay Maxamed Gacal Xaayow waa gobalka Banaadir. "},{"question":"роХро╛ро░ро▓рпН рооро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроЪро┐ройрпН роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"рооройро┐родро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроиро┐ро▓рпИропрпИ роиро┐ро░рпНрогропро┐рокрпНрокродрпБ роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЙрогро░рпНро╡рпБ роЕро▓рпНро▓. рооро╛ро▒ро╛роХ,, роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│родрпБ роЪроорпВроХ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроиро┐ро▓рпИропрпЗ роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│родрпБ роЙрогро░рпНро╡рпИ роиро┐ро░рпНрогропро┐роХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ."},{"question":"┘Д╪п┘К ┘Ж╪╡ ╪║┘К╪▒ ┘Е╪┤┘Г┘Д╪М ┘В┘Е ╪и╪к╪┤┘Г┘К┘Д┘З:  ╪з┘Д┘И╪з┘В┘Б ╪и╪и╪╣╪╢ ┘Е┘Ж╪з┘Б╪╣┘З╪з ┘Г╪п╪▒┘З╪з ╪г┘И ╪╡┘И┘Б┘З╪з ┘Б╪╕╪з┘З╪▒ ╪г┘Ж┘З ┘Д╪з ╪н┘В ┘Д┘З ┘Б┘К ╪м┘Д╪п┘З╪з ╪з ┘З┘А ┘В┘И┘Д┘З ┘И╪е╪░╪з ╪п╪и╪║┘З ╪е┘Д╪о ┘В╪з┘Д ┘Б┘К ╪┤╪▒╪н ╪з┘Д╪▒┘И╪╢ ╪г┘И ╪з┘Ж╪п┘Б╪╣ ╪и┘Ж┘Б╪│┘З ┘Б┘К┘Е╪з ┘К╪╕┘З╪▒ ╪з ┘З┘А ┘В┘И┘Д┘З ┘Д┘Г┘Ж ╪м╪▓┘Е ╪з┘Д┘Е╪з┘И╪▒╪п┘К ╪е┘Д╪о ┘И┘К╪м┘Е╪╣ ╪и┘К┘Ж┘З┘Е╪з ╪и╪н┘Е┘Д ┘Г┘Д ┘Е┘Ж┘З┘Е╪з ╪╣┘Д┘Й ┘Е╪з ╪з┘В╪к╪╢╪к┘З ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╡┘Д╪н╪й ┘Б╪е┘Ж ╪к╪╣╪░╪▒ ╪м┘Е┘К╪╣ ╪░┘Д┘Г ╪╡╪▒┘Б ┘Д┘Д┘Е┘И┘В┘И┘Б ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ┘Б┘К┘Е╪з ┘К╪╕┘З╪▒ ┘Е ╪▒ ┘В┘И┘Д┘З ┘И┘Д┘И ╪╣╪м╪▓╪к ╪╣┘Ж┘З ╪м╪з╪▓ ╪з╪│╪к╪╣┘Е╪з┘Д.","answer":"╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡ ╪з┘Д┘Е╪┤┘Г┘Д:  ╪з┘Д┘Т┘И┘О╪з┘В┘Р┘Б┘П ╪и┘Р╪и┘О╪╣┘Т╪╢┘Р ┘Е┘О┘Ж┘О╪з┘Б┘Р╪╣┘Р┘З┘О╪з ┘Г┘О╪п┘О╪▒┘Р┘З┘О╪з ╪г┘О┘И┘Т ╪╡┘П┘И┘Б┘Р┘З┘О╪з ┘Б┘О╪╕┘О╪з┘З┘Р╪▒┘М ╪г┘О┘Ж┘О┘З┘П ┘Д┘О╪з ╪н┘О┘В┘О ┘Д┘О┘З┘П ┘Б┘Р┘К ╪м┘Р┘Д┘Т╪п┘Р┘З┘О╪з ╪з ┘З┘А ┘В┘О┘И┘Т┘Д┘П┘З┘П ┘И┘О╪е┘Р╪░┘О╪з ╪п┘О╪и┘О╪║┘О┘З┘П ╪е┘Д┘О╪о┘Т ┘В┘О╪з┘Д┘О ┘Б┘Р┘К ╪┤┘О╪▒┘Т╪н┘Р ╪з┘Д╪▒┘О┘И┘Т╪╢┘Р ╪г┘О┘И┘Т ╪з┘Ж┘Т╪п┘О┘Б┘О╪╣┘О ╪и┘Р┘Ж┘О┘Б┘Т╪│┘Р┘З┘Р ┘Б┘Р┘К┘Е┘О╪з ┘К┘О╪╕┘Т┘З┘О╪▒┘П ╪з ┘З┘А ┘В┘О┘И┘Т┘Д┘П┘З┘П ┘Д┘О┘Г┘Р┘Ж┘Т ╪м┘О╪▓┘О┘Е┘О ╪з┘Д┘Т┘Е┘О╪з┘И┘О╪▒┘Т╪п┘Р┘К┘П ╪е┘Д┘О╪о┘Т ┘И┘О┘К┘О╪м┘Т┘Е┘О╪╣┘П ╪и┘О┘К┘Т┘Ж┘О┘З┘П┘Е┘О╪з ╪и┘Р╪н┘О┘Е┘Т┘Д┘Р ┘Г┘П┘Д┘Н ┘Е┘Р┘Ж┘Т┘З┘П┘Е┘О╪з ╪╣┘О┘Д┘О┘Й ┘Е┘О╪з ╪з┘В┘Т╪к┘О╪╢┘О╪к┘Т┘З┘П ╪з┘Д┘Т┘Е┘О╪╡┘Т┘Д┘О╪н┘О╪й┘П ┘Б┘О╪е┘Р┘Ж┘Т ╪к┘О╪╣┘О╪░┘О╪▒┘О ╪м┘О┘Е┘Р┘К╪╣┘П ╪░┘О┘Д┘Р┘Г┘О ╪╡┘П╪▒┘Р┘Б┘О ┘Д┘Р┘Д┘Т┘Е┘О┘И┘Т┘В┘П┘И┘Б┘Р ╪╣┘О┘Д┘О┘К┘Т┘З┘Р ┘Б┘Р┘К┘Е┘О╪з ┘К┘О╪╕┘Т┘З┘О╪▒┘П ┘Е ╪▒ ┘В┘О┘И┘Т┘Д┘П┘З┘П ┘И┘О┘Д┘О┘И┘Т ╪╣┘О╪м┘О╪▓┘О╪к┘Т ╪╣┘О┘Ж┘Т┘З┘П ╪м┘О╪з╪▓┘О ╪з╪│┘Т╪к┘Р╪╣┘Т┘Е┘О╪з┘Д┘П."},{"question":"роЗроирпНродрокрпН рокродрпНродро┐ропро┐ройрпН родрпКроЯро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ропрпИ роОро┤рпБродрпБроЩрпНроХро│рпН: роХро╛ро░рпНроХро┐ро▓рпН рокрпЛро░рпН роироЯроирпНродрокрпЛродрпБ, роиро┐ро╡ро╛ро░рог роиро┐родро┐ роЪрпЗроХро░ро┐рокрпНрокро┐ройрпН роТро░рпБ рокроХрпБродро┐ропро╛роХ роЗро╡ро░рпН родрпЖро░рпБро╡рпЛро░ роиро┐роХро┤рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐роХро│рпИ роЪрпЖропрпНродро╛ро░рпН. 2019роЗро▓рпН рокрпБро▓рпНро╡ро╛рооро╛ родро╛роХрпНроХрпБродро▓рпН роироЯроирпНродрокрпЛродрпБ, роЗро╡ро░рпН, родройродрпБ рооро╛рогро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпБроЯройрпН родрпЗроЪрокрпН рокроХрпНродро┐ рокро╛роЯро▓рпНроХро│рпИ рокро╛роЯро┐ройро╛ро░рпН. рокрпЖроЩрпНроХро│рпВро░ро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ роЪро┐родрпНро░роХро▓ро╛ рокро░ро┐ро╖родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родройродрпБ роЪрпКроирпНрод роЪрпБро░рпНрокро╣ро╛ро░рпН роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБ роорпВро▓роорпН рооро╛роиро┐ро▓родрпНродро┐ройрпН рокро┐ро░роорпБроХро░рпНроХро│рпН роорпБройрпНройро┐ро▓рпИропро┐ро▓рпН \\" роП ро╡родройрпН роХрпЗ роирпМроЬро╛ро╡ройрпН\\" роОройрпНро▒ рокро╛роЯро▓рпИ роЕро░рпНрокрпНрокрогро┐родрпНродро╛ро░рпН.","answer":"рокрпБро▓рпНро╡ро╛рооро╛ родро╛роХрпНроХрпБродро▓рпН"},{"question":"Euskal Herriko mendizalean, zer da turismo aktiboaren eragina?","answer":"Turismo aktiboaren eragina da ekonomia bultzatzea eta ingurumenaren kontserbazioa sustatzea."},{"question":"ржирж┐ржорзНржирж▓рж┐ржЦрж┐ржд ржЬржирзНржп ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржзрж╛рж░рж╛ржмрж╛рж╣рж┐ржХрждрж╛ рж▓рж┐ржЦрзБржи :ржЕржкрзЗржХрзНрж╖ржХ ржмрж╛ ржлрж╛ржВрж╢ржи","answer":"ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржЧрж╛ржгрж┐рждрж┐ржХ ржзрж╛рж░ржгрж╛ ржпрж╛ ржжрзБржЗржЯрж┐ рж░рж╛рж╢рж┐рж░ ржоржзрзНржпрзЗ ржкрж╛рж░рж╕рзНржкрж░рж┐ржХ ржирж┐рж░рзНржнрж░рж╢рзАрж▓рждрж╛ ржкрзНрж░ржХрж╛рж╢ ржХрж░рзЗред ржПржХржЯрж┐ рж░рж╛рж╢рж┐ржХрзЗ ржмрж▓рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ ржкрзНрж░ржжрждрзНржд рж░рж╛рж╢рж┐, ржмрж╛ рж╕рзНржмрж╛ржзрзАржи ржЪрж▓ржХ ржмрж╛ ржЕржкрзЗржХрзНрж╖ржХржЯрж┐рж░ ржЖрж░рзНржЧрзБржорзЗржирзНржЯ ржмрж╛ ржЗржиржкрзБржЯред ржЕржкрж░ржЯрж┐ржХрзЗ ржЙрзОржкрж╛ржжрж┐ржд рж░рж╛рж╢рж┐ ржмрж╛ ржЕржкрзЗржХрзНрж╖ржХрзЗрж░ ржорж╛ржи ржмрж╛ ржЖржЙржЯржкрзБржЯ ржмрж▓рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ред"},{"question":"Pelu bi eto с╗Нrс╗Н-aje с╣гe denukс╗Нlс║╣, ijс╗Нba mi ko ni i gbaс╣гс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ kankan- Akeredolu","answer":"Lasiko to n sinu aawс║╣ pс║╣lu awс╗Нn Musulumi lalс║╣ с╗Нjс╗Н Aiku, Sannde с╗Нsс║╣ yii, ni gbс╗Нngan asa igbalode Doomu, to wa loju с╗Нna Igbatoro, niluu Akurс║╣, ni Gomina ipinlс║╣ Ondo, Rotimi Akeredolu, ti sс╗Н pe oun ko с╣гetan lati gba iс╣гс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н eyikeyii ninu awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba latari eto с╗Нrс╗Н aje orilс║╣-ede to n saisan lс╗Нwс╗Н.Arakunrin ni loootс╗Н la ti ri awс╗Нn ipinlс║╣ bii Kaduna to gba iс╣гс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н с╗Нgс╗Нс╗Нrс╗Н awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣, nigba tawс╗Нn mi-in kс╗Н jalс║╣ lati maa san с║╣gbс║╣run mejidinlogun to jс║╣ owo awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ to kere ju lс╗Н, с╣гugbс╗Нn ti oun ko с╣гetan ati с╣гe bс║╣с║╣ ni toun.O ni с║╣bс║╣ loun n bс║╣ awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ ki wс╗Нn tubс╗Н mu suuru fun ijс╗Нba laarin asiko yii ti nnkan ko fi bс║╣с║╣ rс╗Нgbс╗Н feto с╗Нrс╗Н aje ipinlс║╣ Ondo nitori pe gbogbo с║╣tс╗Н wс╗Нn ko ni i sai tс║╣ wс╗Нn lс╗Нwс╗Н nigbakuugba ti nnkan ba ti n с╣гenuure.Lati bii oс╣гu mс║╣fa sс║╣yin lс╗Нkan-o-jс╗Нkan ede aiyede ti n suyс╗Н laarin ijс╗Нba ati с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ ipinlс║╣ naa latari bi wс╗Нn ko с╣гe rowo osu wс╗Нn san deedee mс╗Н bii ti atс║╣yinwa.с║╕kс╗Нс╗Нkan tijс╗Нba ba si tun fс║╣с║╣ sanwo, aabс╗Н owo-osu ni wс╗Нn n ri san, eyi lo si с╣гokunfa bawс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ eto ilera, awс╗Нn dokita atawс╗Нn nс╗Нс╗Нsi с╣гe bс║╣rс║╣ iyansс║╣lodi с╗Нlс╗Нjс╗Н gbс╗Нс╗Нrс╗Н loс╣гu bii meji sс║╣yin.Ko ti i ju bii с╗Нsс║╣ meji lс╗Н sasiko yii nigba ti wс╗Нn с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ pada с╣гс║╣nu iс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn.Wahala mi-in tun fс║╣с║╣ su yс╗Н laarin ijс╗Нba atawс╗Нn с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja yii pс║╣lu bi wс╗Нn с╣гe fс║╣с║╣ san ida с╗Нgс╗Нta fawс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ gс║╣gс║╣ bii owo-oс╣гu keji, eyi ti с║╣gbс║╣ awс╗Нn nс╗Нс╗Нsi yari kanlс║╣ pe awс╗Нn ko ni i gba lс╗Нwс╗Н ijс╗Нba."},{"question":" Waxaad sheegtaa shahiidkii ugu horeeyey Islaamka","answer":" Waxay ahayd Sumaya bintu Khayaad, (Aala Yaasir) Camaar ibnu Yaasir hooyadii"},{"question":"Isikan tempat-tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang sesuai. \\"Salmah memang cantik orangnya. Namun, dia ibarat __________ kerana suka _________ apabila bergaul dengan masyarakat setempat.\\"","answer":"Jawapannya ialah \\"bunga dedap\\" dan \\"bermuka-muka\\"."},{"question":"╨Р╨▒╨▒╤А╨╡╨▓╨╕╨░╤В╤Г╤А╨░ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ?","answer":"╨Р╨▒╨▒╤А╨╡╨▓╨╕╨░╤В╤Г╤А╨░ (╨╕╤В╨░╨╗╨╕╤П╨╗╤Л╨║ ╤В╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╡╨╜ ╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╨┤╨░ тАФ ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А) ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Г╤Г ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨╛╨╛╨╖╨╡╨║╨╕ ╤А╨╡╤З╤В╨╡╨│╨╕ ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А. ╨Р╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨┐╤А╨░╨║╤В╨╕╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╨║ ╨╝╨░╨░╨╜╨╕╤Б╨╕ тАФ ╥п╨╜╙й╨╝╨┤╥п╥п╨╗╥п╨║. ╨Р╨╗ ╨░╨╖ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛ ╨┤╨░ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╙й╨╝ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╨░ ╨║╨╡╨╖╨┤╨╡╤И╨╡╤В.1.╨б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А╨┤╥п╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И╨║╤Л ╨▒╙й╨╗╥п╨║╤В╙й╤А╥п╨╜╙й╨╜ ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А. ╨в╨╕╨╣╨┤╨╕╨▒╨╕ ╤Н╨╗╨╡, ╨║╨╛╨╝╤Б╨╛╨╝╨╛╨╗, ╨Ц╨░╨╗╨┐╤Л ╨╛╨║╤Г╤Г╨│╨░ ╨╢╨░╤А╨┤╨░╨╝╤Л╥г? (╨Ц. ╨С╙й╨║╙й╨╜╨▒╨░╨╡╨▓)2.╨С╨░╤И╨║╤Л ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐, ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╤Л ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨░╨╗╤Л╨╜╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А. ╨Ю╤В╨║╨╛ ╨║╥п╨╣╨▒╙й╤Б, ╨╛╨║ ╙й╤В╨┐╙й╨│╙й╨╜ ╨┐╨░╤А╤В╨▒╨╕╨╗╨╡╤В, ╨Ъ╥п╨╜╨┤╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╨╣╨╕╨║, ╨▒╨░╨░ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨┐╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨┐╨░╤А╤В╨▒╨╕╨╗╨╡╤В! (╨Р. ╨в╨╛╨║╤В╨╛╨╝╤Г╤И╨╡╨▓)3.╨С╨░╤И╨║╤Л ╤В╤Л╨▒╤Л╤И╤В╨░╤А╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А. ╨Р╨░╨╗╨░╨╝╨┤╨░ ╨║╥п╨╜╨┤╙й╨╜ ╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨║ ╨┤╨░╥г╨║╨║╨░ ╨║╨╛╨╜╨│╨╛╨╜, ╨Р╨╗ ╨з╤Л╨╜╨░╤А тАФ ╨б╨б╨б╨а, ╨║╨╡╥г ╨Ь╨╡╨║╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝! (╨Ъ. ╨Р╨║╨░╨╡╨▓)"},{"question":"рккрк╛ркЗ ркПркЯрк▓рлЗ рк╢рлБ ?","answer":"рккрк╛ркЗ ркП ркЧрк╛ркгрк┐ркдрк┐ркХ ркЕркЪрк▓ рк╕ркВркЦрлНркпрк╛ ркЕркирлЗ рк╡рк░рлНркдрлБрк│ркирк╛ рккрк░рк┐ркШ ркЕркирлЗ ркдрлЗркирк╛ рк╡рлНркпрк╛рк╕ркирлЛ ркЧрлБркгрлЛркдрлНркдрк░ ркЫрлЗ. ркЬрлЗркирлБркВ ркорлВрк▓рлНркп рк╕рк╛ркорк╛ркирлНркп рк░рлАркдрлЗ ркЕркВркжрк╛ркЬрлЗ рлй.рлзрлкрлзрллрлп ркЙрккркпрлЛркЧркорк╛ркВ рк▓рлЗрк╡рк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ. рлзрлоркорлА рк╕ркжрлАркирк╛ ркоркзрлНркп ркнрк╛ркЧркерлА рккрк╛ркЗркирлЗ '╧А' ркдрк░рлАркХрлЗ рк░ркЬрлВ ркХрк░рк╡рк╛ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлЗ ркЫрлЗ."},{"question":"Ayat 1: Pandangan beliau mengenai kematian Greg Dyke dalam sinetron radio, The Archers, yang dipetik oleh Grace Archer dalam McTaggart Lecture pada tahun 2000. Ayat 2: Pandangan beliau mengenai kematian Grace Archer dalam sinetron radio, The Archers, yang dipetik oleh Greg Dyke dalam kuliah McTaggart pada tahun 2000. Soalan: Adakah ayat 1 dan ayat 2 menyatakan makna yang sama? Ya atau tidak?","answer":"Tidak"},{"question":"рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╛ро░ро┐ройрпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ  роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"роЖродрпНродро┐роХройрпН роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН роорпБроЯрпНроЯро╛ро│рпН роЖро░ро╛ропрпНроЪрпНроЪро┐родрпН родройрпНроорпИ роЕро▒рпНро▒ро╡ройрпН роОройрпНро▒рпБ рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: роЗроЪрпИропрпИ роЖродро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛род роорпКроХро▓ро╛роп рооройрпНройройрпН ропро╛ро░рпН? ","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: роТро░рпМроЩрпНроХроЪрпАрокрпН"},{"question":"Ngikubonile mntanomuntu uyiphaka,Ngikubonile nkosazana uyididiyelaNgikuzwile mntanomfazi uyiyalelaNgikuzwile ngane yabantu uyikhakhabeza.Uyiphake angakholwa nkosazana,Uyisuse kwelakini koMelikaWayisingisa kwelenkolo koSadamu,Uyiphake yadl'amadoda mame,Uyiphake kwasuka izidumo Nozidumo.1. Yisho amagama AMABILI imbongi ebiza ngawo uNozidumo","answer":"OKUBILI kwalokhu:тАв MntanomuntuтАв NkosazanaтАв MntanomfaziтАв Ngane yabantu"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢нр╖Ър╢╗р╖Ар╖Тр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╢│р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖П р╖Гр╢╜р╢║р╖Т р╢Йр╖Др╢╜ р╢▒р╖Ьр╢║р╢║р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢н р╢╗р╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖Ьр╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Щр╢║р╖П р╢Ер╢мр╢║р╖Т         ","answer":"р╢Зр╖Г"},{"question":"H├гy ho├аn thiс╗Зn ─Сoс║бn v─Гn sau: Theo Reuters, ├┤ng Mikhail Razvozhayev, l├гnh ─Сс║бo cс╗зa Sevastopol, viс║┐t tr├кn mс║бng x├г hс╗Щi Telegram rс║▒ng \\"mс╗Щt vс║нt thс╗Г kh├┤ng x├бc ─Сс╗Лnh ─С├г bay v├аo s├вn cс╗зa trс╗е sс╗Я hс║бm ─Сс╗Щi. Theo th├┤ng tin s╞б bс╗Щ, ─С├│ l├а mс╗Щt m├бy bay kh├┤ng ng╞░с╗Эi l├бi\\". Sevastopol l├а th├аnh phс╗С lс╗Ыn nhс║еt с╗Я Crimea v├а l├а n╞бi ─С├│ng tr├║ cс╗зa Hс║бm ─Сс╗Щi Biс╗Гn ─Рen thuс╗Щc Hс║гi qu├вn Nga. ├Фng Razvozhayev n├│i rс║▒ng Ukraine ─С├г quyс║┐t ─Сс╗Лnh \\"l├аm hс╗Пng Ng├аy Hс║гi qu├вn\\", mс╗Щt ng├аy lс╗Е hс║▒ng n─Гm cс╗зa Nga, trong ─С├│ c├бc hс║бm ─Сс╗Щi tс╗Х chс╗йc cuс╗Щc thao diс╗Еn hс║гi qu├вn v├а t├┤n vinh c├бc thс╗зy thс╗з. ├Фng cho hay 5 nh├вn vi├кn tс║бi trс╗е sс╗Я Hс║бm ─Сс╗Щi Biс╗Гn ─Рen ─С├г bс╗Л th╞░╞бng trong vс╗е tс║еn c├┤ng v├а C╞б quan An ninh Li├кn bang Nga (FSB) ─Сang ─Сiс╗Бu tra t├мnh h├мnh. ├Фng Razvozhayev cho biс║┐t tс║еt cс║г c├бc hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng kс╗╖ niс╗Зm с╗Я Sevastopol ─С├г bс╗Л hс╗зy bс╗П v├м l├╜ do an ninh, v├а k├кu gс╗Нi mс╗Нi ng╞░с╗Эi giс╗п b├мnh t─йnh. Hiс╗Зn ch╞░a c├│ th├┤ng tin vс╗Б phс║гn с╗йng cс╗зa Bс╗Щ Quс╗Сc ph├▓ng Nga c┼йng nh╞░ Bс╗Щ Quс╗Сc ph├▓ng Ukraine vс╗Б c├бo buс╗Щc tr├кn. Thс╗й tr╞░с╗Яng Quс╗Сc ph├▓ng Ukraine Volodymyr Havrylov h├┤m 19.7 n├│i rс║▒ng Kyiv ─Сang chuс║йn bс╗Л cuс╗Щc tс║еn c├┤ng nhс║▒m v├аo Hс║бm ─Сс╗Щi Biс╗Гn ─Рen cс╗зa Nga. ├Фng Havrylov c┼йng cho biс║┐t Ukraine l├кn kс║┐ hoс║бch gi├аnh lс║бi Crimea th├┤ng qua biс╗Зn ph├бp ngoс║бi giao hoс║╖c qu├вn sс╗▒. C┼йng trong h├┤m 31.7, trang The Kyiv Independent dс║лn th├┤ng b├бo tс╗л Bс╗Щ Chс╗Й huy chiс║┐n dс╗Лch miс╗Бn nam Ukraine n├│i rс║▒ng ─С├г ph├б hс╗зy 2 lс╗▒u ph├бo Msta-B cс╗зa Nga, 1 bс╗З ph├│ng rс╗Сc k├йt ─Сa n├▓ng Grad, 2 kho ─Сс║бn c├╣ng 3 xe bс╗Нc th├йp v├а qu├вn sс╗▒ trong ng├аy 30.7, khiс║┐n 33 binh s─й Nga thiс╗Зt mс║бng. Hiс╗Зn ch╞░a c├│ th├┤ng tin vс╗Б phс║гn с╗йng cс╗зa Nga ─Сс╗Сi vс╗Ыi tс╗Хn thс║еt mс╗Ыi do qu├вn ─Сс╗Щi Ukraine ─С╞░a ra, trong bс╗Сi cс║гnh lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng Ukraine ─Сang phс║гn c├┤ng с╗Я miс╗Бn nam. H├┤m 30.7, ph├нa Ukraine c┼йng n├│i rс║▒ng ─С├г loс║бi 100 binh s─й Nga v├а 7 xe t─Гng khс╗Пi v├▓ng chiс║┐n ─Сс║еu с╗Я miс╗Бn nam. V├╣ng Kherson с╗Я miс╗Бn nam hiс╗Зn l├а t├вm ─Сiс╗Гm cс╗зa chiс║┐n dс╗Лch phс║гn c├┤ng cс╗зa Ukraine, v├а l├а mс╗Щt mс║пt x├нch then chс╗Сt trong tuyс║┐t tiс║┐p tс║┐ cс╗зa Nga. Qu├вn ─Сс╗Щi Ukraine h├┤m 30.7 n├│i ─С╞░с╗Эng sс║пt b─Гng qua s├┤ng Dnipro ─Сс║┐n Kherson ─С├г bс╗Л cс║пt ─Сс╗йt, c├│ thс╗Г l├аm cho lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng Nga с╗Я bс╗Э t├вy s├┤ng bс╗Л c├┤ lс║нp h╞бn nс╗пa. C├▓n с╗Я miс╗Бn ─С├┤ng, qu├вn ─Сс╗Щi Ukraine x├бc nhс║нn Nga \\"th├аnh c├┤ng mс╗Щt phс║зn\\" trong viс╗Зc kiс╗Гm so├бt khu d├вn c╞░ Semyhirya с╗Я ph├нa nam thс╗Л trс║еn Bakhmut, n╞бi Nga xem l├а mс╗Щt mс╗еc ti├кu ch├нnh с╗Я Donetsk. Tr╞░с╗Ыc t├мnh h├мnh giao tranh ├бc liс╗Зt с╗Я miс╗Бn ─С├┤ng, Tс╗Хng thс╗Сng Ukraine Volodymyr Zelensky ng├аy 30.7 ra lс╗Зnh bс║пt buс╗Щc s╞б t├бn ng╞░с╗Эi d├вn с╗Я tс╗Йnh Donetsk. Theo Reuters, trong b├аi ph├бt biс╗Гu tr╞░с╗Ыc to├аn d├вn khuya 30.7, Tс╗Хng thс╗Сng Ukraine Volodymyr Zelensky n├│i h├аng tr─Гm ng├аn ng╞░с╗Эi cс║зn phс║гi rс╗Эi khс╗Пi c├бc khu vс╗▒c chiс║┐n sс╗▒ thuс╗Щc v├╣ng Donbass, bao gс╗Уm tс╗Йnh Donetsk v├а tс╗Йnh Luhansk.","answer":"\\"C├аng c├│ nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi rс╗Эi khс╗Пi khu vс╗▒c Donetsk th├м sс║╜ c├аng ├нt ng╞░с╗Эi thiс╗Зt mс║бng d╞░с╗Ыi tay lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng Nga\\", tс╗Хng thс╗Сng Ukraine n├│i nh╞░ vс║нy, ─Сс╗Уng thс╗Эi cho biс║┐t th├кm rс║▒ng nhс╗пng c╞░ d├вn rс╗Эi ─Сi sс║╜ ─С╞░с╗гc bс╗Уi th╞░с╗Эng. Tс╗Хng thс╗Сng Zelensky c┼йng cho biс║┐t h├аng tr─Гm ng├аn ng╞░с╗Эi vс║лn ─Сang sс╗Сng trong khu vс╗▒c giao tranh diс╗Еn ra ├бc liс╗Зt v├а k├кu gс╗Нi nс╗Ч lс╗▒c thuyс║┐t phс╗еc hс╗Н ─Сi s╞б t├бn. C├╣ng ng├аy, tс╗Э The Kyiv Independent dс║лn lс╗Эi Ph├│ thс╗з t╞░с╗Ыng Ukraine Iryna Vereshchuk cho biс║┐t viс╗Зc s╞б t├бn cс║зn phс║гi diс╗Еn ra tr╞░с╗Ыc khi m├╣a ─С├┤ng bс║пt ─Сс║зu v├м nguс╗Уn cung cс║еp kh├н ─Сс╗Сt tс╗▒ nhi├кn trong khu vс╗▒c ─С├г bс╗Л ph├б hс╗зy. B├а Vereshchuk n├│i rс║▒ng viс╗Зc s╞б t├бn 200.000 d├вn th╞░с╗Эng phс║гi bс║пt ─Сс║зu tr╞░с╗Ыc thс╗Эi ─Сiс╗Гm mс╗Нi ng╞░с╗Эi cс║зn d├╣ng m├бy s╞░с╗Яi. Theo b├а Vereshchuk, nс║┐u tс╗л chс╗Сi s╞б t├бn, ng╞░с╗Эi d├вn sс║╜ buс╗Щc phс║гi k├╜ v├аo mс╗Щt v─Гn bс║гn cam kс║┐t chс╗Лu tr├бch nhiс╗Зm vс╗Б mс╗Нi rс╗зi ro c├│ thс╗Г xс║гy ra. Hiс╗Зn v├╣ng Donbass kh├┤ng c├│ nguс╗Уn cung cс║еp ─Сiс╗Зn th├нch hс╗гp v├а kh├┤ng c├│ nguс╗Уn cung cс║еp kh├н ─Сс╗Сt trong khi Nga tiс║┐p tс╗еc ph├б hс╗зy c├бc thiс║┐t bс╗Л s╞░с╗Яi с║еm, Ph├│ thс╗з t╞░с╗Ыng Vereshchuk cho biс║┐t nh╞░ vс║нy. Trong diс╗Еn biс║┐n kh├бc, Ukraine ─Сang tiс║┐p tс╗еc nhс║нn th├кm v┼й kh├н tс╗л ph╞░╞бng T├вy. Theo The Kyiv Independent, Bс╗Щ Quс╗Сc ph├▓ng Lithuania th├┤ng b├бo hс╗Н sс║╜ cung cс║еp cho Ukraine th├кm 10 xe bс╗Нc th├йp M113 APC c├╣ng c├бc g├│i thuс╗Сc nс╗Х v├а lс╗▒u ─Сс║бn kh├│i. Lithuania c┼йng sс║╜ ─С├аo tс║бo cho thс╗г m├бy v├а ─Сс║╖c c├┤ng Ukraine. Lс║зu N─Гm G├│c c┼йng cho biс║┐t Mс╗╣ sс║пp cung cс║еp hс╗З thс╗Сng ph├▓ng kh├┤ng tс║зm ngс║пn v├а tс║зm trung NASAMS cho Ukraine. T├кn lс╗нa ─Сс║еt ─Сс╗Сi kh├┤ng NASAMS c├│ thс╗Г bс║пn tr├║ng mс╗еc ti├кu с╗Я cс╗▒ ly tс╗Ыi 180 km v├а с╗Я ─Сс╗Щ cao l├кn tс╗Ыi 21 km. \\"T├┤i kh├┤ng c├│ th├┤ng tin chi tiс║┐t vс╗Б qu├б tr├мnh k├╜ kс║┐t hс╗гp ─Сс╗Уng nh╞░ng ch├║ng t├┤i ─Сang trong qu├б tr├мnh mua sс║пm hс╗З thс╗Сng tr├кn\\", mс╗Щt quan chс╗йc quс╗Сc ph├▓ng cс║еp cao cс╗зa Mс╗╣ cho biс║┐t nh╞░ vс║нy."},{"question":"Comment sтАЩappelle une unit├й de force ├йlectromotrice ?","answer":"Une unit├й de force ├йlectromotrice (FEM) est appel├йe ┬л┬аvolt┬а┬╗. Le volt (symbole : V) est l'unit├й standard de mesure de la force ├йlectromotrice, qui est une mesure de la diff├йrence de potentiel entre deux points d'un circuit ├йlectrique. La FEM repr├йsente l'├йnergie ├йlectrique par unit├й de charge fournie par une source, telle qu'une batterie ou un g├йn├йrateur, pour pousser les ├йlectrons ├а travers un circuit."},{"question":"╨Ь╤Н╤Н ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╤Н╤Б-╤В╤Г╤В╤Г╨╝ ╤В╤Г╤Г╤А╨░╨╗╤Г╤Г ╤Д╨░╨║╤В╤Л ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡ ╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╥г╨▒╤Л?","answer":"╨Ь╤Н╤Н ╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╡╨┤╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╨╛╨╣╨│╨╛╨╜╨╛╤В. ╨н╤А╤В╨╡╥г ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨╢╨░╥г╤Л ╨╛╨╣╨│╨╛╨╜╨│╨╛╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╝╤Н╤Н╤Б╨╕ ╤Н╨║╨╕ ╤В╥п╨╜ ╨║╨░╤В╨░╤А╤Л ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨│╨╡╨║╤В╨╡╨╜╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨╡ ╨╝╨░╤Б ╨░╨▒╨░╨╗╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╝╤Н╤Н╤Б╨╕╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨┤╨░ ╨╢╨░╨╝╨░╨╜ ╨╕╤И╤В╨╡╨╣╤В. ╨в╨░╥г ╤Н╤А╤В╨╡ ╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╨╛╨╣╨│╨╛╤В╤Г╤Г ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨║╙й╨╜╥п╨│╥п╥п╨╗╙й╤А ╨╢╨░╤Б╨░╨╗╤Б╨░, ╨╝╤Н╤Н ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨░╨╖ ╨╕╨╜╤В╨╡╨╗╨╗╨╡╨║╤В╤Г╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╨║ ╨║╙й╨╜╥п╨│╥п╥п ╨┐╨░╨╣╨┤╨░. ╨Ь╨╕╤Б╨░╨╗╤Л, ╨╛╨╣╨│╨╛╨╜╨╛╨╛╤А ╨╖╨░╨╝╨░╤В ╤Б╤Л╨╜╨░╨╗╨│╤Л ╨║╙й╤А╥п╥п╨╜╥п╨╜ ╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨╜╨░ ╨║╤А╨╛╤Б╤Б╨▓╨╛╤А╨┤ ╤З╨╡╤З╨║╨╡╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨║╤И╤Л."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cari salah'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berusaha untuk mengetahui kesalahan orang. Contoh ayat: Omar cuba mencari salah Zainal dengan membuka semula laporan peribadi kawannya itu."},{"question":"Jawab soalan teka-teki berikut: Saya beraksi di atas pentas dengan memakai seluar pendek dan berkasut, saya juga bersarung tangan untuk berlawan dengan pencabar saya di atas pentas. Siapakah saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah Ahli Tinju"},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa Kumuu ahaa saxaabigii uu Rasuulka (NNKH) Ku magacaabay amiinka Umadaan?","answer":"Saxaabigii uu Rasuulka (NNKH) Ku magacaabay amiinka umadaan wuxuu ahaa  Abii Cubeyda Caamir Bin Jaraax (RC)."},{"question":"Inona no niseho ny 13 mey 2002 teto Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny 13 mey 2002 dia nanao sesitany ny tenany tany Frantsa ny amiraly Didier Ratsiraka."},{"question":"Escribe una continuaci├│n para el siguiente p├бrrafo: Con 47 votos, el proyecto italiano conformado por las ciudades de Mil├бn y Cortina d'Ampezzo fue seleccionado como sede de los Juegos Ol├нmpicos de Invierno de 2026.","answer":" La otra candidatura, Estocolmo y ├Еre, recibi├│ 34 votos. La votaci├│n ocurri├│ en el marco de la 134.┬к Sesi├│n del Comit├й Ol├нmpico Internacional, en Lausana, Suiza."},{"question":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖А р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╢╗р╢з р╢Фр╢╜р╖Тр╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╢вр╢║р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Др╢лр╢║ р╢Ър╖Ер╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п?","answer":"р╖Гр╖Фр╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╖П р╢вр╢║р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Д р╢╕р╖Др╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╖Тр╢║"},{"question":"ржирж┐ржорзНржирж▓рж┐ржЦрж┐ржд ржЕржирзБржЪрзНржЫрзЗржжрзЗрж░ ржмрж┐рж╖ржпрж╝ ржХрж┐ ?ржЗржирзНржбрж┐ржпрж╝рж╛ ржЧрзЗржЯ ржнрж╛рж░рждрзЗрж░ ржЬрж╛рждрзАржпрж╝ рж╕рзНржорзГрждрж┐рж╕рзМржзред ржПржЯрж┐ ржнрж╛рж░рждрзЗрж░ рж░рж╛ржЬржзрж╛ржирзА ржирждрзБржи ржжрж┐рж▓рзНрж▓рж┐рж░ ржХрзЗржирзНржжрзНрж░рж╕рзНржерж▓рзЗ ржЕржмрж╕рзНржерж┐рждред ржПржЯрж┐ ржжрж┐рж▓рзНрж▓рж┐рж░ ржЕржирзНржпрждржо ржжрзНрж░рж╖рзНржЯржмрзНржп рж╕рзНржерж╛ржиред ржкрзНржпрж╛рж░рж┐рж╕рзЗрж░ ржЖрж░рзНржХ ржжрзЗ рждрзНрж░рж┐ржорзНржлрзЗрж░ ржЖржжрж▓рзЗ рззрзпрзйрзз рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗ ржирж┐рж░рзНржорж┐ржд ржПржЗ рж╕рзМржзржЯрж┐рж░ ржиржХрж╢рж╛ ржХрж░рзЗржи рж╕рзНржпрж╛рж░ ржПржбржЙржЗржи рж▓рзБржЯрж┐ржпрж╝рзЗржирж╕ред ржЖржЧрзЗ ржПрж░ ржирж╛ржо ржЫрж┐рж▓ \\"ржЕрж▓ ржЗржирзНржбрж┐ржпрж╝рж╛ ржУржпрж╝рж╛рж░ ржоржирзБржорзЗржирзНржЯ\\"ред ржкрзНрж░ржержо ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржпрзБржжрзНржз ржУ рждрзГрждрзАржпрж╝ ржЗржЩрзНржЧ-ржЖржлржЧрж╛ржи ржпрзБржжрзНржзрзЗ ржирж┐рж╣ржд рзпрзж,рзжрзжрзж ржнрж╛рж░рждрзАржпрж╝ рж╕рзЗржирж╛ ржЬржУржпрж╝рж╛ржиржжрзЗрж░ рж╕рзНржорзГрждрж┐рж░ржХрзНрж╖рж╛рж░рзНржерзЗ ржПржЗ рж╕рзНржорзГрждрж┐рж╕рзМржзржЯрж┐ ржирж┐рж░рзНржорж┐ржд рж╣ржпрж╝ред ржПржЯрж┐ рж▓рж╛рж▓ ржУ рж╕рж╛ржжрж╛ ржмрзЗрж▓рзЗржкрж╛ржерж░ ржУ ржЧрзНрж░рзНржпрж╛ржирж╛ржЗржЯ ржкрж╛ржерж░рзЗ рждрзИрж░рж┐ред","answer":"рждрзГрждрзАржпрж╝ ржЗржЩрзНржЧ-ржЖржлржЧрж╛ржи ржпрзБржжрзНржз |"},{"question":"╨Р╨╝╤Б╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨░╨╝  ╨╢╙й╨╜╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤З╨░ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ╨░╨╣╤В╨░ ╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╥г ?","answer":"╨Р╨╝╤Б╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨░╨╝ :╨Ъ╤Л╨╣╤И╤Л╨║ ╨╕╨╝╨░╤А╨░╤В╤В╨░╤А, ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨Р╨╝╤Б╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╙й╨╖╨│╙й╤З╙й╨╗╥п╨│╥п.╨Ъ╨░╤З╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╨╡╨╖╨┤╨╡ ╤И╨░╨░╤А ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐╤В╨░ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╤В╤Л╨║╨░╨╜ ╨║╙й╤А╥п╨╜╤З╥п, ╨▒╨╕╤А╨╛╨║ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╤Г╨▒╨░╨║╤Л╤В ╙й╨╖ ╤А╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╜ ╨╛╨╣╨╜╨╛╨┤╤Г. ╥о╨╣╨╗╙й╤А╨┤╥п╨╜ ╨▒╨░╨░╤А╤Л ╥п╨╣╥п╨╗╨│╙й╨╜, ╨║╙й╨▒╥п╨╜╤З╙й ╨╢╤Л╨│╨░╤З. ╥о╨╣╨╝╙й╨║╤В╙й╤А ╤З╨╕╤А╨╕╨┐, ╤В╤Л╨║╨░╨╜ ╨░╨╗╨░╤З╤Л╨║╤В╨░╤А ╤В╨╕╤А╙й╙й╤З╤В╙й╨╜ ╨░╨╢╤Л╤А╨░╨┐, ╤З╙й╨│╥п╨┐, ╨║╨░╨┐╤В╨░╨╗╨│╨░ ╨║╤Г╨╗╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨░╤И╤В╨░╨┤╤Л.╨Э╨╕╨┤╨╡╤А╨╗╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л ЁЯЗ│ЁЯЗ▒"},{"question":"Inona no zavatra voaresaka anatin'ity fanehoan-kevitra manaraka ity?┬л Tahaka ny nanaovana vakisiny ireo zanako jiaby fony fahakeliny, dia ataoko azo antoka ny fanaraha-maso ny zafikeliko rehetra mba ho vita vakisiny ara-potoana, toy ny nataoko fony fahakelinтАЩny zanako, aminтАЩizay koa mitombo tsara ao anatinтАЩny fahasalamana izy ireo ┬╗","answer":"Miresaka momba ny fanaovana vakisiny ny zaza io fanehoan-kevitra io."},{"question":"inona ny laokanay omaly?","answer":"ny laokanay omaly dia hena ritra"},{"question":"╨н╨▓╤Д╨╡╨╝╨╕╨╖╨╝ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡?","answer":"╨н╨▓╤Д╨╡╨╝╨╕╨╖╨╝ (╨│╤А. тАУ ╨╢╨░╨║╤И╤Л ╤Б╥п╨╣╨╗╙й╨╣╨╝╥п╨╜) - ╨║╙й╤А╥п╨╜╥п╤И╤В╙й╤А╨┤╥п╨╜, ╨║╤Г╨▒╤Г╨╗╤Г╤И╤В╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨╡ ╨▒╤Г╤О╨╝╨┤╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╛╨┤╨╛╨╜╨╛, ╨╛╤А╨╛╨╣ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╤Л╤И╤В╨░╤А╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╤Г╨╝╤И╨░╤А╤В╤Л╨┐, ╤Б╤Л╨╗╤Л╨║ ╤Д╨╛╤А╨╝╨░╨│╨░ ╨░╨╗╨╝╨░╤И╤В╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐, ╤Б╨╕╨╜╨╛╨╜╨╕╨╝╨┤╨╕╨║ ╨▒╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л╤И╤В╨░╤А ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨╛╤И╤Г╨┐ ╨░╨╣╤В╤Г╤Г. ╨Ь╨╕╤Б╨░╨╗╤Л, тАЬ╤В╙й╤А╙й╨┤╥птАЭ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨╜╨░ тАУ ┬л╨║╙й╨╖ ╨╢╨░╤А╨┤╤Л┬╗, ┬л╨▒╨╛╤О╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨╛╤И╨╛╨┤╤Г┬╗ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А ╨║╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╨╜╤Г╨╗╨░╤В "},{"question":"риХри╛рйЫрйА рижри╛ рйЮрйИри╕ри▓ри╛ : риЕри░римрйА риХри╣ри╛ригрйА","answer":"риЗри░ри╛риХ рижрйА ри░ри╛риЬризри╛риирйА римрйЪрижри╛риж ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЗри╕ри╛риХ риири╛риВ рижри╛ ри╣ри░рйЮриириорйМри▓ри╛ риЖрижриорйА ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╕рйАред риЙри╣ ри╢ри╣ри┐ри░ рижрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риЪрйЛри░ри╛риВ рижри╛ риЧрйБри░рйВ ри╕рйАред риЙри╕ рижрйЗ риХриИ риЪрйЗри▓рйЗ ри╕рииред риЙри╕ рижрйЗ риШри░ риЗрй▒риХ ри▓рйЬриХрйА риирйЗ риЬриирио ри▓ри┐риЖред риЙри╣ римри╣рйБрид ри╕рйБрй░рижри░ ри╕рйАред риЬриж риЙри╣ ри╡рй▒рибрйА ри╣рйЛриИ ридри╛риВ риЙри╕ рижрйА рйЩрйВримри╕рйВри░ридрйА рижрйА рикрйНри░ри╕ри┐рй▒ризрйА рижрйВри░-рижрйВри░ ридриХ рилрйИри▓ риЧриИред риЗри╕ри╛риХ риирйЗ риЙри╕ рижри╛ риири╛риВ риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░ ри░рй▒риЦри┐риЖред риЗрй▒риХ рижри┐рии риЗрй▒риХ рйЮриХрйАри░ рйЩрйИри░ риорй░риЧриг риЗри╕ри╛риХ рижрйЗ римрйВри╣рйЗ риЖриЗриЖред риЙри╣ рйЮриХрйАри░ риЬрйЛридри┐ри╢-ри╢ри╛ри╕ридри░ рижри╛ риЧри┐риЖридри╛ ри╕рйАред рйЮриХрйАри░ рижрйА риирйЫри░ риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░ тАШридрйЗ рикриИ ридри╛риВ риЙри╕ риирйЗ риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░ рижрйЗ рикри┐ридри╛ риирйВрй░ римрйБри▓ри╛риЗриЖ ридрйЗ риЖриЦри┐риЖ, тАЭридрйБри╣ри╛рибрйА ри▓рйЬриХрйА рижрйА риХри┐ри╕риорид римрйЬрйА риЪрй░риЧрйА ри╣рйИред риЗри╕ рижри╛ рикридрйА ри░ри╛риЬ рижри╛ римрйЬри╛ ри╡рй▒рибри╛ риЕризри┐риХри╛ри░рйА ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗриЧри╛редтАЭриЗри╕ри╛риХ риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЭридрйБри╕рйАриВ риЬрйЛ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, риЙри╣ ри╕рйБригрии ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ римрйЬри╛ риЪрй░риЧри╛ ри▓рй▒риЧрижри╛ ри╣рйИ рикри░ риЗри╕ ри▓рйЬриХрйА ри▓риИ ридри╛риВ риХри┐ри╕рйЗ ри╢ри░рйАрйЮ риЦри╛риирижри╛рии рижри╛ риори╛риорйВри▓рйА ри▓рйЬриХри╛ ри╡рйА риири╣рйАриВ риори┐ри▓ ри╕риХрйЗриЧри╛редтАЭ рйЮриХрйАри░ риирйЗ риЬри╡ри╛рим рижри┐рй▒ридри╛, тАЭрйЩрйБрижри╛ рижрйА риХрйБрижри░рид риири╛ри▓ ри╕рин риХрйБриЭ риЖри╕ри╛рии ри╣рйИред риЙри╣ риХри┐ри╡рйЗриВ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗриЧри╛, риЗри╣ ридри╛риВ риорйИриВ риири╣рйАриВ риЬри╛ригрижри╛ рикри░ риЗри╕ рикри┐риЖри░рйА римрйЗриЯрйА рижрйЗ ри╣рй▒рие рижрйАриЖриВ ри▓риХрйАри░ри╛риВ риЬрйЛ риХри╣ри┐ ри░ри╣рйАриЖриВ ри╣рии, риЙри╣ рйЫри░рйВри░ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗриЧри╛редтАЭ рйЮриХрйАри░ риРриирйА риЧрй▒ри▓ риХри╣ри┐ риХрйЗ риЪри▓ри╛ риЧри┐риЖред риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░ риЬри┐риЙриВ-риЬри┐риЙриВ ри╡рй▒рибрйА ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА риЧриИ, риЙри╕ рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЖри╣ ри▓риИ риЗри╕ри╛риХ рижрйА риЪри┐рй░ридри╛ ри╡рйА ри╡ризрижрйА риЧриИред рйЮриХрйАри░ рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ риЭрйВриарйА ри▓рй▒риЧрйА ри╕рйА риХри┐риЙриВриХри┐ риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░ риири╛ри▓ ри╡ри┐риЖри╣ риХри░ри╡ри╛риЙриг риирйВрй░ риЙриВриЬ ридри╛риВ риХриИ риирйМриЬри╡ри╛рии ридри┐риЖри░ ри╕рии рикри░ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ риЕрикри░ри╛ризрйА риЪрйЗри▓рйЗ ри╕рииред риЕрй░рид риЙри╕ риирйЗ рйЮрйИри╕ри▓ри╛ риХрйАридри╛ риХри┐ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риирйМриЬри╡ри╛риири╛риВ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪрйЛриВ риЬри┐ри╣рйЬри╛ ри╡рйА риЖрикригрйЗ риХрй░рио ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╕рин ридрйЛриВ ри╡рй▒риз риЪри▓ри╛риХ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗриЧри╛, риЙри╕рйЗ риири╛ри▓ риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░ рижри╛ ри╡ри┐риЖри╣ риХри░ рижрйЗри╡рйЗриЧри╛ред риЙри╕ риирйЗ риЖрикригрйЗ риЪрйЗри▓ри┐риЖриВ риирйВрй░ рйЮрйИри╕ри▓ри╛ ри╕рйБригри╛ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ред риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риирйМриЬри╡ри╛риири╛риВ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЕри▓рйА ридрйЗ ри╡ри▓рйА риири╛риВ рижрйЗ риирйМриЬри╡ри╛рии ри╕рииред риЕри▓рйА риЪрйЛри░ ри╕рйА ридрйЗ ри╡ри▓рйА риЬрйЗримриХридри░ри╛ред риЬрижрйЛриВ риЗри╕ри╛риХ риирйЗ риЪрйЗри▓ри┐риЖриВ риирйВрй░ риЖрикригрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ рижрй▒ри╕рйА, риЕри▓рйА риЕридрйЗ ри╡ри▓рйА риЖрикригрйА-риЖрикригрйА рипрйЛриЧридри╛ рижри┐риЦри╛риЙриг ри▓риИ ридрйБри░ рикриПредриЙри╣ рижрйЛри╡рйЗриВ римри╛рйЫри╛ри░ ри╡рй▒ри▓ риЧриПред риЙрй▒риерйЗ риЗрй▒риХ ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА рижрйВриЬрйЗ ри╢ри╣ри┐ри░ ридрйЛриВ риЖриЗриЖ ри╕рйАред риЙри╣ рижрйЛри╡рйЗриВ риЬригрйЗ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ рикри┐рй▒риЫрйЗ ри▓рй▒риЧ риЧриПред риЗрй▒риХ риери╛риВ риорйМриХри╛ рижрйЗриЦ риХрйЗ ри╡ри▓рйА риирйЗ римрйЬрйА рилрйБри░ридрйА риири╛ри▓ риЙри╕ рижрйА риЬрйЗрим ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╣рй▒рие рикри╛риЗриЖ ридрйЗ ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА рижри╛ римриЯрйВриЖ риХрй▒рив ри▓ри┐риЖред ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА риирйВрй░ рикридри╛ ри╡рйА риири╛ ри▓рй▒риЧри┐риЖред риЙри╕ тАШриЪрйЛриВ ри╕рйЛриирйЗ рижрйАриЖриВ риЗрй▒риХ ри╣рйЫри╛ри░ риЕри╢ри░рйЮрйАриЖриВ риири┐риХри▓рйАриЖриВред риЗри╕ри╛риХ, риЕри▓рйА риЕридрйЗ ри╡ри▓рйА рижрйЗ ри╣рй▒рие рижрйА ри╕рйЮри╛риИ рижрйА рикрйНри░ри╢рй░ри╕ри╛ риХри░рии ри▓рй▒риЧри┐риЖред ри╡ри▓рйА риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЭриЙри╕ридри╛риж риЬрйА, риЕриЬрйЗ ридри╛риВ риорйЗри░ри╛ риХрй░рио риЕризрйВри░ри╛ ри╣рйА ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ри╣рйИред риЗри╕ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рикрйНри░ри╢рй░ри╕ри╛ риХри░рии ри╡ри╛ри▓рйА риХри┐ри╣рйЬрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╣рйИ? риЬри┐ри╕ ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА рижри╛ риЗри╣ римриЯрйВриЖ ри╣рйИ, риЙри╣ риЪрйБрй▒рик риХри░ риХрйЗ ридри╛риВ риири╣рйАриВ римрйИриарйЗриЧри╛ред риЙри╣ риХри╛рйЫрйА риХрйЛри▓ риЬри╛ риХрйЗ ри░рйЛри╡рйЗриЧри╛, рикри┐рй▒риЯрйЗриЧри╛ред рилрйЗри░ риорйИриВ рйЫри░рйВри░ рилрйЬри┐риЖ риЬри╛ри╡ри╛риВриЧри╛редтАЭриЗри╕ри╛риХ риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЭридри╛риВ рилрйЗри░ ридрйВрй░ риХрйА риХри░рйЗриВриЧри╛?тАЭри╡ри▓рйА римрйЛри▓ри┐риЖ, тАЭриорйИриВ риЙри╕ ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА риирйВрй░ рилрйЬ риХрйЗ риХри╛рйЫрйА риХрйЛри▓ ри▓рйИ риЬри╛ри╡ри╛риВриЧри╛ред риЙрй▒риерйЗ риорйИриВ ри╕ри╛римрид риЗри╣ риХри░ри╛риВриЧри╛ риХри┐ римриЯрйВриП рижри╛ риори╛ри▓риХ риорйИриВ ри╣ри╛риВред риЗри╕ ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА риирйЗ ри╣рйА римриЯрйВриЖ риЪрйЛри░рйА риХрйАридри╛ ри╣рйИред рилрйЗри░ риХри╛рйЫрйА рйЩрйБриж риорйИриирйВрй░ римриЯрйВриЖ рижрйЗ рижрйЗри╡рйЗриЧри╛редтАЭ риРриири╛ риХри╣ри┐ риХрйЗ ри╡ри▓рйА риирйЗ риЙри╕ римриЯрйВриП ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЖрикригрйЗ рикрй▒ри▓ри┐риУриВ ри╡рйАри╣ риЕри╢ри░рйЮрйАриЖриВ ри╣рйЛри░ рикри╛ рижри┐рй▒ридрйАриЖриВред риЗрй▒риХ рибрй▒римрйА ри╡рйА риЙри╕ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри░рй▒риЦ рижри┐рй▒ридрйА риЬри┐ри╕ тАШридрйЗ риЙри╕ рижри╛ риири╛риВ риЦрйБригри┐риЖ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ри╕рйАредрижрйЛри╡рйЗриВ риЬригрйЗ рилрйЗри░ римри╛рйЫри╛ри░ риЧриПред риЙри╣ ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА риЕриЬрйЗ ридриХ риЙрй▒риерйЗ ри╣рйА риШрйБрй░рио ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйАред риЕриЬрйЗ риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ риЖрикригрйА риЬрйЗрим риХрй▒риЯрйЗ риЬри╛риг рижри╛ ринрйЛри░ри╛ риЗри▓рио риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйАред рижрйЛри╡рйЗриВ рилри┐ри░ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ риориЧри░ ри▓рй▒риЧ риЧриПред ри╡ри▓рйА риирйЗ риорйМриХри╛ рижрйЗриЦ риХрйЗ римриЯрйВриЖ рилрйЗри░ риЙри╕ рижрйА риЬрйЗрим ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риори▓риХрйЬрйЗ риЬри┐ри╣рйЗ рикри╛ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ред рилрйЗри░ риЭриЯрикриЯ риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ ризрйМриг ридрйЛриВ рилрйЬ риХрйЗ риЙрй▒риЪрйА-риЙрй▒риЪрйА ри░рйМри▓ри╛ рикри╛риЙриг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, тАЭрижрйЗриЦрйЛ, риЗри╕ риирйЗ риорйЗри░ри╛ римриЯрйВриЖ риЪрйЛри░рйА риХри░ ри▓ри┐риЖ ри╣рйИредтАЭриХрйБриЭ риЖрижриорйА рижрйЛри╡ри╛риВ риирйВрй░ рилрйЬ риХрйЗ риХри╛рйЫрйА риХрйЛри▓ ри▓рйИ риЧриПред риХри╛рйЫрйА риирйЗ рижрйЛри╡ри╛риВ рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ римрйЬрйЗ риЧри╣рйБ риири╛ри▓ ри╕рйБригрйАред рилрйЗри░ риЙри╣ риХри╣ри┐риг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, тАЭриЗри╕ рижри╛ рйЮрйИри╕ри▓ри╛ ридри╛риВ римрйЬри╛ ри╕рйМриЦри╛ ри╣рйИред риорйИриирйВрй░ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ, ридрйБри╣ри╛рибрйЗ римриЯрйВриП ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риХрйА ри╣рйИред риЬри┐ри╕ рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╕рй▒риЪрйА риири┐риХри▓рйЗриЧрйА, риЙри╕рйЗ рижри╛ римриЯрйВриЖ ри╣рйИредтАЭри╡рикри╛ри░рйА риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЭри╣рйЫрйВри░ риорйЗри░рйЗ римриЯрйВриП ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЗрй▒риХ ри╣рйЫри╛ри░ ри╕рйЛриирйЗ рижрйАриЖриВ риЕри╢ри░рйЮрйАриЖриВ ри╕рииредтАЭри╡ри▓рйА римрйЛри▓ри┐риЖ, тАЭриири╣рйАриВ риХри╛рйЫрйА ри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐рим, римриЯрйВриЖ риорйЗри░ри╛ ри╣рйИред риЗри╕ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЗрй▒риХ ри╣рйЫри╛ри░ ри╡рйАри╣ риЕри╢ри░рилрйАриЖриВ ри╣рииред риЗри╕ ридрйЛриВ риЗри▓ри╛ри╡ри╛ риорйЗри░рйА рибрй▒римрйА ри╡рйА римриЯрйВриП ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╣рйИ риЬри┐ри╕ тАШридрйЗ риорйЗри░ри╛ риири╛риВ риЦрйБригри┐риЖ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ри╣рйИредтАЭриХри╛рйЫрйА риирйЗ римриЯрйВриЖ риЦрйЛри▓рйНри╣ риХрйЗ рижрйЗриЦри┐риЖ ридри╛риВ ри╡ри▓рйА рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╕ри╣рйА риири┐риХри▓рйАред риХри╛рйЫрйА риирйЗ римриЯрйВриЖ риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ рижрйЗ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ред ри╣рйБриг риЕри▓рйА рижрйА ри╡ри╛ри░рйА риЖриИ риЖрикригри╛ ри╣рйБриири░ рижри┐риЦри╛риЙриг рижрйАред риЙри╣ римрйЛри▓ри┐риЖ, тАЭриорйЗри░рйЗ рижрйЛри╕рид ри╡ри▓рйА риирйЗ ри╡рикри╛ри░рйА риЕридрйЗ риХри╛рйЫрйА рижрйАриЖриВ риЕрй▒риЦри╛риВ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риШрй▒риЯри╛ рикри╛риЗриЖ ри╣рйИред риорйИриВ ридри╛риВ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риирйВрй░ риЙрй▒ри▓рйВ римригри╛риЙриг рижрйА ридри╛риХрид ри░рй▒риЦрижри╛ ри╣ри╛риВредтАЭриЗри╕ ридрйЛриВ римри╛риЕриж риЙри╣ рижрйЛри╡рйЗриВ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии рижрйЗ риори╣рй▒ри▓ рижрйЗ рикри┐риЫри╡ри╛рйЬрйЗ рикрйБрй▒риЬрйЗред ри╡ри╛ри╣ри╡ри╛ ри╕рй░риШригри╛ ри╣риирйЗри░ри╛ рикри╕ри░ри┐риЖ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ри╕рйАред риЕри▓рйА рижри░рй▒риЦрид рижрйЗ риЖри╕ри░рйЗ риХрй░риз риЯрй▒рик риХрйЗ риори╣рй▒ри▓ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЪри▓ри╛ риЧри┐риЖред риЙри╕ рижрйЗ рикри┐рй▒риЫрйЗ-рикри┐рй▒риЫрйЗ ри╡ри▓рйА ри╡рйА риЖ риЧри┐риЖред риЕрй░рижри░ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии ридрйЩридрикрйЛри╢ тАШридрйЗ ри╕рйМриВ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйАред риЗрй▒риХ ри╕рйЗри╡риХ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ рикрйИри░ри╛риВ рижрйА риори╛ри▓ри╢ риХри░ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйАред ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риирйВрй░ рикрйИри░ риори▓ри╡ри╛риЙриг рижрйА риЖрижрид ри╕рйАред риЗри╕рйЗ риири╛ри▓ ри╣рйА риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ риирйАриВриж риЖриЙриВрижрйА ри╕рйАредриЕри▓рйА риирйЗ риЭриЯрикриЯ риЖрикригри╛ ри╣рй▒рие ри╕рйЗри╡риХ рижрйЗ риорйВрй░ри╣ тАШридрйЗ ризри░ри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ рижрйВриЬрйЗ ри╣рй▒рие риири╛ри▓ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ ри╣рй▒рие-рикрйИри░ риХрй▒ри╕ риХрйЗ римрй░риирйНри╣ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗред риЙри╕ рижрйЗ риорйВрй░ри╣ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риХрй▒рикрйЬри╛ ридрйБрй░рии рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ ридри╛риВ риХри┐ риЙри╕ рижрйА риЖри╡ри╛рйЫ римри╛ри╣ри░ риири╛ риири┐риХри▓ ри╕риХрйЗред риЙри╣ риЖрик риЙри╕ рижрйА риери╛риВ римрйИриа риХрйЗ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии рижрйЗ рикрйИри░ри╛риВ рижрйА риори╛ри▓ри╢ риХри░рии ри▓рй▒риЧри╛ред ридрижрйЗ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии рижрйА риЕрй▒риЦ риЦрйБрй▒ри▓рйНри╣ риЧриИред риЙри╕ риирйЗ рижрйЗриЦ ри▓ри┐риЖред риЕри▓рйА ри╕рйЗри╡риХ риЬри┐ри╣рйА риЖри╡ри╛рйЫ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ римрйЛри▓ри┐риЖ, тАЭриЬри╣ри╛риВ рикриири╛ри╣ риирйВрй░ риирйАриВриж риири╛ риЖ ри░ри╣рйА ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗ ридри╛риВ риЗрй▒риХ риорйЫрйЗрижри╛ри░ риХри╣ри╛ригрйА ри╕рйБригри╛ри╡ри╛риВ?тАЭри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЭри╢рйБри░рйВ риХри░рйЛ риХри╣ри╛ригрйАредтАЭриЕри▓рйА риХри╣ри╛ригрйА ри╕рйБригри╛риЙриг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛ред риЙри╕ риирйЗ риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░, риЗри╕ри╛риХ, ри╡ри▓рйА риЕридрйЗ риЖрикригрйА риХри╣ри╛ригрйА ри╣рйВ-рим-ри╣рйВ риЬри┐ри╡рйЗриВ ри╡ри╛рикри░рйА ри╕рйА, риЙри╡рйЗриВ ри╣рйА ри╕рйБригри╛риЙригрйА ри╢рйБри░рйВ риХри░ рижри┐рй▒ридрйАред риЙри╕ риирйЗ ри╕ри┐ри░рйЮ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риЕридрйЗ риЙри╕ рижрйА ри╕ри▓ридриирид рижри╛ риири╛риВ римрижри▓ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ред риХри╣ри╛ригрйА рикрйВри░рйА ри╣рйЛриг тАШридрйЗ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риирйВрй░ риирйАриВриж риЖ риЧриИред риЕри▓рйА риирйЗ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии рижрйА рйЫри░рйАрижри╛ри░ риЬрйБрй▒ридрйА риЪрйБрй▒риХ ри▓риИ риЕридрйЗ риЪрйБрй▒рикриЪри╛рик риЙри╣ рижрйЛри╡рйЗриВ риори╣рй▒ри▓ тАШриЪрйЛриВ римри╛ри╣ри░ риЖ риЧриПред риЙри╣ риЖрикригрйЗ риЕрй▒рибрйЗ тАШридрйЗ рикрйБрй▒риЬрйЗред риЕри▓рйА риирйЗ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии рижрйАриЖриВ риЬрйБрй▒ридрйАриЖриВ риЗри╕ри╛риХ риирйВрй░ ри╡ри┐риЦри╛риИриЖриВ ридри╛риВ риЙри╣ ри╣рйИри░ри╛рии ри░ри╣ри┐ риЧри┐риЖред ри╡ри▓рйА риирйЗ риЙри╕ рижрйА риХри░ри╛риори╛рид рижрйА риЧри╡ри╛ри╣рйА рижри┐рй▒ридрйАред риЙри╕ риирйЗ ри╣ри╛ри░ риорй░рии ри▓риИред риЗри╕ри╛риХ риирйЗ риЧрйБри▓риЕриири╛ри░, риЕри▓рйА риирйВрй░ ри╕рйМриВрик рижри┐рй▒ридрйАредриЙризри░ ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии ри╕рйМриВ риХрйЗ риЙриари┐риЖ ридри╛риВ риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ римрйЬри╛ риЧрйБрй▒ри╕ри╛ риЖриЗриЖ риХри┐ риЙри╕ рижри╛ ри╕рйЗри╡риХ риХри┐рй▒риерйЗ риЪри▓ри╛ риЧри┐риЖред риЙри╕ рижрйА ринри╛ри▓ ри╢рйБри░рйВ ри╣рйЛриИред риЖриЦри░ риЙри╣ рикри▓рй░риШ ри╣рйЗриарйЛриВ риори┐ри▓ри┐риЖред риЙри╕ рижрйЗ ри╣рй▒рие-рикрйИри░ риЕридрйЗ риорйВрй░ри╣ риЦрйЛри▓рйНри╣ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ридри╛риВ риЙри╕ риирйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйА риЖрикримрйАридрйА ри╕рйБригри╛ рижри┐рй▒ридрйАред ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риирйЗ риорйБриири╛рижрйА риХри░ри╡ри╛риИ, тАЭриЬрйЛ риЖрижриорйА риХрй▒ри▓рйНри╣ ри░ри╛рид риорйЗри░рйЗ риори╣рй▒ри▓ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЖ риХрйЗ риорйЗри░рйАриЖриВ риЬрйБрй▒ридрйАриЖриВ риЪрйБрй▒риХ риХрйЗ ри▓рйИ риЧри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риорйИриВ риЙри╕ рижри╛ риЬрйБри░рио риорйБриЖрйЮ риХри░рижри╛ ри╣ри╛риВред риЙри╣ римрйЗриЦрйМрйЮ риорйЗри░рйЗ рижри░римри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╣ри╛рйЫри░ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗредтАЭриЕри▓рйА риирйЗ ри╕рйБригри┐риЖ ридри╛риВ риЙри╣ риЬрйБрй▒ридрйАриЖриВ ри▓рйИ риХрйЗ рижри░римри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╣ри╛рйЫри░ ри╣рйЛ риЧри┐риЖред ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риирйЗ риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ риЗриири╛рио рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ риЕридрйЗ ри╢ри╣ри┐ри░ рижри╛ риХрйЛридри╡ри╛ри▓ римригри╛ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ред ри╕рйБри▓ридри╛рии риирйЗ ри╕рйЛриЪри┐риЖ риХри┐ риРриири╛ риЪри▓ри╛риХ риХрйЛридри╡ри╛ри▓ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗриЧри╛ ридри╛риВ риХрйЛриИ риЪрйЛри░ римриЪ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕риХрйЗриЧри╛ред"},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut. Siapakah yang memainkan watak Noah Newman dalam The Young and the Restless?","answer":"Robert Gillespie Adamson IV yang memainkan watak tersebut dalam The Young and the Restless."},{"question":"р╢╗р╖Фр╢░р╖Тр╢╗ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╖Гр╖Ьр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п?","answer":"р╢╗р╖Фр╢░р╖Тр╢╗ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╖Гр╖Ьр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╖КтАМ р╢╜р╖Рр╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Кр╢зр╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╢╗р╖КтАМ р╢╕р╖Др╢нр╖Пр╢║."},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐:роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпИ роЕро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│, рокрпБроХро│рпВро░рпНроХрпН роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБ роОро╡рпНро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН родрпБрогрпИрокрпБро░ро┐роХро┐ро▒родрпБ тАУ ро╡ро┐ро│роХрпНроХрпБроХ.","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН:рокрпБроХро│рпВро░рпН, роХро░рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЗроирпНрод роКро░ро┐ро▓рпН роЖро▒рпБроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛ройрпН роОройрпНро▒рпБ роТро░рпБ рооро▓рпИ роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. рооро▓рпИропроЯро┐ро╡ро╛ро░родрпНродрпБ роКро░рпИ ро╡рпЗро▓ро╛ропрпБродроорпНрокро╛ро│рпИропроорпН роОройрпНрокро░рпН. роЗроорпНрооро▓рпИрокрпНрокроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЗроХрпНроХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роорпКродрпНродроорпН 12 роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЗро╡рпИ роЕройрпИродрпНродрпБроорпН роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓родрпН родрооро┐ро┤рпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роОро┤рпБродрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│ роорпКро┤ро┐ родрооро┐ро┤ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпН роЗро░рпБ роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЪрпЗро░ рооройрпНройро░рпНроХро│рпН ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХро┐роп роХрпКроЯрпИ рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐роХрпН роХрпВро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роОройро╡рпЗ, роЗроХрпНроХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЪроЩрпНроХ ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпИродрпН родрпЖро░ро┐роирпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│рокрпН рокрпЖро░ро┐родрпБроорпН родрпБрогрпИрокрпБро░ро┐роХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБ -1роорпВродро╛ роЕроорогрпНрогройрпН ропро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпВро░рпНроЪрпЖроЩрпНроХро╛ропрокройрпН роЙро▒рпИропрпНроЖродройрпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро▓ро┐ро░рпБроорпН рокрпКро▒рпИ роороХройрпНрокрпЖро░рпБроЩрпНроХроЯрпБроЩрпНроХрпЛройрпН роороХройрпН (роЗро│роЩрпНроХроЯрпБроЩрпНроХрпЛ (роЗро│роЩрпНроХрпЛ роЖроХ роЕро▒рпБродрпНрод роХро▓рпНропро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпВро░рпИроЪрпН роЪрпЗро░рпНроирпНрод роЪрпЖроЩрпНроХро╛ропрокройрпН роОройрпНройрпБроорпН родрпБро▒ро╡ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроЪрпН роЪрпЗро░ рооройрпНройро░рпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро▓ро┐ро░рпБроорпН рокрпКро▒рпИ роороХройро╛рой рокрпЖро░рпБроЩрпНроХроЯрпБроЩрпНроХрпЛро╡ро┐ройрпН роороХройрпН роЗро│роЩрпНроХроЯрпБроЩрпНроХрпЛ роЗро│ро╡ро░роЪро░рпН роЖро╡родрпИ роорпБройрпНройро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роХрпКроЯрпИ. роЪрпЗро░ роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ родро▓рпИроорпБро▒рпИ роЗродройрпН роорпВро▓роорпН родрпЖро░ро┐роп ро╡роирпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЗродро┐ро▓рпБро│рпНро│ роЕро░роЪро░рпНроХро│рпН рокродро┐ро▒рпНро▒рпБрокрпНрокродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН 7, 8, 9 роЖроорпН рокродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБро░ро┐роп родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро╛роХ роЕроЯрпИропро╛ро│рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│ройро░рпН.роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБ -2, 3ропро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпВро░рпН роЪрпЖроЩрпНроХро╛ропрокрпНрокройрпН(родро╛)ро╡ройрпН рокро┐ройрпНройроорпН роХрпКро▒рпНро▒ройрпНроЕро▒рпБрокро┐родрпНрод роЕродро┐роЯрпНроЯро╛ройроорпНропро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпВро░ро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖроЩрпНроХро╛ропрокройрпБроХрпНроХрпБродрпН родро╛ро╡ройрпН рокро┐ройрпНройройрпН роХрпКро▒рпНро▒ройрпН роОройрпНрокро╡ро░рпН роЕродро┐роЯрпНроЯро╛ройроорпН роХрпКроЯрпБродрпНродродрпБ рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐роХрпН роХрпВро▒рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЕродро┐роЯрпНроЯро╛ройроорпН роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН родро░рпИрокрпНрокроХрпБродро┐ роОройрпНро▒рпБ рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН.роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБ тАУ 4роиро▓ро┐ропрпН) роКро░рпН рокро┐роЯройрпН роХрпБро▒рпБроорпНроороХро│рпНроХрпАро░ро│рпНроХрпКро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНрокро┐родрокро│ро┐роиро▓ро┐ роКро░рпИ роЪрпЗро░рпНроирпНрод рокро┐роЯройрпБроЯрпИроп роЗро│ роороХро│ро╛рой роХрпАро░ройрпН роХрпКро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНрокро┐родрпНрод рокро╛ро│ро┐ропрпИрокрпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роХрпВро▒рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБ тАУ 5роиро▓ро┐(ропрпН) роКро░рпН рокро┐роЯроирпНродрпИ роороХро│рпН роХрпАро░ройрпНроХрпКро▒ро┐ роЕродро┐роЯрпНроЯро╛ройрпНроиро▓ро┐ роКро░рпИ роЪрпЗро░рпНроирпНрод рокро┐роЯроирпНродрпИропро┐ройрпН роороХро│ро╛рой роХрпАро░ройрпН роХрпКро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роХрпКроЯрпБродрпНрод рокроЯрпБроХрпНроХрпИ. роорпЗро▒рпНроХрогрпНроЯро╡ро╛ро▒рпБ роорпКродрпНродроорпН 10 роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роХро┐роЯрпИродрпНродрпБро│рпНро│рой. роЕро╡рпИ роЕройрпИродрпНродрпБроорпН родрооро┐ро┤ро┐ройрпН родрооро┐ро┤ро░ро┐ройрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпИропрпБроорпН роЕро░роЪройро┐ройрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпИропрпБроорпН роОроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ропроорпНрокрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН :тАв роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ роЪрпЗро░ роЕро░роЪро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роХро▓рпНро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯрпБ.тАв┬ароХрпЛ роЖродройрпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро▓ро┐ро░рпБроорпН рокрпКро▒рпИ рокрпЖро░рпБроЩрпНроХроЯрпБроЩрпНроХрпЛ, роЗро│роЩрпНроХроЯрпБроЩрпНроХрпЛ роЖроХро┐роп роЕро░роЪро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН рокрпЖропро░рпНроХро│рпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│рой.тАв┬ароЪрпЗро░ роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ родро▓рпИроорпБро▒рпИ роЗродройрпН роорпВро▓роорпН родрпЖро░ро┐ропро╡роирпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.тАв┬арокродро┐ро▒рпНро▒рпБрокрпНрокродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН 7, 8, 9 роЖроорпН рокродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБро░ро┐роп родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро╛роХ роЕроЯрпИропро╛ро│рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНрод рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│ройро░рпН."},{"question":"88 in├з tv kac cm?","answer":"Signature OLED TV 88 ─░n├з 222 cm 8K ├З├╢z├╝n├╝rl├╝k Ak─▒ll─▒ Ses Tan─▒ma."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е╪з ╪з╪│┘Е ╪з┘Д╪│┘И╪▒╪й ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪з┘П┘Б╪к╪к╪н╪к ╪и╪з╪│┘Е┘Н ┘Е┘Ж ╪г╪│┘Е╪з╪б ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪з┘Д╪н╪│┘Ж┘Й╪Я","answer":" ╪з┘Д╪м┘И╪з╪и: ╪│┘И╪▒╪й ╪з┘Д╪▒┘С╪н┘Е┘Ж."},{"question":"р░кр▒Бр░░р░╛р░гр░╛р░▓р░▓р▒Л р░кр▒Нр░░р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░╡р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░ор▒Бр░Цр▒Нр░пр░ор▒Ир░и р░╡р▒Ир░жр▒Нр░пр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Ор░╡р░░р▒Б?","answer":"р░кр▒Бр░░р░╛р░гр░╛р░▓р░▓р▒Л р░зр░ир▒Нр░╡р░Вр░др░░р░┐, р░Ър░░р░Х, р░╕р▒Бр░╢р▒Нр░░р▒Бр░д р░╡р░Вр░Яр░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░Цр▒Нр░пр░╛р░д р░╡р▒Ир░жр▒Нр░пр▒Бр░▓ р░кр▒Нр░░р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░╡р░и р░Йр░Вр░жр░┐. р░╡р░╛р░░р▒Б р░Жр░пр▒Бр░░р▒Нр░╡р▒Зр░ж р░╡р▒Ир░жр▒Нр░пр░╢р░╛р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Нр░░р░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░кр▒Бр░ир░╛р░жр░┐ р░╡р▒Зр░╕р░┐, р░жр░╛р░ир░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░ер░ор░┐р░Х р░╕р▒Вр░др▒Нр░░р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░░р▒Вр░кр▒Кр░Вр░жр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐ р░░р░Ър░ир░▓р▒Б р░Зр░кр▒Нр░кр░Яр░┐р░Хр▒А р░╡р▒Ир░жр▒Нр░п р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░▓р▒Л р░Йр░кр░пр▒Лр░Чр░┐р░Вр░Ър░мр░бр▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░┐ р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░╕р░╛р░Вр░кр▒Нр░░р░жр░╛р░п р░╡р▒Ир░жр▒Нр░пр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░жр▒Ар░ир░┐р░ир░┐ р░Ер░ир▒Бр░╕р░░р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░░р▒Б."},{"question":"Nibo lс║╣yin n gbe, nibo lс║╣yin wa: Nigba tтАЩAbiс╗Нla atawс╗Нn eeyan rс║╣ kс╗Нju ija si Awolс╗Нwс╗Н ni 1979 (5)","answer":"Idi Theophilous Akindele ko le с╣гe ko ma domi, idi rс║╣ yoo domi, nitori gс║╣gс║╣ bii olori ileeс╣гс║╣ to n с╣гeto ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н ijс╗Нba apapс╗Н, с╗Нga agba ni nileeс╣гс║╣ tс║╣lifoonu patapata, o mс╗Н с╗Мgagun Muritala Muhammed daadaa. с║╕с║╣meji ni wс╗Нn ti pade, с╣гugbс╗Нn с║╣с║╣mejeeji, alaafia kс╗Н ni wс╗Нn fi tuka. Muritala ni olori с║╣ka awс╗Нn ologun to n ri si eto ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н, bii tс║╣lifoonu ni o, ati awс╗Нn irinс╣гс║╣ ti wс╗Нn n lo lati maa fi ba awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н ogun wс╗Нn sс╗Нrс╗Н tabi ileeс╣гс║╣ ologun gbogbo sс╗Нrс╗Н kaakiri, bo с╣гe nilс║╣ yii tabi loke-okun. Nidii eyi, gbogbo igba ni wс╗Нn maa n lo irinс╣гс║╣ oriс╣гiiriс╣гii, gbogbo igba ni wс╗Нn si maa n lo awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ lati ileeс╣гс║╣ eleto ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н yii. Eeyan ko si le с╣гe ooс╣гa lodo ki labс║╣labс║╣ ma mс╗Н, ko sohun ti wс╗Нn yoo с╣гe ti Akindele ko ni i mс╗Н, paapaa nigba to ti di с╗Нga patapata fun ileeс╣гс║╣ naa, to si jс║╣ abс║╣ rс║╣ ni awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Нс╗Нс╣гс║╣ gbogbo ti n jade lс╗Н.Ni с╗Нjс╗Н kan, Akindele jokoo si с╗Нс╗Нfiisi rс║╣, bс║╣с║╣ ni akс╗Нwe agba nileeс╣гс║╣ to n ri si eto inawo ijс╗Нba apapс╗Н, Abdul Atta, fi faili kan ranс╣гс║╣ si i, o ni ko ba oun wo o kiakia, ko si gba oun nimс╗Нran lori ohun to yс║╣ ki oun с╣гe. Faili naa jс║╣ ti ileeс╣гс║╣ ologun, wс╗Нn с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ ko irinс╣гс║╣ kan wс╗Нlu ni, irinс╣гс║╣ naa pс╗Н diс║╣, wс╗Нn si ti ra a, ohun to ku ni ki ijс╗Нba san owo rс║╣. Owo ti wс╗Нn kс╗Н pс╗Н gan-an, с╣гugbс╗Нn eyi kс╗Н ni iс╣гoro ibс║╣, nitori owo kuku wa lapo ijс╗Нba Gowon aye с╗Нjс╗Н naa. Ohun ti Atta fс║╣с║╣ mс╗Н ni boya irinс╣гс║╣ naa to iye owo ti wс╗Нn kс╗Н pe o jс║╣ ko too di pe wс╗Нn sanwo fun wс╗Нn. Attah ti mс╗Н pe bi с║╣ni kan ba wa nibi kan to le sс╗Н bi с╗Нrс╗Н naa ti jс║╣ foun gan-an, Akindele ti i с╣гe с╗Нga agba pata ni с║╣ka eto ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н yii ni. Nitori с║╣ lo с╣гe gbe faili naa fun un. Nigba ti Akindele yс║╣ faili wo sс╗Нtun-un, to yс║╣ с║╣ wo sosi, to yс║╣ awс╗Нn irinс╣гс║╣ ti wс╗Нn darukс╗Н wс╗Нnyi wo, ohun to kс╗Н sinu faili naa ree:тАЬIrinс╣гс║╣ ti wс╗Нn ra yii ti pс║╣ nigba, koda, с╗Нjс╗Н ti lс╗Н lori rс║╣. Bii с╗Нdun meje sс║╣yin, iyс║╣n ni 1963, ni wс╗Нn ti с╣гe irinс╣гс║╣ mi-in, iru eleyii gan-an, с╣гugbс╗Нn to jс║╣ ti igbalode. Awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn ra iru irinс╣гс║╣ bayii wa kan n da owo Naijiria sinu omi okun lasan ni, nitori ohun ti wс╗Нn ra yii ko ni i wulo fс║╣ni kan, tabi fun ileeс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn paapaa, ifowoс╣гofo lasan ni. Ohun ti wс╗Нn tori rс║╣ sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn ra irinс╣гс║╣ yii, irinс╣гс║╣ naa ko ni i с╣гee lo fun un, ko si sidii kan ti с║╣nikс║╣ni fi gbс╗Нdс╗Н ko owo le iru irinс╣гс║╣ bс║╣с║╣, tabi ti yoo ni ki wс╗Нn ko o wa fawс╗Нn. Nitori bс║╣с║╣, с║╣ni yoowu to jс║╣ to ra iru irinс╣гс║╣ yii, tabi to ni ki wс╗Нn ko o wa fun ijс╗Нba Naijiria, tс╗Нhun gbс╗Нdс╗Н jiya, bс║╣с║╣ ni wс╗Нn gbс╗Нdс╗Н gba ninu owo to na danu yii lс╗Нwс╗Н oun funra с║╣, ki wс╗Нn ni ko san ninu owo irinс╣гс║╣ buruku to ra, ko le mс╗Н pe ohun ti oun с╣гe ko dara.тАЭс╗Мdun 1970 leleyii с╣гс║╣lс║╣, Akindele ko ti i pade Muritala ri, ohun to kan mс╗Н ni pe ileeс╣гс║╣ ITT lo ta irinс╣гс║╣ buruku bс║╣с║╣ fun wс╗Нn.N loun ba kс╗Нwe, o si fi faili ranс╣гс║╣ pada si с║╣ni to gbe e fun un. Oun ko ranti с╗Нrс╗Н naa mс╗Н, o n ba iс╣гс║╣ rс║╣ lс╗Н. O to с╗Нjс╗Н kс║╣rin ti с╗Нrс╗Н yii с╣гс║╣lс║╣ ni awс╗Нn с╗Нga с╣гс╗Нja meji ba wс╗Н с╗Нс╗Нfiisi rс║╣ lai kan ilс║╣kun, bс║╣с║╣ ni wс╗Нn ko si duro lс╗Нdс╗Н sс║╣kitiri с║╣ ko le lс╗Нс╗Н sс╗Н fun с╗Нga rс║╣ pe с║╣ni kan fс║╣с║╣ waa ri i, wс╗Нn ja wс╗Нle bс║╣с║╣ ni. Asiko naa jс║╣ asiko ti ogun abс║╣le с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ pari, to jс║╣ ko si ibi ti awс╗Нn eeyan ti ri с╣гс╗Нja ti wс╗Нn ki i с╣гe с║╣rujс║╣jс║╣, agaga bi wс╗Нn ba waa jс║╣ с╗Нga с╣гс╗Нja bс║╣с║╣, kaluku yoo fi ara с╣гoko ni. Awс╗Нn с╣гс╗Нja eleyii tilс║╣ waa yatс╗Н, с╗Нkan ninu wс╗Нn ga firigbс╗Нn, ibinu ni wс╗Нn si tun n ba bс╗Н, ko sс║╣ni kan ti wс╗Нn bi daadaa ti yoo duro loju с╗Нna, kaluku sa danu ni. Laye igba naa, ko sс║╣ni ti yoo ni Lebe ko pс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Нс╗Нre, ko с╣гeni ti yoo duro beere с╗Нrс╗Н lс╗Нwс╗Н с╣гс╗Нja, ohun ti с╣гс╗Нja ba с╣гe, aс╣гegbe ni. Nitori bс║╣с║╣ lo с╣гe jс║╣ ko sс║╣ni kan to le da awс╗Нn с╣гс╗Нja meji yii duro, с╗Нkan jс║╣ с╗Нga gidi, ikeji si jс║╣ с╗Нс╗Нfisa to tс║╣le e.Eyi to jс║╣ с╗Нga yii, Kс╗Нnс║╣eli ni ninu iс╣гс║╣ с╣гс╗Нja, awс╗Нn с╗Нga igba naa niyс║╣n. Bo с╣гe wс╗Нle lo leju koko mс╗Н Akindele, iyс║╣n ti ko si ti i mс╗Н ohun to n с╣гс║╣lс║╣, ti с║╣ni to si wa siwaju с║╣ ko sс╗Н pe oun n bс╗Н tс║╣lс║╣, ti ko si mс╗Н с║╣ni to jс║╣, niс╣гс║╣ lo dorikodo sibi iwe to n ka, nitori awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn wс╗Нle naa ko kuku ki i. Nigba ti ko wo oju wс╗Нn yii, eyi to jс║╣ с╗Нga fibinu ju faili kan si ori tabili с║╣. Lс║╣yin naa lo fi ohun ramuramu sс╗Н pe тАШNigba mi-in, ma maa kс╗Н ikс╗Нkukс╗Н bayii nipa с║╣ka ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н ileeс╣гс║╣ ologun o, nijс╗Н mi-ni ti o ba tun с╣гe bс║╣с║╣, mo maa ni ki wс╗Нn yinbс╗Нn pa с║╣ ni!тАЩ Akindele naa ki i с╣гe eeyan daadaa kan tс╗Нrс╗Н ba da bс║╣с║╣, oun naa ki i pс║╣с║╣ binu rara. Nigba ti с╗Нga yii ti sс╗Н ohun to sс╗Н yii, inu ti bi oun naa kс╗Нja aala. O jс╗Н pe ohun to dun un ju ni pe bawo ni с║╣ni kan ti oun ko mс╗Н ri yoo с╣гe  deede ja wс╗Н с╗Нс╗Нfiisi oun, oun naa toun jс║╣ с╗Нga pata laaye oun, ti yoo si maa halс║╣ bayii mс╗Н oun.N lo ba dide naro si с╣гс╗Нja, ohun to si sс╗Н fun un ni pe. тАЬWo o, с╗Мgbс║╣ni Kс╗Нnс║╣eli, bi ki i baa с╣гe aс╣гс╗Н ijс╗Нba to o wс╗Н sс╗Нrun, с╣гe o mс╗Н pe oo kan le deede ja wс╗Н с╗Нс╗Нfiisi mi ko o maa с╣гe bo o ti n с╣гe yii! Nitori bс║╣с║╣, jade nibi yii, ko o sare jade bo o с╣гe sare wс╗Нle, ki ibinu emi naa too di nnkan mi-in mс╗Н с║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н. Nigba mi-in, ki o si kс╗Н с║╣kс╗Н iwa с╗Нmс╗Нluabi, pe bi eeyan ba de с╗Нdс╗Н с║╣ni ti ko mс╗Н ri, eeyan n huwa daadaa ni. с╗Мga с╣гс╗Нja ko mс╗Н pe с║╣ni kan yoo sс╗Н bс║╣с║╣ soun laelae, o si wo Akindele lati oke de isalс║╣, bo si ti n wo o yii, akс╗Нda to tс║╣le e ti mu с╗Нwс╗Н lс╗Н sibi bс║╣liiti с║╣, o fс║╣с║╣ yс╗Н ibс╗Нn to fi ha sibс║╣. с╣вugbс╗Нn с╗Нga rс║╣ sс╗Н pe ko ma yс╗Н ara с║╣ lс║╣nu, o ni ko jс║╣ kawс╗Нn maa lс╗Н, n lawс╗Нn mejeeji ba fibinu jade bi wс╗Нn ti fibinu wс╗Нle. Wс╗Нn n lс╗Н kemс╗Нkemс╗Н. Igba ti wс╗Нn lс╗Н tan ni awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ to ti sa lс╗Н tс║╣lс║╣ too bс║╣rс║╣ si i pada wa, wс╗Нn waa wo Akindele, paapaa nigba ti wс╗Нn ko gbс╗Н iro ibс╗Нn.Bi awс╗Нn с╣гс╗Нja naa ti jade ni Akindele pe Attah to gbe iс╣гс║╣ fun un nijс╗Нsi pada, lo ba с╣гalaye pe ki lo n с╣гe, с╗Нga с╣гс╗Нja kan ma с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ wa sibi yii to ni oun yoo yinbс╗Нn foun ma ni. Attah ni ko juwe с╣гс╗Нja naa, nigba to si juwe с║╣, Attah ni, с╗Мgagun M.R. Muhammed niyс║╣n, oun ni olori с║╣ka eto ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н awс╗Нn с╣гс╗Нja. O ni ki Akindele ma dahun, ko maa с╣гiс╣гс║╣ tirс║╣ lс╗Н, ko с╣гaa mс╗Н bi yoo ti maa с╣гe pс║╣lu wс╗Нn, pe oniwahala kan ni wс╗Нn. Lс║╣yin eyi ni akс╗Нwe agba fun ileeс╣гс║╣ tiwс╗Нn naa, с╗Мgbс║╣ni Lawson, pada waa ba Akindele, o ni ko ma maa с╣гe aya gbangba bс║╣с║╣ yс║╣n mс╗Н si awс╗Нn с╣гс╗Нja o, pe to ba jс║╣ wс╗Нn yinbс╗Нn pa a bс║╣с║╣, ko si ohun ti yoo с╣гс║╣lс║╣ o, nitori awс╗Нn ni wс╗Нn n с╣гejс╗Нba, awс╗Нn nijс╗Нba wa lс╗Нwс╗Н rс║╣, ohun ti wс╗Нn ba si с╣гe, aс╣гegbe ni o. Akindele dupс║╣ dupс║╣, o loun gbс╗Н, oun yoo maa с╣гс╗Н ara oun, igba akс╗Нkс╗Н si niyс║╣n ti oun ati Muritala kс╗Нkс╗Н pade ara wс╗Нn. Ni 1970.Ko si с║╣ni ti yoo gbс╗Н iroyin iku bс║╣с║╣ ti yoo tun maa с╣гe agidi, afi to ba с╣гe pe nnkan mi-in wa nibс║╣ fun tс╗Нhun nikan ni. Firifiri ti Akindele ri yii ti mu ko sс╗Н pe lс╗Нjс╗Н mi-in ti oun ba tun ni anfaani lati pade Muritala, oun yoo ri i pe awс╗Нn ko fija tuka, yoo si le ri i pe eeyan daadaa loun naa i с╣гe. с╣вugbс╗Нn lс║╣yin ti wс╗Нn ti rira ni 1970 yii, wс╗Нn ko tun rira mс╗Н, afi ni 1973, с╗Нdun kс║╣ta lс║╣yin ti wс╗Нn ti kс╗Нkс╗Н pade lakс╗Нс╗Нkс╗Н. Ipo kan naa ti wс╗Нn wa nijс╗Нsi naa ni awс╗Нn mejeeji tun wa. Akindele ni olori с║╣ka ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н to n ri si с╗Нrс╗Н tс║╣lifoonu jake-jado Naijiria, Muritala si ni olori eto ibanisс╗Нrс╗Н nileeс╣гс║╣ awс╗Нn ologun ilс║╣ wa. Ijс╗Нba apapс╗Н lo ni iс╣гс║╣ to gbe awс╗Нn mejeeji pade, ohun to si ta koko nibс║╣ ni pe Akindele ko mс╗Н pe Muritala ni yoo ba pade, Muritala naa ko mс╗Н pe Akindele naa loun yoo tun ba pade, afi bawс╗Нn mejeeji с╣гe tun pade ara wс╗Нn ganboro. O с╣гe ni laaanu pe ipade naa ko tun mu eeso rere kan dani, ajatuka ni ti agbaarin ni wс╗Нn fi i с╣гe!с║╕ maa ka a lс╗Н lс╗Нsс║╣ to n bс╗Н."},{"question":"Londra'da ka├з b├╢lge var?","answer":"Londra birbirini kaplayan ├зemberler ┼Яeklinde 6 b├╢lgeye ayr─▒lm─▒┼Яt─▒r; ula┼Я─▒m ├╝cretleri bu b├╢lgelere g├╢re de─Яi┼Яmektedir."},{"question":"р░И р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░кр░жр░╛р░▓р░Хр▒Б р░╡р▒Нр░пр░др░┐р░░р▒Зр░Х р░кр░жр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐. р░░р▒Жр░Вр░бр▒Б р░кр░жр░╛р░▓р░ир▒В р░Йр░кр░пр▒Лр░Чр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╕р▒Кр░Вр░др░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.р░Йр░жр░╛ :р░Ер░Ьр░╛р░Чр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░д ├Ч р░Ьр░╛р░Чр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░др░ир▒Зр░ир▒Б р░П р░╡р░┐р░╖р░пр░ор▒Ир░ир░╛ р░Ьр░╛р░Чр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░др░Чр░╛ р░кр░░р░┐р░╢р▒Ар░▓р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░ир▒Б. р░Ор░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░бр▒В р░Ер░Ьр░╛р░Чр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░др░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░бр░ир▒Б.р░Е) р░ир▒Ар░др░┐ р░Ж) р░ир░┐р░╕р▒Нр░╕р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Нр░Чр░Вр░З) р░╕р▒Бр░Цр░Вр░И) р░╢р░╛р░Вр░др░┐р░Й) р░ир░┐р░Чр░░р▒Нр░╡р░┐р░К) р░Ер░Вр░Чр▒Ар░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░О) р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░нр░пр░В","answer":"р░Е) р░ир▒Ар░др░┐ ├Ч р░Ер░╡р░┐р░ир▒Ар░др░┐р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░В : р░ир▒Ар░др░┐ р░Хр░▓р░╡р░╛р░░р▒Б, р░Ер░╡р░┐р░ир▒Ар░др░┐р░ир░┐ р░Ър▒Вр░Ър░┐ тАШр░╕р░╣р░┐р░Вр░Ър░▓р▒Зр░░р▒Б.р░Ж) р░ир░┐р░╕р▒Нр░╕р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Нр░Чр░В ├Ч р░╕р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░Вр░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░В : р░ир▒Зр░ир▒Б р░ир░┐р░╕р▒Нр░╕р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░ир▒Б, р░╕р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р░┐р░Вр░Ър░ир▒Б.р░З) р░╕р▒Бр░Цр░В ├Ч р░Хр░╖р▒Нр░Яр░Вр░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░В : р░╕р▒Бр░Цр░В р░╡р▒Жр░Вр░мр░бр░┐ р░Хр░╖р▒Нр░Яр░В р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░ир░┐ р░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Нр░др░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░┐.р░И) р░╢р░╛р░Вр░др░┐ ├Ч р░Ер░╢р░╛р░Вр░др░┐р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░В : р░кр▒Нр░░р░кр░Вр░Ър░Вр░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐ р░Ер░╢р░╛р░Вр░др░┐ р░кр▒Лр░╡р░╛р░▓р░Вр░Яр▒З р░╢р░╛р░Вр░др░┐ р░жр▒Зр░╡р░др░ир▒Б р░Жр░╣р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░ир░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░┐.р░Й) р░ир░┐р░Чр░░р▒Нр░╡р░┐ ├Ч р░Чр░░р▒Нр░╡р░┐р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░В : р░ир░┐р░Чр░░р▒Нр░╡р░┐ р░Жр░ир░Вр░жр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир▒А, р░Чр░░р▒Нр░╡р░┐ р░жр▒Бр░Гр░Цр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░др░кр▒Нр░кр░Х р░кр▒Кр░Вр░жр▒Бр░др░╛р░бр▒Б.р░К) р░Ер░Вр░Чр▒Ар░Хр░╛р░░р░В ├Ч р░Ер░ир░Вр░Чр▒Ар░Хр░╛р░░р░Вр░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░В : р░ир░╛ р░Ър░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Б р░╡р░┐р░╖р░пр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Ер░ор▒Нр░ор░╛р░ир░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░▓ р░ор░зр▒Нр░п р░Зр░Вр░Хр░╛ р░Ер░Вр░Чр▒Ар░Хр░╛р░░р░В, р░Ер░ир░Вр░Чр▒Ар░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░Йр░Вр░жр░┐.р░О) р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░нр░пр░В ├Ч р░нр░пр░Вр░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░В : р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░нр░пр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░ор░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░бр▒Зр░╡р░╛р░░р░Вр░Яр▒З р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р░┐р░Хр▒А р░нр░пр░В."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ╪╣╪з╪╡┘Е╪й ╪е╪│╪и╪з┘Ж┘К╪з ╪Я","answer":"┘Е╪п╪▒┘К╪п"},{"question":"цмбуБоцЦЗчлауВТшкнуВУуБзуАБуБЭуБохЖЕхо╣уБлщБйуБЧуБЯуВ┐уВдуГИуГлуВТф╗ШуБСуБжуБПуБауБХуБДя╝Ъ уАМцОиуБЧуАНуБпхе╜уБНуБкуВвуВдуГЙуГлуВДф┐│хДкуАБш╢гхС│уБкуБйуБоуБУуБиуБзуБЩуАВхМЧц╡╖щБУуБоцЬнх╣Мх╕ВуБлуБВуВЛф┐ЭшВ▓хЬТуБпуАБхГНуБДуБжуБДуВЛф║║уБЯуБбуБМуАМцОиуБЧуАНуБоуВ│уГ│уВ╡уГ╝уГИуВДцШачФ╗уБкуБйуБлшбМуБПуБЯуВБуБлф╗Хф║ЛуВТф╝СуВАуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуВЛуАМцОиуБЧф╝СцЪЗуАНуВТцЭецЬИуБЛуВЙхзЛуВБуБ╛уБЩуАВф╝СуВУуБзуВВч╡жцЦЩуВТуВВуВЙуБЖуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуБ╛уБЩуАВц│Хх╛ЛуБзц▒║уБ╛уБгуБжуБДуВЛф╝СуБ┐уБоуБ╗уБЛуБлуАМцОиуБЧф╝СцЪЗуАНуБз1х╣┤уБл10цЧеф╝СуВАуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуБ╛уБЩуАВуБУуБоф┐ЭшВ▓хЬТуБпуАБцЧецЫЬцЧеуБкуБйуВВф╗Хф║ЛуБМуБВуБгуБжх┐ЩуБЧуБДуБЯуВБуАБхГНуБПф║║уБлшЗкхИЖуБохе╜уБНуБкуБУуБиуВТце╜уБЧуВУуБзуБ╗уБЧуБДуБишАГуБИуБжуАБуБУуБоф╝СуБ┐уВТф╜ЬуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхГНуБДуБжуБДуВЛф║║уБпуАМуГЗуВгуВ║уГЛуГ╝уГйуГ│уГЙуБМхе╜уБНуБкуБоуБзуАБцШачФ╗уБоуГИуВдуГ╗уВ╣уГИуГ╝уГкуГ╝уБоф╣ЧуВКчЙйуБкуБйуВТце╜уБЧуБ┐уБЯуБДуБзуБЩуАВф╗Хф║ЛуВТуВВуБгуБищаСх╝╡уВЛуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуВЛуБицАЭуБДуБ╛уБЩуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВ","answer":"хе╜уБНуБкуВвуВдуГЙуГлуБоуВ│уГ│уВ╡уГ╝уГИуБкуБйуБзф╗Хф║ЛуВТф╝СуВБуВЛуАМцОиуБЧф╝СцЪЗуАН"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Б┘К ╪г┘К ╪п┘И┘Д╪й ╪н╪п┘К╪л╪й ┘И┘П┘Д╪п╪к ╪з┘Д┘Б┘К╪▓┘К╪з╪ж┘К╪й ┘И╪з┘Д┘Г┘К┘Е┘К╪з╪ж┘К╪й ┘Е╪з╪▒┘К ┘Г┘И╪▒┘К╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪и┘И┘Д┘Ж╪п╪з"},{"question":"Gс╗Лnс╗Л bс╗е ajс╗еjс╗е a: \\"Interlibrary mgbazinye (abbreviated ILL, na mgbe с╗еfс╗Нdс╗е a na-akpс╗Н interloan, akwс╗еkwс╗Н nnyefe, ma с╗Н bс╗е akwс╗еkwс╗Н с╗Нkс╗Нnс╗Н) bс╗е с╗Нrс╗е site n'nke a onye с╗Нrс╗е nke otu n'с╗Нb├б akwс╗еkwс╗Н nwere ike gbaziri akwс╗еkwс╗Н ma с╗Н bс╗е na-enweta photocopies nke akwс╗еkwс╗Н na-ekesс╗Лpde с╗Нzс╗Н n'с╗Нb├б akwс╗еkwс╗Н\\"? Isiokwu a bс╗е Interlibrary loan.","answer":"\\"Olee mgbe с╗Лgbaziri ihe n'с╗Н╠Бb├б akwс╗еkwс╗Н si arс╗е с╗Нrс╗е?\\""},{"question":"рк╢рлЛ ркЧрлНрк░рлЗркирлА ркПркирк╛ркЯрлЛркорлАркП ркдрлЗркирк╛ рк╕ркоркЧрлНрк░ ркХрк╛рк░рлНркпркХрк╛рк│ ркжрк░ркорк┐ркпрк╛рки рк╡рк┐рк╡рк┐ркзркдрк╛ ркЕркирлЗ рккрлНрк░ркдрк┐ркирк┐ркзрк┐ркдрлНрк╡ркирк╛ ркорлБркжрлНркжрк╛ркУркирлЗ ркХрлЗрк╡рлА рк░рлАркдрлЗ рк╕ркВркмрлЛркзрк┐ркд ркХрк░рлНркпрк╛ ркЫрлЗ?","answer":"Grey's Anatomy has made an effort to feature a diverse cast of characters, including people of color, LGBTQ+ individuals, and characters with disabilities. While the show has faced criticism for its portrayal of certain groups, it has also been praised for its efforts to represent a wider range of experiences."},{"question":"H├гy viс║┐t mс╗Щt b├аi b├бo c├│ thс╗Г sс╗н dс╗еng ti├кu ─Сс╗Б sau ─С├вy: Ti├кu ─Сс╗Б: Cс║гnh s├бt ├Ъc 'ph├б ├вm m╞░u cho nс╗Х m├бy bay'","answer":"├Фng ─С╞░a ra ph├бt ng├┤n sau khi bс╗Сn ng╞░с╗Эi bс╗Л bс║пt trong c├бc cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Щt k├нch khс║пp Sydney.C├бc nh├а ─Сiс╗Бu tra cho biс║┐t hс╗Н c├│ th├┤ng tin rс║▒ng ├вm m╞░u cho nс╗Х m├бy bay li├кn quan ─Сс║┐n viс╗Зc sс╗н dс╗еng mс╗Щt \\"thiс║┐t bс╗Л nс╗Х tс╗▒ tс║бo\\".├Фng Turnbull n├│i rс║▒ng c├бc cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Щt k├нch tiс║┐n h├аnh theo \\"chiс║┐n dс╗Лch chс╗Сng khс╗зng bс╗С chung\\".├Ъc ph├б ─С╞░с╗гc '├вm m╞░u khс╗зng bс╗С' Ng├аy Gi├бng sinh├Ъc: Cс╗йu rс║бn san h├┤ Great Barrier thс║┐ n├аo?├Фng n├│i th├кm rс║▒ng an ninh ─Сang ─С╞░с╗гc t─Гng c╞░с╗Эng tс║бi c├бc s├вn bay nс╗Щi ─Сс╗Лa v├а quс╗Сc tс║┐.C├бc cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Щt k├нch diс╗Еn ra с╗Я c├бc v├╣ng ngoс║бi ├┤ cс╗зa Sydney: Surry Hills, Lakemba, Wiley Park v├а Punchbowl, ABC t╞░с╗Эng thuс║нt.Mс╗йc ─Сс╗Щ ─Сe dс╗Нa khс╗зng bс╗С tс║бi ├Ъc ─Сang с╗Я mс╗йc \\"c├│ thс╗Г xс║гy ra\\".Cс║гnh s├бt tr╞░с╗Яng Li├кn bang ├Ъc Andrew Colvin n├│i rс║▒ng bс╗Сn ng╞░с╗Эi ─С├аn ├┤ng bс╗Л bс║пt li├кn quan ─Сс║┐n mс╗Щt ├вm m╞░u \\"lс║еy cс║гm hс╗йng tс╗л Hс╗Уi gi├бo\\".\\"Trong nhс╗пng ng├аy gс║зn ─С├вy, ch├║ng t├┤i nhс║нn ─С╞░с╗гc tin cho thс║еy mс╗Щt sс╗С ng╞░с╗Эi с╗Я Sydney ─Сang c├│ ├вm m╞░u tiс║┐n h├аnh mс╗Щt cuс╗Щc tс║еn c├┤ng khс╗зng bс╗С sс╗н dс╗еng thiс║┐t bс╗Л nс╗Х tс╗▒ tс║бo\\", ├┤ng n├│i trong mс╗Щt cuс╗Щc hс╗Нp b├бo."},{"question":"роЪрпЗ роХрпБро╡рпЗро░ро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"роТро╡рпНро╡рпКро░рпБ роЕроирпАродро┐ропрпИропрпБроорпН роХрогрпНроЯрпБ роЖродрпНродро┐ро░родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐ро░рпНроирпНродрпБрокрпЛро╡ро╛ропро╛ройро╛ро▓рпН, роирпА роОройродрпБ родрпЛро┤ройрпН."},{"question":"╨Ч╨░╨║╤Ц╨╜╤З╨╕ ╤А╨╡╤З╨╡╨╜╨╜╤П:  ╨С╤А╨░╨▓ ╤Г╤З╨░╤Б╤В╤М ╤Г ╤З╨╡╨╝╨┐╤Ц╨╛╨╜╨░╤В╤Ц ╤Б╨▓╤Ц╤В╤Г 2002 ╤А╨╛╨║╤Г, ╤П╨║╨╕╨╣ ╨┐╤А╨╕╨╣╨╝╨░╨╗╨╕ ╨п╨┐╨╛╨╜╤Ц╤П ╤Ц ╨Я╤Ц╨▓╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░ ╨Ъ╨╛╤А╨╡╤П, ","answer":"╤Г╤В╤Ц╨╝ ╨╜╨░ ╨╝╤Г╨╜╨┤╤Ц╨░╨╗╤Ц ╨▒╤Г╨▓ ╨╖╨┤╨╡╨▒╤Ц╨╗╤М╤И╨╛╨│╨╛ ╤А╨╡╨╖╨╡╤А╨▓╨╜╨╕╨╝ ╨│╤А╨░╨▓╤Ж╨╡╨╝ ╤Ц ╨▓╨╕╤Е╨╛╨┤╨╕╨▓ ╨╜╨░ ╨┐╨╛╨╗╨╡ ╨╗╨╕╤И╨╡ ╨▓ ╨╛╨┤╨╜╤Ц╨╣ ╨│╤А╤Ц ╨│╤А╤Г╨┐╨╛╨▓╨╛╨│╨╛ ╨╡╤В╨░╨┐╤Г, ╤П╨║╨╕╨╣ ╨╣╨╛╨│╨╛ ╨║╨╛╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨╜╨╡ ╨┐╨╛╨┤╨╛╨╗╨░╨╗╨░."},{"question":"╨в╥п╤И ╤В╤Г╤Г╤А╨░╨╗╤Г╤Г ╨║╤Л╨╖╤Л╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╤Д╨░╨║╤В╤Л╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡ ╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╥г╨▒╤Л?","answer":"╨Ъ╤Н╤Н╨┤╨╡ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╨░╤А ╨╛╨╣╨│╨╛╨╜╤Г╨┐ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╕╨┐,╤В╥п╤И╤В╙й╤А╥п╨╜╨┤╙й╨│╥п ╤В╨░╤В╤В╤Г╤Г ╨║╤Л╤П╨╗╨┤╨░╤А╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨╡╨╣╤В╨░╨░╨╜╤Л╤И ╨▒╨╕╤А╙й╙й╨╜╥п ╨║╙й╤А╨│╙й╨╜╥п╨╜ ╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╤И╨░╤В. ╨з╤Л╨╜╨┤╤Л╨│╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨╕╨╖ ╨║╨░╤З╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╤А ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╙й╤А╨│╙й╨╜ ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕╨╗╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕ ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╨║╙й╤А╙й╨▒╥п╨╖. ╨С╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜╤Г ╤Б╨╕╨╖ ╨░╨╗ ╨╢╙й╨╜╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╤Г╨╜╤Г╤В╤Г╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╤Б╤Л╨╖, ╨░╨╗ ╤Н╨╝╨╕ ╨╝╤Н╤Н ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛ ╨╛╤И╨╛╨╗ ╨╛╨▒╤А╨░╨╖╨┤╤Л ╤Б╨░╨║╤В╨░╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐, ╨║╙й╤А╨│╙й╨╖╙й ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡╤В."},{"question":" ╪┤┘Ж┘И ┘З┘К ╪л╪з┘Ж┘К ╪з┘Г╪и╪▒ ╪п┘И┘Д┘З ╪╣╪▒╪и┘К┘З ┘Е┘Ж ╪н┘К╪л ╪з┘Д┘Е╪│╪з╪н┘З ╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪м╪▓╪з╪ж╪▒"},{"question":"Birle┼Яik Krall─▒k hangi ├╝lkelerinden olu┼Яmaktad─▒r?","answer":"Birle┼Яik Krall─▒k, resmi ad─▒yla B├╝y├╝k Britanya ve Kuzey ─░rlanda Birle┼Яik Krall─▒─Я─▒, ─░ngiltere, ─░sko├зya, Galler ve Kuzey ─░rlanda olmak ├╝zere d├╢rt kurucu ├╝lkeden olu┼Яan bir devlettir. B├╝y├╝k Britanya terimi ise sadece; ─░ngiltere, ─░sko├зya ve GallerтАЩi kapsamaktad─▒r."},{"question":"H├гy viс║┐t mс╗Щt ─Сoс║бn v─Гn ├нt nhс║еt 200 chс╗п dс╗▒a tr├кn nс╗Щi dung ─С╞░с╗гc n├│i tс╗Ыi trong c├вu sau: Top 5 xe tay ga gi├б с╗Хn ─Сс╗Лnh, s├бnh cс║бnh vс╗Ыi Honda Vision с╗Я Viс╗Зt Nam","answer":" Yamaha Janus thiс║┐t kс║┐ thс╗Эi trang, trс║╗ trung n─Гng ─Сс╗Щng, c├│ trang bс╗Л hiс╗Зn ─Сс║бi vс╗Ыi hс╗З thс╗Сng ─Сс╗Щng c╞б Blue Core, mang lс║бi hiс╗Зu suс║еt linh hoс║бt v├а tiс║┐t kiс╗Зm x─Гng. Xe c├│ ch├мa kh├│a th├┤ng minh, cс╗Сp ─Сс╗▒ng ─Сс╗У rс╗Щng, rс║еt ph├╣ hс╗гp vс╗Ыi mс║лu h├мnh mс╗Щt xe tay ga ─С├┤ thс╗Л. Gi├б xe lс║бi hс╗гp l├╜ v├а с╗Хn ─Сс╗Лnh, ├нt ch├кnh gi├б.  Yamaha Latte l├а d├▓ng xe tay ga mс╗Ыi ─С╞░с╗гc ph├вn phс╗Сi tс║бi thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng Viс╗Зt Nam, thiс║┐t kс║┐ theo phong c├бch xe tay ga ch├вu ├Вu, sang chс║гnh nh╞░ng gi├б b├бn ra lс║бi rс║еt dс╗Е chс╗Лu. Ch├мa kh├│a th├┤ng minh, nс║пp b├мnh x─Гng ─Сс║╖t ph├нa tr╞░с╗Ыc, cс╗Сp ─Сс╗▒ng ─Сс╗У rс╗Щng 37 l├нt kh├┤ng k├йm vс╗Ыi LEAD bao nhi├кu, mс║╖t ─Сс╗Уng hс╗У ─Сiс╗Зn tс╗н ─Сс║╣p, v├а ─Сс╗Щng c╞б Blue Core tiс║┐t kiс╗Зm x─Гng┬аl├а nhс╗пng t├нnh n─Гng ─С╞░с╗гc ╞░a chuс╗Щng tr├кn d├▓ng xe tay ga Latte.  SYM New Attila 125 thiс║┐t kс║┐ ─Сс║нm chс║еt nс╗п t├нnh, ─Сс╗Сn tin ph├бi ─Сс║╣p vс╗Ыi c├бc ─С╞░с╗Эng n├йt mс╗Бm mс║бi, ─Сu├┤i xe tr├▓n trс╗Лa cao cс║еp, ─Сс╗Уng hс╗У LCD hiс╗Зn ─Сс║бi, cс╗Сp ─Сс╗▒ng ─Сс╗У rс╗Щng, c├╣ng bс╗Щ ─Сс╗Щng c╞б vс║нn h├аnh nhс║╣ nh├аng v├а c├│ gi├б b├бn ra hс╗гp l├╜.  Thiс║┐t kс║┐ lс║еy cс║гm hс╗йng tс╗л d├▓ng xe ga Burgman huyс╗Бn thoс║бi, Impulse cс╗зa Suzuki nh├мn cao cс║еp vс╗Ыi ─Сс║зu xe c├б t├нnh. Ph├нa tr╞░с╗Ыc xe c├│ hс╗Щc ─Сс╗▒ng ─Сс╗У, trong khi d╞░с╗Ыi y├кn ngс╗Уi l├а khoang ─Сс╗▒ng ─Сс╗У rс╗Щng, ─Сс╗Уng hс╗У ─Сiс╗Бu khiс╗Гn loс║бi mс╗Ыi hiс╗Зn ─Сс║бi, trong khi ─Сс╗Щng c╞б xe loс║бi 125 FI vс║нn h├аnh mс║бnh mс║╜ v├а hiс╗Зu quс║г.  Piaggio Zip 100 thiс║┐t kс║┐ thс╗Эi trang, kiс╗Гu d├бng ─Сс╗Щc ─С├бo, gс╗Нn nhс║╣. Xe sс╗Я hс╗пu ─Сс╗Щng c╞б Hi-PER4 Piaggio Zip 100 4T xy lanh ─С╞бn, c├│ hiс╗Зu suс║еt cao, ─Сс║бt ti├кu chuс║йn kh├н thс║гi Euro 3. Nguс╗Уn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/top-5-xe-tay-ga-gia-on-dinh-sanh-canh-voi-honda-vision-o-viet-nam-1382478.ngnNguс╗Уn: https://nongthonviet.com.vn/top-5-xe-tay-ga-gia-on-dinh-sanh-canh-voi-honda-vision-o-viet-nam-1382478.ngn "},{"question":"K├н ni or├║kс╗Н g├│m├нn├а ├аkс╗Н╠Бkс╗Н╠Б n├н ├мp├нnlс║╣╠А Abia?","answer":"Ogbonnaya Onu ni."},{"question":"Ngiyabonga sayitsheni. Ukube anifikanga ngabe indaba yamiisingumlando. Ngibonga kakhulu sayitsheni.Ubonga ngakhona Duma kodwa nguwe oyimbangela yalokhu.Usho ukuthini sayitsheni? Yimi yini ovimba intuthuko lapha kulendawo?Uyakhumbula ngikubuza ukuthi uyathathisa na enkosini umauzokwenza utho endaweni yayo? Wathini wena? Angithi wadazainkani? Nenhlangano yakho yaphinde yakuyala ngokuhlonipha inkosi,wena wenza okuthandwa nguwe. Bafile-ke manje abantu. UMbandlwasiyezwa ukuthi ubengungqa phambili ekutheni wenze lokhuobukwenza. Naye uDlamini kuyavela ukuthi ubethukuthela aze enzeizinto ezingalungile njengakho ukushaya uMbandlwa.Angimsoli-ke yena kakhulu ngoba ubehlukunyezwa ngukubona wenauthela inkosi yakhe ngothuli.(ukuzithoba kuyadlondlobala. Useze watshekisa ngisho nekhanda.Izandla zakhe ulokhu ezihlanganisa njengomuntu okhuluma nomuntuamhlonipha ngendlela exakile) Ngiyezwa sayitsheni. (athule kancane)Sekwenzekile-ke okubuhlungu sayitsheni. Ngiyaphinda ngithi velesekonakele. Manje, ngizocela nigcine ukuthula endaweni, minasengizowuyeka-ke lo msebenzi wobukhansela.(enyuse izwi ngenxa yentukuthelo) Uthini? Uyeke? Niqala izinto besenigabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele? Lutho! Wena yelekelelaekucisheni lo mlilo wothathe osuwokhele.Kahle sayitsheni. Ngizowucisha kanjani lo mlilo? Bazongibulala phelaabantu.1. Ukungaqondi kukaDuma nenkosi uShandu ukubaluleka kokusebenzisanaphakathi kwabo njengabaholi endaweni kwaba namuphi umphumela? ","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo:тАв Kwaba nodlame.тАв Kwafa uNobhala wekhansela uMbandlwa nenduna uDlamini. "},{"question":"тАЬMiteraka sery ve ny matory amin'ny varavarankely misokatra?тАЭ","answer":"Tsia, tsy voatery hiteraka sery ny matory amin'ny varavarankely misokatra."},{"question":"Est-ce que c'est Vrai ou Faux? Le plagiat inclut le fait de reprendre sans en mentionner la source des propos oraux de prestations publiques (exemples : films, entrevues, conf├йrencesтАж).","answer":"Vrai. Le plagiat ne se limite pas au mat├йriel ├йcrit : il touche tout emprunt, y compris lтАЩinformation orale."},{"question":"┬л┘Е┘Д█М┌Ж┬╗ ╪п╪▒ ┌п┘И█М╪┤ ┘З┘Е╪п╪з┘Ж█М ╪и┘З ┌Ж┘З ┘Е╪╣┘Ж╪з╪│╪к╪Я","answer":"┘З┘Е╪п╪з┘Ж█М ┘З╪з ╪и┘З ┌п┘Ж╪м╪┤┌й ┘Е█МтАМ┌п┘И█М┘Ж╪п ┘Е┘Д█М┌Ж.┌п┘Ж╪м╪┤┌й ┘╛╪▒┘Ж╪п┘ЗтАМ╪з█М ╪з╪│╪к ┌й┘И┌Ж┌й ╪и╪з ┘Е┘Ж┘В╪з╪▒ ┌й┘Д┘Б╪к ┘И ┘Е╪о╪▒┘И╪╖█М ┘И ┘╛╪з┘З╪з█М ┘Ж╪│╪и╪к╪з┘Л ┌й┘И╪к╪з┘З ┌й┘З ╪з╪║┘Д╪и ┘╛╪▒ ┘И ╪и╪з┘Д ╪▒┘Ж┌п╪з╪▒┘Ж┌п ┘Ж╪п╪з╪▒╪п ┘И ╪и┘З ╪▒┘Ж┌п ┘В┘З┘И┘З ╪з█М ╪▒┘И╪┤┘Ж ┘И ╪к█М╪▒┘З ┘З╪│╪к┘Ж╪п. ┌п┘Ж╪м╪┤┌й╪з┘Ж ╪и█М╪┤╪к╪▒ ╪и┘З ╪╡┘И╪▒╪к ╪з╪м╪к┘Е╪з╪╣█М ╪и┘З ╪│╪▒ ┘Е█МтАМ╪и╪▒┘Ж╪п ┘И ╪и┘З ╪╖┘И╪▒ ┌п╪▒┘И┘З█М ╪▓╪з╪п ┘И ┘И┘Д╪п ┘Е█МтАМ┌й┘Ж┘Ж╪п. ┘╛╪▒┘И╪з╪▓█М ┘Ж█М╪▒┘И┘Е┘Ж╪п ╪п╪з╪▒┘Ж╪п. ╪п╪▒ ╪│┘И╪▒╪з╪отАМ┘З╪з█М ╪п╪▒╪о╪к╪з┘Ж╪М ╪┤┌й╪з┘Б ╪п█М┘И╪з╪▒ ┘И ╪╡╪о╪▒┘ЗтАМ┘З╪з ┘Д╪з┘Ж┘З ┘Е█МтАМ╪│╪з╪▓┘Ж╪п. ╪и█М╪┤╪к╪▒ ╪з╪▓ ╪п╪з┘Ж┘ЗтАМ┘З╪з ┘И ┘Е┘И╪з╪п ┌п█М╪з┘З█М ┘И ┌п╪з┘З ╪м╪з┘Ж┘И╪▒█М ╪к╪║╪░█М┘З ┘Е█МтАМ┌й┘Ж┘Ж╪п."},{"question":"цмбуБоуВ┐уВдуГИуГлуБлхЯ║уБеуБДуБжуАБуБУуБоуГИуГФуГГуВпуБлщЦвуБЩуВЛшиШф║ЛуВТцЫ╕уБНуБкуБХуБДя╝Ъ хНГшСЙчЬМуБзщЬЗх║ж5х╝╖уБохЬ░щЬЗуАА1щА▒щЦУуБРуВЙуБДуБпц░ЧуВТуБдуБСуБж","answer":"11цЧехНИхЙН4цЩВ16хИЖуАБхНГшСЙчЬМуБзуГЮуВ░уГЛуГБуГеуГ╝уГЙ5.2уБохЬ░щЬЗуБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхНГшСЙчЬМцЬицЫ┤ц┤ех╕ВуБпщЬЗх║ж5х╝╖уБзуАБх╝╖уБПцП║уВМуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхНГшСЙх╕ВуВДцЭ▒ф║мщГ╜уБо23хМ║уАБчеЮхеИх╖ЭчЬМцикц╡Ьх╕ВуБкуБйуБпщЬЗх║ж4уБзуБЧуБЯуАВц┤ец│вуБпуБВуВКуБ╛уБЫуВУуБзуБЧуБЯуАВуБУуБохЬ░щЬЗуБзуАБхНГшСЙчЬМуБичеЮхеИх╖ЭчЬМуБзуБп11цЧецШ╝уБ╛уБзуБлуАБхо╢уБзш╗вуВУуБаф║║уБкуБй4ф║║уБМуБСуБМуВТуБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВцЬицЫ┤ц┤ех╕ВуБзуБпхо╢уБох▒Лца╣уБочУжуБМшР╜уБбуБЯуВКуАБуГУуГлуБочкУуБоуВмуГйуВ╣уБМхЙ▓уВМуБжшР╜уБбуБЯуВКуБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВц░Чш▒бх║БуБпуАМх╝╖уБПцП║уВМуБЯцЙАуБзуБпуАБх▒▒уБЛуВЙчЯ│уБМшР╜уБбуБжуБНуБЯуВКх┤ЦуБМх┤йуВМуБЯуВКуБЩуВЛхН▒щЩ║уБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЩуАВуБУуВМуБЛуВЙ1щА▒щЦУуБРуВЙуБДуБпуАБуБ╛уБЯхдзуБНуБкхЬ░щЬЗуБМуБВуВЛуБЛуВВуБЧуВМуБкуБДуБоуБзуАБц░ЧуВТуБдуБСуБжуБПуБауБХуБДуАНуБишиАуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВчЙ╣уБлуАБщЫиуБМщЩНуВЛуБих▒▒уБМх┤йуВМуВДуБЩуБПуБкуВЛуБЯуВБуАБхдзщЫиуБошнжха▒уБМхЗ║уБЯуБиуБНуБпцЧйуБПщБ┐щЫгуБЧуБжуБ╗уБЧуБДуБишиАуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВ"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Пр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П  р╢Лр╢пр╖Пр╖Др╢╗р╢лр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒. ","answer":"р╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╢╜ р╢нр╖Ьр╢зр╖Ъ р╢╕р╢╕ р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒        р╢Ър╖Ьр╢зр╢╜р╖Гр╖Кр╖Гр╢▒ р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ер╖Пр╖Ар╢║р╖Т р╢╕р╢Ьр╖Щ р╢Йр╖Гр╖Кр╖Г         р╢╗р╢зр╢Ър╢╗р╖Ъ р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢пр╖Щр╢┤р╖Ьр╢зр╖Ъ р╢╜р╖Гр╖Кр╖Г         р╢▒р╢зр╢Ер╢╗р╢▒р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╢▒р╢║р╖Т р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Фр╢╜р╖Щр╢▒р╖К              р╢Ьр╢╕р╢з"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢Ьр╖Ур╢нр╢║ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Кр╢л р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒. р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢┤р╖Щр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢┤р╖Тр╢▒р╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢Фр╢╢ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Др╖Ьр╢╢р╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢Фр╢╢ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Т р╢пр╖У р╖Гр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖Тр╢╕р╖Ф р╢Фр╢╢ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П","answer":"р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢┤р╖Щр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢┤р╖Тр╢▒р╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢Фр╢╢ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Др╖Ьр╢╢р╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢Фр╢╢ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Т р╢пр╖У р╖Гр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖Тр╢╕р╖Ф р╢Фр╢╢ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢╢р╢╜р╖Тр╢нр╢╗р╖Ф р╢╗р╖Пр╖Ар╢л р╢Ьр╖Рр╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Тр╢вр╢║р╢╢р╖П р╢▒р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢п р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢┤р╖Фр╢╜р╢нр╖Тр╖Гр╖Т р╢пр╖Рр╢╕р╖Т р╖Гр╖Тр╢╗р╖Т р╢╗р╖Др╢╜р╖К р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢╗р╢нр╖Фр╢Яр╖Ф р╢┤р╢мр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢п р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖Ф р╖Гр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖Т р╢╕р╖Д р╢┤р╖Рр╢╗р╖Рр╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢п р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢Фр╢╢ р╢╗р╖Рр╢Ър╖Фр╢▒р╖Ьр╢нр╖К р╢╜р╖Э р╢Ър╖Фр╢╣р╖Фр╖Ар╢п р╢Ер╢┤ р╖Др╢з р╖Гр╖Ур╢н р╢Ьр╢Яр╖Фр╢╜ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢╕р╖Др╖Ар╖Рр╢╜р╖Т р╢Ър╖Ер╖Ф р╢Ър╖Рр╖Ер╢лр╖Т р╖Ар╢╜р╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢нр╖К р╖Др╢нр╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Гр╢╕р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Е р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢Ьр╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢нр╢╜р╖П р╢▒р╖Щр╢Ъ р╢Ър╖Щр╖Др╖Щ р╢Ьр╖Рр╢з р╢╢р╖Рр╢│р╖Т р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢нр╖Ъ р╖Ар╢нр╖Ф р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╜р╖К р╖Ар╢нр╖Ф р╢Ър╖Щр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╢нр╖Ф р╢┤р╖Щр╖Е р╢Лр╢Ър╖Фр╢╜р╖Ъ р╢▒р╢╜р╖Ар╢▒ р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢╕р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢Яр╢╜р╢Ър╖К р╢Фр╢╢ р╖Ар╖Рр╖А р╖Др╖Ьр╢нр╖К р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢┤р╢▒р╖Тр╢╕р╖Ф р╢┤р╢▒р╖Тр╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Др╖Щр╖Е р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢╕р╖Тр╢лр╖Т р╖Ар╖Рр╢╜р╖К р╢Ср╢Ър╢з р╢пр╢╕р╖Пр╢╜р╖П р╢Фр╢╢ р╖Гр╢╗р╖Гр╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢Ьр╖Гр╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢╜р╖К р╖Ар╢╜р╖Р р╢╕р╢╜р╖К р╢Ср╢Ър╢з р╢Ьр╖Ьр╢нр╖Пр╢╜р╖П р╢Фр╢╢ р╢┤р╖Ер╢│р╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢лр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Т р╢┤р╖Рр╢лр╖Т р╢Ср╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢▒р╖Пр╢╜р╖П р╢Фр╢╢ р╢┤р╖Тр╢▒р╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢Фр╢╢ р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ср╢▒ р╖Ар╖Щр╢йр╖Т р╖Гр╖Рр╢╗ р╢╕р╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╖Щр╢нр╖Т р╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Гр╢╜р╢Ър╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢Фр╢╢ р╖Др╢з р╢Ер╢н р╢┤р╖Ьр╖Ар╢▒р╢з р╢Лр╢▒р╖К р╢╕р╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╢з р╢Йр╢й р╢▒р╖Ьр╢нр╢╢р╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢Ер╖Ар╖Др╖Ьр╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢Лр╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢╢р╢│р╖Ар╖П р╢Ьр╖Ьр╖Ер╖Ф р╢╕р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢п р╢Ьр╖Щр╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ьр╢й р╢пр╖Тр╢║ р╢Ер╖Др╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Др╖Рр╢╕р╢нр╖Рр╢▒р╖Р р╢Фр╢╢р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢▒р╢╕ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖Р р╢Фр╢╢р╢з р╢╕р╖Р р╢┤р╖Ьр╖Др╖Ьр╢╗р╢з р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢Ър╢║ р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢╕р╖Р р╖Др╖Ьр╖Ар╢╕р╖Ф р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П"},{"question":"тАЬр░кр▒Жр░жр▒Нр░жр░▓р▒Б р░кр░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ тАУ р░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓р▒Б р░мр░бр░┐р░Хр░┐тАЭ тАУ р░Ер░ир▒З р░ир░┐р░ир░╛р░жр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░╕р░ор░░р▒Нр░ер░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░кр▒Жр░жр▒Нр░жр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Б р░кр░ир░┐р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░бр░мр▒Нр░мр▒Б р░╕р░Вр░кр░╛р░жр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐, р░╕р░Вр░╕р░╛р░░р░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░кр▒Лр░╖р░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░┐. р░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓р▒Б р░Ър░Хр▒Нр░Хр░Чр░╛ р░мр░бр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░╡р▒Жр░│р▒Нр░│р░┐, р░Ър░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░Хр▒Кр░ир░┐ р░ор░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╡р░┐р░Ьр▒Нр░Юр░╛р░ир░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░╕р░Вр░кр░╛р░жр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░┐. р░Ър░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр░ир▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░кр░Вр░кр░┐, р░╡р░╛р░░р▒Б р░╕р░Вр░кр░╛р░жр░┐р░Вр░Ър▒З р░Ър░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир░кр░╛р░Яр░┐ р░Хр▒Вр░▓р▒А р░бр░мр▒Нр░мр▒Бр░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Жр░жр▒Нр░жр░▓р▒Б р░Жр░╢р░┐р░Вр░Ър░░р░╛р░жр▒Б. р░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓р░ир▒Б р░Ър░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░ор░╛р░ир▒Нр░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐р░ир░┐ р░кр░ир▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░кр░Вр░кр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒З, р░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓ р░мр░Вр░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░нр░╡р░┐р░╖р▒Нр░пр░др▒Нр░др▒Б р░ир░╛р░╢р░ир░В р░Ер░╡р▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐."},{"question":"16ф╕Цч┤АуБоуГХуГйуГ│уВ╣ф║║ф║ИшиАшАЕуБзуАБ1999х╣┤уБлхЬ░чРГуБМча┤ц╗ЕуБЩуВЛуБиф║ИшиАуБЧуБЯуБиуБХуВМуВЛф║║чЙйуБпя╝Я","answer":"уГОуВ╣уГИуГйуГАуГауВ╣уБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"ф╕ЦчХМшбЫчФЯч╡Дч╣ФчЪДшЛ▒цЦЗч╕охплцШпя╝Я","answer":"WHO"},{"question":"ЁЯУЪ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨┤╨░╤А╤В╨║╨░ ╨┤╨░╨▒╨░ ╨░╤В╨░╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ЁЯСитАНтЪХя╕П ╨┤╨░╤А╤Л╨│╨╡╤А╨╕ ╨╢╙й╨╜╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ╨░╨╣╤В╨░ ╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╨╖?","answer":"╨Ь╨░╨╝╨▒╨╡╤В ╨Ь╨░╨╝╨░╨║╨╡╨╡╨▓ 2020- ╨╢╤Л╨╗╤Л ╨У╨╕╨╜╨╜╨╡╤Б╤В╨╕╨╜ ╤А╨╡╨║╨╛╤А╨┤╨┤╨╛╤А ╨║╨╕╤В╨╡╨▒╨╕╨╜╨╡ ╨║╨╕╤А╨│╨╡╨╜.╨Ъ╨╕╤В╨╡╨┐╤В╨╕╨╜ ╤А╨░╤Б╨╝╨╕╨╣ ╤Б╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╨╗╨░╤В.╨б╨░╨╣╤В╤В╨░ ╨Ь╨░╨╝╨░╨║╨╡╨╡╨▓ ╨╝╨╡╨┤╨╕╤Ж╨╕╨╜╨░╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╨╢╨╡╤В╨╕╤И╨║╨╡╨╜╨┤╨╕╨│╨╕ ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨░╤А╨┤╨░╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╨░╤В╤Г╤Г╨╗╤Г ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨╡╨╗╨│╨╕╨╗╨╡╨╜╨╡╤В.╨Ь╨░╨╝╨▒╨╡╤В ╨Ь╨░╨╝╨░╨║╨╡╨╡╨▓ 95 ╨╢╨░╤И╤В╨░, ╤Г╤И╤Г╨╗ ╨║╥п╨╜╨│╙й ╤З╨╡╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╨╛╨┐╨╡╤А╨░╤Ж╨╕╤П ╨╢╨░╤Б╨░╨╣╤В. 1927-╨╢╤Л╨╗╤Л ╨л╤Б╤Л╨║-╨Ъ╙й╨╗ ╨╛╨▒╨╗╤Г╤Б╤Г╨╜╤Г╨╜ ╨Ъ╨╡╤А╨╡╨│╨╡-╨в╨░╤И ╨░╨╣╤Л╨╗╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╤В╙й╤А╙й╨╗╨│╙й╨╜. 15 ╨╝╨╕╥г╨┤╨╡╨╜ ╨░╤И╤Г╤Г╨╜ ╨╛╨┐╨╡╤А╨░╤Ж╨╕╤П ╨╢╨░╤Б╨░╨│╨░╨╜. ╨С╨╕╤А ╨╜╨╡╤З╨╡ ╨╕╨╗╨╕╨╝╨╕╨╣ ╨╕╤И╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜, ╨┤╨░╤А╤Л╨╗╨╛╨╛ ╤Л╨║╨╝╨░╨╗╨░╤А╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨░╨▓╤В╨╛╤А╤Г."},{"question":"рд▓рд┐рдирд┐рдЕрд░ рд░рд┐рдЧреНрд░реЗрд╢рди\\" (Linear Regression) ","answer":"\\"рд▓рд┐рдирд┐рдЕрд░ рд░рд┐рдЧреНрд░реЗрд╢рди\\" (Linear Regression) рд╣реЗ рдПрдХ рд╕рд╛рдВрдЦреНрдпрд┐рдХреАрд╢рд╛рд╕реНрддреНрд░реАрдп рдкреНрд░реМрджреНрдпреЛрдЧрд┐рдХреА рдЖрд╣реЗ рдЬреНрдпрд╛рдЪрд╛ рдЙрдкрдпреЛрдЧ рджреЛрди рд╡рд╛ рддреАрди рдЕрджреНрдпрддрд┐рдд рдЪрд░рдгрд╛рдВрдордзреНрдпреЗ рд╕рдВрд╡реЗрдЧ рдЕрдерд╡рд╛ рдПрдХ рдХрд┐рдВрд╡рд╛ рдПрдХрд╛рдзрд┐рдХ рд╕реНрд╡рд╛рдзрд┐рдХреГрдд рдорд╛рдкрджрдВрдбрд╛рдВрдордзреНрдпреЗ рд╕рдВрдмрдВрдз рд╕рд╛рдзрдгреНрдпрд╛рд╕рд╛рдареА рдХреЗрд▓рд╛ рдЬрд╛рддреЛ. рдпрд╛ рдЕрд▓реНрдЧреЛрд░рд┐рдереНрдордордЪрд╛ рдЙрдкрдпреЛрдЧ рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рдЕрдзреНрдпрдпрди рдХреЗрд▓реНрдпрд╛рдирдВрддрд░ рджреЛрди рдХрд┐рдВрд╡рд╛ рджреЛрдирдкреЗрдХреНрд╖рд╛ рдЕрдзрд┐рдХ рдорд╛рдкрджрдВрдбрд╛рдВрд╕рд╛рдареА рдореВрд▓реНрдп рдЕрдерд╡рд╛ рджрд░ рдЕрдерд╡рд╛ рдЗрддрд░ рдкрд░рд┐рдорд╛рдгрд╛рдВрдЪреНрдпрд╛ рдореВрд▓реНрдпрд╛рдВрдЪреНрдпрд╛ рд╕рд╛рдереА рд╡рд░реНрдЧреАрдХрд░рдгрд╕рд╛рдареА рдХреЗрд▓рд╛ рдЬрд╛рддреЛ.рд▓рд┐рдирд┐рдЕрд░ рд░рд┐рдЧреНрд░реЗрд╢рдирдЪреНрдпрд╛ рдореБрдЦреНрдп рдЧреЛрд╖реНрдЯреА:рд╕рд░рд│ рд╕рд░рд╛рдВрд╢: рд▓рд┐рдирд┐рдЕрд░ рд░рд┐рдЧреНрд░реЗрд╢рдирд▓рд╛ рд╕рд░рд│ рд░реВрдкрд╛рдд рдкреНрд░рд╕реНрддреБрдд рдХреЗрд▓реЗ рдЬрд╛рддреЗ, рддреНрдпрд╛рдореБрд│реЗ рд╕рдВрд╡реЗрдЧрд╛рдЪреНрдпрд╛ рджрд░рдореНрдпрд╛рди рд╕рдВрдмрдВрдзрд╛рдЪреА рд╕рд╛рд░рдЦреА рд╕рдВрд░реЗрдЦрд╛ рддрдпрд╛рд░ рдХреЗрд▓реА рдЬрд╛рддреЗ.рдореЙрдбреЗрд▓ рддрдпрд╛рд░ рдХрд░рдгреЗ: рдореЙрдбреЗрд▓ рддрдпрд╛рд░ рдХрд░рдгреНрдпрд╛рд╕рд╛рдареА рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рдЕрдзреНрдпрдпрди рдХреЗрд▓рд╛ рдЬрд╛рддреЛ, рдЬреНрдпрд╛рдордзреНрдпреЗ рд╕реНрд╡рд╛рдзрд┐рдХреГрдд рдорд╛рдкрджрдВрдбрд╛рдВрдордзреНрдпреЗ рджреЛрдирдкреЗрдХреНрд╖рд╛ рдЕрдзрд┐рдХ рдорд╛рдкрджрдВрдб рдЖрдгрд┐ рддреНрдпрд╛рдЪреНрдпрд╛ рд╕рдВрд╡реЗрдЧрд╛рдЪреНрдпрд╛ рдореВрд▓реНрдпрд╛рдВрдЪреНрдпрд╛ рд╕рдВрдмрдВрдзрд╛рдЪреА рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рд╡рд╛рдкрд░рд▓рд╛ рдЬрд╛рддреЛ.рдореЙрдбреЗрд▓ рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рдг: рдореЙрдбреЗрд▓рд▓рд╛ рдкреНрд░рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рдг рджрд┐рд▓реНрдпрд╛рдирдВрддрд░, рдореЙрдбреЗрд▓рд▓рд╛ рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рд╕рдВрд╡реЗрдЧ рдЕрдерд╡рд╛ рдореВрд▓реНрдп рдЕрдерд╡рд╛ рдЗрддрд░ рдкрд░рд┐рдорд╛рдгрд╛рдВрдЪреНрдпрд╛ рдореВрд▓реНрдпрд╛рдВрдЪреА рдореВрд▓реНрдпрд╛рдВрддрд░ рдХрд░рдгреНрдпрд╛рдд рдЖрдгрдгреНрдпрд╛рдЪрд╛ рдкреНрд░рдХреНрд░рд┐рдпрд╛рд╕рд╛рдареА рд╡рд╛рдкрд░рд▓рд╛ рдЬрд╛рддреЛ.рдкреВрд░реНрд╡рд╛рдиреБрдорд╛рди: рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рд┐рдд рдореЙрдбреЗрд▓рдЪрд╛ рдЙрдкрдпреЛрдЧ рдЕрдЬреНрдЮрд╛рдд рдореВрд▓реНрдпрд╛рдВрдЪреНрдпрд╛ рдкреВрд░реНрд╡рд╛рдиреБрдорд╛рди рдХрд┐рдВрд╡рд╛ рдЕрдиреБрдорд╛рдирд╕рд╛рдареА рдХреЗрд▓рд╛ рдЬрд╛рддреЛ.рд▓рд┐рдирд┐рдЕрд░ рд░рд┐рдЧреНрд░реЗрд╢рди рд╣рд╛ рдПрдХ рд╕рд░рд▓, рдкреНрд░рд╕рд┐рджреНрдз рдЖрдгрд┐ рд╡рд╛рдкрд░рдХрд░реНрддреНрдпрд╛рдВрдирд╛ рдкрд░рд┐рдкреВрд░реНрдг рд╕рд╛рдВрдЦреНрдпрд┐рдХреАрд╢рд╛рд╕реНрддреНрд░реАрдп рдЯреВрд▓ рдЖрд╣реЗ рдЖрдгрд┐ рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рдЕрдзреНрдпрдпрдирд╛рдд, рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рдкреНрд░рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рдгрд╛рдд, рдЖрдгрд┐ рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рдкреВрд░реНрд╡рд╛рдиреБрдорд╛рдирд╛рдд рд╡рд┐рд╢рд┐рд╖реНрдЯ рдЕрд░реНрдерд╛рдВрдХрдирд╛рд╕рд╛рдареА рд╡рд╛рдкрд░рд▓рд╛ рдЬрд╛рддреЛ."},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Ур╢Ър╖Т р╢╢р╖Кр╢╜р╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢йр╢╗р╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢зр╖Ьр╢╕р╖У р╖Бр╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢╢р╖Т р╖Гр╢╕р╢Ь р╢╕р╖Фр╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Гр╖Фр╖А р╢Фр╖Др╖Ф р╖Гр╢╕р╢Я р╢╕р╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗ р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Йр╢нр╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╢║р╖П  р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п?","answer":"р╢┤р╖Ур╢Ър╖Т р╢╢р╖Кр╢╜р╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢йр╢╗р╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢зр╖Ьр╢╕р╖У р╖Бр╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢╢р╖Т р╖Гр╢╕р╢Ь р╢╕р╖Фр╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Гр╖Фр╖А р╢Фр╖Др╖Ф р╖Гр╢╕р╢Я р╢╕р╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗ р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Йр╢нр╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╢║р╖П   р╢Зр╢╜р╖Кр╖Жр╖Т р╖Гр╖Ьр╢╜р╢╕р╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╖Ар╖Ъ."},{"question":"*┘Е╪з ╪з┘Д┘Д┘В╪и ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ╪г╪╖┘Д┘В ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪▓┘И╪м╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪▒╪│┘И┘Д ╪Я","answer":"╪г┘Е┘З╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Е╪д┘Е┘Ж┘К┘Ж"},{"question":"Lamento que no se hayan aprobado en el Pleno las propuestas aprobadas por la Comision de Agricultura y Desarrollo Rural que figuran en mi opinion , concretamente las relativas a la necesidad de modificar la PAC y cambiar los objetivos de sus anteriores reformas , pues han provocado una reduccion de los ingresos de las pequenas y medianas explotaciones agricolas , absentismo y el abandono de la actividad agricola y solo favorecen a los grandes terratenientes.Dame una versi├│n m├бs simple del texto anterior. ","answer":"Lamento las propuestas contenidas en mi opinion que presentamos en el Pleno y que la Comision de Agricultura y Desarrollo Rural adopto , en particular sobre la necesidad de revisar la PAC para invertir los objetivos de sus reformas anteriores . Han sido responsables de la perdida de ingresos de los pequenos y medianos agricultores , el absentismo y el abandono de la actividad agricola  , favoreciendo unicamente a los grandes propietarios ."},{"question":"Kinsa ang gipaila sa Dios nga si Jesus human sa iyang baba ug angay siyang pagpaminawon?","answer":"Kini mao ang akong Anak nga hinigugmaon, sa iya ako nalipay.тАЭNganong gipanamkon si Jesus sa Jordan River ni San Juan Bautista?"},{"question":"Fan mooy p├йeyum r├йewum Luxembourg?","answer":"P├йeyum r├йewum Luxembourg mu ngi tudu Luxembourg."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'kicang-kecoh bertembung ciak'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tiap-tiap perkara yang hendak disiasat hendaklah ada buktinya"},{"question":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢┤р╖Пр╢пр╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╢▒р╖П р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║ , р╢Ср╢Ър╢╕ р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╢Жр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Фр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖П р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п ?","answer":"р╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╖Рр╢╗р╢пр╖Т р╢┤р╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╢╗ ................р╖Гр╢╗р╖К  р╖Ар╖Тр╢╜р╖Кр╢╕р╢зр╖К р╖Др╖Эр╢╗р╖Кр╢зр╢▒р╖К ( 1831-1837 )"},{"question":"Isilah titik-titik berikut dengan kata, frasa, atau penggalan kalimat jawaban yang tepat, sehingga membentuk kalimat yang sempurna dan relevan dengan konteks yang diberikan.Konteks: Ciri-ciri zat makananKetika makan tempe atau kacang-kacangan, selanjutnya makanan akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul тАж dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan maka selanjutnya тАжJawaban:","answer":"Ketika makan tempe atau kacang-kacangan, selanjutnya makanan akan dicerna dan diserap tubuh dalam bentuk molekul yang lebih kecil atau halus, yaitu asam amino dan jika jumlahnya berlebihan, maka selanjutnya diubah menjadi urea dan dikeluarkan bersama urin."},{"question":"┘Е╪з┘З┘И ╪и╪н╪▒ ╪з┘Д┘В╪╡┘К╪п╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К╪й : \\"╪н╪к┘Й ╪╣┘О┘Д╪з ╪и┘О┘К╪к┘П┘Г ╪з┘Д┘Е┘П┘З┘О╪░┘С┘О╪и┘П ┘Е┘Ж # ╪о┘Р┘Ж╪п┘Р┘Б┘О ╪╣┘О┘Д┘К┘О╪з╪б┘О ╪к┘О╪н╪к┘О┘З╪з ╪з┘Д╪╣┘О╪▒┘О╪и┘П\\"\\t╪и╪н╪▒ : ","answer":"╪з┘Д┘Е┘Ж╪│╪▒╪н"},{"question":"цИСхЬЛчЩ╝чП╛цЬАцЧйчЪДч┤Щх╣гцШпхЬихУкхАЛцЩВцЬЯя╝Я","answer":"хоЛцЬЭ"},{"question":"р░╢р▒Ар░░р▒Нр░╖р░┐р░Х: р░Ир░Ьр░┐р░кр▒Нр░Яр▒Н р░Яр░┐р░Хр▒НтАМр░Яр░╛р░Хр▒НтАМ, р░Зр░ир▒НтАМр░╕р▒Нр░Яр░╛р░Чр▒Нр░░р░╛р░ор▒Н р░╕р▒Нр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Нр░▓р░ир▒Б 'р░Ер░╕р░нр▒Нр░пр░д' р░кр▒Зр░░р▒Бр░др▒Л р░Ьр▒Ир░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Л р░кр▒Жр░бр▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░и р░кр▒Нр░░р░нр▒Бр░др▒Нр░╡р░Вр░Кр░╣р░╛р░др▒Нр░ор░Х р░Хр░ер░ир░В р░пр▒Кр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░кр▒Ир░и р░кр▒Зр░░р▒Нр░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░и р░╢р▒Ар░░р▒Нр░╖р░┐р░Хр░ир▒Б р░мр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░┐, р░Хр░ер░ир░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Йр░╣р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░Ьр▒Ир░▓р▒Б р░╢р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░Хр▒Б р░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Ир░и р░Ер░пр░┐р░жр▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Б р░╕р▒Лр░╖р░▓р▒Н р░ор▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр░╛ р░╕р▒Нр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Нр░▓р░▓р▒Л р░Тр░Хр░░р▒Ир░и р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░Ер░▓р▒Н-р░Ер░жр░╛р░ор▒Н22 р░Пр░│р▒Нр░▓ р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░Ер░▓р▒Н р░Ер░жр░╛р░ор▒НтАМ р░Ер░ир▒З р░╕р▒Лр░╖р░▓р▒Н р░ор▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр░╛ р░╕р▒Нр░Яр░╛р░░р▒НтАМр░Хр▒Б р░Зр░Яр▒Ар░╡р░▓ р░Ир░Ьр░┐р░кр▒Нр░Яр▒НтАМр░▓р▒Л р░Хр▒Лр░░р▒Нр░Яр▒Б р░░р▒Жр░Вр░бр▒Зр░│р▒Нр░▓ р░Ьр▒Ир░▓р▒Б р░╢р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖ р░╡р░┐р░зр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░Вр░жр░┐.р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐р░и р░ир▒Зр░░р░В р░Яр░┐р░Хр▒НтАМр░Яр░╛р░Хр▒Н р░╡р▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░пр░бр░ор▒З. р░Ер░╡р░┐ р░Хр▒Бр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░м р░╡р░┐р░▓р▒Бр░╡р░▓р░Хр▒Б р░╡р░┐р░░р▒Бр░жр▒Нр░зр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░Вр░Яр▒В р░Хр▒Лр░░р▒Нр░Яр▒Б р░Жр░ор▒Жр░Хр▒Б р░╢р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖ р░╡р░┐р░зр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░Вр░жр░┐.р░Жр░зр▒Бр░ир░┐р░Х р░жр▒Бр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░зр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐, р░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░кр░╛р░кр▒Бр░▓р░░р▒Н р░кр░╛р░Яр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░бр▒Нр░пр░╛р░ир▒Нр░╕р▒Н р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░Яр░┐р░Хр▒НтАМр░Яр░╛р░Хр▒Н, р░Зр░ир▒НтАМр░╕р▒Нр░Яр░╛р░Чр▒Нр░░р░╛р░ор▒НтАМр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Л р░╡р▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Б р░кр▒Лр░╕р▒Нр░Яр▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б. р░лр▒Кр░Яр▒Лр░▓р▒Б р░кр▒Жр░бр▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Чр░д р░ор▒Зр░▓р▒Л р░ор░╡р░бр░╛р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Лр░▓р▒Ар░╕р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Ер░░р▒Жр░╕р▒Нр░Яр▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░╢р░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░╡р▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Б р░Ер░╕р░нр▒Нр░пр░Хр░░р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░ир░┐ р░Хр▒Лр░░р▒Нр░Яр▒Б р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░зр░╛р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. тАШтАШр░ор▒Зр░В р░╖р░╛р░Хр▒Н р░др░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░В. р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░П р░др░кр▒Нр░кр▒В р░Ър▒Зр░пр░▓р▒Зр░жр▒Б, р░ир▒Зр░░р░╕р▒Нр░ер▒Бр░░р░╛р░▓р▒В р░Хр░╛р░жр▒Б. р░лр▒Зр░ор░╕р▒Н р░Ер░╡р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░жр░Вр░др▒ЗтАЩтАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░Ър▒Жр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Жр░▓р▒Б р░░р░╣р▒Нр░о р░Ер░Вр░Яр▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б. тАШтАШр░ор░╛ р░Ер░ор▒Нр░о р░Зр░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░бр▒Б р░кр▒Вр░░р▒Нр░др░┐р░Чр░╛ р░ор░Вр░Ър░В р░кр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Пр░бр▒Бр░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░╕р░╛р░░р▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░░р░╛р░др▒Нр░░р░┐ р░ир░┐р░жр▒Нр░░ р░▓р▒Зр░Ър░┐, р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░Зр░Вр░Яр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░╡р░Ър▒Нр░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐р░Вр░жр░╛ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░Ер░бр▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒БтАЩтАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░░р░╣р▒Нр░о р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Тр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░ор░╡р░бр░╛р░ир▒З р░Хр░╛р░жр▒Б.р░ор░╡р░бр░╛р░Хр▒Б р░ор░╛р░др▒Нр░░р░ор▒З р░Хр░╛р░жр▒Б, р░ор░░р▒Л р░ир░▓р▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Б р░пр▒Бр░╡р░др▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░Яр░┐р░Хр▒НтАМр░Яр░╛р░Хр▒Н р░╡р▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐р░ир░Вр░жр▒Бр░Хр▒Б р░Ир░Ьр░┐р░кр▒Нр░Яр▒Н р░Хр▒Лр░░р▒Нр░Яр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Зр░жр▒З р░╢р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖ р░╡р░┐р░зр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░пр░┐. р░░р▒Жр░Вр░бр▒Зр░│р▒Нр░▓ р░Ьр▒Ир░▓р▒Б р░╢р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░др▒Лр░кр░╛р░Яр▒Б р░жр░╛р░жр░╛р░кр▒Б р░░р▒В.15 р░▓р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░▓ р░Ьр░░р░┐р░ор░╛р░ир░╛ р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░╡р░┐р░зр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░пр░┐.р░И р░Рр░жр▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░ир░┐ р░Зр░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░бр▒Б тАШр░Яр░┐р░Хр▒НтАМр░Яр░╛р░Хр▒Н р░Чр░░р▒Нр░▓р▒Нр░╕р▒НтАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░кр░┐р░▓р▒Бр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б.р░╣р░ир▒Ар░ир▒Н р░╣р▒Лр░╕р░ор▒Н р░Ер░ир▒З р░╕р▒Лр░╖р░▓р▒Н р░ор▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр░╛ р░╕р▒Нр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Н р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░И р░Рр░жр▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░▓р▒Л р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б. р░ор░┐р░Чр░др░╛ р░ор▒Бр░Чр▒Нр░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░мр░пр░Яр░Хр▒Б р░╡р▒Жр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░бр░┐ р░Хр░╛р░▓р▒Зр░жр▒Б.тАШтАШр░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р▒Б р░кр▒Кр░Вр░жр░┐р░и р░лр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╖р░ир▒Н р░мр▒Нр░░р░╛р░Вр░бр▒Нр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░ор░╛ р░Ер░Хр▒Нр░Х р░╕р▒Лр░╖р░▓р▒Н р░ор▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр░╛р░▓р▒Л р░ор▒Лр░бр░▓р░┐р░Вр░Чр▒Н р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░кр▒Жр░жр▒Нр░ж р░кр▒Жр░жр▒Нр░ж р░▓р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░кр▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░Яр▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б. р░ир░Яр░┐ р░Ер░╡р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Нр░ир░жр░┐ р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░Хр░▓тАЩтАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░░р░╣р▒Нр░о р░др░и р░Ер░Хр▒Нр░Х р░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б.р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ тАШр░Ер░╕р░нр▒Нр░пр░Хр░░р░Вр░Чр░╛тАЩ р░Хр░ир░┐р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░Вр░жр░ир░бр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░Жр░зр░╛р░░р░Вр░Чр░╛ 17 р░лр▒Кр░Яр▒Лр░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р▒Кр░╕р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░пр▒Вр░╖р░ир▒Н р░Хр▒Лр░░р▒Нр░Яр▒Бр░Хр▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░ир░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░ор░╛р░ир░╡ р░╣р░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░▓ р░╕р░Вр░╕р▒Нр░е р░Жр░ор▒Нр░ир▒Жр░╕р▒Нр░Яр▒А р░Зр░Вр░Яр░░р▒Нр░ир▒Зр░╖р░ир░▓р▒Н р░др▒Жр░▓р░┐р░кр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ер░пр░┐р░др▒З, р░др░и р░лр▒Лр░ир▒Н р░Чр░д р░Пр░бр░╛р░жр░┐ р░Ър▒Лр░░р▒Ар░Хр░┐ р░Чр░░р▒Ир░Вр░жр░ир░┐, р░жр░╛р░ир░┐ р░ир▒Бр░Вр░Ър░┐ р░И р░лр▒Кр░Яр▒Лр░▓р▒Б р░мр░пр░Яр░Хр▒Б р░▓р▒Ар░Хр▒Н р░Ер░пр▒Нр░пр░╛р░пр░ир░┐ р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Жр░Чр░╕р▒Нр░Яр▒Б 17р░и р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░╢р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░кр▒И р░Ер░кр▒Нр░кр▒Ар░▓р▒Б р░╡р░┐р░Ър░╛р░░р░гр░Хр▒Б р░░р░╛р░╡р░╛р░▓р▒Нр░╕р░┐ р░Йр░Вр░жр░┐.р░др░и р░Ер░Хр▒Нр░Хр░Хр▒Б р░Хр░ир▒Ар░╕р░В р░╢р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░ир▒Ир░ир░╛ р░др░Чр▒Нр░Чр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░░р░ир░┐ р░░р░╣р▒Нр░о р░Жр░╢р░╛р░нр░╛р░╡р░Вр░др▒Л р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б.тАШтАШр░ор░╛ р░Ер░Хр▒Нр░Хр░ир▒З р░Ор░Вр░жр▒Бр░Хр▒Б р░▓р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Нр░пр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б? р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛ р░ор░Вр░жр░┐ р░╕р░┐р░ир▒А р░др░╛р░░р░▓р▒Б р░╢р░░р▒Ар░░р░В р░Хр░ир░┐р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър▒Зр░▓р░╛ р░бр▒Нр░░р▒Жр░╕р▒Нр░╕р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░╡р▒Зр░╕р▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Хр░╛р░ир▒А, р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐р░ир░┐ р░Ор░╡р░░р▒В р░Пр░ор▒А р░Ер░ир░░р▒БтАЩтАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░░р░╣р▒Нр░о р░Жр░Чр▒Нр░░р░╣р░В р░╡р▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░др░В р░Ър▒Зр░╢р░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Хр▒Лр░░р▒Нр░Яр▒Б р░др▒Ар░░р▒Нр░кр▒Б р░╡р░┐р░ир░Чр░╛р░ир▒З р░ор░╡р░бр░╛ р░╕р▒Нр░кр▒Гр░╣ р░др░кр▒Нр░кр░┐ р░кр░бр░┐р░кр▒Лр░пр░╛р░░р░ир░┐ р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░ир▒Нр░пр░╛р░пр░╡р░╛р░жр░┐ р░Ер░╣р▒Нр░ор░жр▒Н р░мр░╛р░╣р▒Нр░Хр▒Нр░░р▒А р░Ер░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б."},{"question":"цмбуБоцо╡шР╜уБпф╜ХуБлуБдуБДуБжшй▒уБЧуБжуБДуВЛуБоуБЛя╝Я NHKуБпуАБф╕нхнжцабуБзуВ╡уГГуВлуГ╝уВДщЗОчРГуБкуБй29уБощБЛхЛХщГиуБлчФЯх╛ТуБМуБйуБоуБПуВЙуБДхЕеуБгуБжуБДуВЛуБЛуАБщГ╜щБУх║ЬчЬМуБоф╜УшВ▓уБохЫгф╜УуБкуБйуБлшБЮуБДуБжшк┐уБ╣уБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхМЧц╡╖щБУуБи36уБочЬМуБзуАБщБЛхЛХщГиуБлхЕеуБгуБжуБДуВЛчФЯх╛ТуБохЙ▓хРИуБМф╗КуБ╛уБзуБзуБДуБбуБ░уВУф╜ОуБДуБУуБиуБМуВПуБЛуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуБДуБбуБ░уВУф╜ОуБЛуБгуБЯуБоуБпхеИшЙпчЬМуБзуАБ50.7%уБзуБЧуБЯуАВщХ╖щЗОчЬМуБМ51%уАБчжПх▓бчЬМуБМ54.6%уБзуБЧуБЯуАВчЬМуБкуБйуБлуВИуВЛуБиуАБчФЯуБ╛уВМуВЛхнРуБйуВВуБМц╕ЫуБгуБжчФЯх╛ТуВВх░СуБкуБДуБЯуВБуАБщБЛхЛХщГиуБкуБйуБМуБкуБПуБкуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВхЕищГиуБочФЯх╛ТуБМщГиц┤╗хЛХуВТуБЧуБкуБСуВМуБ░уБкуВЙуБкуБДуБиуБДуБЖц▒║уБ╛уВКуВТуВДуВБуБЯхнжцабуБМхвЧуБИуБжуБДуВЛуБУуБиуВВчРЖчФ▒уБауБишиАуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВх░ВщЦАхо╢уБпуАМч╖┤ч┐ТуБоуБЧуБЩуБОуБМхХПщбМуБлуБкуБгуБжуБДуБЯщБЛхЛХщГиуБлуБдуБДуБжхнжцабуБкуБйуБМуВИуБПшАГуБИуВЛуБУуБиуБпуБДуБДуБицАЭуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВцОИценуВДхнжцабуБошбМф║ЛуВВхдзхИЗуБлуБЧуБжуБ╗уБЧуБДуБзуБЩуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВ","answer":"щБЛхЛХщГиуБлхЕеуБгуБжуБДуВЛф╕нхнжчФЯуБохЙ▓хРИуБМф╗КуБ╛уБзуБзуБДуБбуБ░уВУф╜ОуБД"},{"question":"Oyetс╗Нla yan с╗Нmс╗Н Bisi Akande ni kс╗Нmiс╣гanna, o tun fiyawo rс║╣ с╣гe oluranlс╗Нwс╗Н lс╗Нfiisi с╗Нkс╗Н с║╣","answer":"Awuyewuye ti bс║╣rс║╣ bayii laarin awс╗Нn lameetс╗Н ilu ninu iс╣гejс╗Нba ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun nigba ti aс╣гiri tu pe ijс╗Нba yan iyawo kс╗Нmisanna fun eto-idajс╗Н, с╗Мnarebu Fс║╣mi Akande, gс║╣gс║╣ bii oluranlс╗Нwс╗Н pataki nileeс╣гс║╣ naa.Gс║╣gс║╣ bo с╣гe wa ninu lс║╣ta igbanisiс╣гс║╣ ti wс╗Нn fun iyawo kс╗Нmiс╣гanna naa, Arabinrin Akande Yeс╣гide Oyinkansс╗Нla, ijс╗Нba yan an lс╗Нjс╗Н kс║╣rin, oс╣гu keji, с╗Нdun 2020, gс║╣gс║╣ bii oluranlс╗Нwс╗Н (Personal Assistant) si с╗Нkс╗Н rс║╣.Akс╗Нwe ijс╗Нba ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun, с╗Мmс╗Нс╗Нba Oluwс╗Нle Oyebamiji, lo fс╗Нwс╗Н si iwe igbanisiс╣гс║╣ naa, wс╗Нn si sс╗Н pe igbanisiс╣гс║╣ rс║╣ bс║╣rс║╣ lс╗Нjс╗Н kс║╣rinlelogun, oс╣гu kс║╣waa, с╗Нdun 2019.O pс║╣ ki aс╣гiri с╗Нrс╗Н naa too tu sita, o si jс║╣ iyalс║╣nu fun awс╗Нn araalu nigba ti wс╗Нn gbс╗Н pe ijс╗Нba le с╣гe iru nnkan bс║╣с║╣ fun kс╗Нmiс╣гanna naa, с║╣ni to jс║╣ с╗Нmс╗Н bibi gomina ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun tс║╣lс║╣, Oloye Adebisi Akande.Gbogbo igbesс║╣ ti awс╗Нn oniroyin gbe lati gbс╗Н tс║╣nu kс╗Нmiс╣гanna ti с╗Нrс╗Н kan ni ko so eso rere, ko gbe ipe rс║╣, bс║╣с║╣ ni ko fesi si atс║╣jiс╣гс║╣ ti wс╗Нn fi ranс╣гс║╣ si i.Bakan naa ni a ko rс║╣ni fesi lori rс║╣ ninu Kс╗Нmiс╣гanna feto iroyin, Funkс║╣ с║╕gbс║╣mс╗Нde ati Akс╗Нwe iroyin fun gomina, Ismail Omipidan."},{"question":"├Сaata fan la jig├йen di am ak dereeti mbaax ?","answer":"digante  ├▒ett fan beu jurrom benn fan"},{"question":"A que categor├нa corresponde la siguiente pregunta : ┬┐Cu├бl fue el primer equipo de Tom Brady?.","answer":"La categor├нa corresponde a deportes. "},{"question":"Lori с║╣sun agbere, wс╗Нn da olukс╗Н Fasiti FUOYE duro","answer":"Latari с║╣sun pe o fс╗Нgbс╗Нn alumс╗Нkс╗Нrс╗Нyi ba akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н kan ni yunifasiti ijс╗Нba apapс╗Н FUOYE to wa ni ilu Oye-Ekiti, igbimс╗Н alaс╣гс║╣ ileewe naa lawс╗Нn ti da olukс╗Н agba kan, Dokita Jonathan Mbachaga, duro lс╗Нgan.Olukс╗Н naa to jс║╣ с╗Нkan ninu awс╗Нn с╗Нga ni с║╣ka eto с║╣kс╗Н ere ori itage ati iroyin (Theatre and Media Art) ni wс╗Нn sс╗Н pe o ba с╗Нmс╗Н ileewe с╗Нhun to wa ni ipele kс║╣rin nileewe naa ni ajс╗Нс╣гepс╗Н pс║╣lu ero pe ko le fun un ni maaki lс║╣yin igba ti akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н naa ti fidi-rс║╣mi nigba meji leralera.Gс║╣gс║╣ bii lс║╣ta kan ti Oludamс╗Нran lori eto iroyin si с╗Нga agba FUOYE naa, с╗Мgbс║╣ni Folusho Ogunmс╗Нdс║╣de, с╣гe wi, o sс╗Н pe с╗Нga agba pata с╗Нhun lo paс╣гс║╣ pe ki olukс╗Н Mbachaga с╣гi lс╗Нс╗Н rс╗Нс╗Нkun nile fun igba kan, lс║╣yin igba ti wс╗Нn gba a mu pс║╣lu с║╣ri to daju pe o с╣гс║╣ с║╣с╣гс║╣ naa.Wс╗Нn sс╗Н pe olukс╗Н naa ba akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н с╗Нhun laс╣гepс╗Н nigba meji leralera, to si tun kс╗Н lati fun un ni maaki to с╣гeleri, eyi ni wс╗Нn sс╗Н po bi akс║╣kс╗Н-binrin naa ninu to pariwo olukс╗Н Mbachaga yii sita.Ninu lс║╣ta naa, wс╗Нn с╣гalaye pe igbesс║╣ dida olukс╗Н yii duro lс╗Нgan jс║╣ lati faaye silс║╣ fun igbimс╗Н с║╣lс║╣ni marun-un kan ti igbimс╗Н alaс╣гс║╣ ileewe naa gbe kalс║╣ lati с╣гewadii с║╣sun yii.с╗Мga agba Fasiti с╗Нhun sс╗Н ninu lс║╣ta naa pe oun ko ni i faaye silс║╣ fun idс╗Нti laarin olukс╗Н ati с╗Нmс╗Н ileewe, ati pe gbogbo olukс╗Н to ba jс║╣bi с╗Нrс╗Н ninu iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ yii lawс╗Нn yoo fс╗Нwс╗Н osi juwe ile fun."},{"question":"Tс╗Ыi n─Гm 2023, Viс╗Зt Nam c├│ bao nhi├кu ngс╗Нn hс║гi ─С─Гng?","answer":"─Р├бp ├бn 92Theo sс╗С liс╗Зu thс╗Сng k├к cс╗зa Tс╗Хng cс╗еc H├аng hс║гi, Viс╗Зt Nam hiс╗Зn c├│ 92 ngс╗Нn hс║гi ─С─Гng, trс║гi d├аi tс╗л M├│ng C├бi ─Сс║┐n H├а Ti├кn v├а tr├кn hс║зu hс║┐t c├бc ─Сс║гo thuс╗Щc l├гnh hс║гi Viс╗Зt Nam.Hс║гi ─С─Гng ─С╞░с╗гc d├╣ng ─Сс╗Г ─С├бnh dс║еu c├бc ─С╞░с╗Эng bс╗Э biс╗Гn hay b├гi cс║бn nguy hiс╗Гm, c├бc lс╗Сi an to├аn v├аo cс║гng. B├кn cс║бnh ─С├│, hс║гi ─С─Гng c├▓n c├│ thс╗Г hс╗Ч trс╗г viс╗Зc ─Сс╗Лnh h╞░с╗Ыng cс╗зa c├бc m├бy bay. Tr╞░с╗Ыc ─С├вy, c├бc ngс╗Нn hс║гi ─С─Гng ─С╞░с╗гc sс╗н dс╗еng rс╗Щng r├гi ─Сс╗Сi vс╗Ыi ng├аnh h├аng hс║гi, nh╞░ng hiс╗Зn nay sс╗С l╞░с╗гng c├бc ngс╗Нn hс║гi ─С─Гng ─С├г giс║гm ─Сi do ─С├г ─С╞░с╗гc thay thс║┐ bс╗Яi c├бc c├┤ng cс╗е dс║лn ─С╞░с╗Эng ─Сiс╗Зn tс╗н hiс╗Зn ─Сс║бi, chс║│ng hс║бn GPS."},{"question":"Ku┼Яkonmaz kimler yememeli?","answer":"Gut hastal─▒─Я─▒ olan ki┼Яiler taraf─▒ndan kullan─▒lmamal─▒d─▒r. Emziren anneler taraf─▒ndan s├╝t artt─▒r─▒c─▒ ├╢zelli─Яi olsa da hamile kad─▒nlar taraf─▒ndan t├╝ketimi zararl─▒ olabilir. Ku┼Яkonmaz ayn─▒ zamanda do─Яum kontrol├╝nde kullan─▒lan bir besin oldu─Яu i├зin hamilelik d├╢neminde kullan─▒m─▒nda ka├з─▒n─▒lmal─▒d─▒r."},{"question":"Amabutho akaZulu alwa impi yaseSandlwana ngaphansi kwayiphi iNkosi?","answer":"Amabutho akaZulu alwa impi yaseSandlwana ngaphansi kwaKing Cetshewayo"},{"question":"Senten├зa 1: L─лvi ├й uma aldeia na freguesia de Biksti e no munic├нpio de Dobele na regi├гo hist├│rica de Zemgale e na regi├гo de planejamento de Zemgale na Let├│nia. Frase 2: L─лvi ├й uma aldeia na Let├┤nia e munic├нpio de Dobele na regi├гo hist├│rica de Zemgale, e na regi├гo de planejamento de Zemgale na freguesia de Biksti. Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou n├гo?","answer":"N├гo."},{"question":"╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖ ╤Н╨╗ ╨░╤А╤В╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕ ╨а╨╛╨╖╨░ ╨Р╨╝╨░╨╜╨╛╨▓╨░  ╨Р╨╗╨░-╨в╨╛╨╛ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╨║╙й ╨║╨╡╨╗╨▒╨╡╨╣╤В, ╤Н╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛-╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Л╤А╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п ╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣?","answer":"╨Р╨║╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Б╤Г╤Г ╤В╥п╨╖ ╨║╨╡╤В╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╤Б╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Ъ╨░╤А╨░╥г╨│╤Л ╨╢╨░╤А╤Л╨║ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╤В, ╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨з╤Л╤А╨░╨║╤В╨░ ╨┐╨╕╨╗╨╕╨║ ╨║╥п╨╣╨▒╙й╨╣╤В, ╨╝╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨в╨░╨╗╨░╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╥п ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░, ╨│╥п╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛?╨У╥п╨╗ ╨░╤З╤Л╨┐, ╨║╤Г╨▒╨░╤В ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╨║╥п╨╜ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Р╨║╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╤А ╤Л╤А╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╤В╨╕╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Ф╤Г╤И╨╝╨░╨╜╤Л╥г ╨╢╨░╨╖╨│╨░╨╜╨░╨▒╤Л, ╤Б╥п╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛?╨Р╨╗╨░-╨в╨╛╨╛ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╨║╙й ╨║╨╡╨╗╨▒╨╡╨╣╤В ╤Н╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛?╨Ъ╨╛╨╝╤Г╨╖╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨░╨▒╨░╨╖ ╤З╤Л╨║╨┐╨░╨╣╤В, ╨║╤Л╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨б╥п╨╣╥п╤И╥п╨┐ ╤Н╨╗ ╨║╨░╨░╨╗╨░╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╤Л╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨Р╤П╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╥п ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░, ╤З╨░╤З ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛╨в╨╛╨╛╨╗╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╤Б╨░╨╗╨╝╨░╨│╤Л ╨░╨╖, ╤В╨░╤И ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨г╨╖╨░╨║╨║╨░ ╨║╨░╨▒╨░╤А ╨╢╨╡╤В╨┐╨╡╨╣╤В, ╨║╨░╤В ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Ц╨╕╨│╨╕╤В╤В╨╕╨╜ ╨╜╨░╨░╨╝╤Л ╤З╤Л╨║╨┐╨░╨╣╤В, ╨╝╨░╤А╤В ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Р╨║ ╨╢╥п╨╖╨┤╙й ╨║╤Л╨╖╤Л╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╤В, ╨╜╤Г╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨б╨╛╨╛╨┤╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨╕╤И╨╕ ╨╢╥п╤А╨▒╙й╨╣╤В, ╨┐╤Г╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Ъ╨╕╤И╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╤Б╤Л╨╜╤Л ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░, ╨▒╨╛╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨г╤З╨║╨░╨╜ ╨║╤Г╤И ╨║╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛ ╤В╥п╤И╨┐╙й╨╣╤В, ╤В╨╛╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨Р╤А ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕ ╨░╨┤╨░╤И╨░╤Б╤Л╥г, ╨╢╨╛╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨в╙й╙й╨╗╙й╤А╨│╙й ╨╢╥п╨║ ╨╢╥п╨║╤В╙й╨╗╨▒╙й╨╣╤В, ╨║╨╛╨╝ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨С╤Г╤Г╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨░╤В ╤В╨░╤И╤Л╤А╨║╨░╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╤В╨╛╥г ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨Ъ╤Г╤А╤Г╤В, ╨╝╨░╨╣ ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В, ╤Б╥п╤В ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛?╨н╨╝╨│╨╡╨║╤З╨╕╨╗ ╤В╨╛╨║╤В╨╛╨╜╨╛ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╨╕╤И ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨в╨░╨╝╨░╨║╨║╨░ ╨┤╨░╨░╨╝ ╨║╨╕╤А╨▒╨╡╨╣╤В, ╤В╤Г╨╖ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Э╨░╨╜ ╤З╨░╨╣╨╜╨░╨┐ ╨╢╤Г╤В╨░ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤Б╤Л╥г, ╤В╨╕╤И ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨С╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨░╤В╤Л ╤З╤Л╨║╨┐╨░╨╣╤В, ╨║╥п╤З ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨Ъ╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╨│╙й╨╜ ╨╝╨░╨║╤Б╨░╤В╤Л╥г╨░ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨╡ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤Б╤Л╥г,╨Ъ╨╛╨╗╤Г╥г╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨║ ╨╢╨░╤А╨░╨║ ╨▒╥п╤В ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╨з╨░╤А╨▒╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╥п ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╤В ╨╝╨░╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨б╤Г╨╗╤Г╤Г╨╜╤Г╨╜ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╥п ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╤В, ╨║╨░╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛.╙и╤А╨┤╙й╨║, ╨║╨░╨╖ ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░ ╨║╨╛╨╜╨╛╤В ╨║╙й╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Р╤А╤З╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╤Б╨░╤П╤Б╤Л ╨╢╨╛╨║, ╤И╨░╨║ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨С╤Г╨╗╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨║╤Г╤И ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░ ╨║╨╛╨╜╨╛╤В, ╨▒╨░╨║ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛╨Ф╨░╨╣╤А╨░╨╗╨░╤А ╤В╨╛╨╗╨║╤Г╨┐, ╤В╨░╤И╨┐╨░╨╣╤В, ╤Б╨╡╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛╨Р╤А╨│╤Л╨╝╨░╨║ ╨░╤В ╨░╤А╤Л╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╨▒╨╡╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Ф╤Л╨╣╨║╨░╨╜╨│╨░ ╤В╥п╤И╥п╨╝ ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░, ╨╢╨╡╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛,╨Р╨╗╨░-╨в╨╛╨╛ ╨║╙й╤А╨║╨║╙й ╨║╨╡╨╗╨▒╨╡╨╣╤В, ╤Н╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛!"},{"question":"╨Р╨▓╤Б╤В╤А╨╛╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╣╨╗╨╡╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ?","answer":"╨Р╨▓╤Б╤В╤А╨╛╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╣╨╗╨╡╤А (Austromenidia) тАФ ╨▒╨░╨╗╤Л╨║╤В╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г╤Б╤Г."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: роЪрпБроХрпНро░рпАро╡ройрпН роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНрод роиро╛роЯрпБ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: роХро┐роЯрпНроХро┐роирпНродрпИ"},{"question":"р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖П р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖П р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╖Рр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Ар╖Ур╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢Ъ р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╢▒р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢╗р╖Гр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢Ър╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╢╗ р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢┤р╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕ р╢нр╖Фр╖Ер╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Тр╖Др╖Т р╖А р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Гр╖Пр╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╢║р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢пр╖У р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Д р╢нр╖Пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢лр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢╕р╢║р╢вр╢▒р╢Ъ р╢Ер╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╢н р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢░р╢▒р╢║р╢▒р╖К, р╢Ер╢╖р╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╢Ър╖Пр╖Б р╢нр╢╗р╢лр╢║ (space exploration), р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╢нр╖К р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Др╢╜р╖Эр╢Ъ р╢┤р╢пр╖Кр╢░р╢нр╖Т р╢вр╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╖Пр╖Г р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕ (space colonization), р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╖Гр╖Кр╢о р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Др╢╜р╖Эр╢Ър╖Ар╢╜ р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢╢р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░р╖Тр╢╕р╢║ р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╖Ур╢▒р╖К (extraterrestrial/alien life), р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╢нр╢╗р╢лр╢║ (time travel), р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Кр╖А (parallel universes) р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢▒ р╢Ер╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╢нр╖Ар╖Пр╢пр╖У (futurism) р╖Гр╖Д р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢Ъ р╢нр╖Ър╢╕р╖П р╢Зр╖Гр╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Ър╢╗р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Тр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢ор╖П р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖Рр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Ф р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢║.р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╖Гр╖Пр╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Д р╢нр╖Пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢лр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢▒р╖А р╖Гр╖Ьр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╢▒р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Тр╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ер╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢┤р╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕ р╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╕ р╢Т р╢Жр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢н р╖А р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢вр╢║ р╢╕р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢л р╢пр╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢Ер╢╖р╖Тр╢║р╖Эр╢Ь р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╖А р╖Гр╖Пр╢Ър╢ар╖Кр╢бр╖П р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕ р╢п р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Ур╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖А р╢Ьр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖П р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╖Гр╖Пр╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╢Ер╢п р╢пр╖Ар╖Гр╖Ъ р╢║р╢нр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖А р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Зр╢нр╖Рр╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢Ъ р╢▒р╖Тр╢┤р╖Рр╢║р╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╖Гр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢Ъ р╢Ер╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢┤р╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢п р╖Гр╢╕р╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖У р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢вр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Вр╢╕р╢нр╖П р╢Жр╢пр╖Тр╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Ър╢ар╢▒ р╖Гр╖Д р╢Тр╖Ар╖Пр╢з р╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢┤ р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢┤р╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Зр╢нр╖Рр╢╕р╖К р╢╜р╖Ър╢Ыр╢Ър╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢║р╖Ьр╢пр╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Ъ."},{"question":"inona no iantsoana ny renin'ny vady?","answer":"rafozana no iantsoana ny renin'ny vady"},{"question":"р╢Ьр╖Юр╢нр╢╕ р╢╢р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╖Бр╖Пр╖Гр╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ \\" р╢Ьр╖Тр╖Др╖Т р╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕ р╢Ър╢ор╖Тр╢Ър╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢нр╢╗р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗ \\" р╖Ар╖Цр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п ?","answer":"р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢н р╢Ьр╖Шр╖Др╢┤р╢нр╖Т "},{"question":"сМ╜сИСсНЙсКХ сМасЙЕсИИсИН сКасЛ╡сИнсМИсИЕ сЙ░сКУсМИсИнсНж  (сИ▓ сКдсКХ сКдсКХ) -- сЛисЙ╝сКн сЙ┤сКТсИ╡ сЛ░сМЛсНКсЛОсЙ╜ сКи30 сЛУсИШсЙ│сЙ╡ сЙасНКсЙ╡ сКисКРсЙасИисЛН сЛисЙмсИНсЙмсЙ╡ сКасЙесЛосЙ╡ сЙасНКсЙ╡ сЙ│сЛнсЙ╢ сЛисИЫсЛнсЙ│сЛИсЙЕ сЛисИАсЙесЙ╡ сИШсМисИШсИн сКесЛлсМИсКЩ сКРсЛНсНв сЛисЙ╝сКн сИксНРсЙесИКсКн сЛисИ┤сЙ╢сЙ╜ сЙбсЛ╡сКХ сКесИБсЛ╡ сКесИИсЙ╡ сЙасЙ░сКисЙ│сЙ│сЛн сИИсИБсИИсЙ░сКЫ сЛУсИШсЙ╡ сЛисНМсЛ┤сИлсИН сЛЛсКХсМлсКХ сКасИ╕сКХсНПсИН - сЙа 1980 сЛОсЙ╣ сЙасИЫсИнсЙ▓сКУ сКУсЙнсИлсЙ▓сИОсЙл сЛисИЪсИШсИлсЛН сЛисЙ╝сКосИ╡сИОсЙлсКксЛл сЙбсЛ╡сКХ сИБсИЙсКХ сЛлсИ╕сКРсНИсЛНсКХ сИ╡сКмсЙ╡ сЙасИЫсИ╡сЙ│сЛИсИ╡ сНв сИЙсИ▓ сИ│сНЛсИосЙл сЙасИ┤сИнсЙвсЛл сИЛсЛн сЛлсИ╕сКРсНИсЙ╜сЛНсКХ сКРсМесЙе сЙасИЫсИ╡сИШсЛЭсМИсЙе сЙасНХсИлсМН сЛисЙАсЛ╡сИЮсЛНсКХ сЛисЛУсИИсИЭ сЙБсМесИн 1 сМДсИМсКУ сМГсКХсКосЙксКнсКХ 6-1 6-1 сЙасИЫсИ╕сКРсНН сЙасИШсМисИисИ╗сЛН сМисЛЛсЙ│ сИЛсЛн сЛисИЫсЛнсКРсКл 3-1 сИШсИксКРсЙ╡сКХ сКасЙЛсЙБсИЫсИИсЙ╜ сНв \\"сЙасЛЪсИЕ сКасЛнсКРсЙ╡ сИЕсЛЭсЙе сЛНсИ╡сМе сКесЛЪсИЕ сЙдсЙ╡ сЛНсИ╡сМе сИШсЙЖсЛисЙ╡ сЙасЙГсИЛсЙ╡ сИКсМИсИИсНЕ сЛисИЫсЛнсЙ╜сИН сКРсЛН сНг сКасИ╡сМИсИлсИЪ сИ╡сИЬсЙ╡ сКРсЛН\\" сЙесИИсЛЛсИН сИ│сНЛсИосЙл сЙасЛУсИИсИЭ сЛ░сИисМГ 17 сКЫ сЛ░сИисМГ сИЛсЛн сЛисИЪсМИсКЩсЙ╡сНв \\"сЙасМгсИЭ сЙесЛЩ сИ╡сИЬсЙ╢сЙ╜сКУ сЛ░сИ╡сЙ│сЛОсЙ╜ сКасИЙ - сЛнсИЕ сЛ░сМНсИЮ сЙасЛисЙАсКС сЛисИЭсКХсИИсИЫсИШсЛ░сЛН сИ╡сИЬсЙ╡ сКРсЛНсНг сИЭсКХсИЭ сКесКХсК│сКХ сИИсИШсИ╡сИлсЙ╡ сИ╡сИЬсЙ╡ сЙгсЛнсКЦсИнсИЕсИЭ сКесКХсК│сНв\\" сЛисНМсЛ┤сИлсИН сЛЛсКХсМл сЙ╡сКйсИ│сЙ╡ сНХсИлсМЛсКХ сЛнсИШсЙ│сИН сНв сЙ╝сКосЙ╣ сКисЙЕсЛ│сИЬсЛН сЛисИШсКнсНИсЙ╗ сМНсМесИЪсЛл сЙасКЛсИЛ 2-0 сИ▓сИШсИй сИ│сИИ сИ░сИнсЙвсЛлсЛНсЛлсКХ сМНсКХ сИМсИЛсЛЛ сЛисЙАсЛ╡сИЮ сЙБсМесИн 1 сЛисИЖсКРсЙ╜сЛН сКасКУ сКвсЙлсКЦсЙксЙ╜ сЙгсИИсНИсЛН сЛУсИШсЙ╡ сЛисЛКсИЭсЙесИМсЛ╢сКХ сИ╗сИЭсНТсЛосКХ сЛисКРсЙасИисЙ╜сЛНсКХ сНФсЙ╡сИл сКнсЙксЙ╢сЙлсКХ 6-3 7-5 сЙасИЫсИ╕сКРсНН сЙасМисЛЛсЙ│сЛН сЛНсИ╡сМе сЙЖсЛнсЙ│сИИсЙ╜сНв сЙгсИИсНИсЛН сЛИсИн сЙасКвсИ╡сЙ│сКХсЙбсИН сЙасЙ░сКлсИДсЛ░сЛН сЛи WTA сИ╗сИЭсНТсЛосКУ сИЛсЛн сЛисЛЛсКХсМлсЛЛсКХ сИШсКисИЛсКисЛл сЛлсМасКУсЙАсЙА сИЕсИШсИЭ сЙвсКЦсИнсИЭ сКисМГсКХсКосЙксЙ╜ сМЛсИн сЛисИШсМАсИШсИксЛлсЛЛсКХ сМисЛЛсЙ│ сЛлсИ╕сКРсНИсЙ╜сЛН сКнсЙксЙ╢сЙл \\"сЙесЛЩ сКГсЛнсИН сКасИНсКРсЙасИисКЭсИЭ сКесКУсИЭ сЙасННсИнсЛ╡ сЙдсЙ▒ сИЛсЛн сМНсИНсНЕ сКРсЙасИн\\" сЙесИЛсИИсЙ╜сНв \\"сИИсМесЙВсЙ╡ сМесЛнсЙ╢сЙ╜ сЙесЙ╗ сИИсИШсМлсЛИсЙ╡ сИЮсКнсИм сКРсЙасИнсНд сИисЛШсИЭ сИЛсИИ сМКсЛЬ сИШсМлсЛИсЙ╡ сКасИНсЙ╗сИНсКйсИЭсНд сИИсЛЪсЛлсИЭ сКРсЛН сИ╡сИЕсЙ░сЙ╡ сИШсИесИлсЙ┤ сЛисМАсИШсИисЛНсНв\\" сЙ╝сКосЙ╜ сКисМгсИКсЛлсКХ (2009-10) сКесКУ сКисИйсИ▓сЛл (2007-08) сЙасКЛсИЛ сИЫсЛХсИисМЙсКХ сИИсИШсКисИЛсКисИН сИжсИ╡сЙ░сКЫсЛН сЙ░сКисЙ│сЙ│сЛн сЙесИФсИн сИЖсКРсЛЛсИН сНв сКесИ╡сКи 1988 сЛ╡сИисИ╡ сЙасКасИосММсЛЛ сЙ╝сКосЛЭсИОсЙлсКксЛл сЛисЙ░сИ╕сКРсНЙсЙ╡сКХ сКасИЭсИ╡сЙ╡ сИ▓сЙЖсМесИй сЙасКасЛНсИ╡сЙ╡сИлсИКсЛл сЛисЙ░сИ╕сКРсНЙсЙ╡сКХ сИ░сЙгсЙ╡ сМЛсИн сЛнсЛЫсИШсЛ│сИЙ - сЙасКасМасЙГсИЛсЛн сИБсИИсЙ░сКЫ сНг сМНсКХ сКисКасИЬсИксКл 10 сЛУсЛнсКУсНЛсИн (* сЛУсЛнсКУсНЛсИн сИ▓сМесЙАсИЭ сИЭсКХ сИИсИЫсИИсЙ╡ сНИсИНсМО сКесКХсЛ░сИЖсКР сКасИЛсЛНсЙЕсИЭ)сНв сЙгсИИсНИсЛН сЛУсИШсЙ╡ сЛисЙ░сМИсКШсЛН сЛ╡сИН сКисИ╡сИОсЙлсКксЛл сМЛсИн сЙа1993 сКисЙ░сИИсЛлсЛи сЛИсЛ▓сИЕ сЛисИШсМАсИШсИксЛлсЛН сКРсЛНсНв сЛнсИЕ сЙасКесКХсЛ▓сИЕ сКесКХсЛ│сИИ сЛ┤сЙксЛ╡ сНМсИмсИн сКесИБсЛ╡ сКесИИсЙ╡ сЙасНУсИксИ╡ сЙасЙ░сЛ░сИисМИсЛН сЛисННсНГсИЬ сЛНсЛ╡сЛ╡сИн сЛисМАсИнсЛЪ сМГсКЦсЙксЙ╜ сМНсЛЩсНН сМИсЛ│сЛн сИйсМлсКХ сКлсЙЖсИШ сЙасКЛсИЛ сЛисИШсМАсИШсИксЛлсЛНсКХ сЛисКдсЙ▓сНТ сИЫсИ╡сЙ░сИнсИ╡сКХ сИЫсЛХсИисМН сКасКРсИ│ сНв сКасИЭсИ╡сЙ░сКЫсЛН сЛ░сИисМГ сИЛсЛн сЛисИЪсМИсКШсЛН сИ╡сНФсКУсЛКсЛН 6-4 6-3 сКасИ╕сКХсНО сКисЛУсИИсИЭ сКасИлсЙ▒ сИЭсИнсМе сЙ░сМлсЛЛсЙ╛сЙ╜ сЛНсМк сКисИосЙвсКХ сИ╢сЛ░сИнсИКсКХсМН сЛИсЛ▓сИЕ сКисИБсИИсЙ╡ сЛУсИШсЙ╡ сЙасНКсЙ╡ сЙасЙ░сИШсИ│сИ│сЛн сЛНсЛ╡сЛ╡сИн сИЫсИ╡сЙ░сИн 1000 сЛНсЛ╡сЛ╡сИнсКХ сЛлсИ╕сКРсНИ сЛисИШсМАсИШсИксЛлсЛН сЙ░сМлсЛЛсЙ╜ сИЖсКЧсИН сНв сЛисНЦсИЛсКХсЛ╡ 69сКЫ сЛ░сИисМГ...","answer":"сЛисЙ╝сКн сИксНРсЙесИКсКн сЛисИ┤сЙ╢сЙ╜ сЙбсЛ╡сКХ сИИсИБсИИсЙ░сКЫ сЙ░сКисЙ│сЙ│сЛн сЛУсИШсЙ╡ сЛисНМсЛ┤сИлсИН сЛЛсКХсМл сННсНГсИЬ сКасИ╕сКРсНИсНв сИЙсИ▓ сИ│сНЛсИосЙл сЙасКасКУ сКвсЙлсКЦсЙксЙ╜ сКасИ╕сКУсНКсКРсЙ╡ 3 сИИ 1 сИШсИксКРсЙ╡сКХ сКасМИсКШсЙ╜ сНв сЛисЙАсЛ╡сИЮсЛЛ сЙ╝сКосЛЭсИОсЙлсКксЛл сКесИ╡сКи 1988 сЛ╡сИисИ╡ сКасИЭсИ╡сЙ╡ сМКсЛЬ сКасИ╕сКУсНК сИЖсКУсИИсЙ╜ сНв сЛ┤сЙксЛ╡ сНМсИмсИн сКесИБсЛ╡ сКесИИсЙ╡ сЙасНУсИксИ╡ сЛисННсНГсИЬ сЛНсЛ╡сЛ╡сИн сКасИ╕сКХсНО сЛисИШсМАсИШсИксЛлсЛНсКХ сЛисКдсЙ▓сНТ сИЫсИ╡сЙ░сИнсИ╡ сЛЛсКХсМл сКасИ╕сКРсНИсНв"},{"question":"рд╕реВрд░реНрдпрдЧреНрд░рд╣рдг рд░ рдЪрдиреНрджреНрд░рдЧрд╣рдг рдХреБрдирдХреБрди рдХрд┐рдирд╛рд░рд╛рдмрд╛рдЯ рд▓рд╛рдЧреНрди рд╕реБрд░реБ рдЧрд░реНрджрдЫ?","answer":"рд╕реВрд░реНрдпрдЧреНрд░рд╣рдг рдкрд╢реНрдЪрд┐рдордмрд╛рдЯ рд░ рдЪрдиреНрджреНрд░рдЧреНрд░рд╣рдг рдкреВрд░реНрд╡рдмрд╛рдЯ"},{"question":"роХрпАро┤рпНроХрпНроХрогрпНроЯ роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐роХрпНроХрпБ рокродро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпКро▓рпНро▓рпБроЩрпНроХро│рпН. роРро░рпЛрокрпНрокро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХ роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯ 5 роироХро░роЩрпНроХро│рпН ропро╛ро╡рпИ?","answer":"роРро░рпЛрокрпНрокро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХ роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯ 5 роироХро░роЩрпНроХро│рпН: роЗро╕рпНродро╛ройрпНрокрпБро▓рпН, рооро╛ро╕рпНроХрпЛ, ро▓рогрпНроЯройрпН, роЪрпЖропро┐ройрпНроЯрпН рокрпАроЯрпНроЯро░рпНро╕рпНрокрпЗро░рпНроХрпН, рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокрпЖро░рпНро▓ро┐ройрпН роЖроХрпБроорпН.роЗро╕рпНродро╛ройрпНрокрпБро▓рпН, родрпБро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ роироХро░роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХрпВроЯро┐роп роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роироХро░рооро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЕроирпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН рокрогрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░родрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░роорпБроорпН роЗродрпБро╡рпЗропро╛роХрпБроорпН. родрпБро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ропро┐ройрпН роЗро╕рпНродро╛ройрпНрокрпБро▓рпН рооро╛роХро╛рогродрпНродро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░рооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЗродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роЙро░рпЛроорпИрокрпН рокрпЗро░ро░роЪройрпН роХро╛ройрпНро╕рпНроЯройрпНроЯрпИройрпН рокрпЖропро░ро╛ро▓рпН рокро┤роЩрпНроХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗродрпБ, роХро╛ройрпНро╕рпНроЯрогрпНроЯро┐ройрпЛрокрпНрокро┐ро│рпН роОрой роЕро┤рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. 41┬░ ро╡ 28┬░ роХро┐ роЗро▓рпН рокрпКро╕рпНрокрпЛро░ро╕рпН роирпАро░ро┐рогрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ роЗроирпНроироХро░роорпН, родроЩрпНроХроХрпН роХрпКроорпНрокрпБ (Golden Horn) роОрой роЕро┤рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИродрпН родрпБро▒рпИроорпБроХродрпНродрпИропрпБроорпН роЙро│рпНро│роЯроХрпНроХро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. рокрпКро╕рпНрокрпЛро░ро╕рпН роирпАро░ро┐рогрпИ, роРро░рпЛрокрпНрокро╛ро╡рпИропрпБроорпН, роЖроЪро┐ропро╛ро╡рпИропрпБроорпН, рокро┐ро░ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН роОро▓рпНро▓рпИропро╛роХ роЗро░рпБрокрпНрокродро╛ро▓рпН, роЗродройрпН роЗро░рпБ роХро░рпИроХро│ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ роЗроирпНроироХро░роорпН роЗро░рпБ роХрогрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ роТро░рпЗ рокрпЖро░рпБ роироХро░рооро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роЙро▓роХ ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпН, роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ рокрпЗро░ро░роЪрпБроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБродрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░рооро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХро┐роп роТро░рпЗ роироХро░роорпН роОройрпНро▒ рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпБроорпН роЗродро▒рпНроХрпБ роЙрогрпНроЯрпБ. роХро┐.рокро┐ 330 - 395 ро╡ро░рпИ ро░рпЛроорокрпН рокрпЗро░ро░роЪро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░рооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, 395 - 1453 ро╡ро░рпИ рокрпИроЪрогрпНроЯрпИройрпН рокрпЗро░ро░роЪро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░ро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, 1453 - 1923 ро╡ро░рпИ роУроЯрпНроЯрпЛрооро╛ройрпН рокрпЗро░ро░роЪро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░рооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЗродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХро┐ропродрпБ. 1923 роЗро▓рпН родрпБро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐роХрпН роХрпБроЯро┐ропро░роЪрпБ роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрокрпЛродрпБ, родро▓рпИроироХро░роорпН, роЗро╕рпНродро╛ройрпНрокрпБро▓рпНро▓ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роЕроЩрпНроХро╛ро░ро╛ро╡рпБроХрпНроХрпБ рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. роРро░рпЛрокрпНрокро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН, рооро╛ро╕рпНроХрпЛро╡ро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ роЕроЯрпБродрпНродрокроЯро┐ропро╛роХ роЕродро┐роХ роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роироХро░роорпН роЗродрпБро╡рпЗ роЖроХрпБроорпН."},{"question":"Ngiyabonga sayitsheni. Ukube anifikanga ngabe indaba yamiisingumlando. Ngibonga kakhulu sayitsheni.Ubonga ngakhona Duma kodwa nguwe oyimbangela yalokhu.Usho ukuthini sayitsheni? Yimi yini ovimba intuthuko lapha kulendawo?Uyakhumbula ngikubuza ukuthi uyathathisa na enkosini umauzokwenza utho endaweni yayo? Wathini wena? Angithi wadazainkani? Nenhlangano yakho yaphinde yakuyala ngokuhlonipha inkosi,wena wenza okuthandwa nguwe. Bafile-ke manje abantu. UMbandlwasiyezwa ukuthi ubengungqa phambili ekutheni wenze lokhuobukwenza. Naye uDlamini kuyavela ukuthi ubethukuthela aze enzeizinto ezingalungile njengakho ukushaya uMbandlwa.Angimsoli-ke yena kakhulu ngoba ubehlukunyezwa ngukubona wenauthela inkosi yakhe ngothuli.(ukuzithoba kuyadlondlobala. Useze watshekisa ngisho nekhanda.Izandla zakhe ulokhu ezihlanganisa njengomuntu okhuluma nomuntuamhlonipha ngendlela exakile) Ngiyezwa sayitsheni. (athule kancane)Sekwenzekile-ke okubuhlungu sayitsheni. Ngiyaphinda ngithi velesekonakele. Manje, ngizocela nigcine ukuthula endaweni, minasengizowuyeka-ke lo msebenzi wobukhansela.(enyuse izwi ngenxa yentukuthelo) Uthini? Uyeke? Niqala izinto besenigabisa ngokuyeka uma sekonakele? Lutho! Wena yelekelelaekucisheni lo mlilo wothathe osuwokhele.Kahle sayitsheni. Ngizowucisha kanjani lo mlilo? Bazongibulala phelaabantu. 1. Fingqa ngamaphuzu AMABILI imizamo eyenziwa nguhulumeni kanyenezinhlangano zepolitiki ekudambiseni udlame endaweni yenkosi? ","answer":"тАв Amaphoyisa kahulumeni enza yonke imizamo yokuthi kube nokuthulakule ndawo.тИЪ/тАв Uhulumeni wathumela iziphathimandla ngosuku lomhlangano ukuthizizofaka isandla ekudaleni uxolo.тИЪ/тАв Izinhlangano zezepolitiki zathumela abaholi bazo ukuzosiza endaweni.тИЪ/тАв Inhlangano kaDuma yezepolitiki yameluleka ukuthi akahloniphe inkosiukuze kube nokuthula endaweni yenkosi.тИЪ"},{"question":"риори╛ридри░ри╡рй░ри╕ри╝рйА рикри░ри┐ри╡ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╕рй░рикрй▒ридрйА риХри┐ри╕ риирйВрй░ риори┐ри▓рижрйА ри╣рйИ ?","answer":"риори╛ридри░ри╡рй░ри╕ри╝рйА рикри░ри┐ри╡ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╕рй░рикрй▒ридрйА рикрйБрй▒ридри░рйА риирйВрй░ риори┐ри▓рижрйА ри╣рйИ ред"},{"question":"Qual ├й o nome do filme brasileiro que ganhou o Oscar de Melhor Filme Internacional em 2020?","answer":"O filme brasileiro que ganhou o Oscar de Melhor Filme Internacional em 2020 ├й 'A vida invis├нvel'."},{"question":"Adeshina di Aarс║╣ banki idagbasoke Afrika lс║╣с║╣keji","answer":"с╗Мmс╗Н ilс║╣ wa, Akinwumi Adeshina, ti wс╗Нle lс║╣с║╣keji gс║╣gс║╣ bii Aarс║╣ banki idagbasoke ilс║╣ Afrika fun с╗Нdun marun-un mi-in.Eyi waye lonii lс║╣yin ipade ti awс╗Нn alaс╣гс║╣ banki naa с╣гe lori ayelujara, bс║╣с║╣ ni ko sс║╣ni to ba a du ipo naa.Laipс║╣ yii ni wс╗Нn fi с║╣sun ipaс╣гipayс╗Н owo kan Adeshina, с╣гugbс╗Нn wс╗Нn pada da с║╣jс╗Н naa nu nitori ko lс║╣sс║╣ nilс║╣, eyi to fun un lanfaani lati du ipo yii nigba keji.Tс║╣ o ba gbagbe, с╗Нdun 2015 ni Adeshina di aarс║╣ banki yii, eyi to sс╗Н с╗Н di с╗Нmс╗Н Naijiria akс╗Нkс╗Н to di ipo naa mu.с║╕ni с╗Нgс╗Нta с╗Нdun ni с╗Нkunrin naa, o si ti с╣гe minisita fun nnkan с╗Нgbin ati idagbasoke igberiko nilс║╣ Naijiria laye iс╣гejс╗Нba с╗Мmс╗Нwe Goodluck Jonathan."},{"question":"fehezanteny voalohany: Nahafantatra fanjakana sy firenena maro namolavola ny tantarany i Madagasikara.fehezanteny faharoa: Ny Mpanjaka Radama I dia nampifandray ny fanjakana malagasy taminтАЩireo fanjakana eoropeanina, indrindra fa i Frantsa.Misy ifandraisany ve ireo fehezanteny ireo?","answer":"Eny, misy ifandraisany ireo fehezanteny ireo."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"awak menangis diberi pisang\\"?","answer":"Pujukan yang tepat pada masa"},{"question":"р░кр▒Нр░░р░зр░╛р░и р░╕р░Вр░Цр▒Нр░п р░▓р▒Зр░Х р░╕р░Вр░пр▒Бр░Хр▒Нр░д р░╕р░Вр░Цр▒Нр░пр░ир▒Б р░кр▒Кр░Вр░жр▒Б р░Шр░Яр░ир░▓р▒Б(A) р░кр░░р░╕р▒Нр░кр░░ р░╡р░░р▒Нр░Ьр░┐р░д р░Шр░Яр░ир░▓р▒Б(B) р░╕р░ор░╕р░Вр░нр░╡ р░Шр░Яр░ир░▓р▒Б(C) р░Ер░╕р░Вр░нр░╡ р░Шр░Яр░ир░▓р▒Б(D) р░Пр░жр▒Ар░Хр░╛р░жр▒Б","answer":"(A) р░кр░░р░╕р▒Нр░кр░░ р░╡р░░р▒Нр░Ьр░┐р░д р░Шр░Яр░ир░▓р▒Б"},{"question":"H├гy viс║┐t mс╗Щt ─Сoс║бn v─Гn ├нt nhс║еt 200 chс╗п dс╗▒a tr├кn nс╗Щi dung ─С╞░с╗гc n├│i tс╗Ыi trong c├вu sau: T├аi xс║┐ gс║еp r├║t d├бn thс║╗ thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng tr╞░с╗Ыc giс╗Э 'G' ngay cao tс╗Сc","answer":"Tс╗Сi 31/7, tr├кn chuyс║┐n xe tс╗л B├а Rс╗Лa - V┼йng T├аu vс╗Б TP.HCM, anh Trс║зn Thanh Ho├аng tranh thс╗з dс╗лng lс║бi с╗Я tuyс║┐n cao tс╗Сc TP.HCM - Long Th├аnh - Dс║зu Gi├вy ─Сс╗Г d├бn thс║╗ thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng. Sс╗н dс╗еng 2 chiс║┐c ├┤t├┤ v├а th╞░с╗Эng xuy├кn di chuyс╗Гn tr├кn cao tс╗Сc, anh Ho├аng nhс╗Э nh├вn vi├кn hс╗Ч trс╗г ─Сс╗Уng bс╗Щ v├аo mс╗Щt t├аi khoс║гn. T├аi xс║┐ n├аy cho biс║┐t mс╗Чi tuс║зn anh ─Сс╗Бu ─Сi qua cao tс╗Сc n├аy v├а bс║еt ngс╗Э khi h├┤m nay l├а ng├аy cuс╗Сi tuс║зn, cao tс╗Сc kh├┤ng ├╣n tс║пc do nhiс╗Бu xe ─С├г sс╗н dс╗еng thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng. \\"H├┤m nay l├а ng├аy cuс╗Сi c├╣ng c├▓n thu v├й thс╗з c├┤ng n├кn t├┤i tranh thс╗з d├бn thс║╗ kh├┤ng dс╗лng. T├┤i kh├б bс║еt ngс╗Э v├м vс╗Б muс╗Щn thс║┐ n├аy vс║лn c├▓n nh├вn vi├кn hс╗Ч trс╗г d├бn thс║╗ cho m├мnh\\", anh Ho├аng b├аy tс╗П. Biс║┐t tс╗Ыi viс╗Зc thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng ─С├г l├вu nh╞░ng tс╗Ыi h├┤m nay, anh Thanh Thiс╗Зn (ngс╗е tс╗Йnh B├а Rс╗Лa - V┼йng T├аu) mс╗Ыi quyс║┐t ─Сс╗Лnh d├бn thс║╗. Chс║зn chс╗л v├м t├аi xс║┐ n├аy thс║еy th├┤ng tin thu ph├н cс╗зa c├бc trс║бm ch╞░a thс╗Сng nhс║еt, \\"trс║бm th├м y├кu cс║зu ─С╞бn vс╗Л n├аy, n╞бi th├м ─С╞бn vс╗Л nс╗Н\\". Sau khi ─С╞░с╗гc h╞░с╗Ыng dс║лn d├бn thс║╗, anh Thiс╗Зn vui mс╗лng cho biс║┐t tс╗л mai ─Сс╗б phс║гi chuс║йn bс╗Л tiс╗Бn mс║╖t mс╗Чi khi ─Сi xe, tс║еt cс║г th├┤ng tin ─С╞░с╗гc th├┤ng b├бo qua с╗йng dс╗еng. Viс╗Зc n├аy gi├║p anh tiс║┐t kiс╗Зm thс╗Эi gian, ─Сс╗б phс║гi chс╗Э ─Сс╗гi khi qua trс║бm thu ph├н. \\"Nhс╗пng ng├аy gс║зn ─С├вy, t├┤i ─Сс╗Нc th├┤ng tin tr├кn b├бo, thс║еy hс╗З thс╗Сng ETC c├▓n nhiс╗Бu lс╗Чi kс╗╣ thuс║нt. Mong thс╗Эi gian tс╗Ыi, c├бc lс╗Чi ─С╞░с╗гc khс║пc phс╗еc ─Сс╗Г t├аi xс║┐ thuс║нn tiс╗Зn\\", anh Thiс╗Зn n├│i th├кm. D├бn thс║╗ ETC tс╗л l├вu, nh╞░ng anh C├┤ng Nghiс╗Зp (quс║нn B├мnh T├вn, TP.HCM) bс╗Л mс║еt thс║╗ sau mс╗Щt lс║зn va chс║бm giao th├┤ng. Biс║┐t ng├аy mai c├бc trс║бm ├бp dс╗еng thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng bс║пt buс╗Щc, t├аi xс║┐ n├аy tranh thс╗з dс╗лng xe d├бn lс║бi thс║╗ ETC. L├║c ─Сс║зu, anh Nghiс╗Зp kh├┤ng ─Сс╗Уng ├╜ trс║г mс╗йc ph├н 120.000 ─Сс╗Уng cho lс║зn ─Сс╗Хi thс║╗ tiс║┐p theo v├м nghe th├┤ng tin \\"miс╗Еn ph├н\\". Sau khi ─С╞░с╗гc nh├вn vi├кn C├┤ng ty VETC giс║гi th├нch, anh Nghiс╗Зp d├бn thс║╗ lс║зn thс╗й 2 v├а ph├н sс║╜ ─С╞░с╗гc trс╗л sau khi anh nс║бp tiс╗Бn v├аo t├аi khoс║гn, t├аi xс║┐ n├аy ─Сс╗Уng ├╜. Trao ─Сс╗Хi vс╗Ыi Zing, anh Ho├аng Trung Hiс║┐u, chuy├кn vi├кn kinh doanh C├┤ng ty VETC, cho hay l╞░с╗гng kh├бch h├аng c├│ nhu cс║зu d├бn thс║╗ nhс╗пng ng├аy gс║зn ─С├вy t─Гng ─Сс╗Щt biс║┐n. ─Рс╗Г ─С├бp с╗йng nhu cс║зu cс╗зa kh├бch h├аng, VETC triс╗Гn khai mс║бng l╞░с╗Ыi cс╗Щng t├бc vi├кn hс╗Ч trс╗г v├а t─Гng c╞░с╗Эng tс║бi nhiс╗Бu ─Сiс╗Гm d├бn thс║╗, ─Сс║╖c biс╗Зt l├а tr├кn c├бc tuyс║┐n cao tс╗Сc lс╗Ыn. H├┤m nay, VETC sс║╜ bс╗С tr├н nh├вn vi├кn hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng xuy├кn ─С├кm ─Сс╗Г hс╗Ч trс╗г kh├бch h├аng ch╞░a kс╗Лp d├бn thс║╗. ─Р╞бn vс╗Л ─Сang d├бn thс║╗ miс╗Еn ph├н cho kh├бch h├аng v├а bс║пt ─Сс║зu thu ph├н d├бn thс║╗ tс╗л ng├аy 6/8 vс╗Ыi mс╗йc 120.000 ─Сс╗Уng/lс║зn. Sau h╞бn 6 n─Гm triс╗Гn khai hс╗З thс╗Сng thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng v├а d├бn thс║╗ ─Сс╗Лnh danh ETC, Ch├нnh phс╗з с║еn ─Сс╗Лnh 0h ng├аy 1/8 l├а \\"giс╗Э G\\" ─Сс╗Г ├бp dс╗еng thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng bс║пt buс╗Щc tс║бi c├бc tuyс║┐n cao tс╗Сc tr├кn to├аn quс╗Сc. с╗Ю khu vс╗▒c ph├нa nam hiс╗Зn c├│ 3 tuyс║┐n cao tс╗Сc gс╗Уm: TP.HCM - Long Th├аnh - Dс║зu Gi├вy, TP.HCM - Trung L╞░╞бng v├а Trung L╞░╞бng - Mс╗╣ Thuс║нn. ─Рс║┐n nay, chс╗Й c├│ tuyс║┐n TP.HCM - Long Th├аnh - Dс║зu Gi├вy do VEC quс║гn l├╜ sс║╡n s├аng vс║нn h├аnh thu ph├н kh├┤ng dс╗лng ho├аn to├аn. Tuyс║┐n TP.HCM - Trung L╞░╞бng ─Сang cho khai th├бc miс╗Еn ph├н. C├▓n tuyс║┐n Trung L╞░╞бng - Mс╗╣ Thuс║нn ─С├г vс║нn h├аnh, nh╞░ng ch╞░a ─С╞░с╗гc cс║еp c├│ thс║йm quyс╗Бn ph├к duyс╗Зt thu ph├н."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'macam ular kekenyangan'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang buncit perutnya sehingga berjalannya pun sudah tidak betul lagi."},{"question":"ржорзМрж▓рж┐ржХ ржЧржгрждржирзНрждрзНрж░ ржирж╛ржорзЗ ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржмрзНржпржмрж╕рзНржерж╛ ржЪрж╛рж▓рзБ ржХрж░рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ ржХрзЗржи?","answer":"рж╕рж╛ржорж░рж┐ржХ рж╢рж╛рж╕ржиржХрзЗ ржжрзАрж░рзНржШрж╛ржпрж╝рж┐ржд ржХрж░рж╛рж░ рж▓ржХрзНрж╖рзНржпрзЗ рззрзпрзлрзо рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗ ржЖржЗржпрж╝рзБржм ржЦрж╛ржи ржорзМрж▓рж┐ржХ ржЧржгрждржирзНрждрзНрж░ ржЪрж╛рж▓рзБ ржХрж░рзЗржиредржорзМрж▓рж┐ржХ ржЧржгрждржирзНрждрзНрж░ ржмрзНржпржмрж╕рзНржерж╛ржпрж╝ ржкрзВрж░рзНржм ржкрж╛ржХрж┐рж╕рзНрждрж╛ржи ржУ ржкрж╢рзНржЪрж┐ржо ржкрж╛ржХрж┐рж╕рзНрждрж╛ржи ржерзЗржХрзЗ ржорзЛржЯ рзорзж рж╣рж╛ржЬрж╛рж░ ржирж┐рж░рзНржмрж╛ржЪрж┐ржд ржЗржЙржирж┐ржпрж╝ржи ржХрж╛ржЙржирзНрж╕рж┐рж▓ рж╕ржжрж╕рзНржп ржирж┐ржпрж╝рзЗ ржирж┐рж░рзНржмрж╛ржЪржХржоржгрзНржбрж▓рзА ржЧржаржи ржХрж░рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ред рж░рж╛рж╖рзНржЯрзНрж░ржкрждрж┐ ржирж┐рж░рзНржмрж╛ржЪржи, ржЬрж╛рждрзАржпрж╝ ржУ ржкрзНрж░рж╛ржжрзЗрж╢рж┐ржХ ржкрж░рж┐рж╖ржж ржирж┐рж░рзНржмрж╛ржЪржирзЗ ржПрж░рж╛ржЗ рж╢рзБржзрзБ ржЕржВрж╢ржЧрзНрж░рж╣ржгрзЗрж░ ржорж╛ржзрзНржпржорзЗ ржорждрж╛ржоржд ржкрзНрж░ржХрж╛рж╢рзЗрж░ рж╕рзБржпрзЛржЧ ржкрзЗрждред ржорзВрж▓ржд ржП ржирж┐рж░рзНржмрж╛ржЪржи ржкржжрзНржзрждрж┐ ржкрзВрж░рзНржм ржкрж╛ржХрж┐рж╕рзНрждрж╛ржирзЗрж░ рж╕ржм ржХрзНрж╖рзЗрждрзНрж░рзЗ ржмрзИрж╖ржорзНржпрзЗрж░ рж╕рзГрж╖рзНржЯрж┐ ржХрж░рзЗред ржПрж░ ржоржзрзНржп ржжрж┐ржпрж╝рзЗ ржЖржЗржпрж╝рзБржм ржЦрж╛ржи рждрж╛рж░ рж╢рж╛рж╕ржирж╛ржорж▓ржХрзЗ рж╕рзБрж╕ржВрж╣ржд ржХрж░рж╛рж░ ржЪрзЗрж╖рзНржЯрж╛ ржХрж░рзЗржиред"},{"question":"р╖Ар╖Тр╖Вр╢╕р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Ур╢║ р╢╕р╖Тр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢л р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢п?","answer":"р╖Ар╖Тр╖Вр╢╕р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Ур╢║ р╢╕р╖Тр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢л р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Тр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Пр╢╕ р╖Гр╢Вр╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╢Тр╢Ър╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╢▒ р╢╕р╖Тр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢л р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖Т."},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira de Om├г.","answer":"A bandeira de Om├г ├й uma faixa vermelha vertical no canto superior esquerdo, seguida por uma faixa branca horizontal no meio da bandeira e uma faixa vermelha vertical no canto inferior direito. No cant├гo superior esquerdo, h├б um emblema nacional que inclui uma adaga cruzada com duas espadas, conhecida como o \\"Khanjar.\\""},{"question":"шп╖хЫЮчнФф╗еф╕ЛщЧощвШя╝ЪщЧощвШя╝Ъф╗Аф╣ИцШпф╕нхЫ╜хПдф╗гхолх╗╖щЯ│ф╣Ря╝МхоГцЬЙхУкф║ЫчЙ╣шЙ▓я╝Я","answer":"чнФцбИя╝Ъф╕нхЫ╜хПдф╗гхолх╗╖щЯ│ф╣РцШпф╕нхЫ╜чЪЗходхТМш┤╡цЧПцЙАхИЫщАахТМцмгш╡ПчЪДщЯ│ф╣Рх╜вх╝ПуАВхЕ╢чЙ╣шЙ▓хМЕцЛмх║ДщЗНхЕ╕щЫЕчЪДцЫ▓ш░ГуАБхПдцЬ┤хНОч╛ОчЪДф╣РхЩиц╝ФхеПхТМф╕еш░ичЪДщЯ│ф╣РхИ╢х║жя╝Мф╗гшбиф║Жф╕нхЫ╜хПдф╗гхолх╗╖цЦЗхМЦчЪДч▓╛щлУхТМчЛмчЙ╣щгОца╝уАВ"},{"question":"╪▒╪┤╪н┘Д┘Й ╪о┘Е╪│ ╪г┘Б┘Д╪з┘Е ╪╣╪▒╪и┘Й ╪г╪к┘Б╪▒╪м ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З┘Е.","answer":"╪и╪з┘Д╪к╪г┘Г┘К╪п╪М ╪з┘Д╪│┘К┘Ж┘Е╪з ╪з┘Д╪╣╪▒╪и┘К╪й ╪н╪з┘Б┘Д╪й ╪и╪з┘Д╪г┘Б┘Д╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д┘Е┘Е╪к╪╣╪й. ┘Д┘И ╪╣╪з┘И╪▓ ╪о┘Е╪│ ╪г┘Б┘Д╪з┘Е ┘Е┘Е┘Г┘Ж ╪г╪▒╪┤╪н┘Д┘Г ╪п┘И┘Д:1. ╪з┘Д╪н╪▒┘К┘Б2. ╪з┘Д╪и┘К╪╢╪й ┘И ╪з┘Д╪н╪м╪▒3. ╪з┘Д╪н┘Е┘И╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Б╪з╪к┘Ж╪з╪к4. ╪з┘Д╪н┘Б┘К╪п5. ╪╡╪╣┘К╪п┘Й ┘Б┘Й ╪з┘Д╪м╪з┘Е╪╣╪й ╪з┘Д╪г┘Е╪▒┘К┘Г┘К╪й"},{"question":"╨г╨╣ ╨╢╙й╨╜╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╨╝╨░╨╗╤Л╨╝╨░╤В ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡ ╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╥г╨▒╤Л?","answer":"╨Ъ╨╛╨╣ - ╨╝╨░╨╣╨┤╨░ ╨╝╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨║╨░╤В╨░╤А╤Л╨╜╨░ ╨║╨╕╤А╨╕╨┐, ╨╝╨╕╨╜╨╡╤А╨│╨╡ ╨╢╨╡ ╨╢╨░╨╗╨│╤Л╨╖ ╙й╨╖╥п ╤З╨╛╥г ╤В╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╤Б╨╛╤О╤И╤Г╨╜╨░ ╨╢╨░╤А╨░╨▒╨░╤Б╨░ ╨┤╨░, ╨║╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г ╤З╨╛╥г. ╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╜ ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║╨║╨░ ╤В╨╕╨╡╤И╨╡╨╗╥п╥п ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А ╨║╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖ ╤В╨╕╨╗╨╕╨╜╨┤╨╡ ╨║╙й╨┐.╨Ю╤И╨╡╨╜╤В╨╕╨┐, ╨║╨╛╨╣ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л ╨║╨╛╨╖╤Г ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В. ╨С╨╕╤А ╨╢╨░╤И╨║╨░ ╤В╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨║╥п╤А╨┐╙й╥г ╨┤╨╡╤И╨╡╤В. ╨Ь╨╕╨╜╤В╨╕╨┐ ╨░╨╢╤Л╤А╨░╤В╤Л╨┐ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╤Л, ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨╢╨░╤И╤В╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г ╤Б╨╛╤С ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╡ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜. ╨Ъ╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╤Н╨║╨╕ ╨╢╨░╤И╨║╨░ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨░╤З╤Л╤Б╤Л тАУ ╤В╨╛╨║╤В╤Г. ╨Р╨╗ ╤В╙й╨╗╨┤╙й╨╣ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╨╢╨░╤И╤Л╨╜╨░ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨║╨╡╨╜╨┤╨╡ ╤В╤Г╨▒╨░╤А ╨║╨╛╨╣ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╨░╤В. ╨С╨╕╤А╨╛╨║ ╨╢╨╕╨▒╨╡╨║ ╨║╨╡╨╖╨┤╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╤В╥п╤А╥п╨╜ ╨░╤В╨╛╨╛╤З╤Г ╤В╤Г╨▒╨░╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨│╙й ╥п╨╜╨┤╙й╤И ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜╤Г ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜, ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╤Б╙й╨╖ ╤З╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╤В╤Г╤Г╤А, ╤В╤Г╤Г╨╣ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╤Г╥г╨│╤Г╨╗╨░╤И. ╨в╙й╤А╤В ╨╢╨░╤И╤В╨░╨╜ ╨░╤И╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨░╤З╤Л ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г ╤Б╨╛╨╛╨╗╤Г╨║ ╨┤╨╡╤И╨╡╤В.╨в╤Г╨║╤Г╨╝ ╤Г╨╗╨╛╨╛╨│╨╛ ╤Н╨╝╨╡╤Б, ╤Б╨╡╨╝╨╕╤А╤В╨╕╨┐ ╤Н╤В╨║╨╡ ╤Б╨╛╤О╨╗╨░ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Н╤А╨║╨╡╨║ ╨║╨╛╨╖╤Г ╨▒╤Л╤З╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐, ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨╢╨░╤И╤В╨░╨╜ ╨░╤И╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╨╕╤А╨╕╨║ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╨░╤В.╨Р╨╗ ╤Н╨╝╨╕ ╨▒╤Л╤З╤Л╨╗╨▒╨░╨│╨░╨╜, ╤В╤Г╨║╤Г╨╝╨┤╤Г╨║╨║╨░ ╨▒╨░╨│╤Л╨╗╨░ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Н╤А╨║╨╡╨║ ╨║╨╛╨╣ ╨║╨╛╤З╨║╨╛╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В.╨Ъ╨╛╨╣ ╨╢╥п╨╜╥п╨╜╙й ╨╢╨░╤А╨░╤И╨░ ╨┤╨░ ╨▒╙й╨╗╥п╨╜╙й╤В. ╨Р╨╣╤Л╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤Н╨╜╨╡╨╗╨╡╤А╨╕ ╨╢╥п╨╜╥п ╨║╤Л╤А╨║╤Л╨╗╨░ ╤Н╨╗╨╡╨║ ╨║╨╛╨╣╨╗╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨░╤А╨░╨┐ \\"╨╢╨░╤А╨░╨│╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨╢╥п╨╜╥п ╨▒╨░╤А ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜\\" ╨┤╨╡╤Б╨╡, ╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╨▒╨╕╤А╨╕╨╜ \\"╨╝╤Г╨╜╤Г ╨║╤Л╤А╨║╤Б╨░╥г, ╤Б╨░╤В╤Л╨┐ ╤Н╨╗╨╡ ╨╕╨╣╨▒╨╡╤Б╨╡╥г ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╤В\\" ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨║╙й╨╖ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╗╨╡ ╨▒╨░╨░╨╗╨░╨┐ ╨║╨╛╤О╤И╨░╤В. ╨Р╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨░╨╣╤Л╤А╨╝╨░╤Б╤Л ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡?╨Ь╤Л╤В╤Л╤Б (╨╝╨╡╤В╨╕╤Б) ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╥п╨╜╥п ╨╢╤Г╨╝╤И╨░╨║ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨╕╤З╨║╨╡ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В (╨╝╨╡╤А╨╕╨╜╨╛╤Б). ╨Р╨╜╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨░╨╣╤Л╤А╨╝╨░╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л╨┐ ╨║╤Л╨╗╤З╤Л╨║ ╨╢╥п╨╜╨┤╥п╥п ╨║╨╛╨╣. ╨Ц╨░╨╜╨░╨│╤Л ╤Б╨░╤В╤Л╨┐ ╨╕╨╣╨│╨╡╨╜╨│╨╡ ╨╢╨░╤А╨░╤З╤Г╤Б╤Г ╨┤╨░╨╗ ╤Г╤И╤Г╨╗ ╨║╤Л╨╗╤З╤Л╨║╤В╤Г╤Г╤Б╤Г ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В.╨г╤П╥г ╨╢╥п╨╜╨┤╥п╥п ╨║╨╛╨╣╨╗╨╛╤А ╨║╨╡╨╖╨┤╨╡╤И╨╡╤В. ╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╜╤Г ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨║╨░╤А╨░ ╨╢╥п╨╜╨┤╥п╥п ╨║╨╛╨╣╨╗╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г ╨║╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖ ╨║╨╛╨╣ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨┤╨░ ╨░╤В╨░╤И╨░╤В. ╨в╨╡╨│╨╡╤А╨╡╨║ ╨╝╨░╨╣ ╨║╤Г╨╣╤А╤Г╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╨║╨╛╨╣╨╗╨╛╤А ╤Н╨╗ ╨░╤А╨░╤Б╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨║╨╕╤Б╨╡╤А ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╨░╤В. ╨Р╨╜╤Л ╨║╙й╨▒╥п╨╜╤З╙й ╨║╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖ ╨║╨╛╨╣ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨╢╨░╥г╤Л╨╗╤Л╤И ╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╤И╨░╤В. ╨з╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░, ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨в╨░╨╢╨╕╨║╤Б╤В╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╜ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜ ╨│╨╕╤Б╨░╤А (╨╢╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╤Л╤И╤Л ╨▒╨╛╤О╨╜╤З╨░) ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╤З╤Г, ╨║╤Л╨╗╤З╤Л╨║ ╨╢╥п╨╜╨┤╥п╥п ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╙й╨╖╥п. ╨Р╨╜╤Л ╤Б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В ╨┤╨╛╨╛╤А╤Г╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨║╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤Г╤П╥г ╨╢╥п╨╜╨┤╥п╥п ╨║╨╛╤О ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨░╤А╨│╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╤И╤В╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐, ╨░╨╣╨║╙й╨╗ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╤В╥п╤А╥п╨╜ ╙й╤Б╤В╥п╤А╥п╤И╨║╙й╨╜. ╨Р╨╗ ╤Н╤В-╨╝╨░╨╣ ╨╢╨░╨│╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨┤╨░, ╨╢╥п╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨│╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡╨║╨╡╨╗╥п╥п ╨╝╨░╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╤Н╤Б╨╡╨┐╤В╨╡╨╗╨╡╤В."},{"question":"╨н╨╝╨╜╨╡╨│╨╡ ╨╕╤В╤В╨╡╤А ╤В╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╡╤А╨╕╨╜ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤А╤Л╨┐ ╤Н╤Б ╨░╨╗╨░╤В?","answer":"╨Ш╤В╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨╛╨╛╨╖╤Г╨╜ ╨░╤З╤Л╨┐, ╤В╨╕╨╗╨╕╨╜ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤А╤Л╨┐ ╤Н╤Б ╨░╨╗╤Г╤Г╤Б╤Г ╨╛╤А╨│╨░╨╜╨╖╨╝╨╕╨╜╨╡ ╨░╨▓╤В╨╛╨╝╨╛╨▒╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╤А╨░╨┤╨╕╨░╤В╨╛╤А╤Г ╤Б╤Л╤П╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╤Д╤Г╨╜╨║╤Ж╨╕╤П╤Б╤Л╨╜ ╨░╤В╨║╨░╤А╨░╤В. ╨Ц╙й╨╜╙й╨║╙й╨╣ ╤В╨╕╨╗ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨░╨╣╤В╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░, ╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╡╤Б╨╕╨╜ ╤Л╤Б╤Л╨║╤В╤Л╨║╤В╨░╨╜ ╤Б╨░╨║╤В╨░╨╣╤В. ╨Ш╤В╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╡╤Б╨╕╨╜╨┤╨╡ ╨░╤П╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨░╨╖ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜ \\"╤В╨╡╤А ╨▒╨╡╨╖╨┤╨╡╤А╨╕\\" ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В, ╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨║╙й╨┐ ╨▒╙й╨╗╥п╨│╥п ╨▒╤Г╤В╤Г╨╜╤Г╨╜ ╤В╨░╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░.╨С╨╕╨╖ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╨░╤А ╤Л╤Б╤Л╨│╨░╨╜╤Л╨▒╤Л╨╖╨┤╨░ ╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╡╨▒╨╕╨╖ ╨╜╤Л╨╝╨┤╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨╡╨╣╨▒╨╕╨╖, ╨░ ╨▒╨╕╤А╨╛╨║, ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨╜╨╡╤А╤Б╨╡ ╨╕╤В╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨╡ ╨╢╨╛╨║. ╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╜╨┤╤Г╨║╤В╨░╨╜, ╨░╨╗╨░╤А ╤В╨╕╨╗╨╕╨╜ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤А╤Л╨┐ ╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╙й╨┐╨║╙й╤Б╥п╨╜╥п╨╜ ╨╢╨░╤А╨┤╨░╨╝╤Л ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╥п╤В╥п╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╡╤Б╨╕╨╜╨┤╨╡╨│╨╕ ╤Л╤Б╤Л╨║╤В╤Л╨║╤В╤Л ╤В╙й╨╝╙й╨╜╨┤╙й╤В╙й╤В."},{"question":" sheeg sanadkii uu geeriyooday boqorkii Quree Victoria","answer":" jawab. wuxu geeriyooday sanadkii 1901-dii."},{"question":"роорпЖропрпНрокрпНрокро╛роЯрпБ роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН роОройрпНрой?","answer":"роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропродрпНродрпИрокрпН рокроЯро┐роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рокрпЛродрпБ роЕродройрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпИ роЖро┤рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроорпН ро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роХро╛роЯрпНроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роЙрогро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ ро╡рпЖро│ро┐рокрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЪрпБро╡рпИропрпЗ роорпЖропрпНрокрпНрокро╛роЯрпБ роОройрпНрокро░рпН. тАШроЪрпКро▒рпНроХрпЗроЯрпНроЯро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН роХрогрпН роХрпВроЯро╛родро▓рпНроХро╡ро┐ роХрогрпН роХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроорпНтАЩ роОройрпНро▒рпБ роЙро░рпИропро╛роЪро┐ро░ро┐ропро░рпН, рокрпЗро░ро╛роЪро┐ро░ро┐ропро░рпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН."},{"question":"рдиреЗрдкрд╛рд▓реА рд▓рд┐рдкрд┐ рдХреЗ рд╣реЛ рд░ рдпрд╕рдорд╛ рдХрддрд┐рд╡рдЯрд╛ рдЕрдХреНрд╖рд░рд╣рд░реВ рдЫрдиреН?","answer":"рдиреЗрдкрд╛рд▓реА рд▓рд┐рдкрд┐рд▓рд╛рдИ \\"рджреЗрд╡рдирд╛рдЧрд░реА\\" рднрдирд┐рдиреНрдЫ рд░ рдпрд╕рдорд╛ рейрем рдЕрдХреНрд╖рд░рд╣рд░реВ рдЫрдиреНред"},{"question":"╪│139 - ┘Г┘Е ┘К╪и┘Д╪║ ╪╣╪п╪п ╪з┘Д╪╡┘Д┘И╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ┘Б╪▒╪╢┘З╪з ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д┘К┘И┘Е┘И╪з┘Д┘Д┘К┘Д╪й ╪Я","answer":"╪м139 - 5 ╪╡┘Д┘И╪з╪к"},{"question":"╨У╨╡╤В╨╡╤А╨╕╨╖╨╝ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ?","answer":"╨У╨╡╤В╨╡╤А╨╕╨╖╨╝ тАФ ╨▒╨░╨╣╤Л╤А╨║╤Л ╨│╤А╨╡╨║╤З╨╡ ╨│╨╡╤В╨╡╤А╨░ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╨╜ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜ ╤В╨╡╤А╨╝╨╕╨╜; ╨╢╤Л╨╜╤Л╤Б╤В╤Л╨║ ╨║╨░╤В╨╜╨░╤И╤Г╤Г╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤В╨░╤А╤В╨╕╨┐╨║╨╡ ╤Б╨░╨╗╤Л╨╜╨▒╨░╨│╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨│╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╤Г╨╗╨░╨╝ ╨╢╤Л╨╜╤Л╤Б╤В╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╛╤А╤В╨╛╤Б╤Г╨╜╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╨╝╨░╨╝╨╕╨╗╨╡╨╗╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И╤В╨░╨╗╤Л╤И ╤В╨░╤А╤Л╤Е╤Л╨╣ ╤Д╨╛╤А╨╝╨░╤Б╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨░╨╗ ╤Д╨╛╤А╨╝╨░╨╜╤Л ╨░╨╗╨╝╨░╤И╤В╤Л╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╨░╤А╨░╨╗╨░╤И ╨╜╨╕╨║╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╨▒╨╡╨╗╨│╨╕╨╗╙й╙й ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╤И╨▓╨╡╨╣╤Ж╨░╤А╨╕╤П╨╗╤Л╨║ ╤В╨░╤А╤Л╤Е╤З╤Л ╨Ш. ╨п. ╨С╨░╤Е╨╛╤Д╨╡╨╜ ╤В╨░╤А╨░╨▒╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨╛╤А╤Г╨╜╤Б╤Г╨╖ ╨║╨╕╤А╨│╨╕╨╖╨╕╨╗╨│╨╡╨╜.╨Р╨╖╤Л╤А╨║╤Л ╨╕╨╗╨╕╨╝╨┤╨╡ ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ┬л╨┐╤А╨╛╨╝╨╕╤Б╨║╤Г╨╕╤В╨╡╤В┬╗ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤В╨╡╤А╨╝╨╕╨╜ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨╡╨╗╨│╨╕╨╗╨╡╨╜╨╕╨┐, ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╨░╤В╨░╤А ╤Н╨╗╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╡ ╤Б╨░╨║╤В╨░┬н╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨░╤А╨░╨╗╨░╤И ╨╜╨╕╨║╨╡ ╤Б╨░╤А╨║╤Л╨╜╨┤╤Л╨╗╨░╤А╤Л╨╜ ╨░╤В╨╛╨╛ ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╨║╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╨╜╤Г╨╗╨░╤В."},{"question":"Cad ├й an Cogadh na Saoirse a tharla in ├Йirinn? ","answer":"Tugtar Cogadh na Saoirse, Uaireanta ar a dtugtar Cogadh Angla-├Йireannach, 21 Ean├бir 1919 go dt├н 11 I├║il 1921, ar an treallchogadh idir Rialtas na Breataine in ├Йirinn agus ├Уglaigh na h├Йireann, a bh├н faoi smacht na Ch├йad D├бla. Parlaimint neamhsple├бch a bh├н ann, agus ├н curtha i dtoll le ch├йile as feisir├н ├Йireannacha a v├│t├бladh isteach in olltoghch├бn Westminster sa bhliain 1918, an tromlach acu a thoiligh le dul ar an D├бil mar theachta├н."},{"question":"ркирлАркЪрлЗркирк╛ рк╢ркмрлНркжрк╕ркорлВрк╣ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркПркХ рк╢ркмрлНркж ркЖрккрлЛ:ркПркХ ркЬ рк╕ркоркпркорк╛ркВ ркеркИ ркЧркпрлЗрк▓рлБркВ","answer":"рк╕ркоркХрк╛рк▓рлАрки"},{"question":"Completa il testo seguente:\\"Il nome Bangladesh ...\\"","answer":"\\"... significa in bengalese Paese del Bengala. Il Bengala (in bengalese B├┤ngo (ржмржЩрзНржЧ), Bangla (ржмрж╛ржВрж▓рж╛), B├┤ngodesh (ржмржЩрзНржЧржжрзЗрж╢), o Bangladesh (ржмрж╛ржВрж▓рж╛ржжрзЗрж╢)), ├и una regione nord-orientale del Subcontinente indiano. La maggior parte ├и divisa tra il Bangladesh (Bengala Orientale) e lo Stato federato indiano del Bengala Occidentale, mentre alcuni territori appartenenti allo scomparso Regno del Bengala (durante il periodo della monarchia locale e del dominio britannico) sono divenuti territorio di alcuni Stati confinanti dell'India nord-orientale, come Bihar, Tripura e Orissa. La gran parte del territorio del Bengala ├и abitata da bengalesi.La regione del Bengala ├и una tra le pi├╣ densamente popolate della terra, con un tasso superiore a 900 ab./km┬▓. La maggior parte della regione soggiace nel delta del Gange-Brahmaputra, il pi├╣ grande delta fluviale del mondo. Nella parte meridionale del delta si trovano le Sundarbans, la pi├╣ grande foresta di mangrovie del mondo nonch├й habitat della tigre del Bengala. Anche se la maggior parte della popolazione ├и di estrazione rurale e agraria, nella regione si trovano le metropoli di Calcutta, Dacca e Chittagong.\\""},{"question":"р╢╕р╖Ьр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Ур╖Гр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╢п?  ","answer":"р╢╕р╖Эр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Ур╖Гр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф, р╢╗р╖Эр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Фр╢Ъ р╢Жр╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╢║ р╖Гр╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖А р╢┤р╖Бр╖Кр╢ар╖Пр╢нр╖К-р╢╕р╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╢нр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢Зр╢╗р╢╢р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╖Бр╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖Фр╢л, р╢╕р╖Эр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Ур╖Гр╖К р╢вр╢▒р╢║р╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢╗р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╢╢р╢▒ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢║р╖Т. р╢Ср╢║ р╢Зр╖Жр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Э- р╢Жр╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢┤р╖Ар╖Фр╢╜р╖Ъ, р╖Гр╖Щр╢╕р╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢Лр╢┤р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢┤р╖Ар╖Фр╢╜р╢з р╢Ер╢║р╢нр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖Т. р╢Ср╢║ р╢╕р╖Эр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗, р╢Ср╢║ р╢║р╖Фр╢╗р╖Эр╢┤р╖П р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ьр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Тр╖Е р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Гр╖Рр╢╜р╢Ър╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ср╢Ъ р╢╕ р╖Гр╖Щр╢╕р╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢║р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Т.р╖А. 831 - 1091 р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╢║р╖Ъ р╢пр╖У р╖Гр╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ср╢╕р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ър╢зр╖К р╖Др╖У р╢пр╖У р╢╕р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ър╢╢р╖У р╢Зр╢╗р╢╢р╖Ур╢║ р╢Лр╢┤р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╖Бр╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖Фр╢л р╖Гр╖Тр╢Ър╖КтАНр╢║р╖Фр╢╜р╖Э- р╢Зр╢╗р╢╢р╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢н р╢Ср╢▒, р╢╗р╖Эр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢║р╢з р╢▒р╢нр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Фр╢л р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Тр╢н тАНр╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Пр╢л р╢Зр╢╗р╢╢р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢н р╢Ср╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢Ър╖Т. р╢╕р╖Эр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Пр╖А р╢╕р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢л р╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Эр╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢Жр╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕р╢лр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Др╖П р╢╕р╖Эр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Пр╖А р╢║р╖Ер╖Т р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ур╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖Тр╢╡р╢╜р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г, р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Пр╢╢р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╢░р╖Ур╢▒ р╖А р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Фр╢Ър╖Цр╢╜ р╖А р╢╗р╖Эр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╖Ар╖Щр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╖Бр╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖Тр╢║. р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Пр╢╢р╖Т р╖Др╖Э р╢▒р╖Цр╢нр╢▒ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╢н р╢Ер╢╗р╖Пр╢╢р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢йр╖Тр╢Ьр╖Кр╢╜р╖Ьр╖Гр╖Ур╢║ р╢ер╖Пр╢нр╖Ур╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╕р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢Т р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Фр╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Ър╖Вр╖У р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Др╖Рр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕ р╢Лр╢ар╖Тр╢н р╢║. р╢Йр╢нр╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╖Др╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢╜ р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕р╢з р╢╜р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Ц р╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╖Кр╢Ър╖Эр╖Вр╢║ р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ср╢║ р╢Ер╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢Ер╢╗р╖Пр╢╢р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Гр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Др╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖П р╢Ьр╢н р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢║.["},{"question":"fenoy ny banga :\\"Ny marina toy ny rano ka _\\"","answer":"\\"tsy mety kapaina\\""},{"question":"Bu metin hangi ├╢nemli olayla ilgilidir: B├╝y├╝k Kafkas S─▒rada─Яlar─▒, G├╝rcistan'─▒n kuzey s─▒n─▒r─▒n─▒ olu┼Яturur. S─▒rada─Яlardan Rusya topraklar─▒na giden ana yollar, ┼Юida Kartli ile Kuzey Osetya aras─▒ndaki Roki T├╝neli'nden ve (G├╝rc├╝ Hevi b├╢lgesinde) Daryal Bo─Яaz─▒'ndan ge├зmektedir. Roki T├╝neli, 2008 Rus-G├╝rc├╝ Sava┼Я─▒'nda Rus ordusu i├зin hayati ├╢neme sahipti, ├з├╝nk├╝ Kafkas Da─Яlar─▒'ndan ge├зen tek do─Яrudan yoldu. ├Ьlkenin g├╝ney k─▒sm─▒ K├╝├з├╝k Kafkas Da─Яlar─▒ ile s─▒n─▒rlanm─▒┼Яt─▒r. B├╝y├╝k Kafkas S─▒rada─Яlar─▒, deniz seviyesinden 5.000 metre y├╝ksekli─Яe ve daha fazlas─▒na ula┼Яan en y├╝ksek zirveler ile K├╝├з├╝k Kafkas Da─Яlar─▒'ndan ├зok daha y├╝ksektir.","answer":"2008 Rus-G├╝rc├╝ Sava┼Я─▒"},{"question":"с╣вe oju lasan lс╗Нrс╗Н baba agba yii с╣гa, с╗Нmс╗Н с╗Нdun meji lo ba lo pс╗Н lтАЩAgbado","answer":"с╗Мwс╗Н awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa Agbado, nipinlс║╣ Ogun, ti tс║╣ baba agbalagba с║╣ni с╗Нdun mс║╣rinlelс╗Нgс╗Нta yii (64), Alagba Ayс╗Нtunde Taiwo, с║╣ni ti wс╗Нn lo fipa ba с╗Нmс╗Н с╗Нdun meji pere lo pс╗Н lс╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun,Tusidee, с╗Нjс╗Н keje, oс╣гu kс║╣san-an yii, lтАЩAgbado.Gс║╣gс║╣ bi iya с╗Нmс╗Нdebinrin naa с╣гe с╣гalaye fawс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ni nnkan bii aago mс╗Нkanla aarс╗Н с╗Нjс╗Н naa, o ni oun kan deede ri i pe с╗Нmс╗Н oun ko le rin daadaa ni, niс╣гe lo n gadi rin. O loun sun mс╗Н с╗Нn, oun yс║╣ ara rс║╣ wo, nigba naa loun si ri с║╣jс║╣ loju ara rс║╣.Iya с╗Нmс╗Н naa ni oun beere lс╗Нwс╗Н с╗Нmс╗Нde yii pe ki lo с╣гс║╣lс║╣ si i, o si nawс╗Н si ile to wa lс╗Нс╗Нс╗Нkan ile awс╗Нn, loun ba mu un gba ibс║╣ lс╗Н.O ni nigba tawс╗Нn debс║╣, niс╣гe lawс╗Нn ba baba agba yii, Ayс╗Нtunde Taiwo, to n fс╗Н с╣гokoto penpe tawс╗Нn с╗Нkunrin maa n wс╗Н tс║╣lс║╣ (boxer), eyi ti с║╣jс║╣ wa lara rс║╣, eyi si fi han pe oun lo fipa с╣гe ere buruku fun с╗Нmс╗Н kekere с╗Нhun.Ohun to mu iya с╗Нmс╗Н gba teс╣гan lс╗Н ree, ti CSP Kс║╣hinde Kuranga, DPO teс╣гan Agbado, fi ko awс╗Нn ikс╗Н rс║╣ lс║╣yin, ti wс╗Нn si lс╗Нс╗Н mu baba agba yii.с╗Мmс╗Н kekere to с╣гe yankanyankan naa ti wa labс║╣ itс╗Нju lс╗Нsibitu, wс╗Нn si ti taari baba naa si с║╣ka to n gbс╗Н с║╣sun bii eyi lтАЩс╗Мta, nibi ti wс╗Нn yoo ti pe Ayс╗Нtunde Taiwo lс║╣jс╗Н."},{"question":"Kumuu ahaa saxaabigii dilay musaylamah Al-kadaab ?","answer":"Waxshi RC ."},{"question":"What are the components of the Attention Mechanism in a Transformer?","answer":"The Attention Mechanism includes three components: Query, Key, and Value. It computes attention scores by measuring the similarity between the query and key, then uses these scores to weight the values for the final output."},{"question":"р┤Хр╡Зр┤░р┤│р┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤▓р╡Ж р┤╣р╡Ир┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Лр┤Яр┤др┤┐ р┤Ор┤╡р┤┐р┤Яр╡Жр┤пр┤╛р┤гр╡Н р┤╕р╡Нр┤ер┤┐р┤др┤┐ р┤Ър╡Жр┤пр╡Нр┤пр╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир┤др╡Н р┤Ур┤кр╡Нр┤╖р╡╗: 1. р┤Ор┤▒р┤гр┤╛р┤Хр╡Бр┤│р┤В 2. р┤др┤┐р┤░р╡Бр┤╡р┤ир┤ир╡Нр┤др┤кр╡Бр┤░р┤В 3. р┤др╡Гр┤╢р╡Вр╡╝ 4. р┤Хр╡Лр┤┤р┤┐р┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Лр┤Яр╡Н","answer":"р┤Йр┤др╡Нр┤др┤░р┤В: р┤Ур┤кр╡Нр┤╖р╡╗ 1. р┤Ор┤▒р┤гр┤╛р┤Хр╡Бр┤│р┤В"},{"question":"Inona no vanim-potoana ahafahan'ny lehilahy manan-janaka sy manangana fianakaviana?a) Fahatanoranab) Fahamatoranad) Fahazazanae) Ray aman-dreny","answer":"b) Fahamatorana no vanim-potoana ahafahan'ny lehilahy manan-janaka sy manangana fianakaviana."},{"question":"Mo mс╗Н Tinubu daadaa, oun lo le с╣гe aarс║╣ lс╗Нdun 2023- Alagba Faс╣гс╗Нranti","answer":"Olori с║╣gbс║╣ Afс║╣nifс║╣re to с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ gbe kinni с╗Нhun silс║╣ fun Oloye Ayс╗Н Adebanjс╗Н, Alagba Reuben Faс╣гс╗Нranti, ti sс╗Н pe oun fara mс╗Н с╗Нn daadaa pe ki Aс╣гiwaju Bс╗Нla Tinubu, di aarс║╣ Naijiria lс╗Нdun 2023, nitori с║╣ni toun mс╗Н daadaa ti yoo si с╣гe ohun ti araalu n fс║╣ ni bo ba de ipo naa.Ikс╗Н to n polongo ibo fun Tinubu, eyi ti wс╗Нn n pe ni тАШSouth West Agenda For Asiwaju Bola Ahmed TinubuтАЩ(SWAGA 23) lo с╣гabс║╣wo sile Alagba Faс╣гс╗Нranti niluu Akurс║╣, ti wс╗Нn waa beere fun atilс║╣yin baba naa.Ninu с╗Нrс╗Н ti baba с║╣ni с╗Нdun marundinlс╗Нgс╗Нrun-un(95) naa sс╗Н fun wс╗Нn lo ti fi atilс║╣yin rс║╣ han fun Tinubu, baba naa sс╗Н pe,тАЩтАЩTinubu kunju oс╣гuwс╗Нn lati с╣гakoso Naijiria, nitori oriс╣гiiriс╣гii nnkan lo ti gbe с╣гe lorilс║╣-ede yii. Mo fс╗Нwс╗Н si i, mo si tun gba a ladura pe ki с╗Мlс╗Нrun jс║╣ ko с╣гee с╣гe fun un. Nitori to ba depo naa tan, gbogbo ohun ti a fс║╣ ni yoo с╣гe. Tinubu ko ni i ja awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н Naijiria kulс║╣, mo mс╗Н с╗Нn daadaaтАЩтАЩBaba fi kun un pe с╗Нna kan с╣гoс╣гo ti ipo aarс║╣ ko fi ni i bс╗Н mс╗Н Yoruba lс╗Нwс╗Н lс╗Нdun 2023 ni ki gbogbo eeyan gbaruku ti Tinubu, o ni didun lс╗Нsan yoo so bi gbogbo ilu ba с╣гatilс║╣yin fun un.с╣вugbс╗Нn latigba ti baba ti sс╗Нrс╗Н yii lawс╗Нn eeyan ti n bu с║╣nu atс║╣ lu olori с║╣gbс║╣ Afс║╣nifс║╣re tс║╣lс║╣ naa, oriс╣гiiriс╣гii с╗Нrс╗Н lo si n ja ran-in lori ayelujara bayii si baba naa, ti wс╗Нn n sс╗Н pe ojo ogbo ti n da с╗Нkunrin yii laamu, wс╗Нn ni ko daju pe o mс╗Н ohun to n sс╗Н.с╗Мpс╗Н eeyan lo n sс╗Н pe с╣гe baba ti gbagbe iku с╗Нmс╗Н rс║╣ tawс╗Нn Fulani pa lс╗Нdun 2019, Funkс║╣ с╗Мlakunrin, ni. Wс╗Нn ni с╣гe ko ranti с╗Нrс╗Н ti Tinubu sс╗Н nigba to lс╗Нс╗Н ki baba naa nile lori iku Funkс║╣, to ni ki i с╣гe Fulani lo pa obinrin naa, abi maaluu wo lawс╗Нn to n sс╗Н bс║╣с║╣ ri lс╗Нwс╗Н awс╗Нn to pa Funkс║╣.Awс╗Нn mi-in tilс║╣ sс╗Н pe afс║╣nifс║╣bi ni baba, o ti kuro ninu с║╣gbс║╣ Afс║╣nifс║╣re. Bс║╣с║╣ lawс╗Нn mi-in sс╗Н pe owo ti wс╗Нn gbe wa fun baba arugbo naa lo n с╣гiс╣гс║╣ rс║╣. Wс╗Нn ni nigba tawс╗Нn SWAGA 23 ko ti i wa sile rс║╣, njс║╣ o polongo atilс║╣yin fun Tinubu bi, wс╗Нn ni owo ti wс╗Нn waa fi di Baba Faс╣гс╗Нranti lс║╣nu lo jс║╣ ko maa sс╗Н ohun ti ko tс╗Н sс║╣nu с║╣ni ti с╗Нjс╗Н ti dalс║╣ fun bii eyi.Yatс╗Н si Baba Faс╣гс╗Нranti, awс╗Нn с╗Нba meji to tun fi atilс║╣yin wс╗Нn han fun Bс╗Нla Tinubu lтАЩOndo ni, с╗Мsс║╣mawe, с╗Мba Victor Kiladejс╗Н, ati Abodi Ikalс║╣, с╗Мba George Faduyile. Wс╗Нn ni ki gbogbo с╗Нmс╗Н Yoruba ti Jagaban lс║╣yin, nitori oun ni ipo aс╣гiwaju Naijiria tс╗Н si."},{"question":"роорпБроХроородрпБ роХроЬро┐ройро┐ роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡рпИ роОродрпНродройрпИ роорпБро▒рпИ родро╛роХрпНроХро┐ройро╛ро░рпН?","answer":"рооро╣рпНроорпВродрпН роХроЬро┐ройро┐ 1000 роорпБродро▓рпН 1027 ро╡ро░рпИ роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡рпИ 17 роорпБро▒рпИ родро╛роХрпНроХро┐ройро╛ро░рпН."},{"question":"Following the Wall Street Crash of 1929 , greatest gains for the Nazis came in the Protestant , rural towns of the North , while Catholic areas remained with the Centre Party .","answer":" the Wall Street Crash of 1929 , the Nazis and Communists made great gains at the 1930 Election ."},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢Ьр╖Ур╢нр╢║ р╢Ьр╢║р╢▒р╖П  р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Кр╢п ?р╖Ер╢╕р╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Т р╖Гр╖Фр╖Ар╢│ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╖Ер╢╕р╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╖Ър╢пр╖Ур╢Ър╖Гр╖Пр╖Ар╢нр╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖Рр╢│ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢йр╖Т р╖Др╖Пр╢╕р╖Фр╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Ь р╢┤р╖Фр╢Вр╢ар╖Тр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╖Ър╢нр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢╕ р╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖Тр╢╜р╢п р╢╕р╖Др╢л р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╖Гр╖Гр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢пр╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖Ъ р╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Тр╢┤р╖Щр╢╗ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Пр╢╗р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢╜р╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Тр╢┤р╖Ьр╢йр╖Т р╖Др╖Пр╢╕р╖Фр╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Ь р╢┤р╖Фр╢Вр╢ар╖Тр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╖Ър╢нр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢╕ р╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖Тр╢╜р╢п р╢╕р╖Др╢л р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╢┤р╖Ьр╢йр╖Т р╖Др╖Пр╢╕р╖Фр╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Ь р╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Фр╢╗р╢нр╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╖Фр╢Вр╢ар╖Т р╖Ер╢╕р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Щр╖Ер╖Т р╖Гр╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╢╕р╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Щр╢п р╖Ар╢йр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ър╖Гр╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╢╕р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╖Кр╢зр╢▒р╖Т р╢┤р╖Гр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╗р╢╜р╖П","answer":"р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜р╢▒р╖У р╢╢р╖Фр╢╜р╢нр╖Кр╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜"},{"question":"╪╡┘Д╪з╪й ┘К┘В┘И┘Е ┘Б┘К┘З╪з ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╡┘Д┘К ╪и╪з┘Д╪▒┘Г┘И╪╣ ┘И╪з┘Д╪│╪м┘И╪п ╪г╪▒╪и╪╣ ┘Е╪▒╪з╪к╪М ┘Б┘Е╪з ┘З┘К ╪к┘Д┘Г ╪з┘Д╪╡┘Д╪з╪й ╪Я\\t","answer":"╪╡┘Д╪з╪й ╪з┘Д┘Г╪│┘И┘Б"},{"question":"Iza no renivohitr'i Espaina?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Espaina dia \\"Madrid\\"."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao :   \\"raha tonga ny tokoa tokoa  _\\" ","answer":" \\"raha tonga ny tokoa tokoa dia alavitra ny lainga\\" "},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпИрокрпНрокро▒рпНро▒ро┐роЪрпН роЪро┐ро▓ родроХро╡ро▓рпНроХро│рпИродрпН родро░рпБроХ.","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ :роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН роЗроирпНродро┐роп рооро╛роиро┐ро▓рооро╛рой родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН 38 рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роиро┐ро░рпНро╡ро╛роХродрпН родро▓рпИроорпИропро┐роЯроорпН роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН роЖроХрпБроорпН. роЗроирпНрод рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН 1,940.00 роЪ.роХро┐.роорпА рокро░рокрпНрокро│ро╡рпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЪрпЛро┤ рооройрпНройро░рпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роТро░рпБро╡ро░ро╛рой, роЗро░ро╛роЬрпЗроирпНродро┐ро░ роЪрпЛро┤ройро╛ро▓рпН роХроЯрпНроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роХроЩрпНроХрпИроХрпКрогрпНроЯ роЪрпЛро┤рокрпБро░роорпН, роЗроирпНрод рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ ропрпБройрпЖро╕рпНроХрпЛ роЙро▓роХрокрпН рокро╛ро░роорпНрокро░ро┐ропроХрпН роХро│рооро╛роХрпБроорпН. рокро┐ро░роорпНрооро╛рогрпНроЯрооро╛рой роорпБродрпБроХрпЖро▓рпБроорпНрокро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро╛род роЙропро┐ро░ро┐ройроЩрпНроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН родро╛роЯрпИ роорпАройрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН рокро▓ рокрпБродрпИрокроЯро┐ро╡роЩрпНроХро│рпН, роЯрпИройрпЛроЪро░рпН роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИроХро│рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡рпИ роЗроЩрпНроХрпБ роХрогрпНроЯрпБрокро┐роЯро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│рой. рокрпБродрпИрокроЯро┐ро╡роЩрпНроХро│рпИ рокро╛родрпБроХро╛рокрпНрокродро▒рпНроХрпБ роХрпАро┤рокрпНрокро┤рпВро░ро┐ро▓рпН роТро░рпБ роЖройрпН-роЪрпИроЯрпН роЕро░рпБроЩрпНроХро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐ропроХроорпН роЕроорпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН, роЪро┐роорпЖрогрпНроЯрпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▒рпНроЪро╛ро▓рпИроХро│рпН роЕродро┐роХро│ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ.ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпБроЪройро╡ро░ро┐ 1, 2001-роЗро▓рпН рокрпЖро░роорпНрокро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роЪро┐ро▓ рокроХрпБродро┐роХро│рпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. роЖройро╛ро▓рпН рооро╛ро░рпНроЪрпН 31, 2002роЗро▓рпН роЕрогрпНрогро╛ родро┐ро░ро╛ро╡ро┐роЯ роорпБройрпНройрпЗро▒рпНро▒роХрпН роХро┤роХ роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░родрпНродрпИ роХро╛ро░рогроорпН роХрпВро▒ро┐ роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН роорпАрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН рокрпЖро░роорпНрокро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпБроЯройрпН роЗрогрпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. рокро┐ройрпНройро░рпН роорпАрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН рокрпЖро░роорпНрокро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпИ роЗро░рогрпНроЯро╛роХ рокро┐ро░ро┐родрпНродрпБ, родрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ройрпН 31-ро╡родрпБ рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯрооро╛роХ роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН роиро╡роорпНрокро░рпН 23, 2007роЗро▓рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ.рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯ роиро┐ро░рпНро╡ро╛роХроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯ ро╡ро░рпБро╡ро╛ропрпН роиро┐ро░рпНро╡ро╛роХроорпНроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН, роЙроЯрпИропро╛ро░рпНрокро╛ро│рпИропроорпН роЖроХро┐роп 2 ро╡ро░рпБро╡ро╛ропрпН роХрпЛроЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпН, роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН, роЪрпЖроирпНродрпБро▒рпИ, роЙроЯрпИропро╛ро░рпНрокро╛ро│рпИропроорпН, роЖрогрпНроЯро┐роороЯроорпН роЖроХро┐роп 4 ро╡ро░рпБро╡ро╛ропрпН ро╡роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпН, 15 роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпН, 195 ро╡ро░рпБро╡ро╛ропрпН роХро┐ро░ро╛роороЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯродрпБ.роЙро│рпНро│ро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роКро░роХ ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ роиро┐ро░рпНро╡ро╛роХроорпНроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН 12 роЙро▒рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройро░рпНроХро│рпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роТро░рпБ рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯ роКро░роХ ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ роорпБроХроорпИропрпБроорпН, 6 роКро░ро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐ роТройрпНро▒ро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпН, 201 роХро┐ро░ро╛роо роКро░ро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐роХро│рпБроорпН, роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН, роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН роОрой роЗро░рогрпНроЯрпБ роироХро░ро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐роХро│рпБроорпН, ро╡ро░родро░ро╛роЬройрпНрокрпЗроЯрпНроЯрпИ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЙроЯрпИропро╛ро░рпНрокро╛ро│рпИропроорпН роОрой 2 рокрпЗро░рпВро░ро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐роХро│рпБроорпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯродрпБ.роороХрпНроХро│рпН ро╡роХрпИрокрпНрокро╛роЯрпБ2011 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роЗроирпНродро┐роп роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИ роХрогроХрпНроХрпЖроЯрпБрокрпНрокро┐ройрпН рокроЯро┐, 1,940 роЪродрпБро░ роХро┐ро▓рпЛ роорпАроЯрпНроЯро░рпН рокро░рокрпНрокрпБро│рпНро│  роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роорпКродрпНрод роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИ 754,894 роЖроХ роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роЖрогрпНроХро│рпН 374,703 роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпН 380,191 роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН роЙро│рпНро│ройро░рпН. рокро╛ро▓ро┐рой ро╡ро┐роХро┐родроорпН роЖропро┐ро░роорпН роЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ 1015 рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпН ро╡рпАродроорпН роЙро│рпНро│ройро░рпН. роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИ роЕроЯро░рпНродрпНродро┐ роТро░рпБ роЪродрпБро░ роХро┐ро▓рпЛ роорпАроЯрпНроЯро░ро┐ро▓рпН 389 рокрпЗро░рпН роОройрпНро▒ ро╡рпАродроорпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН. роЗроорпНрооро╛роиро┐ро▓родрпНродро┐ройрпН роЪро░ро╛роЪро░ро┐ рокроЯро┐рокрпНрокро▒ро┐ро╡рпБ 71.34% роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, роЖрогрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН рокроЯро┐рокрпНрокро▒ро┐ро╡рпБ 81.23% роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН рокроЯро┐рокрпНрокро▒ро┐ро╡рпБ 61.74% роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЖро▒рпБ ро╡ропродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБроЯрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роХрпБро┤роирпНродрпИроХро│ро┐ройрпН роОрогрпНрогро┐роХрпНроХрпИ 81,187 роЖроХ роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ ро╡ро┐роХро┐родроорпН 8.54% роЖроХ роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ.роЪрооропроорпНроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗроирпНродрпБ роЪрооропродрпНродро╡ро░ро┐ройрпН роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 708,397 (93.84 %) роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, роЗроЪрпБро▓ро╛рооро┐роп роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 7,942 (1.05 %)  роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, роХро┐ро▒ро┐родрпНродро╡ роЪрооропродрпНродро┐ройро░ро┐ройрпН роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 37,403 (4.95 %) роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, роЪрпАроХрпНроХро┐роп роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 104 (0.01 %) роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, рокрпМродрпНрод роЪроороп роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 88 (0.01 %) роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, роЪрпИрой роЪроороп роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 65 (0.01 %) роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН, рокро┐ро▒ роЪрооропродрпНродрпБ роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 42 (0.01 %) роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЪрооропроорпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯро╛родро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИ 853 (0.11 %) роЖроХро╡рпБроорпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ.роЕро░роЪро┐ропро▓рпНроЪроЯрпНроЯрооройрпНро▒роорпНроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН, роХрпБройрпНройроорпН, роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН роОрой роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ роЪроЯрпНроЯрооройрпНро▒родрпН родрпКроХрпБродро┐роХро│рпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯродрпБ.роороХрпНроХро│ро╡рпИроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯрокрпН рокроХрпБродро┐роХро│рпН роЪро┐родроорпНрокро░роорпН роороХрпНроХро│ро╡рпИродрпН родрпКроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ.рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░роорпНроЗроЩрпНроХрпБ роЪрпБрогрпНрогро╛роорпНрокрпБроХрпН роХро▓рпН рооро┐роХрпБродро┐ропро╛роХ роХро┐роЯрпИрокрпНрокродро╛ро▓рпН роЗроЩрпНроХрпБ родрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ро▓рпЗропрпЗ роЕродро┐роХрооро╛рой роОрогрпНрогро┐роХрпНроХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐роорпЖрогрпНроЯрпН роЖро▓рпИроХро│рпН роЙро│рпНро│рой. роЗродройро╛ро▓рпН роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН роЪро┐роорпЖрогрпНроЯрпН роЪро┐роЯрпНроЯро┐ (Cement city) роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро░ро╡ро▓ро╛роХ роЕро┤рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роЪро┐роорпЖрогрпНроЯрпН родро╡ро┐ро░ роиро┐ро▓роХрпНроХро░ро┐ роЕродро┐роХ роЕро│ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роХро┐роЯрпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. родрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН  роирпЖропрпНро╡рпЗро▓ро┐роХрпНроХрпБ роЕроЯрпБродрпНродрокроЯро┐ропро╛роХ роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН рокроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХ роЕро│ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН рокроЯро┐роороЩрпНроХро│ро╛роХроХрпН  роХро┐роЯрпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ, роЗродройрпИропроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ родрооро┐ро┤роХ роЕро░роЪрпБроорпН роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН роЕройро▓рпН рооро┐ройрпНроиро┐ро▓рпИроп родро┐роЯрпНроЯроорпН роОройрпНро▒ роТро░рпБ родро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпИ роЖро░роорпНрокро┐родрпНродрпБ роЕродро▒рпНроХро╛рой рокрпВро░рпНро╡ро╛роЩрпНроХрокрпН рокрогро┐роХро│рпИ роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роЗродрпБ родро╡ро┐ро░ роЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖроорпНроорогрпН рооро┐роХрпБроирпНродрпБ роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡родро╛ро▓рпН роорпБроирпНродро┐ро░ро┐ роЕродро┐роХ роЕро│ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН рокропро┐ро░ро┐роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рокрпБро╡ро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпНроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп роиродро┐роХро│ро╛ро╡ройтАМ : роХрпКро│рпНро│ро┐роЯроорпН, рооро░рпБродрпИропро╛ро▒рпБ, ро╡рпЖро│рпНро│ро╛ро▒рпБ.роЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп роироХро░роЩрпНроХро│рпН :  роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН, роЙроЯрпИропро╛ро░рпНрокро╛ро│рпИропроорпН, роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН.роОро▓рпНро▓рпИроХро│рпНро╡роЯроХрпНроХрпБ ро╡роЯроХро┐ро┤роХрпНроХрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роХро┐ро┤роХрпНроХро┐ро▓рпН : роХроЯро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпНродрпЖро▒рпНроХрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН родрпЖройрпНроХро┐ро┤роХрпНроХро┐ро▓рпН : родроЮрпНроЪро╛ро╡рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпНродрпЖройрпНроорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЗ : родро┐ро░рпБроЪрпНроЪро┐ро░ро╛рокрпНрокро│рпНро│ро┐ рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпНроорпЗро▒рпНроХрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡роЯроорпЗро▒рпНроХро┐ро▓рпН : рокрпЖро░роорпНрокро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпНро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпБроЯрпИроп рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИродрпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпН, роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп рокроЩрпНроХро╛роХ родрпКроЯро░рпНроирпНродрпБ роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роОро┤рпБрокродрпБ роЪродро╡ро┐роХро┐род роороХрпНроХро│рпН ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЕродрпБ роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНродродрпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпНроХро│рпИроЪрпН роЪрпЖропрпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН. родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роПро┤рпБ рокрпЖро░ро┐роп ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпН роХро╛ро▓роиро┐ро▓рпИ роорогрпНроЯро▓роЩрпНроХро│ро╛роХ ро╡роХрпИрокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН роорогрпНроЯро▓ роОрогрпН -V роОройроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐ропрпАроЯрпБ родро░рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЕродро╛ро╡родрпБ роХро╛ро╡ро┐ро░ро┐ роЯрпЖро▓рпНроЯро╛ роорогрпНроЯро▓роорпН. ро╡рпЖрокрпНрокроиро┐ро▓рпИ роЕродро┐роХрокроЯрпНроЪрооро╛роХ 38тДГ-ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роХрпБро▒рпИроирпНродрокроЯрпНроЪрооро╛роХ 24тДГ ро╡ро░рпИ роиро┐ро▓ро╡ро┐ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рокро░рокрпНрокро│ро╡рпБроЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роорпКродрпНрод рокро░рокрпНрокрпБ, 1,949.31 роЪродрпБро░ роХро┐ро▓рпЛ роорпАроЯрпНроЯро░ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роорпКродрпНрод рокропро┐ро░рпН рокро░рокрпНрокро╛ройродрпБ 1.118 роЗро▓роЯрпНроЪроорпН роОроХрпНроЯрпЗро░ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЪро░ро╛роЪро░ро┐ ро╡ро░рпБроЯро╛роирпНродро┐ро░ рооро┤рпИ роЕро│ро╡ро╛ройродрпБ 954 рооро┐.роорпА роЖроХрпБроорпН. роЗроирпНроиро┐ро▓рокрпНрокро░рокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН 45136 роОроХрпНроЯрпЗро░рпН роирпАро░рпН рокро╛роЪрой ро╡роЪродро┐рокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роХро╛ро╡ро┐ро░ро┐ропро┐ройрпН роХро┐ро│рпИроХро│рпН ро╡ро┤ро┐ропро╛роХ 10389 роОроХрпНроЯрпЗро░рпН родро┐ро░рпБрооро╛ройрпВро░рпН, родро╛. рокро┤рпВро░рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН ро╡роЯрпНроЯро╛ро░роорпН рокро╛роЪройроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роорпАродроорпБро│рпНро│ 66738 роОроХрпНроЯрпЗро░рпН, рооро┤рпИ роирпАро░рпИ роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод рооро╛ройро╛ро╡ро╛ро░ро┐ (рооро┤рпИ роирпАро░рпИ роороЯрпНроЯрпБроорпЗ роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИ) рокроХрпБродро┐роХро│ро╛роХрпБроорпН.роорогрпН ро╡роХрпИроорпИроорогрпНрогро┐ройрпН роЗропро▓рпНрокрпБ рокрпЖро░рпБроорпНрокро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роХро│ро┐роорогрпН рокро╛роЩрпНроХро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, роЪро┐ро╡рокрпНрокрпБ роиро┐ро▒рооро╛ройрпИ роорпЗро▒рпНрокроХрпБродро┐ропрпБроорпН, роороЮрпНроЪро│рпН роиро┐ро▒рооро╛рой роЕроЯро┐рокрпНрокроХрпБродро┐ропрпБроорпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЗродройрпН ро╡рпЗродро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпН родройрпНроорпИроХро│ро╛рой роЗро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроЪрпН роЪродрпНродрпБ роЕродро┐роХроорпБроорпН, роЪрпБрогрпНрогро╛роорпНрокрпБроХрпН роХро▓рпНро▓рпБроорпН роХро▓роирпНродрпБро│рпНро│, роЪрпЖроирпНроиро┐ро▒ роХро│ро┐роорогрпН (Ferruginous red loam) роЙро│рпНро│ роиро┐ро▓родрпНродро┐ройрпН родройрпНроорпИ роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роорогрпНрогро┐ройрпН роироЯрпБ роЖро┤родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН, роЪро┐ро▒роирпНрод ро╡роЯро┐роХро╛ро▓рпН ро╡роЪродро┐ропрпБроорпН, роЙрокрпНрокрпБроорпН, роХро╛ро░родрпН родройрпНроорпИропрпБроорпН роЗро▓рпНро▓ро╛рооро▓рпН,  роХро╛ро░роХро╛роЯро┐родрпНродройрпНроорпИроЪрпН роЪрпБроЯрпНроЯрпЖрогрпН 6.5-ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ 8 ро╡ро░рпИ роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЕроЩрпНроХроХродрпН родройрпНроорпИроХро│ро╛рой, родро┤рпИроЪрпНроЪродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро│рпБроорпН, роорогро┐роЪрпНроЪродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро│рпБроорпН роЕро│ро╡рпБ роХрпБро▒рпИроирпНродрпБ роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЖройро╛ро▓рпН, роЪро╛роорпНрокро▓рпН роЪродрпНродрпБроорпН, роЪрпБрогрпНрогро╛роорпНрокрпБроорпН роЕро│ро╡рпБ роЕродро┐роХрооро╛роХро╡рпЗ роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЪрпЖроирпНродрпБро▒рпИ, родро╛. рокро┤рпВро░рпН, роЖрогрпНроЯро┐роороЯроорпН, роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН ро╡роЯрпНроЯро╛ро░роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖроорпНроорпИропро╛рой роЪро░ро│рпИроорогрпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. родро┐ро░рпБрооро╛ройрпВро░ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН, роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН ро╡роЯрпНроЯро╛ро░роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН, роХро░ро┐роЪро▓рпН роорогрпН роЕродро┐роХрооро╛роХроХрпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.роорогрпН ро╡ро│родрпНродрпИ роЙропро┐ро░рпН роЙро░роЩрпНроХро│рпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ роорпЗроорпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБродро▓рпН, родрпЗроЪро┐роп ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИ ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐родрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роТро░рпБроЩрпНроХро┐рогрпИроирпНрод роКроЯрпНроЯроЪрпНроЪродрпНродрпБ роорпЗро▓ро╛рогрпНроорпИ, ро╡ро┐родрпИ роХро┐ро░ро╛роородрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роорогрпНро╡ро│ роЕроЯрпНроЯрпИ роЗропроХрпНроХроорпН, родрпЗроЪро┐роп роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН ро╡ро┐родрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН рокройрпИ роЗропроХрпНроХроорпН, рокроЪрпБроирпНродро╛ро│рпН роЙро░роорпН, родрпЗроЪро┐роп роЙрогро╡рпБрокрпН рокро╛родрпБроХро╛рокрпНрокрпБ роЗропроХрпНроХроорпН, родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпБ рокро░рпБродрпНродро┐роЪрпН роЪро╛роХрпБрокроЯро┐ роЗропроХрпНроХроорпН, родрпЗроЪро┐роп роирпАроЯро┐родрпНрод ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИ роЗропроХрпНроХроорпН, роТро░рпБроЩрпНроХро┐рогрпИроирпНрод рокрпВроЪрпНроЪро┐ роорпЗро▓ро╛рогрпНроорпИродрпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпН роирпБроЯрпНрокроЩрпНроХро│рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒родрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ропродрпНродрпБро╡роорпН роЕро│ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рооро╛роиро┐ро▓ роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН рокроЩрпНроХрпБроЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рокро▓ро╡роХрпИропро╛рой рокропро┐ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЪро╛роХрпБрокроЯро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНропрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡родро╛ро▓рпН ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпН роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод родрпКро┤ро┐ро▒рпНроЪро╛ро▓рпИроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роорпВро▓рокрпНрокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроХро│рпН родрпЗро╡рпИропрпИрокрпН рокрпВро░рпНродрпНродро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНродро▓рпН, роКро░роХ роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИроХрпНроХрпБ ро╡рпЗро▓рпИ ро╡ро╛ропрпНрокрпНрокро┐ройрпИ роЕро│ро┐родрпНродро▓рпН роЖроХро┐ропро╡рпИропрпЗ ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИродрпН родрпБро▒рпИропро┐ройрпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп роХрпКро│рпНроХрпИропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, роХрпЛроЯрпНрокро╛роЯрпБроХро│ро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЗро░рпБрокрпНрокродро╛роХ родрпЖро░ро┐ро╡ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпН ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐родрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпИ роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБродро▓рпН, роЕродро▒рпНроХрпБро░ро┐ропродрпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпН роирпБроЯрпНрокроЩрпНроХро│рпИ роХрогрпНроЯро▒ро┐родро▓рпН, роЕродройрпИ рокро░рокрпНрокрпБродро▓рпН роЖроХро┐роп роЪрпЖропро▓рпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройро╛ро▓рпН ро╡рпЗро│ро╛рогрпНроорпИ родрпБро▒рпИ роЪрпЖропро▒рпНродро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпБроЯройрпН роЪрпЖропро▒рпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роироЯрпБро╡рогрпН роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН рокроЩрпНроХрпБроЗро░рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройрпБроорпН, роироЯрпБро╡рогрпН роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро╛рой, рокро┐ро░родроо роороирпНродро┐ро░ро┐ роХро┐ро╕ро╛ройрпН роЪроорпНрооро╛ройрпН роиро┐родро┐ родро┐роЯрпНроЯроорпН ро╡ро┤ро┐ропрпЗ роЪрпКроирпНрод роХро┐ро░ро╛роородрпНродро┐ро▓рпН ро╡роЪро┐роХрпНроХро╛род ро╡ро┐ро╡роЪро╛ропро┐роХро│ро┐ройрпН рокроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро▓рпНроХро│рпИ роХро╛рогрпБроорпН рокрпЛродрпБ, роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роПро▓ро╛роХрпНроХрпБро▒ро┐роЪрпНроЪро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роХрпАро┤рокрпНрокро┤рпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роиро╛роХроороЩрпНроХро▓роорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, родро┐ро░рпБрооро╛ройрпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЪрпЖроирпНродрпБро▒рпИ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, рокрпКройрпНрокро░рокрпНрокро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН,  роЖро░рпН.роОро╕рпН. рооро╛родрпНродрпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЙроЯрпИропро╛ро░рпНрокро╛ро│рпИропроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роХрпБрогрпНроЯро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЪрпБродрпНродрооро▓рпНро▓ро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, родро╛.рокро┤рпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЖрогрпНроЯро┐роороЯроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роХрпБро╡ро╛роХроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, рокро▓рпНро╡рпЗро▒рпБ ро╡роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роХрпБроЯро┐рокрпЖропро░рпНро╡рпБ роироЯрпИрокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│родрпИ роЕро▒ро┐роп роЗропро▓рпБроорпН. роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН, рокро┐ро░родроо роороирпНродро┐ро░ро┐ роХро┐роЪро╛ройрпН роЪроорпНрооро╛ройрпН роиро┐родро┐ родро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роХрпАро┤рпН родро┐ро░рпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ родроХрпБродро┐ропро▒рпНро▒рпЛро░рпН рокроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро▓рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роПро▓ро╛роХрпНроХрпБро▒ро┐роЪрпНроЪро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роХрпАро┤рокрпНрокро┤рпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роиро╛роХроороЩрпНроХро▓роорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН,родро┐ро░рпБрооро╛ройрпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЪрпЖроирпНродрпБро▒рпИ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, рокрпКройрпНрокро░рокрпНрокро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН,  роЖро░рпН.роОро╕рпН. рооро╛родрпНродрпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЙроЯрпИропро╛ро░рпНрокро╛ро│рпИропроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роХрпБрогрпНроЯро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЪрпБродрпНродрооро▓рпНро▓ро┐ роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, родро╛.рокро┤рпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роЖрогрпНроЯро┐роороЯроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роХрпБро╡ро╛роХроорпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН роЖроХро┐роп роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН роЙро│рпНро╡роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХро╛рой родройро┐родрпНродройро┐ рокроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│рой.рокрпЛроХрпНроХрпБро╡ро░родрпНродрпБ ро╡роЪродро┐роХро│рпНродрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ройрпН рокро▓ рокроХрпБродро┐роХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЪро╛ро▓рпИ роорпВро▓роорпН роЪрпЖройрпНро▒рпБ ро╡ро░ роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЬрпЖропроЩрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯроорпН роЖроХро┐роп роироХро░роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН рокрпЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБроХро│рпН роЗропроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН родрпКроЯро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роорпВро▓роорпН роЪрпЖройрпНро▒рпБ ро╡ро░ роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН родрпКроЯро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роиро┐ро▓рпИропроорпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп роЪроирпНродро┐рокрпНрокро╛роХ роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН роЕро░ро┐ропро▓рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН родрпКроЯро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роиро┐ро▓рпИропроЩрпНроХро│ро╛рой роЪро┐ро▓рпНро▓роХрпНроХрпБроЯро┐, ро╡рпЖро│рпНро│рпВро░рпН, роТроЯрпНроЯроХрпНроХрпЛро╡ро┐ро▓рпН, роЪрпЖроирпНродрпБро▒рпИ, роЖро░рпН.роОро╕рпН.рооро╛родрпНродрпВро░рпН, роИроЪрпНроЪроЩрпНроХро╛роЯрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роИроЪрпНроЪроЩрпНроХро╛роЯрпБ (ро╣ро╛ро▓рпНроЯрпН) ро╡ро░рпИ роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ.роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБро▓ро╛ родро│роЩрпНроХро│рпНроХроЩрпНроХрпИроХрпКрогрпНроЯ роЪрпЛро┤рокрпБро░роорпНроЪрпЛро┤ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН рокрпЖро░рпБрооро░роЪрпИ роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡ро┐роп роорпБродро▓ро╛роорпН роЗро░ро╛роЬро░ро╛роЬ роЪрпЛро┤ройрпН роороХройро╛рой роЗро░ро╛роЪрпЗроирпНродро┐ро░ роЪрпЛро┤ройро╛ро▓рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБ рокро┐ро▒рпНроХро╛ро▓роЪрпН роЪрпЛро┤ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░рооро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХро┐ропродрпБ. роЗроЩрпНроХрпБ роЗро░ро╛роЬрпЗроирпНродро┐ро░ роЪрпЛро┤ройро╛ро▓рпН роХроЯрпНроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роЪро┐ро╡ро╛ро▓ропроорпН роЗройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЕродройрпИ роРроХрпНроХро┐роп роиро╛роЯрпБроХро│рпН роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБ роЙро▓роХ рокро╛ро░роорпНрокро░ро┐роп роЪро┐ройрпНройрооро╛роХ роЕро▒ро┐ро╡ро┐родрпНродродрпБ. роХроЩрпНроХрпИроХрпКрогрпНроЯ роЪрпЛро┤рокрпБро░роорпН роХрпЛропро┐ро▓рпН родроЮрпНроЪро╛ро╡рпВро░рпН роХрпЛропро┐ро▓рпИ ро╡ро┐роЯ роЪро┐ро▒ро┐ропродрпБ, роЖройро╛ро▓рпН роЪрпБродрпНродро┐роХро░ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЗро╡рпИ роЗро░рогрпНроЯрпБроорпН родрпЖройрпНройро┐роирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН, рооро┐роХрокрпНрокрпЖро░ро┐роп роЪро┐ро╡ройрпН роХрпЛропро┐ро▓рпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗроХрпНроХрпЛропро┐ро▓рпН родроЮрпНроЪро╛ро╡рпВро░ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роЪрпБрооро╛ро░рпН 70 роХро┐ро▓рпЛроорпАроЯрпНроЯро░рпН (43 роорпИро▓рпН) родрпКро▓рпИро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ.ро╡рпЗроЯрпНроЯроХрпНроХрпБроЯро┐ тАН роХро░рпИро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯро┐ рокро▒ро╡рпИроХро│рпН роЪро░рогро╛ро▓ропроорпНродрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпБро│рпНро│ рооро┐роХ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ропрооро╛рой роиройрпНройрпАро░рпН роПро░ро┐роХро│рпБро│рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. рооро╛роиро┐ро▓родрпНродро┐ройрпН рокрпЖро░ро┐роп роПро░ро┐роХро│рпБро│рпН роЗродрпБро╡рпБроорпН роТройрпНро▒рпБ. роЗроирпНрод роПро░ро┐, рооро╛роиро┐ро▓родрпНродро┐ройрпН рооро┐роХ роЕродро┐роХ роЕро│ро╡ро┐ро▓ро╛рой роирпАро░рпНрокрпНрокро▒ро╡рпИроХро│рпН ро╡роирпНродрпБ роХрпВроЯрпБроорпН роЗроЯрооро╛роХ рокродро┐ро╡рпБ роЪрпЖропрпНропрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЗроЪрпНроЪро░рогро╛ро▓ропродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ 188 рокро▒ро╡рпИ роЗройроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН 82 роЗройроЩрпНроХро│рпН роирпАро░рпНрокрпНрокро▒ро╡рпИроХро│ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЕро░рпБроХро┐ро╡ро░рпБроорпН рокроЯрпНроЯрпИродро▓рпИ ро╡ро╛родрпНродрпБ, роЗроирпНрод роПро░ро┐ропро┐ройрпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро░рпБроХрпИропро╛ро│ро░рпНроХро│рпБро│рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХрпБроорпН."},{"question":"'Kulungile-ke. Asihlale phansi njengoba usho. Sizoqhubeka. Vele useleleumntanami, isilele indodana yami.''Hlala lapha-ke. Ngizohlala la, ungangithinti bandla Sipho, ngiyakucela.Ungangithinti.' Ahlale abheke le. Kusobala ukuthi usengilahlile ngempelauNokwazi. Kodwa pho eminyakeni emibili nje vo!'Uphumaphi Sipho?' ebuza.'Nokwazi, ngicela uxolo, Sithandwa. Ngizozama ukulubeka udaba lonke, yizengizolubeka ngezinqamulelayo nje ukuze sisheshe singene endlini. Ngasengikhathele ukusebenza ngingayiboni imali. Ngase ngifuna ukusheshangiqedele ilobolo ebese sishada. Ngangifuna sithi singashada ebese siyohlalasobathathu edolobheni, mina nawe nendodana yethu, sibe ngumndenionentokozo.' Ngigwinye amathe.'Kwase kubanjani Sipho?' kubuza yena.'Ngahamba Nokwazi sengiyibonile imali laphaya emsebenzini ukuthiigcinwaphi. Akekho owayesebenza ngalelo langa engahamba ngalo. Ngafikasekumnyama kuthule kuthe cwaka. Ngavula kahle ngokhiye engasengiwebile, ngayithatha yonke leyo mali.''Uqonde ukuthi wawufuna ukungishada ngemali yokwebiwa? Ngemaliyokwebiwa Sipho?''Ayikho into engangizoyenza Nokwazi. Uyihlo nawe uyazi ukuthi wayejahekanjani ukuthi sishade nawe. Nami futhi ngangifuna ukuba usheshe usondeleneno.''Qhubeka Sipho.''Ngayithatha-ke imali ngaphuma. Kwaba yinhlanhla nje ukuthi onogadabangangizwa ngisangena. Inkinga yaba lapho sengiphuma, bangibona.Saqhuma kanye isibhamu ...!''Isibhamu futhi!' egxuma ema laphaya. 'Namanje usakhuluma ngesibhamu!'Uyazwelana yini nomlingiswa onguSipho ngesimo ayesebhekenenaso ngasekugcineni kwale ndaba emfushane?","answer":"Yebo ngiyazwelana ngoba ...Ukuzithola usuhlezi phezu kwethuna akuyona into emnandi,isimo esethusayo nesihlasimulisa umzimba.  Ukungabibikho kwezinto zokuhamba eziningi endaweniyakubo kaNokwazi kwamenza wafika ebusuku, watholaizinkinga endleleni.Cha angizwelani ngoba ...Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo: Wakhombisa ukungethembeki ngesikhathi entshontsha imalilapho ayesebenza khona. Kwakungafanele avumele ukuthi izinkinga zakhe zimfakeesilingweni sokuntshontsha."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai udang bertahi di kepala\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang yang sentiasa berhutang. Contohnya, Ghanesh terjebat dalam ketagihan judi dan bagai udang bertahi di kepala akibatnya. "},{"question":"чП╛хЬиуБоуГЬуВжуГкуГ│уВ░уБохОЯхЮЛуБзуБВуВЛуАМуГКуВдуГ│уГФуГ│уВ║уАНуВТшАГцбИуБЧуБЯуБиуБДуВПуВМуВЛуАБуГЙуВдуГДуБохоЧцХЩцФ╣щЭйшАЕуБиуБДуБИуБ░шк░уБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"уГЮуГлуГБуГ│уГ╗уГлуВ┐уГ╝"},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Descascar o abacaxi?\\"","answer":"Significa resolver algo complicado."},{"question":"Unsa ang nasudnon nga hayop sa Pilipinas?","answer":"Ang nasudnon nga prutas sa Pilipinas mao ang Kabaw/Kalabaw."},{"question":"Zadzikisa nyaudzosingwi nezvainoreva:ndee ","answer":"kutarisa"},{"question":"шлЛхЫЮчнФщАЩхАЛхХПщбМя╝Ъч╛ОхЬЛчЪДуАМхдзцПРщаУхЬЛхо╢хЕмхЬТуАНф╜НцЦ╝хУкхАЛх╖Юя╝Я","answer":"чнФцбИя╝Ъч╛ОхЬЛчЪДхдзцПРщаУхЬЛхо╢хЕмхЬТя╝ИGreat Smoky Mountains National Parkя╝Йф╜НцЦ╝чФ░ч┤Нше┐х╖ЮхТМхМЧхНбч╛Еф╛Жч┤Нх╖ЮчЪДф║дчХМшЩХуАВщАЩцШпч╛ОхЬЛцЬАхПЧцнбш┐ОчЪДхЬЛхо╢хЕмхЬТф╣Лф╕Ая╝Мф╗ехЕ╢хгпщ║ЧчЪДх▒▒шДИцЩпшзАхТМш▒РхпМчЪДчФЯцЕЛч│╗ч╡▒шАМшБЮхРНуАВ"},{"question":"чП╛хЬиуГвуГПуГбуГГуГЙуГ╗уВиуГлуГРуГйуГАуВд (Mohammed Elbaradei) уБМф║ЛхЛЩх▒АщХ╖уВТхЛЩуВБуБжуБДуВЛ уАБ1957х╣┤уБлхОЯхнРхКЫх╣│хТМхИйчФиф┐ГщА▓уБица╕цЛбцХгщШ▓цнвуВТчЫочЪДуБлшинчлЛуБХуВМуБЯхЫ╜щАгцйЯщЦвуБпф╜ХуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"хЫ╜щЪЫхОЯхнРхКЫцйЯщЦв (IAEA: International Atomic Energy Agency)уБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"Apakah latar belakang Bank Muamalat? ","answer":"Bank Muamalat Malaysia Berhad adalah bank kedua yang menawarkan Perbankan Islam di bawah \\"Akta Perbankan Islam 1983\\" di Malaysia, selepas Bank Islam.Bank Muamalat memulakan operasinya pada 1 Oktober 1999 dan merupakan gabungan aset dan liabiliti bahagian perbankan Islam daripada Bank Bumiputra Malaysia Berhad, Bank of Commerce (M) Berhad dan BBMB Kewangan. Khazanah Nasional Berhad memegang 70% daripada saham syarikat, manakala 30% lagi dipegang oleh Commerce Asset-Holdings Berhad.Pada pertengahan Ogos 2012, diketahui bahawa DRB Hicom memegang 70% saham di dalam bank manakala Khazanah Nasional Berhad memegang selebihnya dan Bank Affin dibenarkan oleh Bank Negara Malaysia untuk berbincang dengan pemilik bank ini mengenai penggabungan bank ini dengan Bank Affin."},{"question":"Wasu launika ne a jikin tutar Najeriya?","answer":"Launikan jikin tutar Najeriya sune kore da fari. Wanda aka jerasu kamar haka: \\"kore, fari, kore\\"."},{"question":"Ahlaki davran─▒┼Я ne demek?","answer":"AHL├ВK├О DAVRANI┼Ю VE B─░LG─░1Ahl├вk─▒n konusu insan davran─▒┼Яlar─▒d─▒r. Ancak insan─▒n her davran─▒┼Я─▒ de─Яil, iradeli, bilin├зli, iyi veya k├╢t├╝ olarak nitelendirilebilecek, toplum i├зinde uymas─▒ gereken kurallara uygun davran─▒┼Яlar─▒d─▒r."},{"question":"inona no teny mifanohitra amin'ny hoe fitiavana?","answer":"ny teny mifanohitra amin'ny hoe fitiavana dia fankahalana"},{"question":"Londres mooy p├йeyu man r├йew ?","answer":"Londres mooy p├йeyu r├йewum Royaume-Uni"},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐: роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБро╡рпИ роЕроХро▒рпНро▒рпБро╡родрпБ роОрокрпНрокроЯро┐?","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН :роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБро╡рпИ роЕроХро▒рпНро▒ ро╡ро┤ро┐роорпБро▒рпИроХро│рпН :роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ ро╡ро▓рпНроХро╛ро░ро┐ро╕рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ роОройрпНрокродрпБ роорпБроХроорпН, рооро╛ро░рпНрокрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роорпБродрпБроХро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ рооропро┐ро░рпНроХрпНроХро╛ро▓рпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роТро░рпБ роирпЛропро╛роХрпБроорпН, роЗродрпБ рокро░рпБро╡роороЯрпИропрпБроорпН рокрпЛродрпБ роХро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпНродроЯрпНроЯ роЕройрпИродрпНродрпБ роЗро│роорпН ро╡ропродро┐ройро░рпИропрпБроорпН рокро╛родро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН. рокро╛роХрпНроЯрпАро░ро┐ропро╛роХрпНроХро│рпН роЗродрпИ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро╛родрпБ, роЖройро╛ро▓рпН рокро╛роХрпНроЯрпАро░ро┐ропро╛роХрпНроХро│рпН роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп рокроЩрпНроХрпБ ро╡роХро┐роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ ро╡ро▓рпНроХро╛ро░ро┐ро╕рпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ ро╡ро┤роХрпНроХрооро╛рой роЯрпАройрпЗроЬрпН роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ роЖроХрпБроорпН, роЗродрпБ роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ ро╡роХрпИропро╛рой рокрпБрогрпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН ро╡роХрпИрокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ:роХро╛роорпЖроЯрпЛ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роХро░рпБроорпНрокрпБро│рпНро│ро┐ роЕро┤ро▒рпНроЪро┐ рокро░рпБрокрпНрокрпБроЕро┤ро▒рпНроЪро┐ рокро░рпБрокрпНрокрпБроХрпКрокрпНрокрпБро│роорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро░рпБроорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ родрпЛро▓ро┐ро▓рпН родрпЛройрпНро▒рпБроорпН:роХро░рпБроорпНрокрпБро│рпНро│ро┐роХро│рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ ро╡рпЖрогрпНрокрпБро│рпНро│ро┐роХро│рпНрокро░рпБроХрпНроХро│рпНроХрпКрокрпНрокрпБро│роЩрпНроХро│рпНроирпАро░рпНроХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯро┐роХро│рпНроЕро▒ро┐роХрпБро▒ро┐роХро│рпНроЙроЯро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роХро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпНродроЯрпНроЯ роОро▓рпНро▓ро╛ роЗроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБро╡рпИ роЕроЯрпИропро╛ро│роорпН роХро╛рогро▓ро╛роорпН. роЗродрпБ рокрпЖро░рпБроорпНрокро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роорпБроХроорпН, роорпБродрпБроХрпБ, роХро┤рпБродрпНродрпБ, рооро╛ро░рпНрокрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН родрпЛро│рпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роиро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роПро▒рпНроХройро╡рпЗ роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ роЗро░рпБроирпНродро╛ро▓рпН, ро╡рпЖро│рпНро│рпИ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роХро░рпБрокрпНрокрпБ рооро╛родрпНродро┐ро░рпИроХро│рпИ роирпАроЩрпНроХро│рпН роХро╡ройро┐роХрпНроХродрпН родрпКроЯроЩрпНроХрпБро╡рпАро░рпНроХро│рпН. рокро┐ро│ро╛роХрпНро╣рпЖроЯрпНро╕рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роТропро┐роЯрпНро╣рпЖроЯрпНро╕рпН роЖроХро┐ропро╡рпИ роОро░ро┐родрпНрооро╛ро╡ро╛роХ роЕроЩрпНроХрпАроХро░ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. ро╡ро│ро┐роорогрпНроЯро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ роЖроХрпНро╕ро┐роЬройрпН роХро╛ро░рогрооро╛роХ, роХро░рпБроорпНрокрпБро│рпНро│ро┐роХро│рпН родрпЛро▓ро┐ройрпН роорпЗро▒рпНрокро░рокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН родро┐ро▒роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роТропро┐роЯрпНро╣рпЖроЯрпНро╕рпН родрпЛро▓ро┐ройрпН роорпЗро▒рпНрокро░рокрпНрокро┐ройрпН роХрпАро┤рпН роорпВроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН, роЗродрпБ роТро░рпБ ро╡рпЖро│рпНро│рпИ родрпЛро▒рпНро▒родрпНродрпИ роЕро│ро┐роХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роЕро┤ро▒рпНроЪро┐ роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роХро░рпБроорпНрокрпБро│рпНро│ро┐роХро│рпН роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН рокрпКродрпБро╡ро╛рой рокрпБрогрпНроХро│рпН роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпБроорпН, роЕроирпНрод роЪро┐ро▓ ро╡роХрпИроХро│рпБроорпН роПро▒рпНрокроЯро▓ро╛роорпН. роЕро┤ро▒рпНроЪро┐ рокрпБрогрпНроХро│рпН родрпЛро▓ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡роЯрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБро╡родро▒рпНроХро╛рой ро╡ро╛ропрпНрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН роЕродро┐роХроорпН. роЗродро┐ро▓рпН роЕроЯроЩрпНроХрпБроорпН:рокро░рпБроХрпНроХро│рпНроХрпКрокрпНрокрпБро│роЩрпНроХро│рпНроорпБроЯро┐роЪрпНроЪрпБроХро│рпНроирпАро░рпНроХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯро┐роХро│рпНрооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡ро░рпН роЖро▓рпЛроЪройрпИроорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ ро╡роХрпИроХро│рпНрокро┐ро│ро╛роХрпНро╣рпЖроЯрпНро╕рпНроЕродро┐роХрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛рой роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЗро▒роирпНрод роЪрпЖро▓рпНроХро│рпИ роПро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН родрпЛро▓ро┐ро▓рпН родро┐ро▒роирпНрод рокрпБроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН. роЕро╡рпИ рокрпБроЯрпИрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН роЕро┤рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роХрпБро╡ро┐роирпНродро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокродрпИрокрпН рокрпЛро▓ родрпЛро▒рпНро▒рооро│ро┐роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой, роЖройро╛ро▓рпН роЕродрпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡роЪро┐роп рокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роХрпБро▒рпИрокро╛роЯрпБ, роЕроЯрпИрокроЯрпНроЯ роирпБрогрпНрогро▒рпИропро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ рокро┐ро░родро┐рокро▓ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЕроЪро╛родро╛ро░рог роТро│ро┐ропро╛ро▓рпН роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.ро╡рпИроЯрпНро╣рпЖроЯрпНро╕рпНроОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЗро▒роирпНрод роЪро░рпБроородрпНродро╛ро▓рпН роорпВроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН рокрпБроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН.рокро░рпБроХрпНроХро│рпНроЪро┐ро▒ро┐роп роЪро┐ро╡рокрпНрокрпБ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЗро│роЮрпНроЪро┐ро╡рокрпНрокрпБ рокрпБроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН ро╡рпАроХрпНроХроороЯрпИроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.роХрпКрокрпНрокрпБро│роЩрпНроХро│рпНроЪрпАро┤рпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН рокро░рпБроХрпНроХро│рпН. роЕро╡рпИ роЪро┐ро╡рокрпНрокрпБ ро╡ро│рпИропроЩрпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роЪрпВро┤рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ ро╡рпЖрогрпНрокрпБро│рпНро│ро┐роХро│рпН рокрпЛро▓ роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН. роЕро╡рпИ роХрпАро▒рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▓ родрпАро╡ро┐ро░ роОродро┐ро░рпНро╡ро┐ройрпИроХро│рпИ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроорпН.рокрпВроЮрпНроЪрпИ роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБрооропро┐ро░рпНроХрпНроХро╛ро▓рпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛рой роИро╕рпНроЯрпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпБроорпНрокрпЛродрпБ роЗроирпНрод ро╡роХрпИ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЗродрпБ роЕро░ро┐рокрпНрокрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡рпАроХрпНроХрооро╛роХ рооро╛ро▒рпБроорпН.роорпБроЯро┐роЪрпНроЪрпБроХро│рпНроЗродрпБ родрпЛро▓ро┐ройрпН роЖро┤родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роТро░рпБ родро┐роЯрооро╛рой рокро░рпБ. роЕро╡рпИ рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╡рпИ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН ро╡рпЗродройрпИропро╛ройро╡рпИ.роирпАро░рпНроХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯро┐роХро│рпНроЪрпАро┤рпН роиро┐ро▒рпИроирпНрод рокро░рпБроХрпНроХро│рпН роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпЛро▓ро┐ро▓рпН родро┤рпБроорпНрокрпБроХро│рпИ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроорпН.роХро╛ро░рогроЩрпНроХро│рпНроЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЪро░рпБроородрпНродро┐ройрпН родрпБро│рпИроХро│рпН роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН, роЗро▒роирпНрод роЪрпЖро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ рокро╛роХрпНроЯрпАро░ро┐ропро╛ро╡ро╛ро▓рпН родроЯрпБроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН рокрпЛродрпЖро▓рпНро▓ро╛роорпН роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпЛро▓ро┐ройрпН роТро╡рпНро╡рпКро░рпБ родрпБро│рпИропрпБроорпН роЙрогрпНроорпИропро┐ро▓рпН роТро░рпБ роирпБрогрпНрогро▒рпИ родро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБ роЖроХрпБроорпН. роирпАро░рпНроХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯро┐ роорпБроЯро┐ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роТро░рпБ роЪрпЖрокро╛роЪро┐ропро╕рпН (роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН) роЪрпБро░рокрпНрокро┐ропрпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН роЪрпБро░рокрпНрокро┐ роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роорпБроЯро┐ ро╡ро┤ро┐ропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпБро│рпИ ро╡ро┤ро┐ропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпЛро▓рпН ро╡ро┤ро┐ропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро▓рпБроорпН роЪрпЖрокроорпН (роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН) ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро┐роЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЪро░рпБроороорпН роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЪро░рпБроородрпНродрпИ роорпЖройрпНроорпИропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роирпАро░рпЗро▒рпНро▒рооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН ро╡рпИродрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХ роЙродро╡рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роЗроирпНрод роЙропро╡рпБ роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роТройрпНро▒рпБ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЕродро▒рпНроХрпБ роорпЗро▒рпНрокроЯрпНроЯ рокро┐ро░роЪрпНроЪро┐ройрпИроХро│рпН роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБро╡рпИ рокро╛родро┐роХрпНроХро▓ро╛роорпН. роЗродрпБ роОрокрпНрокрпЛродрпБ роиро┐роХро┤ро▓ро╛роорпН:роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роирпБрогрпНроХрпБрооро┐ро┤ро┐роХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛рой роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпНроХро│рпН роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНропрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройроЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпБро│рпИроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро▒роирпНрод роЪро░рпБроо роЪрпЖро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХро┐ройрпНро▒ройроЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпБро│рпИроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН рокро╛роХрпНроЯрпАро░ро┐ропро╛ро╡рпИ роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрпБроЩрпНроХро│рпНроЗроирпНрод роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп рокро┐ро░роЪрпНроЪро┐ройрпИроХро│рпН роХрпБро┤ро╛ропрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐роХрпНроХрпБ рокроЩрпНроХро│ро┐роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЕроЯрпИрокроЯрпНроЯ родрпБро│рпИропро┐ро▓рпН рокро╛роХрпНроЯрпАро░ро┐ропро╛ рокрпЖро░рпБроХрпБроорпН рокрпЛродрпБ роЕройрпНройро╛роЪро┐ родрпЛройрпНро▒рпБроорпН, роЕродрпЗ рокрпЛро▓рпН роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропрпЗро▒ роорпБроЯро┐ропро╛родрпБ.роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБро╡рпИ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроорпН рокро┐ро▒ родрпВрогрпНроЯрпБродро▓рпНроХро│рпН:роХрпНро░рпАро╕рпН роЕро┤роХрпБроЪро╛родройрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроХро│рпНро╣ро╛ро░рпНроорпЛройрпН рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒роЩрпНроХро│рпНроЙрогро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ роорой роЕро┤рпБродрпНродроорпНрооро╛родро╡ро┐роЯро╛ропрпНроЖрокродрпНродрпБ роХро╛ро░рогро┐роХро│рпНроЪро┐ро▓ роХроЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпНроХродрпИроХро│рпН роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛ро╡родро▒рпНроХрпБ рокроЩрпНроХро│ро┐роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЪро╛роХрпНро▓рпЗроЯрпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЪро╛роХрпНро▓рпЗроЯрпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роЙрогро╡рпБроХро│рпИ рокро▓ро░рпН родро╡ро▒ро╛роХрокрпН рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН French рокрпКро░ро┐ропро▓рпН роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБро╡рпБроХрпНроХрпБ рокроЩрпНроХро│ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН. роЗроирпНрод роХрпВро▒рпНро▒рпБроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▒ро┐роп роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпНроЯ роЖродро░ро╡рпБ роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роЪро┐ро▓ роЖрокродрпНродрпБ роХро╛ро░рогро┐роХро│рпН роЙро│рпНро│рой:рокро░рпБро╡роороЯрпИродро▓рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роХро░рпНрокрпНрокроорпН роХро╛ро░рогрооро╛роХ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБроорпН ро╣ро╛ро░рпНроорпЛройрпН рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒роЩрпНроХро│рпНроХро░рпБродрпНродроЯрпИ рооро╛родрпНродро┐ро░рпИроХро│рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роХро╛ро░рпНроЯро┐роХрпЛро╕рпНроЯрпАро░ро╛ропрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЕроЯроЩрпНроХро┐роп рооро░рпБроирпНродрпБроЕродро┐роХ роЕро│ро╡рпБ роХро╛ро░рпНрокрпЛро╣рпИроЯрпНро░рпЗроЯрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЪро░рпНроХрпНроХро░рпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯ ро░рпКроЯрпНроЯро┐ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЪро┐рокрпНро╕рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роЙропро░рпН роЙрогро╡рпБроЪро┐роХро┐роЪрпНроЪрпИро╡рпАроЯрпНроЯрпБ рокро░ро╛рооро░ро┐рокрпНрокрпБ роЪро┐роХро┐роЪрпНроЪрпИ:роорпБроХрокрпНрокро░рпБ роЪро┐роХро┐роЪрпНроЪрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЙродро╡рпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▓ роЪрпБроХро╛родро╛ро░ роироЯро╡роЯро┐роХрпНроХрпИроХро│рпН:роЕродро┐роХрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛рой роЕро┤рпБроХрпНроХрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпНроХро│рпИ роЕроХро▒рпНро▒, родро┐ройроорпБроорпН ро▓рпЗроЪро╛рой роЪрпЛрокрпНрокрпБроЯройрпН роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЪро░рпБроородрпНродрпИ роЪрпБродрпНродроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНропро╡рпБроорпН.роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН родро▓рпИроорпБроЯро┐ропрпИ роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роорпБроХродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропрпЗ ро╡рпИроХрпНроХ родро╡ро▒ро╛рооро▓рпН родрпБро╡рпИроХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпНродро┐ро░ро╡ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ \\"роиро╛ройрпН-роХро╛роорпЖроЯрпЛроЬрпЖройро┐роХрпН\\" роОройрпНро▒рпБ рокрпЖропро░ро┐роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роТрокрпНрокройрпИропрпИрокрпН рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро╡рпБроорпН (родрпБро│рпИ-роЕроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБ роЕро▓рпНро▓)рокро╛роХрпНроЯрпАро░ро┐ропро╛ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЕроЯрпИрокроЯрпНроЯ родрпБро│рпИроХро│рпИ рокро░рокрпНрокрпБроорпН рокро░рпБроХрпНроХро│рпИ роХроЪроХрпНроХро╡рпЛ роОроЯрпБроХрпНроХро╡рпЛ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯро╛роорпН.родрпКрокрпНрокро┐роХро│рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЗро▒рпБроХрпНроХрооро╛рой родро▓рпИропрогро┐роХро│рпИ роЕрогро┐роп ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯро╛роорпНроЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роорпБроХродрпНродрпИродрпН родрпКроЯро╛родрпЗ"},{"question":"Aiza no misy an'i Jordana mifandray amin'ny fanjakan'i Palestina?","answer":"ny misy an'i Jordana mifandray amin'ny fanjakan'i Palestina dia ny ao Atsinanana"},{"question":"щЧощвШя╝ЪщУЕчмФхИАчЪДф╜┐чФицШпхРжщЬАшжБщвЭхдЦчЪДцКАх╖зя╝Я","answer":"чнФцбИя╝ЪхЯ║цЬмчЪДщУЕчмФхИАф╜┐чФиф╕НщЬАшжБщвЭхдЦчЪДцКАх╖зя╝Мф╜ЖчЖЯч╗ГчЪДф╜┐чФишАЕхПпф╗ещАЪш┐ЗцОМцПбщАВх╜УчЪДцЧЛш╜мхТМцЦ╜хКахКЫх║жцЭешО╖х╛ЧцЫ┤хе╜чЪДхЙКщУЕчмФцХИцЮЬуАВ"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ┘Е┘Ж ╪г┘Е┘З╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Е╪д┘Е┘Ж┘К┘Ж ┘Г╪з┘Ж╪к ┘Е┘Ж ╪│┘Д╪з┘Д╪й ╪з┘Д╪г┘Ж╪и┘К╪з╪б ┘З╪з╪▒┘И┘Ж ┘И┘Е┘И╪│┘Й ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З┘Е╪з ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д╪з┘Е╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪╡┘Б┘К╪й ╪и┘Ж╪к ╪н┘К┘К ╪и┘Ж ╪г╪о╪╖╪и"},{"question":"Ki laa ti waa с╣гeyi si, awo╠гn Fulani tun pa agbe╠г meji nтАЩIgangan","answer":"O kere tan, eeyan meji lo ku, to╠гpo╠г eeyan si fara pa nigba ti awo╠гn Fulani agbegbe Oke-Ogun, nipinle╠г O╠гyo╠г, tun  ko╠г lu awo╠гn agbe╠г niluu Igangan, niro╠гle╠г o╠гjo╠г E╠гti, Furaidee.ALAROYE gbo╠г pe niс╣гe lawo╠гn Fulani to filu Igangan s╠гebugbe с╗Нhun lo╠гo╠г da awo╠гn agbe╠г to n ti inu oko wo╠гn bo╠г lo╠гna, ti wo╠гn si pa meji ninu wo╠гn loju-e╠гse╠г.Iroyin awo╠гn is╠гe╠гle╠г to ni i s╠гe pe╠гlu iroyin i╠Аs╠гeku╠Бpani, ijinigbe ati i╠Аko╠гlu╠А lo n ti agbegbe Oke-Ogun jade le╠гnu o╠гjo╠г me╠гta yii, paapaa lawo╠гn ilu bii Igboo╠гra, Igangan, Iganna, Idere, Ayete╠г ati be╠гe╠г be╠гe╠г lo╠г. Awo╠гn Fulani lawo╠гn ara agbegbe naa si maa n to╠гka si ge╠гge╠г bii afurasi o╠гdaran lo╠гpo╠гlo╠гpo╠г igba ti awo╠гn is╠гe╠гle╠г ibanuje╠г be╠гe╠г ba waye.Eyi la gbo╠г pe o mu ki akinkanju o╠гmo╠г Yoruba nni, Oloye Sunday Adeye╠гmo╠г ti gbogbo eeeyan mo╠г si Sunday Igboho, lo╠гo╠г s╠гabe╠гwo si Seriki Fulani ti Igangan, O╠гgbe╠гni Saliu Kadiri, lati ba awo╠гn eeyan e╠г so╠гro╠г pe ki wo╠гn de╠г╠Бkun ijinigbe ati pipa ti wo╠гn n pa awo╠гn Yoruba nile╠г baba wo╠гn.Ge╠гge╠г bi oludari e╠гgbe╠г to n ja fun idagbasoke ile╠г Igangan, O╠гladiran O╠гladokun, s╠гe fidi e╠г mule╠г, o ni тАЬSunday Igboho wa si Igangan lati de╠гkun awo╠гn iwa o╠гdaran ti awo╠гn Fulani maa n hu. O ko╠гko╠г lo╠г si o╠гja Kaara, nitori inu o╠гja ye╠гn lawo╠гn Fulani wo╠гnye╠гn ti saaba maa n s╠гe awo╠гn laabi wo╠гn. Nitori e╠г lawo╠гn kan s╠гe n so╠г pe ki ijo╠гba ti o╠гja ye╠гn pa.тАЬLe╠гyin naa lo lo╠г si aafin Seriki Fulani, to si so╠г fun un pe oun ko gbo╠гdo╠г gbo╠г pe awo╠гn Fulani tun pa Yoruba nibi kankan mo╠г, nitori naa, ko yaa kilo╠г fun awo╠гn eeyan e╠г daadaa.тАЭIgbese╠г ti Sunday Igboho gbe yii la gbo╠г pe awo╠гn Fulani kan ninu ilu naa ka si iwa arifin si o╠гba wo╠гn, ti wo╠гn fi lo╠гo╠г ko╠г lu awo╠гn agbe╠г to n lo╠г sile je╠гe╠гje╠г wo╠гn niro╠гle╠г o╠гjo╠г с║╕ti o╠гhun, ti wo╠гn si pa meji ninu wo╠гn da so╠гna oko.Nigba ti ako╠гroyin wa pe O╠гgbe╠гni Dapo╠г Salami ti i s╠гe oludamo╠гran fun Sunday Igboho lori e╠гro╠г ibaniso╠гro╠г, o╠гkunrin naa s╠гalaye pe тАШтАШLoooto╠г lтАЩAlaye╠Б (Igboho) lo╠г si Igangan lati lo╠гo╠г ba Seriki Fulani ibe╠г so╠гro╠г. Ko si si o╠гro╠г pupo╠г naa nibe╠г ju ikilo╠г lo╠г.тАЬWo╠гn kilo╠г fun Seriki Fulani lati ba awo╠гn eeyan e╠г so╠гro╠г, pe du╠Аn╠Аdu╠Б awo╠гn Fulani ti n la╠Бta ju nile╠г Yoruba. Bawo lawo╠гn ajeji s╠гe le maa ji wa gbe, ti wo╠гn yoo maa pa wa nile╠г baba wa. Wo╠гn ni ki Seriki kilo╠г fawo╠гn eeyan e╠г ki wo╠гn so ewe╠Б agbe╠Бje╠г╠Бe╠г╠Б mo╠г╠Бwo╠г╠Б.тАЬLe╠гyin ti wo╠гn (Igboho) kuro nтАЩIgangan tan la gbo╠г pe awo╠гn Fulani ko ibo╠гn ati ada jade, ti wo╠гn si pa o╠гmo╠г Yoruba meji. Nje╠г o ye╠г ki awo╠гn Fulani le maa gbe ibo╠гn ati ada rin bo s╠гe wu wo╠гn nigba ti ko si anfaani iru e╠г fun awa ta a ni╠Аlu╠Б nitori pe ofin orileede yii ko faaye e╠г sile╠г?тАЩтАЩ"},{"question":"ф╕ЦчХМуБошЦмхУБхМЦхнжуГбуГ╝уВлуГ╝уБзуАБуАМуГБуГРуВмуВдуВоуГ╝уАНуБпуВ╣уВдуВ╣уБоф╝Ъчд╛уБзуБЩуБМуАБуАМуГРуВдуВиуГлуАНуБпуБйуБУуБохЫ╜уБоф╝Ъчд╛уБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"уГЙуВдуГДуБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Н р░пр▒Кр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░мр░Вр░бр░┐р░Ър░Хр▒Нр░░р░В р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░╛р░гр░Вр░кр▒И р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╛р░Цр▒Нр░пр░╛р░ир░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░╕р▒Лр░ор▒Н р░Ер░ир▒З р░Хр░гр░╛р░Вр░Чр░ор▒Б р░╕р░╛р░зр░╛р░░р░гр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░Ер░ир▒З р░░р▒Жр░Вр░бр▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░ер▒Вр░кр░╛р░Хр░╛р░░ р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░╛р░гр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░кр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Зр░╡р░┐ р░░р▒Вр░кр░░р░╣р░┐р░д р░кр▒Жр░░р░┐р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р░╛р░░р▒Н р░кр░жр░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░╛р░▓р░др▒Л р░Жр░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░╕р▒Лр░ор▒Нр░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐ р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░Тр░Хр░жр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░ор░░р▒Кр░Хр░Яр░┐ р░▓р░Вр░мр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Ер░ор░░р▒Нр░Ър░мр░бр░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░др░┐р░жр░╛р░ир░┐р░▓р▒Л р░мр░Вр░бр░┐ р░Ър░Хр▒Нр░░р░Вр░▓р░╛р░Вр░Яр░┐ р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░╛р░гр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Хр░▓р░┐р░Чр░┐ р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Л р░др▒Кр░ор▒Нр░ор░┐р░жр░┐ р░╕р░ор░жр▒Вр░░р░Вр░Хр░▓ р░Яр▒Нр░пр▒Вр░мр▒Нр░пр▒Бр░▓р░┐р░ир▒Нр░Ър▒З р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░┐р░Вр░Ър░мр░бр░┐р░и р░кр░░р░┐р░зр▒Ар░п р░кр▒Лр░Ър░▓р▒Б р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░кр▒Нр░░р░др░┐ р░кр░░р░┐р░зр▒Ар░п р░кр▒Лр░Ър░▓р▒Л 3 р░╕р▒Вр░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Нр░о р░ир░╛р░│р░┐р░Хр░▓р▒Б р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░кр▒Нр░░р░Хр▒Нр░Х р░кр▒Нр░░р░Хр▒Нр░Хр░ир▒Бр░ир▒Нр░и р░кр░░р░┐р░зр▒Ар░п р░кр▒Лр░Ър░▓р▒Б р░др▒Нр░░р░┐р░Хр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Хр░▓р▒Бр░кр░мр░бр░┐ р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Н р░Хр▒Зр░Вр░жр▒Нр░░р░нр░╛р░Чр░ор▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░Яр▒Ар░ир▒Б р░кр░жр░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░В р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░┐р░др░ор▒И р░╣р░мр▒Н р░Чр░╛ р░кр░┐р░▓р░╡р░мр░бр▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░╣р░мр▒Н р░нр░╛р░Чр░ор▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░Яр▒Ар░ир░╛р░пр▒Бр░др░ор▒Ир░и р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╛р░╕р░╛р░░р▒Нр░з р░кр▒Лр░Ър░▓р░др▒Л р░кр░░р░┐р░зр▒Ар░пр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░и р░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░кр▒Нр░▓р▒Жр░Яр▒Н р░кр▒Лр░Ър░▓р░Хр▒Б р░Хр░▓р░кр░мр░бр░┐ р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░╕р▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр▒Лр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░╢р▒Ир░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓р▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░жр░╛ р░Хр░╢р░╛р░нр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б, р░Хр░Вр░бр▒Жр░кр▒Лр░Чр▒Бр░▓р░ир▒Б р░Йр░др▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒З р░Жр░зр░╛р░░р░Хр░гр░┐р░Хр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░кр░ир░┐р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░пр░┐. р░Хр░гр░╡р░┐р░нр░Ьр░и р░╕р░ор░пр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Ьр░Вр░др▒Бр░Хр░гр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Хр░Вр░бр▒Жр░кр▒Лр░Чр▒Бр░▓ р░ир▒Бр░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Хр░Вр░бр▒Ж р░кр░░р░┐р░Хр░░р░ор▒Бр░ир▒Б р░Йр░др▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░пр░┐."},{"question":"р╢╢р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╖Пр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ьр╢╜р╖К р╢Ер╢Яр╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Жр╢Ър╢╗ р╢╢р╖Др╖Фр╢╜ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢пр╖Ър╖Б р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢п?","answer":"р╢╢р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╖Пр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢пр╖Ър╖Б р╖Ар╢╜ р╢Ьр╢╜р╖К р╢Ер╢Яр╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╢╢р╖Др╖Фр╢╜р╖А р╢Зр╢н.- р╢пр╢Ър╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Гр╖К- р╢║р╖Эр╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢║р╢╗р╖К- р╢╜р╖Рр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ър╖Рр╖Вр╢║р╢╗р╖К"},{"question":"роХрпКроЯрпБроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│ роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроЪрпН роЪро░ро┐ропро╛рой рокродро┐ро▓ро│ро┐:роорпБроХро▓ро╛ропро░рпН роХро╛ро▓ роУро╡ро┐роп роХро▓рпИроХрпНроХрпБ ро╡ро┐родрпНродро┐роЯрпНроЯро╡ро░рпН ропро╛ро░рпН?роЕ) роЕроХрпНрокро░рпНроЖ) роЬроХро╛роЩрпНроХрпАро░рпНроЗ) ро╣рпВрооро╛ропрпВройрпН роИ) ро╖ро╛роЬроХро╛ройрпН","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: роЗ) ро╣рпВрооро╛ропрпВройрпН. роорпБроХро▓ро╛роп роУро╡ро┐ропроорпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ, рокродро┐ройро╛ро░ро╛роорпН роирпВро▒рпНро▒ро╛рогрпНроЯрпБ родрпКроЯроХрпНроХроорпН, рокродрпНродрпКройрпНрокродро╛роорпН роирпВро▒рпНро▒ро╛рогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро░рпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНрод роорпБроХро▓ро╛ропрокрпН рокрпЗро░ро░роЪрпБроХрпН роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХро┐ ро╡ро│ро░рпНроирпНрод роТро░рпБ роУро╡ро┐ропрокрпН рокро╛рогро┐ропро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗро░рогрпНроЯро╛ро╡родрпБ роорпБроХро▓ро╛ропрокрпН рокрпЗро░ро░роЪройро╛рой ро╣рпБрооро╛ропрпВройрпН, родрокрпНро░рпАроЪро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрокрпЛродрпБ, роЕро╡ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокро╛ро░роЪрпАроХ роУро╡ро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЕро▒ро┐роорпБроХрооро╛ройродрпБ. ро╣рпБрооро╛ропрпВройрпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ родро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокро┐ропрокрпЛродрпБ, рокро╛ро░роЪрпАроХ роУро╡ро┐ропрокрпН рокро╛рогро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН родро┐ро▒роорпИ рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ роЗро░рогрпНроЯрпБ роУро╡ро┐ропро░рпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роЕро┤рпИродрпНродрпБ ро╡роирпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЗро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роорпВро▓роорпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЕро▒ро┐роорпБроХрооро╛рой роЗрокрпН рокро╛рогро┐, рокро┐ройрпНройро░рпН роЙро│рпНро│рпВро░рпНрокрпН рокро╛рогро┐роХро│рпБроЯройрпБроорпН роХро▓роирпНродрпБ роорпБроХро▓ро╛ропрокрпН рокро╛рогро┐ роОройрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ рокрпБродро┐роп рокро╛рогро┐ропрпКройрпНро▒рпИ роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХро┐ропродрпБ."},{"question":"Rujuk petikan di bawah dan kemudian jawab soalan selepas itu dalam bahasa yang sama seperti petikan:  Petikan: Dilahirkan di Tardebigge, Worcestershire, John Vane adalah salah satu daripada tiga anak dan dibesarkan di pinggir bandar Birmingham. Bapanya, Maurice Vane, ialah anak imigran Yahudi Rusia dan ibunya, Frances Vane, berasal dari keluarga petani Worcestershire. Beliau belajar di sekolah negeri tempatan dari usia 5 tahun, sebelum berpindah ke Sekolah King Edward di Edgbaston, Birmingham. Minat beliau dalam kimia menjadi inspirasi untuk mengkaji subjek tersebut di Universiti Birmingham pada tahun 1944.  Soalan: Siapakah bapa beliau?","answer":"Maurice Vane"},{"question":"рдорд╣рд╛рднрд╛рд░рддрд╛рдЪреЗ рдпреБрджреНрдз рдХреЛрдгрддреНрдпрд╛ рдХрд╛рд▓рдЦрдВрдбрд╛рдд рдЭрд╛рд▓реЗ?рдЙрддреНрддрд░ - ","answer":"рджреНрд╡рд╛рдкрд░ рдпреБрдЧ."},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:Du├▒u ko m├йb├йt mukk ngir la seen yoxo ya j├лf [ci lu bon]. Y├аlla ku xam la way-too├▒ ├▒a.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Du ├▒u ko m├йbat mukk ng├мr la s├йen yoxo ya j├лf [ci lu bon]. Y├аlla ku x├аm la waytoo├▒ ├▒a."},{"question":"родрооро┐ро┤рпНроорпКро┤ро┐ роОро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпИ роЕро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБ ро╡ро│ро░рпБроорпН роОройрпНро▒рпБ рокро╛ро░родро┐ропро╛ро░рпН роХрпВро▒рпБроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН?","answer":"родрооро┐ро┤рпНроорпКро┤ро┐ ро╡ро╛ройроорпН ро╡ро░рпИ роЙро│рпНро│роЯроЩрпНроХро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│ роОро▓рпНро▓ро╛рокрпН рокрпКро░рпБрогрпНроорпИроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роЕро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБ роорпЗройрпНроорпЗро▓рпБроорпН ро╡ро│ро░рпБроорпН роОройрпНро▒рпБ рокро╛ро░родро┐ропро╛ро░рпН роХрпВро▒рпБроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН."},{"question":"2023 р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╢р╖Щр╢╜р╖К р╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╢╜р╖Пр╢╖р╖Ур╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢йр╖Тр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╢╢р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╖Ар╖У р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╗р╢з р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"2023 р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╢р╖Щр╢╜р╖К р╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╢╜р╖Пр╢╖р╖Ур╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢йр╖Тр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╢╢р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╖Ар╖У р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╗р╢з р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Зр╢╕р╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╖П р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢вр╢▒р╢┤р╢пр╢║р╢║р╖Т. 2023 р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢Зр╢╕р╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╖П р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢вр╢▒р╢┤р╢птАЛр╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╢р╖Щр╢╜р╖К р╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╢╜р╖Пр╢╖р╖Ур╢▒р╖К 403р╢Ър╖К р╢ЗтАЛр╢н. р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╢▒ р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╢╜р╖Пр╢╖р╖Ур╢▒р╖К 137р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢▒ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢╗р╖Пр╢вр╢░р╖Пр╢▒р╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Тр╢╕р╖Т р╢Ър╢╗ р╢Ьр╢▒р╖У."},{"question":"р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╖Рр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╖Рр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Щр╢Ьр╢╗р╖Т р╢пр╖Тр╢▒ р╢пр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒ р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖А р╢Ер╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢пр╖Ъ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Ьр╖Ер╖Ьр╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢▒ р╢╕р╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╢║р╖Т."},{"question":"1 тАУ 10, 11 тАУ 20 р░кр▒Мр░ир░Гр░кр▒Бр░ир▒Нр░п р░╡р░┐р░нр░╛р░Ьр░и р░др░░р░Чр░др▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Л 1-10 р░др░░р░Чр░др░┐ р░Ор░Чр▒Бр░╡ р░╣р░жр▒Нр░жр▒Б р░Ор░Вр░д ?","answer":"1-10 р░др░░р░Чр░др░┐ р░Ор░Чр▒Бр░╡ р░╣р░жр▒Нр░жр▒Б = 10.5"},{"question":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖Т р╢Ср╢Ър╢╕ р╢нр╖Щр╢нр╖Кр╢╢р╖Тр╢╕р╖К р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╢▒р╖Эр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖Т р╢Ср╢Ър╢╕ р╢нр╖Щр╢нр╖Кр╢╢р╖Тр╢╕р╖К р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╢▒р╖Эр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╜р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖ТтАЛр╢зр╖Т р╢вр╢╜р╢Ьр╖Рр╢╜р╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢╕р╖Кр╢▒ р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╢▒р╖Эр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╢║р╢║р╖Т."},{"question":"Inty misy fehezanteny:\\"Mody ny mpianatra.\\"Omeo ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay mandrafitra io fehezanteny io.","answer":"Indro ny anjara asan'ny teny tsirairay mandrafitra io fehezanteny io:Mody: Enti-milazany mpianatra: Lazaina"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki ini?  Apa yang hanya anjing ada tetapi binatang lain tiada?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah anak anjing. "},{"question":"╨Ь╨╛╤В╨╕╨▓╨░╤Ж╨╕╤П (╤В╥п╤А╤В╨║╥п) ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╙й╨╗╥п╤И !","answer":"╨Ц╨░╤И╨╛╨╛ - ╤В╨╡╨░╤В╤А╨┤╨░ ╨╛╨╣╨╜╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜ ╨┐╤М╨╡╤Б╨░ ╤Б╤Л╤П╨║╤В╤Г╤Г. ╨Ь╨░╨░╨╜╨╕╨╗╥п╥п╤Б╥п ╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╜╤З╨░╨╗╤Л╨║ ╤Г╨╖╨░╨║╨║╨░ ╤Б╨╛╨╖╤Г╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨│╤Л ╤Н╨╝╨╡╤Б, ╨║╨░╨╜╤З╨░╨╗╤Л╨║ ╨╝╤Л╨║╤В╤Л ╨┤╨╡╥г╨│╤Н╤Н╨╗╨┤╨╡ ╨╛╨╣╨╜╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜╨┤╤Г╨│╤Г."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'nyawa-nyawa ikan'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud hampir mati. Contoh ayat: Burung itu nyawa-nyawa ikan semasa ditemui Ali."},{"question":"Unsay bisaya sa light","answer":"Ang bisaya sa light kay suga"},{"question":"Bella Awa Gassama","answer":"Bella Awa Gassama jс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├йb├мnrin с╗Нmс╗Н or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и G├бmb├н├а.Gassama n├н ├мb├бtan pс║╣╠Аl├║ on├н├мd├бjс╗Н╠Б bс╗Н╠Бс╗Н╠Аl├╣ ├аfс║╣sс║╣╠Аgb├б t├н n с╣гe Bakary \\"Papa\\" Gassama. ├У par├н с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б girama rс║╣╠А n├н il├й-├мw├й Marina International School n├н с╗Нd├║n 2004. ├У k├│ ├аkс╗Н╠Бkс╗Н╠Б ipa rс║╣╠А n├нnu f├н├мm├╣ t├н ├аkс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б Arrou n├н с╗Нd├║n 2004 y├м├н kan n├б├а. Wс╗Н╠Бn wo f├н├мm├╣ n├б├а n├нbi ayс║╣yс║╣ Pan-African Film Festival kan t├н ├│ w├бy├й n├н ├мl├║ Los Angeles, Gassama n├б├а s├м t├║n r├н y├нy├аn f├║n ├аm├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ am├║gb├бlс║╣╠Бgbс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├й t├н ├│ d├бra j├╣lс╗Н n├нbi ayс║╣yс║╣ 2nd Africa Movie Academy Awards. Wс╗Н╠Бn t├║n y├а├бn f├║n ├▓с╣г├иr├й ilс║╣╠А G├бmb├н├а t├н ├│ d├бra j├╣lс╗Н n├нbi ayс║╣yс║╣ Vinasha Film Festival. N├н с╗Нd├║n 2008 b├бkan n├б├а, Gassama t├║n k├│ ├аkс╗Н╠Бkс╗Н╠Б ipa rс║╣╠А n├нnu f├н├мm├╣ ilс║╣╠А N├а├мj├нr├н├а t├н ├аkс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б My Gambian Holiday pс║╣╠Аl├║ ├аjс╗Нс╣гepс╗Н╠А Desmond Elliot ├аti Oge Okoye. ├У t├║n k├│ ipa am├║gb├бlс║╣╠Бgbс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б n├нnu f├н├мm├╣ Mirror Boy ti с╗Нd├║n 2011, n├н ├аjс╗Нс╣гepс╗Н╠А pс║╣╠Аl├║ Fatima Jabbe ├аti Genevieve Nnaji. N├н с╗Нd├║n 2012, Gassama par├н ├мkс║╣╠Бkс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Б l├бti il├й-с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б g├нgaTask Crown College.Gassama k├│pa n├нnu er├й Sidy Diallo kan ti с╗Нd├║n 2014 t├н ├аkс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б The Soul. Wс╗Н╠Бn y├а├бn f├║n ├аm├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ am├║gb├бlс║╣╠Бgbс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├й t├н ├│ d├бra j├╣lс╗Н n├нbi ayс║╣yс║╣ Zulu African Film Academy Awards. ├У k├│pa n├нnu er├й tс║╣lif├нс╣гс╗Н╠Аn├╣ ti с╗Нd├║n 2019 kan t├н ├аkс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б Nakala. N├н Oс╣г├╣ kс╗Нk├аnl├б с╗Мd├║n 2019, Gassama с╣гe ├мgb├йy├аw├│ pс║╣╠Аl├║ Pa Lie Low"},{"question":"р░Хр░┐р░░р░гр░Ьр░ир▒Нр░п р░╕р░Вр░пр▒Лр░Чр░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр░Хр▒Б р░Ер░╡р░╕р░░р░ор▒Ир░и р░ор▒Бр░Цр▒Нр░п р░Хр░╛р░░р░Хр░╛р░▓р▒БA) р░Хр░╛р░Вр░др░┐, р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░мр░ир▒Н р░бр▒И р░Жр░Хр▒Нр░╕р▒Ир░бр▒Н, р░кр░др▒Нр░░р░╣р░░р░┐р░др░В, р░Йр░╖р▒Нр░гр▒Лр░Чр▒Нр░░р░дB) р░Хр░╛р░Вр░др░┐, р░ир▒Ар░░р▒Б, р░кр░др▒Нр░░р░╣р░░р░┐р░др░В, р░Йр░╖р▒Нр░гр▒Лр░Чр▒Нр░░р░дC) р░Хр░╛р░Вр░др░┐, р░Йр░╖р▒Нр░гр▒Лр░Чр▒Нр░░р░д, р░кр░др▒Нр░░р░╣р░░р░┐р░др░В, р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░мр░ир▒Н р░бр▒И р░Жр░Хр▒Нр░╕р▒Ир░бр▒НD) р░Хр░╛р░Вр░др░┐, р░ир▒Ар░░р▒Б, р░кр░др▒Нр░░р░╣р░░р░┐р░др░В, р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░мр░ир▒Н р░бр▒И р░Жр░Хр▒Нр░╕р▒Ир░бр▒Н","answer":"D) р░Хр░╛р░Вр░др░┐, р░ир▒Ар░░р▒Б, р░кр░др▒Нр░░р░╣р░░р░┐р░др░В, р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░мр░ир▒Н р░бр▒И р░Жр░Хр▒Нр░╕р▒Ир░бр▒Н"},{"question":"ц║лхУешПпф║║хПгцЬЙхдЪх░Ся╝Я","answer":"ца╣цУЪ2021х╣┤хКацЛ┐хдзч╡▒шиИх▒Аф║║хПгцЩоцЯея╝Мц║лхУешПпх╕Вф║║хПгцЬЙ66.2шРмф║║я╝МшАМхдзц║лхУешПпхЬ░хНАчЪДф║║хПгчВ║264шРмуАВ"},{"question":"Thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn b├аi tс║нp: Em h├гy viс║┐t ─Сoс║бn v─Гn ph├бt biс╗Гu cс║гm ngh─й vс╗Б mс╗Щt trong c├бc b├аi th╞б c├│ yс║┐u tс╗С tс╗▒ sс╗▒, mi├кu tс║г ─С├г hс╗Нc (тАЬ─Р├кm nay B├бc kh├┤ng ngс╗зтАЭ, тАЬL╞░с╗гmтАЭ, тАЬGс║еu con ch├вn v├▓ng kiс╗БngтАЭ).","answer":"B├аi th╞б L╞░с╗гm cс╗зa Tс╗С Hс╗пu ─С├г ─Сс╗Г lс║бi с║еn t╞░с╗гng s├вu ─Сс║нm trong l├▓ng ng╞░с╗Эi ─Сс╗Нc h├мnh с║гnh mс╗Щt em b├й thiс║┐u nhi hi sinh v├м nhiс╗Зm vс╗е trong cuс╗Щc kh├бng chiс║┐n chс╗Сng thс╗▒c d├вn Ph├бp. Nс╗Щi dung ch├нnh cс╗зa b├аi th╞б tс╗▒ sс╗▒ тАУ trс╗п t├мnh kс╗Г vс╗Б cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Эi ngс║пn ngс╗зi nh╞░ng rс║еt anh d┼йng cс╗зa ch├║ b├й li├кn lс║бc, hс╗Уn nhi├кn, nh├н nhс║гnh, y├кu ─Сс╗Эi, d┼йng cс║гm ─С├г ng├г xuс╗Сng ─Сс╗Г bс║гo vс╗З sс╗▒ b├мnh y├кn cho ch├нnh mс║гnh ─Сс║еt qu├к h╞░╞бng m├мnh. Vс╗Б nghс╗З thuс║нt, Tс╗С Hс╗пu chс╗з yс║┐u sс╗н dс╗еng sс╗н dс╗еng tс╗л l├бy, lс╗Сi th╞б tс╗▒ sс╗▒, ─Сiс╗Зp tс╗л, so s├бnh,тАж g├│p phс║зn thс╗Г hiс╗Зn h├мnh с║гnh L╞░с╗гm тАУ mс╗Щt em b├й li├кn lс║бc hс╗Уn nhi├кn, vui t╞░╞бi say m├к tham gia c├┤ng t├бc kh├бng chiс║┐n thс║нt ─С├бng mс║┐n, ─С├бng y├кu. L╞░с╗гm xuс║еt hiс╗Зn vс╗Ыi d├бng ng╞░с╗Эi nhс╗П nhс║пn, mang theo chiс║┐c xс║пc xinh xinh vui s╞░с╗Ыng ─Сi l├аm nhiс╗Зm vс╗е. Ngoс║бi h├мnh vс╗Ыi ─С├┤i m├б с╗нng ─Сс╗П bс╗У quс║йn, d├бng ─Сi tho─Гn thoс║пt, c├бi ─Сс║зu ngh├кnh ngh├кnh, miс╗Зng hu├╜t s├бo vang,тАж ─Сс╗Бu t├┤ ─Сс║бm n├йt hс╗Уn nhi├кn с╗Я ch├║ b├й. Thс║┐ nh╞░ng giс╗пa c├бnh ─Сс╗Уng l├║a ch├нn, em nс║▒m ─С├│, m├бu chс║гy ─Сс╗П nh╞░ ho├аng h├┤n. L╞░с╗гm ─С├г hi sinh tr├кn ─С╞░с╗Эng l├аm nhiс╗Зm vс╗е nh╞░ng h├мnh с║гnh cс╗зa em c├▓n m├гi vс╗Ыi qu├к h╞░╞бng, ─Сс║еt n╞░с╗Ыc v├а trong l├▓ng mс╗Нi ng╞░с╗Эi. Bс║▒ng lс╗Эi th╞б bс╗Сn chс╗п giс║гn dс╗Л, t├бc giс║г ─С├г thс╗Г hiс╗Зn th├аnh c├┤ng lс╗Ыp ng╞░с╗Эi thiс║┐u ni├кn nhс╗П tuс╗Хi y├кu n╞░с╗Ыc trong thс╗Эi k├м kh├бng chiс║┐n."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е╪з ┘З┘К ╪з┘Д╪│┘И╪▒╪й ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ┘К╪м╪и ┘В╪▒╪з╪б╪к┘З╪з ┘Б┘К ┘Г┘Д ╪▒┘Г╪╣╪й ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪╡┘Д╪з╪й╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪з┘Д┘Б╪з╪к╪н╪й"},{"question":"Inona no niseho teto Madagasikara ny 07 febroary 2009?","answer":"Ny 07 febroary 2009 dia nanao diabe nankany aminтАЩny Lapa-mpanjakana Ambohitsorohitra ny mpomba ny TGV. Nitifitra niaro ny Lapa ny mpiambina ka nahafaty olon-tsotra maro. Nierendoza kosa ny mpitarika ny fihetsiketsehanaтАж Nitsangana ny Fahefana AvonтАЩny Tetezamita (FAT) na тАЬHaute Autorit├й de la TransitionтАЭ notarihanтАЩi Andry Rajoelina. "},{"question":"Qual ├й o pa├нs mais populoso do mundo?","answer":"China. Em 2020, tinha 1.439.323.776 de habitantes, de acordo com a Organiza├з├гo das Na├з├╡es Unidas (ONU)."},{"question":"Gbogbo с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, lawс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ yoo fi maa wс╗Нс╣гo adirс║╣ nipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun bayii","answer":"Gomina ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun, Alhaji Adegboyega Oyetс╗Нla, ti kede pe с╣гiс╣гс║╣ aс╣гс╗Н adirс║╣ lс╗Нpс╗Н yanturu ati tita rс║╣ yoo bс║╣rс║╣ nipinlс║╣ naa bayii.Bakan naa ni gomina pс╗Нn с╗Нn ni dandan fun gbogbo awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba lati maa wс╗Н aс╣гс╗Н adirс║╣ lс║╣с║╣kan laarin с╗Нsс║╣, iyс║╣n Ojс╗Нbс╗Н, eyi to pe orukс╗Н rс║╣ ni тАЬс╗Мjс╗Н Adirс║╣ с╗Мс╣гunтАЭLasiko to n с╣гe ifilс╗Нlс║╣ с╣гiс╣гe adirс║╣ naa nibi  ayс║╣yс║╣ тАШс╗Мsс║╣ OgeтАЩ to wa lati с╣гagbelarugс║╣ lilo aс╣гс╗Н adirс║╣ eleyii ti ileeс╣гс║╣ aс╣гa atibudo isс║╣mbaye lтАЩс╗Мс╣гun pс║╣lu ajс╗Нс╣гepс╗Н Musty Great Development and Alexandria Jones Cultures, ni USA, с╣гe ni Oyetс╗Нla ti ni ilu aro ti wс╗Нn mс╗Н Oс╣гogbo ti i с╣гe olu ilu ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun mс╗Н gbс╗Нdс╗Н di gbajugbaja.O ni igbesс║╣ naa wa lati ran awс╗Нn eeyan leti с╗Нkan lara awс╗Нn nnkan to jс║╣ ami idanimс╗Н ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun, paapaa, lati с╣гi oju Adirс║╣ с║╕lс║╣kс╗Н si gbogbo agbaye.Oyetс╗Нla, с║╣ni ti akс╗Нwe ijс╗Нba rс║╣, с╗Мmс╗Нс╗Нba Wс╗Нle Oyebamiji, с╣гoju fun с╣гalaye pe igbelarugс║╣ awс╗Нn aс╣гa ti Eledua fi jinnku ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun jс║╣ oun logun, nitori yoo tun mu ki eto с╗Нrс╗Н-aje burс║╣kс║╣ si i.O ni yoo tun jс║╣ orisun ipese iс╣гс║╣ fun ogunlс╗Нgс╗Н awс╗Нn olugbe ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun, bс║╣с║╣ ni awс╗Нn oniс╣гowo atawс╗Нn to fс║╣ran aс╣гa kaakiri orileede yii ati loke-okun yoo lo anfaani naa lati с╣гabс║╣wo sibi.Gс║╣gс║╣ bo с╣гe wi, тАЬA ti bс║╣rс║╣ atunс╣гe oniruuru awс╗Нn ibudo aс╣гa atawс╗Нn nnkan isс║╣mbaye ti a ni kaakiri с╗Мс╣гun, bс║╣с║╣ nijс╗Нba apapс╗Н atawс╗Нn abaniс╣гiс╣гс║╣ ti n dowo pс╗Н pс║╣lu wa lati sс╗Н awс╗Нn ibudo yс║╣n di apewaawo lagbaaye.тАЬLati sс╗Н ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun di aс╣гaaju ninu aс╣гa Yoruba, gbogbo с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, lс╗Нsс╗Нс╗Нsс║╣ ti di с╗Нjс╗Н ti awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba yoo maa wс╗Н aс╣гс╗Н adirс║╣ bayii, nitori a gbс╗Нdс╗Н fi apс║╣с║╣rс║╣ rere lelс║╣.тАЬс╗Мjс╗Н kс║╣tadinlс╗Нgbс╗Нn, oс╣гu kс║╣jс╗Н, с╗Нdun yii, ni aс╣гс║╣ yii yoo bс║╣rс║╣ si i fс║╣sс║╣ mulс║╣. Mo rс╗Н gbogbo awс╗Нn eeyan ipinlс║╣ yii lati lo anfaani yii fun idagbasoke iс╣гс║╣ ti wс╗Нn n с╣гeтАЭGbogbo awс╗Нn lookс╗Н-lookс╗Н nidii igbelarugс║╣ с╗Нrс╗Н aс╣гa nilс║╣ yii bii oludasilс║╣ iwe iroyin Alaroye, Alagba Alao Adedayс╗Н, Iyaafin Nikс║╣ Okundaye, Oloye Jimoh Buraimon ati Oloye Muraina Oyelami ni wс╗Нn rс╗Н awс╗Нn eeyan ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun lati с╣гagbelarugс║╣ igbesс║╣ ijс╗Нba naa."},{"question":"цККф╗еф╕ЛчЪДхПдцЦЗцИРчО░ф╗гц▒ЙхнЧя╝ЪхМбшббхЛдхнжшАМчГЫя╝МщВ╗х▒ЕцЬЙчГЫшАМф╕НщАоя╝Мшббф╣Гчй┐хгБх╝ХхЕ╢хЕЙя╝МхПСф╣жцШахЕЙшАМшп╗ф╣ЛуАВщВСф║║хдзхзУцЦЗф╕НшпЖя╝Мхо╢хпМхдЪф╣жя╝Мшббф╣Гф╕ОхЕ╢ф╜гф╜ЬшАМф╕Нц▒ВхБ┐уАВф╕╗ф║║цАкщЧошббя╝МшббцЫ░я╝ЪтАЬцД┐х╛Чф╕╗ф║║ф╣жщБНшп╗ф╣ЛуАВтАЭф╕╗ф║║цДЯхП╣я╝Мш╡Дч╗Щф╗еф╣жя╝МщБВцИРхдзхнжуАВ","answer":"хМбшббх╛ИхЛдхнжя╝Мф╜Жц▓бцЬЙшЬбчГЫя╝МщВ╗х▒ЕцЬЙшЬбчГЫхН┤чЕзф╕НхИ░я╝Иф╗ЦчЪДцИ┐щЧ┤я╝ЙуАВхМбшббф║ОцШпх░▒хЬихвЩф╕КцЙУф║Жф╕Аф╕кц┤ЮчФицЭех╝Хш┐ЫчГЫхЕЙя╝МчФиф╣жцШачЭАхЕЙцЭешп╗ф╣жуАВх╜УхЬ░цЬЙф╕АхдзцИ╖ф║║хо╢хПлцЦЗф╕НшпЖя╝Мхо╢щЗМхНБхИЖхпМцЬЙя╝Мф╣жхПИх╛ИхдЪя╝МхМбшббх░▒ч╗Щф╗Цхо╢ф╜ЬщЫЗх╖ея╝Мш╛ЫшЛжхК│хКишАМф╕НшжБц▒ВцКещЕмя╝Мф╕╗ф║║цДЯхИ░хеЗцАкя╝Мх░▒щЧохМбшббя╝МхМбшббхЫЮчнФшп┤я╝ЪтАЬх╕МцЬЫхПпф╗ешп╗щБНф╕╗ф║║чЪДф╣жуАВтАЭф╕╗ф║║цДЯхП╣я╝Мх░▒цККф╣жхАЯч╗Щф╗Ця╝Мя╝ИхМбшббя╝Йч╗Иф║ОцИРф║ЖхдзхнжщЧохо╢уАВ"},{"question":"р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╢з р╢┤р╢╗р╖Кр╢ар╖Гр╖К р╢Ър╖Ур╢║р╢п?","answer":"р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╢з р╢┤р╢╗р╖Кр╢ар╖Гр╖К 160 р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢н "},{"question":"┘Г┘К┘Б ┘К┘Е┘Г┘Ж┘Ж┘К ╪н┘Е╪з┘К╪й ┘Ж┘Б╪│┘К ╪е╪░╪з ┘Г┘Ж╪к ┘Б┘К ┘Е┘Ж╪╖┘В╪й ┘Е╪к╪г╪л╪▒╪й╪Я","answer":"╪к╪к┘Е╪л┘Д ┘Е╪и╪з╪п╪ж ╪з┘Д╪н┘Е╪з┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪л┘Д╪з╪л╪й ┘Б┘К \\"╪з┘Д╪з╪н╪к┘Е╪з╪б ┘И╪з┘Д╪и┘В╪з╪б ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪п╪з╪о┘Д ┘И╪з┘Д╪з╪│╪к┘Е╪з╪╣\\" ┘Д╪к┘Д┘В┘К ╪з┘Д╪к╪╣┘Д┘К┘Е╪з╪к.┘И╪╣┘Д┘К┘Г ╪и╪з┘Д╪н╪▒╪╡ ╪п┘И┘Е╪з┘Л ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з╪к╪и╪з╪╣ ╪е╪▒╪┤╪з╪п╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д╪з┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д╪╡╪з╪п╪▒╪й ╪╣┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д╪╖╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Е╪н┘Д┘К╪й ┘И╪з┘Д┘И╪╖┘Ж┘К╪й ┘И╪з┘Д╪и┘В╪з╪б ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з╪к╪╡╪з┘Д ┘Д╪к┘Д┘В┘К ╪в╪о╪▒ ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╣┘Д┘И┘Е╪з╪к. ╪е╪░╪з ╪╖┘П┘Д╪и ┘Е┘Ж┘Г ╪з┘Д╪и┘В╪з╪б ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪п╪з╪о┘Д ┘Б╪з┘Б╪╣┘Д ╪░┘Д┘Г╪М ┘Д╪г┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪м╪п╪▒╪з┘Ж ┘И╪з┘Д╪│┘В┘Б ┘К┘Е┘Г┘Ж ╪г┘Ж ╪к┘И┘Б╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪н┘Е╪з┘К╪й ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪к╪│╪▒╪и ╪з┘Д╪е╪┤╪╣╪з╪╣┘К ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪о╪з╪▒╪м. ┘И╪╣┘Ж╪п ╪з┘Д╪е┘Е┘Г╪з┘Ж╪М ╪з┘Е┘Г╪л ┘Б┘К ╪║╪▒┘Б╪й ╪и┘Д╪з ┘Ж┘И╪з┘Б╪░ ╪г┘И ╪г╪и┘И╪з╪и ╪о╪з╪▒╪м┘К╪й ┘И╪г╪║┘Д┘В ╪з┘Д┘Ж┘И╪з┘Б╪░ ┘И╪г┘Ж╪╕┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д╪к┘З┘И┘К╪й ╪п╪з╪о┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Е┘Ж╪▓┘Д (╪г╪м┘З╪▓╪й ╪з┘Д╪к┘Г┘К┘К┘Б ╪г┘И ╪з┘Д╪к╪п┘Б╪ж╪й)."},{"question":"Lс║нp dan ├╜ ─Сс╗Г kс╗Г lс║бi truyс╗Бn thuyс║┐t тАЬTh├бnh Gi├│ngтАЭ.","answer":"+ Truyс╗Бn thuyс║┐t Th├бnh Gi├│ng kс╗Г lс║бi cuс╗Щc chiс║┐n ─Сс║еu mс╗Щt m├мnh cс╗зa Gi├│ng chiс║┐n thс║пng qu├вn th├╣.+ Truyс╗Зn c├│ nhс╗пng sс╗▒ kiс╗Зn v├а nh├вn vс║нt ch├нnh: C├вu chuyс╗Зn kс╗Г vс╗Б nh├вn vс║нt ch├нnh Th├бnh Gi├│ng:┬Я Sс╗▒ ra ─Сс╗Эi k├м lс║б cс╗зa Th├бnh Gi├│ng.┬Я Th├бnh Gi├│ng biс║┐t n├│i v├а ─С├▓i ─Сi ─С├бnh giс║╖c.┬Я Gi├│ng lс╗Ыn nhanh nh╞░ thс╗Хi, v╞░╞бn vai mс║╖c ├бo gi├бo sс║пt, c╞░с╗бi ngс╗▒a sс║пt, cс║зm roi sс║пt.┬Я Th├бnh Gi├│ng dс║╣p tan qu├вn giс║╖c.┬Я Sau ─С├│, ng╞░с╗Эi c├╣ng vс╗Ыi ngс╗▒a bay l├кn trс╗Эi.+ Diс╗Еn biс║┐n cс╗зa c├вu chuyс╗Зn (mс╗Я ─Сс║зu, ph├бt triс╗Гn, kс║┐t th├║c):┬Я Mс╗Я ─Сс║зu: Sс╗▒ ra ─Сс╗Эi k├м lс║б cс╗зa Th├бnh Gi├│ng.┬Я Ph├бt triс╗Гn: Th├бnh Gi├│ng biс║┐t n├│i v├а ─С├▓i ─Сi ─С├бnh giс║╖c. тЖТ Gi├│ng lс╗Ыn nhanh nh╞░ thс╗Хi, v╞░╞бn vai mс║╖c ├бo gi├бo sс║пt, c╞░с╗бi ngс╗▒a sс║пt, cс║зm roi sс║пt. тЖТ Th├бnh Gi├│ng dс║╣p tan qu├вn giс║╖c.┬Я Kс║┐t th├║c: Th├бnh Gi├│ng c├╣ng vс╗Ыi ngс╗▒a sс║пt bay l├кn trс╗Эi.+ C├│ thс╗Г th├кm, bс╗Ыt nhс╗пng chi tiс║┐t, h├мnh с║гnh,тАж cс╗зa truyс╗Зn nh╞░:┬Я Cс║гnh d├вn l├аng n├┤ nс╗йc c├╣ng nhau gom g├│p gс║бo;┬Я Cс║гnh Th├бnh Gi├│ng ─Гn nhiс╗Бu nh╞░ thс║┐ n├аo?┬Я Mi├кu tс║г k─й h╞бn h├мnh с║гnh Th├бnh Gi├│ng khi mс║╖c ├бo gi├бp;┬Я Th├кm cс║гnh Th├бnh Gi├│ng tс║бm biс╗Зt gia ─С├мnh v├а l├аng;..."},{"question":"Vraag: Hoe heet het lied van de band Bots dat begint met de regel \\"Wat zullen we drinken\\"","answer":"Antwoord: Zeven dagen lang"},{"question":"\\"р╢Зр╢▒р╢╢р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ \\" р╢Ер╢╗р╖Фр╢н р╢┤р╖Рр╖Др╖Рр╢пр╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╢Лр╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╖Фр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Ур╢╕,р╢Зр╢▒р╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Др╖Тр╢│р╖Ур╢╕.р╢пр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢Ъ р╢Лр╢йр╢з р╢╕р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢л р╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖Тр╖Др╢з р╢Йр╢пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ар╢зр╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Ар╖П  р╢Зр╢▒р╢╢р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ар╖П р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢╜р╖П"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: роХрогрпНрогро╛роЯро┐ропрпИ роХро░рпИроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЕрооро┐ро▓роорпН?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: ро╣рпИроЯрпНро░рпЛроХрпБро│рпЛро░ро┐роХрпН роЕрооро┐ро▓роорпН"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Пр╖А р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ер╖Ъ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п ? \\"р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╖Др╖Тр╖Гр╢╗р╢пр╖Щр╢║р╢нр╖К р╖Др╖Ьр╢пр╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Ур╖Ар╖П р╖Гр╖Ъ\\"","answer":"р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒ р╢Хр╢▒р╖Ср╢╕ р╢пр╖Щр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Йр╢нр╖П р╢Йр╖Др╖Ер╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕"},{"question":"Zadzisa dimikara rinotevera:Anokotsira nebadza mumawoko","answer":"aneusimbe"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Рр╢╗р╢лр╖Т р╢Ър╖Шр╖Вр╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢вр╢▒р╖Ар╖Др╢╗р╖Ър╢пр╖У \\" р╖Др╖Фр╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╖Пр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Щр╢зр╖Кр╢зр╖Тр╢║ \\" р╢║р╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п ?","answer":"р╢┤р╖Рр╢╗р╢лр╖Т р╢Ър╖Шр╖Вр╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢вр╢▒р╖Ар╖Др╢╗р╖Ър╢пр╖У \\" р╖Др╖Фр╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╖Пр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Щр╢зр╖Кр╢зр╖Тр╢║ \\" р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╢╕р╢нр╢з р╢Жр╖Др╖Пр╢╗ р╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒р╢║р╢▒ р╢┤р╖Щр╢зр╖Кр╢зр╖Тр╢║"},{"question":"Deprem bolgesinde barajlar ne durumda?","answer":"Tar─▒m ve Orman Bakanl─▒─Я─▒ yapt─▒─Я─▒ t├╝m a├з─▒klamalarda barajlar─▒n kontrol edildi─Яini ve herhangi bir sorunun olmad─▒─Я─▒n─▒ a├з─▒klad─▒. Depremin ya┼Яand─▒─Я─▒ b├╢lgelerdeki barajlar─▒n g├╝venli oldu─Яunu belirten ─░n┼Яaat ve ├Зevre Y├╝ksek M├╝hendis Su Uzman─▒ Hasan Akyar'a g├╢re 30 metrenin alt─▒ndaki g├╢letlere dikkat etmek gerekiyor."},{"question":"Ny rano dia mangotraka amin'ny 100 ┬░ C eo ambanin'ny tsindrin'ny atmosfera mahazatra. Marina sa diso?","answer":"Marina. Eo ambanin'ny tsindrin'ny atmosfera mahazatra, ny rano dia mangotraka amin'ny 100 ┬░ C."},{"question":"Meyasa aka sami Daidatacciyar Hausa?","answer":"kai tsaye muna iya cewa, daidaitaciyyar Hausa, wacce wasu marubutan ke kira kar╔Уa╔У╔Уiyar Hausa, ita ce Hausar da masana Harshen Hausa tun dauri suka ha╔Чu a kan cewa, da ita za a yi amfani wajen yin rubutun Hausa domin samun daidaito.Wannan kuma saboda akwai kare-karen Hausa da dama, da suka ha╔Чa da Kananci, Katsinanci, Zazzaganci, Dauranci, Sakkwatanci, Aranci, da sauransu. Idan aka ce kowa zai yi rubutu da nasa karin kamar yadda ya ke magana da shi, to abin zai zama babu tsari babu kan-gado, wanda kuma hakan za ta hana samun ╞ЩaтАЩida."},{"question":"ри░ри╕рйЛриИ рижрйА римригридри░ ридрйЛриВ ридрйБри╕рйАриВ риХрйА ри╕риориЭрижрйЗ ри╣рйЛ ? риири╡рйАриВ риЕридрйЗ рикрйБри░ри╛ригрйА риХри┐ри╕рио рижрйА ри░ри╕рйЛриИ ри╡ри┐риЪ риХрйА риЕрй░ридри░ ри╣рйБрй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ ?","answer":"ри░ри╕рйЛриИ рижрйЗ рижри░ри╡ри╛риЬри╝рйЗ риЕридрйЗ риЦри┐рйЬриХрйАриЖриВ тАШридрйЗ риЬри╛ри▓рйА ри▓рй▒риЧрйА ри╣рйЛригрйА риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижрйА ри╣рйИ ридрйЗ риЗри╣риири╛риВ рижри░ри╡ри╛риЬри╝ри┐риЖриВ риирйВрй░ ри╣риорйЗри╕ри╝ри╛ римрй░риж ри░рй▒риЦригри╛ риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред риЗри╕ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риорй▒риЦрйА риорй▒риЫри░ ри░ри╕рйЛриИ ри╡ри┐риЪ риири╣рйАриВ ри╡рйЬ ри╕риХрйЗриЧри╛ | ри░ри╕рйЛриИ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░рйЛри╕ри╝риирижри╛риири╛риВ рижри╛ ри╣рйЛригри╛ ри▓ри╛риЬри╝риорйА ри╣рйИ ред | ри░ри╕рйЛриИ рижри╛ ризрйВрй░риЖриВ риХрй▒ривриг ри▓риИ риЪри┐риориирйА риЬри╛риВ риРриЧриЬри╝ри╛ри╕риЯ рикрй▒риЦри╛ ри▓рй▒риЧри╛ ри▓рйИригри╛ риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред риЖрио рикри░ри┐ри╡ри╛ри░ ри▓риИ ри░ри╕рйЛриИ рижри╛ риЖриХри╛ри░ 9тА▓ ├Ч 10тАЩ рилрйБрй▒риЯ рижри╛ ри╣рйБрй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред рикри░ риЗри╣ риШри░ рижрйЗ риЖриХри╛ри░ рижрйЗ риЕриирйБри╕ри╛ри░ ри╡рйА ри╣рйЛ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редриири╡рйАриВ риЕридрйЗ рикрйБри░ри╛ригрйА риХри┐ри╕рио рижрйА ри░ри╕рйЛриИ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЕрй░ридри░-рикрйБри░ри╛ригрйЗ риХри┐ри╕рио рижрйА ри░ри╕рйЛриИ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬри╝риорйАрии ридрйЗ римрйИриа риХрйЗ ри╣рйА ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ риХрй░рио риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ | рикри░ риири╡рйЗриВ риХри┐ри╕рио рижрйАриЖриВ ри░ри╕рйЛриИриЖриВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЦрйЬрйЗ ри╣рйЛ риХрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ риХрй░рио риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред риЗри╕ ри▓риИ ри╕ри╝рйИри▓рилри╝ри╛риВ рикри╛риИриЖриВ риЬри╛риВрижрйАриЖриВ ри╣рии ред риЗри╣риири╛риВ ри╕ри╝рйИри▓рилри╝ри╛риВ рижрйА риЙриЪри╛риИ риЖрио риХри░риХрйЗ рилри╝ри░ри╕ри╝ ридрйЛриВ 21/2 рилрйБрй▒риЯ ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА ри╣рйИ рикри░ ридрйНри░ри┐ригрйА рижрйА ри▓рй░римри╛риИ риорйБридри╛римри┐риХ риЗри╣ риЙриЪри╛риИ ри╡рй▒риз-риШрй▒риЯ ри╡рйА риХрйАридрйА риЬри╛ ри╕риХрижрйА ри╣рйИ ред"},{"question":"р╢Ър╢╜р╖П р╢Фр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢Ър╢╜р╖П р╢Фр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖Т р╢нр╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢пр╖Тр╢Ьр╢╕ р╢Фр╢║ р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢пр╖Тр╢Ь р╢Жр╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╜р╖Э р╢╕р╖Ур╢зр╢╗ 145 р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╢╕р╢л р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Ър╢╜р╖П р╢Фр╢║ р╢Ер╖Гр╢╜ р╢┤р╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╢╜р╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖П р╢┤р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ъ р╢Ьр╢н р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ."},{"question":"Cuba jawab teka-teki berikut:  Alat yang boleh membeku setiap benda yang dijumpa.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah kamera. Kamera ialah alat optik yang digunakan untuk menangkap dan menyimpan imej atau video, sama ada secara digital melalui penderia imej elektronik, atau secara kimia melalui bahan sensitif cahaya seperti filem fotografi."},{"question":"р┤ир┤┐р┤Щр╡Нр┤Щр┤│р╡Бр┤Яр╡Ж р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤╛р┤пр┤др╡Нр┤др╡Зр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр┤╛р╡╛ р┤Ър╡Жр┤▒р╡Бр┤кр╡Нр┤кр┤ор┤╛р┤пр┤┐ р┤Хр┤╛р┤гр┤╛р┤ир╡Бр┤│р╡Нр┤│ р┤ор┤┐р┤Хр┤Ър╡Нр┤Ъ р┤╡р┤┤р┤┐р┤Хр┤│р╡Бр┤Яр╡Ж р┤Тр┤░р╡Б р┤▓р┤┐р┤╕р╡Нр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р╡Н р┤Ор┤ир┤┐р┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Н р┤др┤░р╡В.","answer":"р┤лр┤┐р┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р╡Нр┤ир┤╕р╡Н р┤ир┤┐р┤▓р┤ир┤┐р╡╝р┤др╡Нр┤др┤╛р╡╗, р┤др╡Жр┤│р┤┐р┤Юр╡Нр┤Ю р┤Ър╡╝р┤ор╡Нр┤ор┤В р┤ир┤┐р┤▓р┤ир┤┐р╡╝р┤др╡Нр┤др╡Бр┤Х, р┤кр╡Лр┤╕р┤┐р┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р╡Ар┤╡р┤╛р┤пр┤┐р┤░р┤┐р┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Бр┤Х, р┤Ор┤▓р╡Нр┤▓р┤╛ р┤Хр┤╛р┤░р╡Нр┤пр┤Щр╡Нр┤Щр┤│р┤┐р┤▓р╡Бр┤В р┤Ор┤кр╡Нр┤кр╡Лр┤┤р╡Бр┤В р┤Хр┤╛р┤▓р┤┐р┤Хр┤ор┤╛р┤пр┤┐р┤░р┤┐р┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Бр┤Х, р┤╢р┤╛р┤ир╡Нр┤др┤д р┤кр┤╛р┤▓р┤┐р┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Бр┤Х. "},{"question":"Formule una respuesta a esta pregunta elaborada: ┬┐A qu├й categor├нa taxon├│mica pertenecen tanto Hyacinthoides como Anthriscus?","answer":"A la categor├нa g├йnero."},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ┬┐Qui├йn es mayor, Britney Spears o Christina Aguilera?","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es comparar edades de dos mujeres famosas y determinar qui├йn de las dos es mayor. "},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegta magacii caalimkii muslinka ahaa ee loo yaqiinay aabihii Cilmiga Kimistiriga (Chemistry) ?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Jaabir Bin Xayaan."},{"question":"╨Ъ╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨║╤Л╨╖╤Л╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╨╛╨║╤Г╤П╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨╡╤Б╨╕╨╖?","answer":"2016-╨╢╤Л╨╗╤Л ╤Б╨░╤П╨║╨░╤В╤З╤Л ╨б╨╛╤О╨╖╨▒╨╡╨║ ╨б╨░╨╗╨╕╨╡╨▓╨┤╨╕╨╜ ЁЯЗ░ЁЯЗм ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨╡╨╗╨╡╨│╨╕ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨╢╨╡╤А ╤И╨░╤А╤Л╨╜ ╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л╨┐ ╙й╤В╨║╙й╨╜. ╨б╨░╨╗╨╕╨╡╨▓ ╨╢╨╡╨╗╨╡╨║ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╨░╨┐╨░╤А╤Л╨╜ 25-╨░╨▓╨│╤Г╤Б╤В╤В╨░ ╨▒╨░╤И╤В╨░╨┐, ╨║╨░╨╣╤А╨░ 27-╨╛╨║╤В╤П╨▒╤А╨┤╨░ ╨╝╨╡╨║╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜╨╡ ╨║╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨│╨╡╨╜."},{"question":"Vijf matrozen overleven een schipbreuk en zwemmen naar een klein eiland waar ze alleen een kokosnotenboom en een aap aantreffen. De matrozen verzamelen alle kokosnoten en leggen ze in een stapel onder de boom. Uitgeput besluiten ze om pas de volgende ochtend de kokosnoten te verdelen.Om een uur 's nachts wordt de eerste matroos wakker. Hij realiseert zich dat hij de anderen niet kan vertrouwen en besluit zijn deel alvast te nemen. Hij verdeelt de kokosnoten in vijf gelijke stapels, maar houdt daarbij een kokosnoot over. Hij geeft die kokosnoot aan de aap, verbergt zijn eigen kokosnoten (├й├йn van de vijf stapels), en plaatst de rest van de kokosnoten (de andere vier stapels) terug onder de boom.Om twee uur 's nachts wordt de tweede matroos wakker. Zich niet bewust van het feit dat de eerste matroos zijn deel al heeft weggenomen, verdeelt ook hij de kokosnoten in vijf gelijke stapels en houdt daarbij ook een kokosnoot over, die hij aan de aap geeft. Dan verbergt hij zijn kokosnoten (├й├йn van de vijf stapels), en plaatst de rest van de kokosnoten (de andere vier stapels) terug onder de boom.Om drie, vier en vijf uur 's nachts worden achtereenvolgens de derde, vierde en vijfde matroos wakker en voeren dezelfde handelingen uit als de eerste twee matrozen.'s Morgens, als ze opstaan, proberen ze allemaal zo onschuldig mogelijk te kijken. Geen van de matrozen maakt een opmerking over de gekrompen stapel kokosnoten, en geen van hen besluit om eerlijk te zijn en toe te geven dat hij zijn deel al genomen heeft. Ze verdelen de kokosnoten voor de zesde maal in vijf gelijke stapels en houden daarbij alweer een kokosnoot over, die ze aan de aap geven.De vraag: Wat is de kleinste hoeveelheid kokosnoten waaruit de oorspronkelijke stapel kan hebben bestaan?","answer":"Elke matroos laat 4/5(n-1) kokosnoten over van de stapel van n kokosnoten. Dit resulteert in een vreselijke formule voor het hele proces (want iedere keer moet een kokosnoot weggehaald worden om de stapel deelbaar door 5 te maken):r = 1/5(4/5(4/5(4/5(4/5(4/5(p-1)-1)-1)-1)-1)-1), waarbij p het aantal kokosnoten in de originele stapel is, en r het aantal kokosnoten is dat iedere matroos bij de laatste verdeling krijgt (wat een geheel getal moet zijn).De truc is om het aantal kokosnoten in de stapel deelbaar door 5 te maken, door 4 kokosnoten toe te voegen. Dit is mogelijk omdat je deze 4 kokosnoten weer weg kan halen, nadat een vijfde deel van de stapel is weggenomen: normaal zijn 4/5(n-1) kokosnoten over van een stapel van n kokosnoten; nu zijn 4/5(n+4) = 4/5(n-1)+4 kokosnoten over van een stapel van n+4 kokosnoten. In de laatste stap zijn er 1/5(n+4) = 1/5(n-1)+1 kokosnoten over van een stapel van n+4 kokosnoten. Op deze manier blijft het aantal kokosnoten in de stapel deelbaar door 5 gedurende het hele proces. We zijn dus op zoek naar een p waarvoor het volgende geldt:r + 1= 1/5├Ч4/5├Ч4/5├Ч4/5├Ч4/5├Ч4/5├Ч(p+4)=(45/56)├Ч(p+4), waarbij r een geheel getal moet zijn.De kleinste (p+4) waarvoor het bovenstaande geldt is 56. Dus er waren p = 56-4 = 15621 kokosnoten in de originele stapel. "},{"question":"цЦЗчлауБЛуВЙуВнуГ╝уГпуГ╝уГЙуВТщБ╕уБ│уАБуБЭуБошзгщЗИуВТш┐░уБ╣уБкуБХуБДуАВ щжЩх╖ЭчЬМщлШцЭ╛х╕ВуБзуАБуБ╛уБбуВДц╡╖уБоф╕нуБоуБФуБ┐уВТх░СуБкуБПуБЩуВЛуБЯуВБуБл11цЧеуАБуБФуБ┐уВТцЛ╛уБЖхдзф╝ЪуБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхо╢цЧПуВДщлШцабчФЯуБкуБй14уБоуВ░уГлуГ╝уГЧуБо40ф║║уБРуВЙуБДуБМхПВхКауБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуВ░уГлуГ╝уГЧуБпщБУуБкуБйуБлшР╜уБбуБжуБДуВЛуБФуБ┐уВТ1цЩВщЦУцЛ╛уБДуБ╛уБЩуАВуБЭуБЧуБжуАБчЗГуБИуВЛуБФуБ┐уВДуГЧуГйуВ╣уГБуГГуВпуБкуБйуБлхИЖуБСуБ╛уБЩуАВуБФуБ┐уБочиощбЮуВДщЗНуБХуБзуГЭуВдуГ│уГИуБМц▒║уБ╛уБгуБжуБДуБжуАБуВ╣уГЭуГ╝уГДуБоуВИуБЖуБлчл╢ф║ЙуБЧуБ╛уБЩуАВхР╕уБДч╡ВуВПуБгуБЯуБЯуБ░уБУуВДуВмуГауБоч┤ЩуБкуБйуАБ1цЩВщЦУуБз60kgуБоуБФуБ┐уБМщЫЖуБ╛уВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхДкхЛЭуБЧуБЯуБоуБпуАБ17kgф╗еф╕КуБоуБФуБ┐уВТцЛ╛уБгуБЯхдзхнжчФЯуБоуВ░уГлуГ╝уГЧуБзуБЧуБЯуАВхПВхКауБЧуБЯф║║уБпуАМцАЭуБгуБжуБДуБЯуВИуВКуБЯуБПуБХуВУуБоуБФуБ┐уБМуБВуБгуБжуАБуБ│уБгуБПуВКуБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхдзф╝ЪуВТшбМуБгуБЯхЫгф╜УуБлуВИуВЛуБиуАБчАмцИ╕хЖЕц╡╖уБзуБп1х╣┤уБл4500tуБРуВЙуБДуБоуБФуБ┐уБМшжЛуБдуБЛуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВуБУуБоф╕нуБо60%ф╗еф╕КуБМуБ╛уБбуБкуБйуБЛуВЙц╡БуВМуБЯуБФуБ┐уБауБишиАуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВ","answer":"уБУуБоцЦЗчлауБлхРлуБ╛уВМуВЛуВнуГ╝уГпуГ╝уГЙуБиуБЭуБошзгщЗИуБпф╗еф╕ЛуБзуБЩуАВ- хдзф╝Ъ: 1я╝ЙхдЪуБПуБоф║║уБМщЫЖуБ╛уВЛф╝ЪуАВ2я╝ЙуБВуВЛч╡Дч╣ФуБохЕихУбуБМщЫЖуБ╛уВЛф╝ЪуАВ- уВ░уГлуГ╝уГЧ: 1я╝Йф╗▓щЦУуАВщЫЖхЫгуАВ- хПВхКа: 1я╝Йф╗▓щЦУуБлхЕеуВЛуБУуБиуАВ- чЗГуБИуВЛ: 1я╝ЙчБлуБМуБдуБДуБжуАБуБ╗уБоуБКуБМф╕КуБМуВЛуАВ2я╝ЙчЗГуБИуБжуБДуВЛуВИуБЖуБкуВИуБЖуБЩуБлуБкуВЛуАВ3я╝ЙуБЭуБоц░ЧцМБуБбуБМуАБуБХуБЛуВУуБлш╡╖уБУуВЛуАВ- уГЧуГйуВ╣уГБуГГуВп: 1я╝ЙчЖ▒уВДхЬзхКЫуВТхКауБИуБжуАБшЗкчФ▒уБлх╜вуВТф╜ЬуВЛуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуВЛчЙйш│куАВчЙ╣уБлхРИцИРци╣шДВуВТцМЗуБЩуАВф╜┐уБДщБУуБМх║ГуБДуАВ- хИЖуБС: 1я╝ЙхИеуАЕуБлуБЩуВЛуАВуБпуБкуБЩуАВ2я╝ЙщЕНуВЛуАВхИЖщЕНуБЩуВЛуАВ3я╝Йф╕бхБ┤уБлуАБуБКуБЧщЦЛуБПуАВ4я╝Йх╝ХуБНхИЖуБСуБлуБЩуВЛуАВ5я╝ЙчнЛщБУуВТчлЛуБжуВЛуАВ- чиощбЮ: 1я╝ЙхЕ▒щАЪуБЩуВЛх╜вуВДцАзш│куБлуВИуБгуБжхИЖуБСуБЯуВВуБоуАВ- уГЭуВдуГ│уГИ: 1я╝ЙчВ╣уАВшжБчВ╣уАВ2я╝Йх╛ЧчВ╣уАВчВ╣цХ░уАВ3я╝ЙхЬ░чВ╣уАВха┤цЙАуАВ4я╝Йч╖Ъш╖пуБохИЖуБЛуВМчЫоуБзуАБш╗Кф╕буВТхИеуБоч╖ЪуБлхЕеуВМуБЛуБИуВЛф╗ХуБЛуБСуАВш╗вуБжуБдцйЯуАВ- уВмуГа: 1я╝ЙуБЛуВУуБзхС│уВПуБЖшПУхнРуАВуВмуГауАВ- хДкхЛЭ: 1я╝Йчл╢цКАуБкуБйуБзуАБф╕Аф╜НуБзхЛЭуБдуБУуБиуАВ- хЫгф╜У: 1я╝ЙхдзхЛвуБоф║║уБощЫЖуБ╛уВКуАВ2я╝ЙхРМуБШчЫочЪДуВТцМБуБгуБЯф║║уАЕуБощЫЖуБ╛уВКуАВ- чАмцИ╕хЖЕц╡╖: 1я╝ЙцЬмх╖ЮуГ╗хЫЫхЫ╜уГ╗ф╣Эх╖ЮуБлхЫ▓уБ╛уВМуБЯц╡╖уАВхдЪуБПуБох│╢уАЕуБМуБВуВЛуАВц░ЧхАЩуБпц╕йцЪЦуБзщЫиуБМх░СуБкуБДуАВ- t: 1я╝ЙуГбуГ╝уГИуГлц│ХуБзуАБщЗНуБХуБохНШф╜НуБоф╕АуБдуАВ1уГИуГ│уБпуАБ1000уВнуГнуВ░уГйуГауАВшиШхП╖уБпуАМtуАНуАВ2я╝ЙшИ╣уБохдзуБНуБХуВТшбиуБЩхНШф╜НуАВ- ц╡БуВМ: 1я╝Йц╢▓ф╜УуБкуБйуБМуАБф╜ОуБДуБ╗уБЖуБ╕хЛХуБПуАВ2я╝ЙцЩВуБМуБЯуБдуАВ3я╝ЙчЙйуБМц░┤уБзхЛХуБЛуБХуВМуВЛуАВ4я╝Йх║ГуБМуБгуБжшбМуБПуАВ5я╝ЙуБиуВКуВДуВБуБлуБкуВЛуАВ"},{"question":"р╢╢р╢нр╖Кр╢Ър╖Цр╢╗р╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ур╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╢╕р╖Цр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢п?","answer":"Dragonflies Animalia р╢╗р╖Пр╢вр╢░р╖Пр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ Insecta р╢┤р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢║р╢нр╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ Odonata р╢Ьр╖Эр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ Anisoptera р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢Ъ р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢зр╢нр╖Ъ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ур╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╢Ър╢╗ р╢Зр╢н. р╢╜р╖Ьр╖А р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖П р╢╢р╢нр╖Кр╢Ър╖Цр╢╗р╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Ър╖В 7,000 р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╢╕р╢л р╢Зр╢н. Odonata р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜ р╢┤р╖Рр╢╗р╢лр╖Тр╢нр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Шр╢╕р╖Т р╢Зр╢лр╖Ар╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ср╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗, р╖Ар╖Гр╢╗ р╢╕р╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢▒ 330 р╢Ър╢з р╢┤р╖Щр╢╗, р╢йр╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖Эр╖Гр╖Эр╢╗р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢┤р╖Щр╢╗ р╢Йр╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢н."},{"question":"┘В┘Е ╪и┘Г╪к╪з╪и╪й ┘Е┘В╪з┘Д ┘К╪м┘К╪и ╪╣┘Д┘Й ┘З╪░╪з ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ┘Е┘Ж ┘З┘К ╪з┘Д╪м╪з┘Е╪╣╪й ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪к┘В┘И┘Е ╪и┘Е┘Ж╪н ╪м┘И╪з╪ж╪▓ ╪и┘И┘Д┘К╪к╪▓╪▒ ╪Я.","answer":"╪к╪н╪╕┘Й ┘З╪░┘З ╪з┘Д╪м┘И╪з╪ж╪▓╪М ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ┘Е┘И┘Д╪к ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪г╪│╪з╪│ ╪и┘Е┘Ж╪н╪й ┘Е┘Ж ╪▒╪з╪ж╪п ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н╪з┘Б╪й ╪з┘Д╪г┘Е╪▒┘К┘Г┘К ╪м┘И╪▓┘К┘Б ╪и┘И┘Д┘К╪к╪▓╪▒ ╪и╪к┘В╪п┘К╪▒ ┘Г╪и┘К╪▒. ┘И╪к┘Е┘Ж╪н ╪м╪з┘Е╪╣╪й ┘Г┘И┘Д┘И┘Е╪и┘К╪з ╪з┘Д╪м┘И╪з╪ж╪▓ ╪и╪к┘И╪╡┘К╪й ┘Е┘Ж ┘З┘К╪ж╪й ╪м┘И╪з╪ж╪▓ ╪и┘И┘Д┘К╪к╪▓╪▒╪М ╪з┘Д┘Е┘Г┘И┘Ж╪й ┘Е┘Ж ┘Е╪н┘Г┘Е┘К┘Ж ╪к╪╣┘К┘Ж┘З┘Е ╪з┘Д╪м╪з┘Е╪╣╪й ┘Ж┘Б╪│┘З╪з ┘И┘К╪╡┘Д ╪╣╪п╪п ╪з┘Д╪м┘И╪з╪ж╪▓ ╪з┘Д┘Е┘Е┘Ж┘И╪н╪й ╪│┘Ж┘И┘К┘Л╪з ╪е┘Д┘Й ┘И╪з╪н╪п ┘И╪╣╪┤╪▒┘К┘Ж ╪м╪з╪ж╪▓╪й."},{"question":"█М┌й ╪│┘И╪з┘Д ╪╕╪▒╪н ┌й┘Ж█М╪п ┌й┘З ┘╛╪з╪│╪о ╪в┘Ж ╪з█М┘Ж ╪з╪│╪к: \\"┘Ж┘Е█М ╪к┘И╪з┘Ж ┌п┘Б╪к\\" ┘И ╪│┘╛╪│ ╪м╪▒█М╪з┘Ж ┘Б┌й╪▒█М ╪о┘И╪п ╪▒╪з ┘З┘Е ╪п╪▒ ╪к┘И╪м█М┘З ┘╛╪з╪│╪о ╪к╪з┘Ж ╪и█М╪з┘Ж ┌й┘Ж█М╪п.","answer":"╪│┘И╪з┘Д: ╪в█М╪з ╪м┘Е┘Д┘З \\"█М┌й ┘Е╪▒╪п ╪п╪▒ █М┌й ┘Ж┘Е╪з█М╪┤ ┌й╪к ┘И ╪┤┘Д┘И╪з╪▒ ╪и┘З █М┌й ╪▓┘Ж╪М ╪▒┘Ж┌п ╪│█М╪з┘З ╪з╪▒╪з╪ж┘З ┘Е█М┌й┘Ж╪п\\" ╪и╪п╪з┘Ж ┘Е╪╣┘Ж█М ╪з╪│╪к ┌й┘З \\"█М┌й ┘Б╪▒╪п ╪з┘З╪п╪з┘Б ╪о┘И╪п ╪▒╪з ╪и┘З ╪┤╪о╪╡ ╪п█М┌п╪▒█М ╪з╪▒╪з╪ж┘З ┘Е█М┌й┘Ж╪п╪Я\\" ┌п╪▓█М┘Ж┘З ┘З╪з: ╪в╪▒┘З - ╪к┘И╪╢█М╪н█М ┘Ж╪п╪з╪▒┘Е.┘Ж┘Е┘К╪┤┘З ┌п┘Б╪к - ╪к┘И╪╢█М╪н█М ┘Ж╪п╪з╪▒┘Е.┘Ж┘З - ╪м╪▒█М╪з┘Ж ┘Б┌й╪▒█М: ╪з╪▒╪з╪ж┘З █М┌й ╪з█М╪п┘З ╪п╪▒ █М┌й ┘Ж┘Е╪з█М╪┤╪М ┘Д╪▓┘И┘Е╪з ┘Ж╪┤╪з┘Ж ╪п╪з╪п┘Ж ╪з┘З╪п╪з┘Б ╪о┘И╪п ╪и┘З ╪┤╪о╪╡ ╪п█М┌п╪▒ ┘Ж█М╪│╪к."},{"question":"р░░р▒Жр░Вр░бр▒Б р░╕р░░р▒Вр░к р░др▒Нр░░р░┐р░нр▒Бр░Ь р░╡р▒Ир░╢р░╛р░▓р▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓ р░ир░┐р░╖р▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐ a:9 р░Ер░пр░┐р░и , р░╡р░╛р░ир░┐ р░нр▒Бр░Ьр░╛р░▓ р░ир░┐р░╖р▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐ р░Ор░Вр░д ?","answer":"р░нр▒Бр░Ьр░╛р░▓ р░ир░┐р░╖р▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐ = тИЪa : 3."},{"question":"р┤И р┤Цр┤гр╡Нр┤бр┤┐р┤Хр┤пр╡Нр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Н р┤Тр┤░р╡Б р┤др╡Бр┤Яр╡╝р┤Ър╡Нр┤Ъ р┤Ор┤┤р╡Бр┤др╡Бр┤Х: р┤И р┤ор╡Зр┤Цр┤▓р┤пр┤┐р┤▓р╡Ж р┤Пр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р┤╡р╡Бр┤В р┤Йр┤пр┤░р┤ор╡Бр┤│р╡Нр┤│ р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤жр╡Зр┤╢р┤ор┤╛р┤гр╡Н р┤Яр╡Ир┤Чр╡╝ р┤╣р┤┐р╡╜. р┤╢р╡Нр┤░р╡Ар┤ир┤Чр╡╝ р┤ор╡Бр┤др╡╜ р┤Хр┤╛р╡╝р┤Чр┤┐р╡╜ р┤╡р┤░р╡Ж, р┤Хр┤╛р╡╝р┤Чр┤┐р╡╜ р┤ор╡Зр┤Цр┤▓р┤пр┤┐р╡╜ р┤ир┤╛р┤╖р┤гр╡╜ р┤╣р╡Ир┤╡р╡З 1D, р┤мр┤ир╡Нр┤зр┤┐р┤кр╡Нр┤кр┤┐р┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤и р┤▒р╡Лр┤бр╡Н р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤зр┤╛р┤и р┤╡р┤┐р┤др┤░р┤г р┤кр┤╛р┤др┤пр┤╛р┤гр╡Н р┤Зр┤др╡Н. р┤Хр╡Кр┤Яр╡Бр┤ор╡Бр┤Яр┤┐р┤пр┤┐р┤▓р╡Ж р┤Пр┤др╡Кр┤░р╡Б р┤╢р┤др╡Нр┤░р╡Бр┤╡р┤┐р┤ир╡Бр┤В р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤жр╡Зр┤╢р┤др╡Нр┤др╡Ж р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤зр┤╛р┤и р┤Зр┤ир╡Нр┤др╡Нр┤пр╡╗ р┤пр╡Вр┤гр┤┐р┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р┤╛р┤п 56 р┤мр╡Нр┤░р┤┐р┤Чр╡Зр┤бр┤┐р┤ир╡Нр┤▒р╡Ж р┤Жр┤╕р╡Нр┤ер┤╛р┤ир┤др╡Нр┤др╡Зр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Н р┤ир╡Зр┤░р┤┐р┤Яр╡Нр┤Яр╡Н р┤Хр┤╛р┤гр┤╛р┤ир┤╛р┤Хр╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤и р┤Тр┤░р╡Б р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤жр╡Зр┤╢р┤В р┤Хр╡Вр┤Яр┤┐р┤пр┤╛р┤гр╡Н р┤Зр┤др╡Н р┤Ор┤ир╡Нр┤ир┤др┤┐р┤ир┤╛р╡╜, р┤кр╡Ар┤░р┤Щр╡Нр┤Хр┤┐ р┤╡р╡Жр┤Яр┤┐р┤╡р┤пр╡Нр┤кр╡Нр┤кр┤┐р┤ир╡Бр┤│р╡Нр┤│ р┤╕р┤╛р┤зр╡Нр┤пр┤др┤Хр╡Вр┤Яр┤┐р┤пр╡Бр┤гр╡Нр┤Яр╡Н. р┤Зр┤ир╡Нр┤др╡Нр┤пр╡╗ р┤╕р╡Ир┤ир┤┐р┤Хр┤░р╡Бр┤Яр╡Ж р┤пр┤╛р┤др╡Нр┤░р┤пр╡Нр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Бр┤В р┤╡р┤╕р╡Нр┤др╡Бр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр┤│р╡Бр┤Яр╡Ж р┤╡р┤┐р┤др┤░р┤гр┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Бр┤В р┤др┤Яр┤╕р╡Нр┤╕р┤ор╡Бр┤гр╡Нр┤Яр┤╛р┤Хр┤╛р┤▒р╡Бр┤гр╡Нр┤Яр┤╛р┤пр┤┐р┤░р╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤и р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤жр╡Зр┤╢р┤В р┤Хр╡Вр┤Яр┤┐р┤пр┤╛р┤пр┤┐р┤░р╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир╡Б р┤Зр┤др╡Н. р┤Хр┤╛р╡╝р┤Чр┤┐р╡╜ р┤пр╡Бр┤жр╡Нр┤зр┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Н","answer":"р┤╢р╡Зр┤╖р┤В р┤Зр┤ир╡Нр┤др╡Нр┤пр╡╗ р┤кр┤Яр╡Нр┤Яр┤╛р┤│р┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Н р┤Хр╡Бр┤▒р╡Зр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Вр┤Яр┤┐ р┤ир┤┐р┤пр┤ир╡Нр┤др╡Нр┤░р┤гр┤В р┤▓р┤нр┤┐р┤Ър╡Нр┤Ър┤др┤┐р┤ир┤╛р╡╜, р┤╕р┤ор╡Ар┤кр┤др╡Нр┤др╡Бр┤│р╡Нр┤│ р┤ор┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р╡Н р┤Хр╡Кр┤Яр╡Бр┤ор╡Бр┤Яр┤┐р┤Хр┤│р┤┐р┤▓р╡Зр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Бр┤В р┤Тр┤░р╡Б р┤ир┤┐р┤░р╡Ар┤Хр╡Нр┤╖р┤г р┤Хр╡Зр┤ир╡Нр┤жр╡Нр┤░р┤В р┤И р┤Хр╡Кр┤Яр╡Бр┤ор╡Бр┤Яр┤┐ р┤ир╡╜р┤Хр╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир╡Бр┤гр╡Нр┤Яр╡Н."},{"question":"Apakah terjun lelabah?","answer":"Terjun lelabah adalah satu aktiviti yang melibatkan penerjunan dari bangunan yang tinggi sementara pelompat disambungkan kepada tali elastik besar. Struktur ini biasanya objek yang tetap seperti sebuah bangunan, jambatan atau kren, tetapi lompatan juga boleh dibuat daripada objek bergerak seperti belon udara panas atau helikopter yang mempunyai keupayaan untuk berlegar di atas tanah. Rasa keterujaan sewaktu melakukan aktiviti ini datangnya dari terjunan bebas serta lonjakan semula yang terhasil. Apabila orang yang diikut itu menerjun, tali menjadi tegang lalu si penerjun 'terbang' ke atas lagi akibat pengecutan tali dan terus berayun ke atas dan ke bawah sehingga kesemua tenaga kinetik yang tersimpan akhirnya hilang."},{"question":"Ndiani aive Mambokadzi Nzinga, uye nei achikosha munhoroondo yeAfrica?","answer":"Mambokadzi Nzinga aiva mutongi wezana remakore rechi17 weNdongo neMatamba Kingdoms (yanhasi Angola). Akadzivisa kutorwa kwechiPutukezi, achitungamirira vanhu vake muhondo dzinotyisa kurwisa vapambi."},{"question":"\\"р╖Гр╖Фр╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢вр╢нр╖Ф\\" р╢нр╖Щр╢╗р╖Фр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒","answer":"р╖Гр╖Ф= р╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢вр╢нр╖Ф= р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢Зр╢╜р╖Щр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╖П."},{"question":"Qaab Qoraalka Tolmoon?","answer":"Qaab Qoraalka Tolmoon_____________________________Nabad jaallayaal, ku soo dhowaada qaybta koowaad ee casharada taxanaha inoo noqon doona, kuwaasi oo ku saabsan qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee afkeena hooyo. Kadib markii ay farriimo badan iiga yimaadeen asxaab iyo akhyaar badan oo halkan ku jira, doonistooda iyo dadaalkoodana aan arkay, waxa aan go'aansaday in aan halkan idiinka bilaabo casharro taxane inoo noqon doona oo qofku qoraalka tayadiisa ku hagaajinayo.Qoraalku waa xifad ay dad badan ku shaqaystaan meelo badan oo caalamka ka mid ah, waana xirfadaha ugu qaalisan ee xitaa qof kasta oo shaqo codsanaya lagu xidho in uu yaqaan. Walow aanu afkeena wax badan lagu qorin xarumaha dawladda iyo meelihihii ay ahayd in lagu weyneeyo, haddana dal kasta afkiisu waa waxa koowaad ee ay kuwada xidhiidhaan waxna isugu qoraan. Ma jirto dawlad Soomaaliyeed oo xil iyo ahmiyad weyn iska saartay kor u qaaddida iyo dhawridda afkeena si saxan.Maamulada faraha badan ee gayiga Soomaalida ka jira, runtii waa meelaha adeegsiga qoraalka iyo afkeena hoos u liiday, ee luuqaddo kale wax ku qorta. Marka laga yimaado halganka ay ugu jiraan dhallinyarta wax qorta iyo dadka si uun afkeena u ilaasha oo u kaydiya, ma jirto cid kale oo xil iska saarta tayaynta iyo nooleynta afkeena.Aqoondarradaasi waxa ay keentay in aynu aragno boqollaal buug oo dibadda u soo baxay, marka aad akhriso ama aad eegtona aad ka yaxyaxayso tayo-xumada qoraalka buuggaas. Dawlad la'aantu, waxa kale oo ay keentay in aan la dhamaystiran qabyadii ku jirtay qoraalka Soomaaliga, waxana ay illaa maanta sabab u tahay muranno badan iyo aragtiyo badan oo la isku khilaafsan yahay.Khilaafyadaas iyo qabyadaa qoraalka ku jiraa waxa ay dhaleen in lagu kala duwanaado meelaha qaar iyo adeegsiga qoraalada qaar.Nasiib darrooyinka kale ee ina haysta waxa ka mida, in aanay jirin goobo iyo meelo u gaara oo loogu hagaago barashada qoraalka. Dad dadaalay uun baa wixii ay ka yaqaaniin wax ka mida dadka uga sii faa'iideeya mooyee. Madashan akhriska iyo qoraalka runtii qoraallo dhisan waad arkaysaa, laakiin qoraalada u badan ee halkan la soo galiyo waa qaar laga xishoonayo akhriskooda tayo-xumada qoraalkooda, se dhalliil kaliya waxba ma tarayso, waa in isu faa'iidaynaa waxa aan is dheer nahay.HORDHACSida aad la wada socotaan af walba oo dunida ka jira waxa uu leeyahay qaab loo qoro, xeerar iyo qawaaniin la raaco marka la qorayo, haddii laga tagona ka dhigaysa qoraalkaaga mid ma dhalays ah. Af Somaaliguna waa la mid, waxa uu leeyahay xeerar iyo qawaaniin ay tahay in aad isticmaasho marka aad qorayso, ma noqonayso sax in sida aad ugu hadkayso u qorto, balse waxa lagama maarmaan ah in aad barato sida loo qoro, kaliya aanad baran sida loogu dhawaaqo ama loo akhriyo oo qudha.Guddidii farta Soomaaliga dajisay 1972kii, ayaa sida oo kale inoo qeexay qaab qoraalka Soomaaliga iyo xeerarkiisa, metelan shaqallada labanlaabmaya, marka xarafka la weyneeyo iyo adeegsiga calaamadahaba.Waxa aynnu isku dayi doonaa insha Allah, inta aqoonteydan gaabani gaadhsiisan tahay in aan uga faa'iideeyo bulsho-weynta Soomaaliyeed, siiba dhallinyarada jecel barashada qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee afkeena, kuwaasi oo halkan ka qaadan doona casharro taxane ah duhur walba insha Allah.Si lamida sida hadalku ugu baahan yahay marka aad hadlayso, in aad ugu kala samayso meel hakad, meelna joogsi, meel weyddiin, meel dareen muujiso, meel yaab aad muujiso, sidaa iyo si lamida ayaa uu qoraalkuna ugu baahan yahay in aadan isku dhex yaacin waxa aad qorayso, balse ay tahay in aad ukala nidaamiso si qof walba fahmi karo.Qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee afkeena,  marka uu qofku barto ama wax ka yaqaan ugu yaraan,  waxa macne u samaynaya waxa uu qorayo ama akhrinayo, metelan qoraagu marka uu wax qorayo uma qorayo sida uu isagu u fahansan yahay, balse waxa uu u qorayaa si qof kasta oo akhriyaa u fahmi karayo ujeedka qoraalkiisa.Guddidii farta Soomaaligu waxa ay isku afgarteen xilligaas, in toddobo shibbane ay labanlaabmayaan af Soomaliga, kuwaasi oo kala ah M, N, L, G, R, D, B, laguna jamciyo weedha caanka ah ee, \\"MaNaLaGaaraaDBaa,\\" walow ay jiraan weedho kale, haddana tani waa ta ugu caansan. Waxa jira af-aqoollo Soomaali iyo ajaaniib ah, kuwaasi oo ku doodda in ay jiraan xarfo kale oo labanlaabma, balse ay guddidu ka tagtay iyaga oo tusaalayaal usoo qaata xarfo ay ka mid yihiin \\"Q,S,\\" innaguse waqtigan doodda furitaankeeda iyo ka sheekaynteeda taag uma hayno, waxa aynnu kari la'nahayba barashada toddobadii la isku waafaqsanaa.Khaladaadka u waaweyn ee dhallinyarteenan danbe ay ka galaan qoraalka, waa in ay isticmaalaan xarfo aan ku jirin shibbanayaasha Soomaaliga, sida \\"Z, P, V,\\" kuwaasi oo meesha ka saara inta badan xarfaha \\"S, B, F,\\" waa wax lagu tilmaami karo nasiib darro in xarfo aan ku jirin shibbanayaasha khasab ugu darno, walibana aan booska uga saarno kuwii saxda ahaa ee booskaas lahaa. Waxa aan dhallinyarta kula talinayaa in saddexdaas xaraf adeegsigooda loogu daayo luuqadda ay ku jiraan, balse aan lagu dhex wadin Afkeena, maadaama oo aanay meelna kaga jirin.Astaamaha kala duwan ee qoraalku waxa ay qayb ka yihiin qaab qoraalka tolmoon ee qofka wax qoraya looga baahan yahay in uu aad u kala barto calaamadaha kala duwan ee la isticmaalo qoraalka dhexdiisa.Adeegsiga khaldan ee calaamaduhu mararka qaar waxa uu sababi karaa shil dhaca ama arrin dhibaato keeni karta, ay sababtu tahay in aan si saxan loo isticmaalin calaamadaas.Waxa jirta weedh caan ah, \\"Coma can a kill man.\\" Oo macnaheedu yahay, \\"Hakadku waxa uu dili karaa nin.\\" Waan filayaa in qisadeeda aan kawada dharagsanahay, waa sheeko hakad si khaldan loo adeegsaday sabab u noqday in nin la dilo naftana daqiiqado gudahood lagu dhaafiyo. \\"Kill him, not wait for me!тАЭ oo macnaheedu yahay: тАЬDila, aniga ha i sugina!\\" Sidaas ayaa uu sarkaalkii warqada usoo qoray, balse sida saxda ah ee ujeeday waxa ay ahayd,\\"Kill him not, wait for me!тАЭ oo macnaheedu yahay тАЬHa dilina, aniga i suga!\\"Halkii ayaa ninkii lagu dilay, waxana galaaftay noloshiisii dhamayd waa hakad si khaldan loo adeegsaday ama meel aan meeshiisii ahayn la dhigay!.Waxa kale oo aynu isku dul taagi doonaa muddada casharadani inoo socon doonaan haddii Rabbi idmo, xilliyada ay habboon tahay in xarafka la weyneeyo ama xarfaha la weyneeyo, marka aad qoraallo badan aragto ama akhriso waxa aad ku dhex arkaysaa xarfo ay ahayd in la waaweyneeyo oo la yareeyay iyo xarfo ay ahayd in la yareeyo oo la weyneeyay, taasina waa khalad iyo gef cad oo afkeena lagula kacayo. Ugu dambeyn, maanta hordhacaas ayaynu qaadan, insha Allah barri duhur ayay inoo bilaabmi oo aan soo galin doonaa qaybta koowaad, la socod iyo ka faa'iidaysi wanaagsan walaalayaal."},{"question":"р╢Ер╖Ар╖Ър╢╜р╖Пр╖А р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢пр╖Др╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢пр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖П  р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.. ","answer":"р╢Ер╖Ар╖Ър╢╜р╖Пр╖А р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢┤р╢пр╢║ р╖Ар╖Ър╢╜р╖Пр╖А р╖Ар╖Ъ"},{"question":"Kush e fitoi Kampionatin Evropian n├л vitin 1964?","answer":"N├л vitin 1964 Kampionatin Evropian e fitoi Spanja."},{"question":"╪┤┘Ж┘И ┘З┘К ╪з┘Г╪и╪▒ ╪м╪▓┘К╪▒┘З ┘Г╪з┘К┘Ж┘З ┘Б╪з┘Д╪и╪н╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪з╪и┘К╪╢ ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к┘И╪│╪╖  ╪Я","answer":"╪╡┘В┘Д┘К╪й."},{"question":"Alerjik sivilce nas─▒l olur?","answer":"Alerjiler do─Яrudan bir belirti olarak sivilceye neden olmazken, ikincil bir ┼Яekilde olabilir. Alerjiler v├╝cutta iltihaplanmaya neden olur, bu da ┼Яi┼Яmeye ve cilt tahri┼Яine yol a├зabilir. Bu iltihaplanma daha sonra bir ba─Я─▒┼Я─▒kl─▒k tepkisini tetikleyerek akneyi k├╢t├╝le┼Яtirebilecek hormonlar─▒n sal─▒nmas─▒na neden olabilir."},{"question":"риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риХри░риХрйЗ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐ри╕риери╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ ри╣рйЗриари╛риВ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗ рижри╛ риХрйА риЕри░рие ри╣рйИред\\"риЧриЙрйЬрйА риори╣ри▓ри╛ рйз реерибри░ри┐ риШри░рйБ риШри░ри┐ рибри░рйБ рибри░ри┐ рибри░рйБ риЬри╛риЗ реери╕рйЛ рибри░рйБ риХрйЗри╣ри╛ риЬри┐ридрйБ рибри░ри┐ рибри░рйБ рикри╛риЗ рееридрйБризрйБ римри┐риирйБ рижрйВриЬрйА риири╛ри╣рйА риЬри╛риЗ реериЬрйЛ риХри┐риЫрйБ ри╡ри░ридрйИ ри╕рин ридрйЗри░рйА ри░риЬри╛риЗ реерйзреерибри░рйАриР риЬрйЗ рибри░рйБ ри╣рйЛри╡рйИ ри╣рйЛри░рйБ реерибри░ри┐ рибри░ри┐ рибри░ригри╛ риории риХри╛ ри╕рйЛри░рйБ реерйзрее ри░ри╣ри╛риЙ реериири╛ риЬрйАриЙ риори░рйИ рии рибрйВримрйИ ридри░рйИ реериЬри┐риири┐ риХри┐риЫрйБ риХрйАриЖ ри╕рйЛ риХри┐риЫрйБ риХри░рйИ реери╣рйБриХриорйЗ риЖри╡рйИ ри╣рйБриХриорйЗ риЬри╛риЗ реериЖриЧрйИ рикри╛риЫрйИ ри╣рйБриХриори┐ ри╕риори╛риЗ реерйиреери╣рй░ри╕рйБ ри╣рйЗридрйБ риЖри╕ри╛ риЕри╕риори╛риирйБ рееридри┐ри╕рйБ ри╡ри┐риЪри┐ ринрйВриЦ римри╣рйБридрйБ риирйИ ри╕ри╛риирйБ рееринриЙ риЦри╛ригри╛ рикрйАригри╛ риЖризри╛ри░рйБ реери╡ри┐ригрйБ риЦри╛ризрйЗ риори░ри┐ ри╣рйЛри╣ри┐ риЧри╡ри╛ри░ реерййреериЬри┐ри╕ риХри╛ риХрйЛриЗ риХрйЛриИ риХрйЛриЗ риХрйЛриЗ реери╕ринрйБ риХрйЛ ридрйЗри░ри╛ ридрйВрй░ ри╕ринриири╛ риХри╛ ри╕рйЛриЗ реериЬри╛ риХрйЗ риЬрйАриЕ риЬрй░рид ризриирйБ риори╛ри▓рйБ реериири╛риириХ риЖриЦригрйБ римри┐риЦриорйБ римрйАриЪри╛ри░рйБ реерйкреерйирее\\"","answer":"риЗри╣ ри╕рйНри░рйА риЧрйБри░рйВ риЧрйНри░рй░рие ри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐рим риЬрйА рижрйЗ рикрй░риири╛ 151 ридрйЛриВ ри▓ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риЧрйБри░рйВ риири╛риириХ рижрйЗри╡ риЬрйА риЗри╣риири╛риВ римри╛ригрйАриЖриВ рижрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЦри╛ри░рйА ри╣рииредриЗри╕ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйЗриа ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ риЕриирйБри╕ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЦри┐риЖрии риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ,\\"(ри╣рйЗ рикрйНри░ринрйВ┬а!) ридрйЗри░рйЗ рибри░-риЕрижрим ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛риВ риЙри╣ риЖридриориХ риЕри╡ри╕риери╛ риори┐ри▓ риЬри╛риВрижрйА ри╣рйИ риЬри┐риерйЗ риории ридрйЗри░рйЗ риЪри░риири╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬрйБрйЬри┐риЖ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ, ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЗри╣ риприХрйАрии римриг риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ ридрйВрй░ риорйЗри░рйЗ риЕрй░рижри░ ри╡рй▒ри╕рижри╛ ри╣рйИриВ ридрйЗ ри╕рин ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╡рй▒ри╕рижри╛ ри╣рйИриВ ред ридрйЗри░рйЗ рибри░ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛риВ (рижрйБриирйАриЖ рижри╛ ри╣ри░рйЗриХ риХри┐ри╕рио рижри╛) ри╕ри╣рио рижрйВри░ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред ридрйЗри░ри╛ рибри░ риРри╕ри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рй░рйБрижри╛ риХри┐ риЙри╕ рибри░ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛риВ риХрйЛриИ ри╣рйЛри░ ри╕ри╣рио риЯри┐риХри┐риЖ ри░ри╣рйЗ ред(ри╣рйЗ рикрйНри░ринрйВ┬а!) ридрйИриерйЛриВ римри┐риири╛риВ риЬрйАри╡ рижри╛ риХрйЛриИ ри╣рйЛри░ риери╛риВ-риЖри╕ри░ри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйИ редриЬриЧрид ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬрйЛ риХрйБриЭ ри╣рйЛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИ ри╕рин ридрйЗри░рйА риори░рйЫрйА риири╛ри▓ ри╣рйЛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйзред(ри╣рйЗ рикрйНри░ринрйВ┬а!) ридрйЗри░ри╛ рибри░-риЕрижрим риЯри┐риХриг рижрйЗ риери╛риВ) риЬрйЗ риЬрйАри╡ рижрйЗ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ риХрйЛриИ ри╣рйЛри░ рибри░ риЯри┐риХри┐риЖ ри░ри╣рйЗ, ридри╛риВ риЬрйАри╡ ри╕рижри╛ ри╕ри╣риори┐риЖ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ, риории рижрйА риШримри░ри╛ри╣риЯ риории рижри╛ ри╕ри╣рио ри╣ри░ ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ римригри┐риЖ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйзредри░ри╣ри╛риЙред(рикрйНри░ринрйВ рижрйЗ рибри░-риЕрижрим ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛риВ ри╣рйА риЗри╣ риприХрйАрии римриг ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐) риЬрйАри╡ риири╛ри╣ риори░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ риири╛ри╣ риХри┐ридрйЗ рибрйБрй▒рим ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ риири╛ри╣ риХри┐ридрйЛриВ ридри░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ (ринри╛ри╡, риЬрйЗри╣рйЬри╛ риХри┐ридрйЗ рибрйБримрижри╛ ри╣рйА риири╣рйАриВ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ ридри░рии рижри╛ ри╕ри╡ри╛ри▓ ри╣рйА рикрйИрижри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рй░рйБрижри╛) ред(риЗри╣ риприХрйАрии римригри┐риЖ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐) риЬри┐ри╕ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ риирйЗ риЗри╣ риЬриЧрид римригри╛риЗриЖ ри╣рйИ риЙри╣рйА ри╕рин риХрйБриЭ риХри░ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИ,риЙри╕ рижрйЗ ри╣рйБриХрио ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╣рйА риЬрйАри╡ риЬрй░риорижри╛ ри╣рйИ ридрйЗ ри╣рйБриХрио ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╣рйА риори░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ,ри▓рйЛриХ рикри░ри▓рйЛриХ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬрйАри╡ риирйВрй░ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ ри╣рйБриХрио ри╡ри┐риЪ риЯри┐риХрйЗ ри░ри╣ри┐ригри╛ рикрйИриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйиред(риЬри┐ри╕ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ рикрйНри░ринрйВ рижри╛ рибри░-риЕрижрим риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйИ, риорйЛри╣ ри╣рйИ, риЕри╣рй░риХри╛ри░ ри╣рйИ, риЙри╕ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ ридрйНри░ри┐ри╢риири╛ рижрйА риХри╛риВриЧ риирижрйА ри╡ри╛риВриЧ (риари╛риари╛риВ риори╛ри░ ри░ри╣рйА) ри╣рйИ редрикрйНри░ринрйВ рижри╛ рибри░-риЕрижрим ри╣рйА риЖридриориХ риЬрйАри╡рии рижрйА рйЩрйБри░ри╛риХ ри╣рйИ, риЖридриори╛ рижри╛ риЖри╕ри░ри╛ ри╣рйИ;риЬрйЛ риЗри╣ рйЩрйБри░ри╛риХ риири╣рйАриВ риЦри╛риВрижрйЗ риЙри╣ (рижрйБриирйАриЖ рижрйЗ) ри╕ри╣рио ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░ри╣ри┐ риХрйЗ риХриори▓рйЗ ри╣рйЛриП ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижрйЗ ри╣рии редрййред(ри╣рйЗ рикрйНри░ринрйВ┬а! ридрйЗри░рйЗ рибри░-риЕрижрим ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛риВ ри╣рйА риЗри╣ риприХрйАрии римригрижри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐) риЬри┐ри╕ риХри┐ри╕рйЗ рижри╛ риХрйЛриИ ри╕ри╣ри╛риИ римригрижри╛ ри╣рйИ риХрйЛриИ ри╡ри┐ри░ри▓ри╛ ри╣рйА римригрижри╛ ри╣рйИ (ринри╛ри╡, риХри┐ри╕рйЗ рижри╛ риХрйЛриИ ри╕рижри╛ ри▓риИ ри╕ри╛риерйА ри╕ри╣ри╛риЗриХ риири╣рйАриВ римриг ри╕риХрижри╛),рикри░ ри╣ри░рйЗриХ риЬрйАри╡ ридрйЗри░ри╛ (рикрйИрижри╛ риХрйАридри╛ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ) ри╣рйИ, ридрйВрй░ ри╕рин рижрйА ри╕ри╛ри░ ри░рй▒риЦриг ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ ри╣рйИриВ редри╣рйЗ риири╛риириХ┬а! риЬри┐ри╕ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйЗ риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риЬрйАри╡ риЬрй░рид рикрйИрижри╛ риХрйАридрйЗ ри╣рйЛриП ри╣рии (риЬрйАри╡ри╛риВ ри╡ри╛ри╕ридрйЗ) риЙри╕рйЗ рижри╛ ри╣рйА риЗри╣ ризрии-риори╛ри▓ (римригри╛риЗриЖ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ) ри╣рйИ ред(риЗри╕ ридрйЛриВ ри╡риз риЗри╣) ри╡ри┐риЪри╛ри░риири╛ ридрйЗ риЖриЦригри╛ (риХри┐ риЙри╣ рикрйНри░ринрйВ риЖрикригрйЗ рикрйИрижри╛ риХрйАридрйЗ риЬрйАри╡ри╛риВ рижрйА риХри┐ри╡рйЗриВ ри╕рй░ринри╛ри▓ риХри░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ) риФриЦри╛ риХрй░рио ри╣рйИ ред редрйкредрйиред\\""},{"question":"Ahoana ny fomba atao hitsaboana ny aphte ?","answer":"Sitrana ho azy ny aphte ary afaka tanteraka ny aphte eo aminтАЩny 10 hatraminтАЩny 15 andro eo. Noho izany dia tsy dia misy fitsaboana atao hanatsitranana azy ireny. Ny tokony atao kosa nefa dia ny mampitony ny fanaintainana ary misoroka ny hipoitrany aminтАЩny ho avy.Misy ireo fomba natoraly azo atao ampitoniana ankizy misy aphte. AnisanтАЩizany ohatra ny fanaovana gararaka aminтАЩny rano iray vera nasiana karibonetra 2 tsongon-tanana. Azo atao ihany koa ny manosotra tantely eo aminтАЩilay ratra kely mba ampitoniana ilay marary. Atao indroa isanтАЩandro ireo torohevitra ireo. A"},{"question":"р╢║р╖Фр╢╗р╖Эр╢┤р╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ср╢Ър╢╕ р╢╢р╖Юр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╢╗р╖Пр╢вр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╢╗ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╢╗ р╢Ср╢╜р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢зр╖Пр╢║."},{"question":"рдЖрд░реНрдЯрд┐рдлрд┐рд╕рд┐рдпрд▓ рдЗрдиреНрдЯреЗрд▓рд┐рдЬреЗрдиреНрд╕ рднрдиреЗрдХреЛ рдХреЗ рд╣реЛ?","answer":"рдЖрд░реНрдЯрд┐рдлрд┐рд╕рд┐рдпрд▓ рдЗрдиреНрдЯреЗрд▓рд┐рдЬреЗрдиреНрд╕ рднрдиреЗрдХреЛ рдПрд▓реНрдЧреЛрд░рд┐рджрдо рд░ рдбреЗрдЯрд╛рдХреЛ рдкреНрд░рдпреЛрдЧ рдорд╛рд░реНрдлрдд рд╕рд┐рдХрд╛рдЗ, рд╕рдорд╕реНрдпрд╛ рд╕рдорд╛рдзрд╛рди, рд░ рдирд┐рд░реНрдгрдп рд▓рд┐рдиреЗ рдЬрд╕реНрддрд╛ рдХрд╛рд░реНрдпрд╣рд░реВ рдЧрд░реНрди рд╕рдХреНрд╖рдо рдХрдореНрдкреНрдпреБрдЯрд░ рдкреНрд░рдгрд╛рд▓реАрд╣рд░реВрдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рд╣реЛ рдЬрд╕рд▓рд╛рдИ рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрдпрд╛ рдорд╛рдирд╡ рдмреБрджреНрдзрд┐рдХреЛ рдЖрд╡рд╢реНрдпрдХрддрд╛ рдкрд░реНрджрдЫред"},{"question":"Inona no il├аna ny lalamby Antananarivo - Toamasina?","answer":"ny lalamby Antananarivo - Toamasina dia itaterana ny vokatry ny tany halefa amin'ny sambo sy itondrana ireo entam-barotra avy any ivelanyary ny solitany voadio tao Toamasina"},{"question":"╨в╤Г╤Г╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨║╥п╨╜╨│╙й ╨║╨░╤А╨░╤В╨░ ╨║╤Г╤В╤В╤Г╨║╤В╨╛╨╛ ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡ ╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╥г╨▒╤Л  ?","answer":"╨Ъ╨╡╨╗╨╡ ╨╢╨░╤В╨║╨░╨╜ ╨╢╤Л╨╗╨┤╨░╤А ╤Б╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨╢╨░╤И╨╛╨╛╥г╤Г╨╖╨│╨░ ╨░╨║╤Л╨╗╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║, ╨╢╤Л╨╗╤Г╤Г╨╗╤Г╨║ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨╕╨╣╨│╨╕╨╗╨╕╨║ ╨║╨╛╤И╤Б╤Г╨╜. ╨Ц╥п╨╖╥п╥г╥п╨╖╨┤╙й╨│╥п ╨╢╤Л╨╗╨╝╨░╤О╤Г ╤В╥п╨▒╙й╨╗╥п╨║╨║╙й ╨║╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╕╨╜! ╨в╤Г╤Г╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨║╥п╨╜╥п╥г╥п╨╖ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨║╤Г╤В╤В╤Г╨║╤В╨░╨╣╨╝!"},{"question":"Sheeg magaca ninkii uu Nabiga (scw) u bixiyey Seeyfulaahil masluul?","answer":"wuxuu ahaa Khaalid Ibnu Waliid."},{"question":"╨Ф╥п╨╣╨╜╙й╨┤╙й╨│╥п ╤Н╥г ╤З╨╛╥г ╤Б╥п╤В ╤Н╨╝╥п╥п╤З╥п ╨╢╨░╨╜╤Л╨▒╨░╤А","answer":"╨Ъ╙й╨║ ╨║╨╕╤В."},{"question":"чВ║ф╗Ащ║╝цдНчЙйцЬГчФЯщХ╖я╝Я","answer":"цдНчЙйщА▓шбМхЕЙхРИф╜ЬчФия╝МхИйчФищЩ╜хЕЙхТМц░┤хРИцИРщдКхИЖя╝Мф┐ГщА▓чФЯщХ╖уАВ"},{"question":"ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрж░ ржорзНржпрж╛ржЩрзНржЧрзЗржЯрж┐ржХ ржЦрзБржБржЯрж┐рж░ ржХрж╛рж░ржг ржХрзА","answer":"ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрж░ ржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржорзЗрж░рзБржЧрзБрж▓рж┐ ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрж░ ржХрзЗржирзНржжрзНрж░рзЗ ржкржжрж╛рж░рзНржерзЗрж░ ржЪрж▓рж╛ржЪрж▓рзЗрж░ ржХрж╛рж░ржгрзЗ рждрзИрж░рж┐ рж╣ржпрж╝ ржпрж╛ ржПржХржЯрж┐ рж╢ржХрзНрждрж┐рж╢рж╛рж▓рзА ржЪрзБржорзНржмржХрзЗрж░ ржорждрзЛ ржХрж╛ржЬ ржХрж░рзЗ ржПржмржВ ржжржХрзНрж╖рж┐ржг ржорзЗрж░рзБ ржПржмржВ ржЙрждрзНрждрж░ ржорзЗрж░рзБржХрзЗ рж╕рж╛рж░рж┐ржмржжрзНржз ржХрж░рзЗред ржЪрзБржорзНржмржХрзЗрж░ ржЙрждрзНрждрж░ ржорзЗрж░рзБ ржЙрждрзНрждрж░ ржжрж┐ржХрзЗ ржирж┐рж░рзНржжрзЗрж╢ ржХрж░рзЗ ржХрж╛рж░ржг ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрж░ ржЪрзБржорзНржмржХрзЗрж░ ржжржХрзНрж╖рж┐ржг ржорзЗрж░рзБ ржЙрждрзНрждрж░ ржжрж┐ржХрзЗ ржирж┐рж░рзНржжрзЗрж╢рж┐ржд"},{"question":"Kodi Malawi ndi dziko losauka kapena lolemera?","answer":"Dziko la Malawi ndi limodzi mwa mayiko osauka kwambiri padziko lonse lapansi ndipo lili pa nambala 174 mwa mayiko 189 pa ndondomeko ya chitukuko cha anthu. Oposa theka la anthu amakhala mu umphawi, ndipo gawo limodzi mwa magawo asanu ali umphawi wadzaoneni."},{"question":"рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╛ро░ро┐ройрпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ  роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЪроородрпНродрпБро╡рооро╛рой роХро▓рпНро╡ро┐ роЕро│ро┐роХрпНроХ роПро▒рпНрокро╛роЯрпБ роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпЗ роороХрпНроХро│рпН роорпБройрпНройрпЗро▒рпНро▒родрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ роПро▒рпНро▒родро╛роХрпБроорпН."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокро┐роп роЗро▓роХрпНроХрпИ роЕроЯрпИроп роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роорпБродро▓рпН роорпБро▒рпИропро╛роХ роороХро╛родрпНрооро╛ роХро╛роирпНродро┐ роОроирпНрод роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роЙрогрпНрогро╛ро╡ро┐ро░родрокрпН рокрпЛро░ро╛роЯрпНроЯ роорпБро▒рпИропрпИрокрпН рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ройро╛ро░рпН?","answer":": 1918 роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ"},{"question":"\\"р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║\\" р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╖Щ р╢нр╖Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢╕ р╢╕р╖Ьр╢Ър╢Ър╖Кр╢п ? р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Ьр╢╕ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢п р╢Тр╢Ъ р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Ьр╢╕ р╖Др╖Рр╢пр╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Ср╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╢п?р╢Е+р╖Гр╖Др╢║ р╢п?р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢║ р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Ьр╢╕р╢п?","answer":"р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢н р╢нр╢нр╖Кр╖Гр╢╕ р╢┤р╢пр╢║р╢Ър╖Т.рдЕрд╕рд╣рд╛рдпр╢нр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢╕ р╖Ар╖Рр╢й р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒, р╢Лр╢пр╖Ар╖Кр╖Ар╢з р╢Ър╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╖Ар╢Ър╖Ф р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢║р╢▒ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢║р╖Т.р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║ р╢Ьр╖Пр╢║р╢Ър╢║р╖П, р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║ р╢▒р╖Пр╢║р╢Ър╢║р╖П, р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╢нр╖Рр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╢╜ р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖П р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ър╢п, р╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢║р╢▒ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Фр╢нр╢╕р╢║р╖Т.р╢Ър╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢Ър╖Фр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Тр╖А р╢нр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╖Бр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Щр╢Ър╖Ф р╖Др╖Э р╢Ср╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Ър╢╗р╢Ьр╢нр╖К р╢нр╖Рр╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Щр╢Ър╖Ф р╖Др╖Э р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║ р╢┤р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢Ьр╢╜р╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖Ф р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Др╖Рр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ъ.р╢Т р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╢║р╖Т, р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║ р╢Ьр╖Пр╢║р╢Ър╢║р╖П, р╢Ер╖Гр╖Др╖Пр╢║ р╢╢р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░р╖Тр╢╕р╢нр╖П р╢Жр╢пр╖У р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ.р╢Ср╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╖Кр╢╜р╢╖ р╖Др╖Щр╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К, р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╢п р╖Др╖Рр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Т."},{"question":"Kas yra klausimas: \\"┼╜moni┼│ matuoklis yra auditorijos matavimo ─пrankis, naudojamas TV ir kabelin─Чs televizijos ┼╛i┼лrov┼│ ┼╛i┼лr─Чjimo ─пpro─Нiams matuoti.\\" Tema yra \\"┼╜moni┼│ matuoklis\\".","answer":"\\"Kur naudojamas ┼╛moni┼│ matuoklis?\\""},{"question":"роЯро╛роХрпНроЯро░рпН ро╡роирпНродро╛ро░рпБ, роКроЪро┐ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро╛ро░рпБ, роХро╛роЪрпБ ро╡ро╛роЩрпНроХро╛рооро▓рпН рокрпЛройро╛ро░рпБ.роЕродрпБ роОройрпНрой ?","answer":"роХрпКроЪрпБ. роорпЖро▓рпНро▓ро┐роп роЙроЯро▓рпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роХрпКроЪрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН роУро░рпН роЗрогрпИ роЗро▒роХрпНроХрпИроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ роЗрогрпИ роирпАрогрпНроЯ роХро╛ро▓рпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрой. рокрпКродрпБро╡ро╛роХ роЖрогрпН роХрпКроЪрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН родро╛ро╡ро░роЪрпН роЪро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпИрокрпН рокро░рпБроХрпБроорпН. рокрпЖрогрпН роХрпКроЪрпБроХрпНроХро│рпЗ рооройро┐родро░рпНроХро│ро┐роЯрооро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБроорпН рокро┐ро▒ роЙропро┐ро░ро┐ройроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБроорпН роЗро░родрпНродродрпНродрпИ роЙро▒ро┐роЮрпНроЪрпБроорпН роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпБроорпН рокрпЖрогрпН роХрпКроЪрпБроХрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроХрпНроХрпВроЯ роЗро░родрпНродроорпН роорпБродройрпНроорпИропро╛рой роЙрогро╡ро▓рпНро▓."},{"question":"роЗроирпНродро┐роп родрпЗроЪро┐роп роХро╛роЩрпНроХро┐ро░ро╕рпН роОроирпНрод ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпЗроЪрпИ рооро╛роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН рокроЩрпНроХрпЗро▒рпНро▒родрпБ?","answer":"1931 роЗро▓рпН роЗро░рогрпНроЯро╛ро╡родрпБ ро╡роЯрпНроЯ роорпЗроЪрпИ рооро╛роиро╛роЯрпБ"},{"question":"Idibo wс╗Нс╗Нdu lтАШс╗Мс╣гun: Awс╗Нn с╗Нdс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu APC fс║╣honu han, wс╗Нn ni Oyetс╗Нla ko le yan le awс╗Нn lori","answer":"с╣вe lawс╗Нn с╗Нdс╗Н kan ninu с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu APC, nipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun, fс╗Нn soju titi nirс╗Нlс║╣ с╗Нjс╗Н с║╕ti, Furaidee, с╗Нgbс╗Нnjс╗Н, oс╣гu keje yii, lati fс║╣honu han si ohun ti wс╗Нn pe ni с╗Нgbс╗Нn alumс╗Нkс╗Нrс╗Нyin ti Gomina Oyetс╗Нla ati alaga с║╣gbс║╣ naa, с╗Мmс╗Нс╗Нba Gboyega Famс╗Нdun, n lo lati ma с╣гe jс║╣ ki eto idibo wс╗Нс╗Нdu waye lс╗Нla.Lati bii oс╣гu kan ni igbimс╗Н afun-n-с╣гс╗Н apapс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ naa lorileede yii ti kede с╗Нjс╗Н Abamс║╣ta,       Satide, с╗Нjс╗Н kс╗Нkanlelс╗Нgbс╗Нn, oс╣гu keje, gс║╣gс║╣ bii с╗Нjс╗Н ti idibo wс╗Нс╗Нdu yoo waye, latigba naa ni awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn jс║╣ тАШThe Osun ProgressivesтАЩ ti n fс║╣sun kan awс╗Нn Ileri Oluwa pe с╣гe ni wс╗Нn fс║╣с║╣ yan le gbogbo с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н.Lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja ni awс╗Нn TOP kegbajare si awс╗Нn alakooso с║╣gbс║╣ lorileede yii pe Gomina Oyetс╗Нla ko gbogbo fс╗Нс╗Нmu ti wс╗Нn ko ranс╣гс║╣ lati Abuja sabс║╣, ti wс╗Нn ko si jс║╣ ki awс╗Нn miiran lanfaani si fс╗Нс╗Нmu с╗Нhun ju awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn n pe ara wс╗Нn ni Ileri Oluwa lс╗Н.Nigba ti с╗Нrс╗Н ti di bayii lawс╗Нn naa mori le Abuja lati gba fс╗Нс╗Нmu wс╗Нn, eleyii ti wс╗Нn ni o fa a ti gomina tun fi ko awс╗Нn ti Abuja ran wa lati с╣гakoso idibo с╗Нjс╗Н с║╕ti naa pamс╗Н, ti wс╗Нn ko si jс║╣ ki wс╗Нn lс╗Н si sс║╣kiteriati с║╣gbс║╣ to wa ni Ogo-Oluwa, lтАЩOс╣гogbo.Gс║╣gс║╣ bi с╗Нkan lara awс╗Нn olufс║╣honu han naa, Rasheed Raji, с╣гe wi, тАЬIwa to le tu с║╣gbс║╣ ni Gomina Oyetс╗Нla ati с╗Мmс╗Нс╗Нba Famс╗Нdun n hu lс╗Нwс╗Нlс╗Нwс╗Н bayii, inu otс║╣с║╣li ni wс╗Нn ko awс╗Нn ti с║╣gbс║╣ ran wa lati ta fс╗Нс╗Нmu fun wa si, wс╗Нn ko jс║╣ ka lanfaani si fс╗Нс╗Нmu bo tilс║╣ jс║╣ pe ogunlс╗Нgс╗Н awс╗Нn eeyan wa ni wс╗Нn ti sanwo fс╗Нс╗Нmu tipс║╣.тАЬA ko mс╗Н idi ti idibo fi n ba wс╗Нn lс║╣ru, a sс╗Н fun wс╗Нn pe ki wс╗Нn jс║╣ ka dibo yan awс╗Нn to ba wu wa, awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn yoo с╣гeto idibo lс╗Нla tun ti de, wс╗Нn tun ti ti wс╗Нn mс╗Н inu ile-ijс╗Нba dipo sс║╣kiteriaati to yс║╣ ki wс╗Нn wa.тАЬA n fi asiko yii ke si igbimс╗Н ti Mai Mala Buni n dari lati da si wahala to n с╣гс║╣lс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н bayii nipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun ko too с╣гe akoba to pс╗Н fun с║╣gbс║╣ wa.тАЭBakan naa ni Arabinrin с╗Мpс║╣yс║╣mi Awotipс║╣ bu с║╣nu atс║╣ lu iwa ko sс║╣ni ti yoo mu mi ti alaga с║╣gbс║╣ naa lтАЩс╗Мс╣гun, с╗Мmс╗Нс╗Нba Famс╗Нdun n hu. O ni с║╣gbс║╣ alaafia ni wс╗Нn mс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu APC si tс║╣lс║╣, с╣гugbс╗Нn iwa ti alaga naa n hu bayii n kс╗Н awс╗Нn lominu.O с╣гalaye pe wс╗Нn ti pinnu lati maa na с║╣nikс║╣ni to ba bс╗Н sipo lati dibo lс╗Нla nitori с╣гe ni wс╗Нn fс║╣с║╣ maa buwс╗Н lu orukс╗Н awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn ri bii oloootс╗Н si wс╗Нn, ti wс╗Нn yoo maa lo lati dari с║╣gbс║╣ bo с╣гe wu wс╗Нn.Adetipс║╣ waa ke si awс╗Нn alakooso с║╣gbс║╣ lati ke si awс╗Нn to n da wahala silс║╣ ninu с║╣gbс║╣ naa lтАЩс╗Мс╣гun pe ki wс╗Нn ki с╗Нwс╗Н с╗Нmс╗Н wс╗Нn bс╗НтАЩс╣гс╗Н, ki awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ alaabo si с╣гiс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn lс╗Нna to ba ofin orileede yii mu."},{"question":"Unsa ang hinagiban nga gipili ni David sa pagpildi kang Goliath","answer":"Usa ka bato ug usa ka lambuyog"},{"question":"┘Е┘Ж ┘З┘Е ╪з┘Д╪л┘Д╪з╪л╪й ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н╪з╪и┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪░┘К┘Ж ╪к╪┤╪к╪з┘В ╪е┘Д┘К┘З┘Е ╪з┘Д╪м┘Ж╪й╪Я .","answer":"╪з┘Д╪м┘И╪з╪и ╪╣┘Д┘К ╪и┘Ж ╪г╪и┘К ╪╖╪з┘Д╪и╪М ╪│┘Д┘Е╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Б╪з╪▒╪│┘К╪М ╪╣┘Е╪з╪▒ ╪и┘Ж ┘К╪з╪│╪▒"},{"question":"Njengoba senizizwele osopolitiki bekhuluma nani, naphinde nezwanoDuma exolisa ngokushayisa kwakhe, manje-ke ngizonifundelaumbiko wenkosi. (alungise ipheshana aliphethe maqede aqaleafunde) Ithi inkosi yesizwe sakithi, 'Ngibingelela isikhulusikaHulumeni, osopolitiki bezinhlangano zabantu kanye nesizwesonke. Sizwe sami engisithandayo, okwenzekile kufana nentoesingeke sisakwazi ukuyiguqula. Asebefile ngeke sibavuse kodwangethemba ukuthi sifunde lukhulu kukho konke osekwenzekile.Ngabe angiyazi into engiyiphilelayo uma ngingababongi laba bantubesifazane ababili umkami uMaNgema, kanye noMaShezi,umkaDuma. Bobabili babambe iqhaza elibaluleke kakhulu ekucishenilo mlilo. Ngempela baqinisile abathi, abantu besimame bayimbokodo.Kusukela manje ikhansela lizoqhubeka nohlelo lokuletha intuthukoesizweni sami. Nalo liqaphele ukuthi lisebenzisana nabantu abanjani.Mina-ke ngizolisiza ikhansela. Njengoba alikabi nayo indluyokusebenzela, mina nginikela ngendlu elaphaya emzini wami. Leyondlu iseduze kwesango. Yiyo-ke ezoba yigunjana azohlelela kulokonke okuqondene nemisebenzi yakhe. Ngizovala ngokubongaamaphoyisa asebenze ngokuzikhandla ukubhula lo mlilo. Yiminainkosi yenu, uShandu.'1. Ukuba wena wawunguMbandlwa yiziphi izeluleko ezakhayoowawungazinikeza uDuma? Bhala amaphuzu AMABILI.","answer":"Amaphuzu AMABILI kwalandelayo:Ngangingamtshela ukuthi:тАв Emhlabeni kuyahlonishwana, kuyaboniswana.тАв Akafunde ukulalela.тАв Akafunde ukusebenzisana nabo bonke abaholi emphakathini.тАв Akukuhle ukubamba igqubu, kuhle ukuxola uqhubeke nempilo."},{"question":"р╢╢р╖Фр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╢пр╖Пр╖Е р╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢║ р╢нр╖Фр╖Е р╖Ар╖Рр╢│р╢╜р╖П р╢Йр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Ц р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ър╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢н.р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Пр╢║р╖Эр╢Ьр╖Тр╢Ър╖А р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕ р╢нр╖Фр╖Е р╢┤р╢╕р╢лр╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖Тр╢╡р╢╜ р╢Зр╢н. р╢╕р╖Щр╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢Ър╖Пр╖Бр╢║ р╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Фр╢Ър╖Цр╢╜р╢п?","answer":"р╢Фр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢╕ р╢Ср╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢╕ р╖Др╖Тр╢н р╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢пр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢╜р╖Пр╢╖р╢║р╢Ър╖Кр╢╕р╢║р╖Тр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╢▒р╖Пр╖А р╢┤р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Т р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Др╖Тр╢н р╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢╕р╖Тр╖Г р╢Йр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒, р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢▒р╖П р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢▒р╖Щр╖Ар╖Щр╢║р╖Тр╢Ер╢▒р╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢Ср╢Ъ р╢Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╗р╢лр╖Пр╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ыр╖Ър╢нр╢║р╢Ър╖Кр╢Т р╖Ар╢Ьр╖Ър╢╕р╢║р╖Т р╖Гр╢вр╖Кр╢вр╖Пр╢║р╢▒р╖Пр╖А. р╖Др╖Рр╢╢р╖Рр╢║р╖Т р╢╕р╖Ър╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║ р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒ р╢║р╢╕р╖К р╢Ер╖Ар╢╢р╖Эр╢░р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢╕ р╢Хр╢▒р╖Ар╖Тр╢┤р╖Гр╖Кр╖Гр╢▒р╖Пр╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╢▒р╖Пр╖А р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢Ър╖Щр╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Щр╖Др╖Щр╖Г р╢Ер╢йр╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Фр╢║ р╢пр╖Щр╢Ър╢╕ р╢Йр╢нр╖П р╖Ар╢зр╖Тр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢Фр╢║ р╢Ер╢вр╖Пр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Др╢╕р╖К, р╢Ер╢вр╖Пр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Фр╢╕р╖Ър╢░р╖Э р╖Ар╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢║р╢нр╖Тр╖Ар╢╗ р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╢╕р╖Ур╢лр╖Кр╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Щр╢╜р╖П р╢┤р╖Ар╖П р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╢▒р╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Д р╖Гр╢вр╖Кр╢вр╖Пр╢║р╢▒р╖Пр╖А р╢нр╖Ар╢╕ р╢Ър╢╗р╢╜р╖П р╢Жр╢пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢║ р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Ар╖П р╢╢р╢зр╖Др╖Тр╢╗ р╢Ер╢║р╢з р╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╢нр╖К (р╢Ср╢║р╖Пр╢╜р╖П р╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╢▒р╖Пр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Ар╢╜р╢з р╖Др╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Ер╢║ р╢▒р╖Щр╖Ар╖Щр╢║р╖Т р╢▒р╖Ъ)р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║р╖Эр╢вр╢▒р╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢╜р╖П р╢║р╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢╜р╖П р╢╢р╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Ър╖Тр╖Ар╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╢╕ р╢Хр╢▒ р╢Ър╖Щр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Ар╖П."},{"question":"р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖Тр╢╖р╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п ?","answer":"р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖Тр╢╖р╖Пр╢▒р╢║ (Intuition) р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Ар╖Тр╢ер╖Пр╢▒р╢Ъ р╢нр╢╗р╖Кр╢Ър╢▒р╢║ р╖Др╖Э р╢┤р╖Рр╖Др╖Рр╢пр╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢нр╖Ьр╢╗р╖А р╢║р╢╕р╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╖П р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢лр╢║р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ар╖Ър╖Б р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ер╢пр╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖Ур╢║ р╖Гр╖Др╢в р╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╢║р╖Т.р╢╕р╖Щр╢║ р╢Ер╖Ар╖Тр╢ер╖Пр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Фр╢╕р╢з р╖Гр╖Шр╢вр╖Ф р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ар╖Ър╖Бр╢║ ,р╢Ер╖Ар╖Тр╢ер╖Пр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢Вр╢вр╖Пр╢▒р╢▒р╢║, р╢Ер╢╖р╖КтАНр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Ар╖Ър╢пр╢▒р╖П ,р╢Ер╖Ар╖Тр╢ер╖Пр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢╗р╢зр╖Пр╖А-р╖Др╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ер╢╖р╖КтАНр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╢Ер╖Ар╢╢р╖Эр╢░р╢║ р╢Жр╢пр╖У р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢░ р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Ър╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗ р╖Ар╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Ъ .р╢Ър╖Щр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Щр╢нр╢нр╖К р╢Жр╢Ьр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Йр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╢нр╖Фр╢╜ р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╢Лр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╢╕р╢▒р╖Фр╖Вр╖КтАНр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖П р╢Ср╢╕р╢зр╢║ ."},{"question":"Python р╖Др╖Т р╢Ер╢Вр╢Ър╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢ор╢╕р╢Ъ р╢пр╖Рр╢║р╖Т р╢┤р╢╗р╖Ур╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖П р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Щр╖Гр╖Ър╢п?","answer":"def is_prime(num):    if num <= 1:        return False    for i in range(2, int(num0.5) + 1):        if num % i == 0:            return False    return Trueprint(is_prime(7))  # Outputs: True"},{"question":"╪з┘Г╪к╪и ┘Е┘В╪з┘Д╪й ╪к╪╡┘Б ╪з┘Д╪о╪и╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К: ╪з┘Д┘К┘Е┘Ж: ┘Е┘В╪к┘Д 3 ┘Б┘К ┘В╪╡┘Б ╪н┘И╪л┘К ┘Д┘Е╪п╪▒╪│╪й ┘Б┘К ╪п┘Е╪з╪м","answer":"┘К┘Е┘Ж┘К┘И┘Ж ┘Е┘Ж ╪п┘Е╪з╪м ┘К╪н╪к╪м┘И┘Ж ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘З╪м┘Е╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪н┘И╪л┘К╪й ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪и┘Д╪п╪к┘З┘Е╪М ┘И┘К╪│┘К╪╖╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪н┘И╪л┘К┘И┘Ж ╪╣┘Д┘Й ┘Е╪╣╪╕┘Е ┘Е╪н╪з┘Б╪╕╪й ╪╡╪╣╪п╪й ╪з┘Д╪┤┘Е╪з┘Д┘К╪й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪н╪з╪░┘К╪й ┘Д┘Д╪н╪п┘И╪п ┘Е╪╣ ╪з┘Д╪│╪╣┘И╪п┘К╪й╪М ┘И┘К╪│╪к╪о╪п┘Е┘И┘Ж┘З╪з ┘Е╪╣┘В┘Д╪з ┘Д┘З┘Е ┘Б┘К ╪╡╪▒╪з╪╣┘З┘Е ┘Е╪╣ ╪з┘Д╪н┘Г┘И┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д┘К┘Е┘Ж┘К╪й. ┘И┘К╪│╪з┘З┘Е ╪з┘Д╪╡╪▒╪з╪╣ ╪з┘Д╪╖╪з╪ж┘Б┘К ┘Б┘К ╪п┘Е╪з╪м ┘Б┘К ╪╣╪▒┘В┘Д╪й ╪м┘З┘И╪п ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╡╪з┘Д╪н╪й ╪и┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪н┘И╪л┘К┘К┘Ж ┘И╪з┘Д╪н┘Г┘И┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪▒┘Г╪▓┘К╪й ┘Б┘К ╪╡┘Ж╪╣╪з╪б. ┘И┘Г╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘В╪к╪з┘Д ╪и┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪н┘И╪л┘К┘К┘Ж ┘И╪з┘Д╪│┘Д┘Б┘К┘К┘Ж ┘В╪п ╪к╪╡╪з╪╣╪п ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪┤┘З╪▒ ╪з┘Д┘Е╪з╪╢┘К ╪и╪╣╪п ╪з┘Ж ╪з╪к┘З┘Е ╪з┘Д╪н┘И╪л┘К┘И┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д┘Б┘К┘К┘Ж ╪и╪к╪м┘Ж┘К╪п ╪з┘Д╪в┘Д╪з┘Б ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Е┘В╪з╪к┘Д┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪з╪м╪з┘Ж╪и ╪з╪│╪к╪╣╪п╪з╪п╪з ┘Д┘Е┘З╪з╪м┘Е╪к┘З┘Е. ┘И┘В╪к┘Д ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╣╪з╪▒┘Г ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪к┘Д╪к ╪░┘Д┘Г ╪з┘Г╪л╪▒ ┘Е┘Ж 100 ╪┤╪о╪╡ ┘Б┘К ╪╡┘Б┘И┘Б ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д┘Б┘К┘К┘Ж╪М ┘И┘Д┘Е ┘К╪╣┘Д┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪н┘И╪л┘К┘И┘Ж ╪╣┘Ж ╪о╪│╪з╪ж╪▒┘З┘Е."},{"question":"Cad is br├н le bogearra├н saora? ","answer":"Is ├йard at├б i gceist le bogearra├н saora n├б c├│d foinseach a bheith ar f├бil go r├йidh don ├║s├бideoir agus ├й a bheith saor le hathruithe a dh├йanamh don ch├│d is a roinnt le daoine eile gan coinn├нollacha cead├║nais a rialacha. N├н cheist airgid at├б ├б phl├й leis an gcur s├нos seo, n├н g├б na bogearra├н a bheith saor in aisce. Mar a deir Richard Stallman, bunaitheoir an Free Software Foundation, ├й тАЬsaoirse cainteтАЭ at├б i gceist, seachas тАЬbeoir saor in aisceтАЭ."},{"question":"Sheeg sanadkii uu dhashay General Maxamed Faarax Ceydiid?","answer":"General Maxamed Faarax Ceydiid wuxu dhashay sanadkii 1934-kii, isla sanadkaan waxaa dhashay Cabdullaahi Yuusuf Axmed."},{"question":"Jox ma p├йeteg waat yi ci k├аddu gii: Am tiit daldi ko roofu.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci k├аddu gii di \\"Am tiit daldi ko roofu.\\" ak s├йen i p├йete ├▒oo di:Am: DETtiit: NOUNdaldi: ADVko: PRONroofu: VERB.: PUNCT"},{"question":"сЙасКасКХсЛ╡ сИКсЙ╡сИн сЛисЙ░сИИсИШсЛ░сЛН сЛисЙгсИЕсИн сЛНсИГ сЛНсИ╡сМе сИ╡сКХсЙ╡ сМНсИлсИЭ сМисЛН (сИ╢сЛ▓сЛисИЭ сКнсИОсИлсЛнсЛ╡) сКасИИ?","answer":"сИЭсКХсИЭ"},{"question":"\\"рдХреНрд╡рд╛рдиреНрдЯрдо рдореЗрд╕рд┐рди рд▓рд░реНрдирд┐рдЩ\\" рд░ рдЬрдЯрд┐рд▓ рдЧрдгрдирд╛рд▓рд╛рдИ рдЧрддрд┐ рджрд┐рдиреЗ рдпрд╕рдХреЛ рд╕рдореНрднрд╛рд╡рдирд╛рдХреЛ рд╡реНрдпрд╛рдЦреНрдпрд╛ рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реНред","answer":"рдХреНрд╡рд╛рдиреНрдЯрдо рдореЗрд╕рд┐рди рд▓рд░реНрдирд┐рдЩрд▓реЗ рдХреНрд╡рд╛рдиреНрдЯрдо рдХрдореНрдкреНрдпреБрдЯрд┐рдЩ рд░ рдореЗрд╕рд┐рди рд▓рд░реНрдирд┐рдЩ рдкреНрд░рд╡рд┐рдзрд┐рд╣рд░реВрд▓рд╛рдИ рд╢рд╛рд╕реНрддреНрд░реАрдп рдХрдореНрдкреНрдпреБрдЯрд░рд╣рд░реВ рднрдиреНрджрд╛ рдЫрд┐рдЯреЛ рдЬрдЯрд┐рд▓ рд╕рдорд╕реНрдпрд╛рд╣рд░реВ рд╕рдорд╛рдзрд╛рди рдЧрд░реНрдирдХрд╛ рд▓рд╛рдЧрд┐ рдЕрдиреБрдХреВрд▓рди рд░ рдбреЗрдЯрд╛ рд╡рд┐рд╢реНрд▓реЗрд╖рдгрдХрд╛ рдЕрдиреБрдкреНрд░рдпреЛрдЧрд╣рд░реВ рд╕рдВрдпреЛрдЬрди рдЧрд░реНрджрдЫред"},{"question":"╪в█М╪з ┘Е█МтАМ╪к┘И╪з┘Ж ╪з╪▓ ┌й┘И┌й┘И┘╛█М╪к ╪и┘З ╪╣┘Ж┘И╪з┘Ж ╪и╪│╪к╪▒█М ╪и╪▒╪з█М ┘╛╪▒┘И╪▒╪┤ ╪н┘Д╪▓┘И┘Ж ╪з╪│╪к┘Б╪з╪п┘З ┌й╪▒╪п╪Я","answer":"╪и┘Д┘З╪М ┌й┘И┌й┘И┘╛█М╪к ┘Е█М ╪к┘И╪з┘Ж╪п ╪и┘З ╪╣┘Ж┘И╪з┘Ж ╪и╪│╪к╪▒█М ╪и╪▒╪з█М ┘╛╪▒┘И╪▒╪┤ ╪н┘Д╪▓┘И┘Ж ╪з╪│╪к┘Б╪з╪п┘З ╪┤┘И╪п. ╪н┘Д╪▓┘И┘ЖтАМ┘З╪з ╪и┘З ╪и╪│╪к╪▒ ┘Е┘Ж╪з╪│╪и█М ┘Ж█М╪з╪▓ ╪п╪з╪▒┘Ж╪п ┌й┘З ╪▒╪╖┘И╪и╪к ╪▒╪з ╪н┘Б╪╕ ┌й┘Ж╪п ┘И ┘Е╪н█М╪╖█М ╪▒╪з╪н╪к ╪п╪з╪┤╪к┘З ╪и╪з╪┤╪п. ┌й┘И┌й┘И┘╛█М╪к ╪╕╪▒┘Б█М╪к ┘Ж┌п┘З╪п╪з╪▒█М ╪в╪и ╪о┘И╪и█М ╪п╪з╪▒╪п ┘И ┘Е╪н█М╪╖█М ┘╛╪з█М╪п╪з╪▒ ┘И ╪║┘Ж█М ╪з╪▓ ╪▒╪╖┘И╪и╪к ╪▒╪з ┘Б╪▒╪з┘З┘Е ┘Е█МтАМ┌й┘Ж╪п ┌й┘З ┘Е█М ╪к┘И╪з┘Ж╪п ╪и╪▒╪з█М ╪│┘Д╪з┘Е╪к ┘И ╪▒╪┤╪п ╪н┘Д╪▓┘И┘Ж ┘Е┘Б█М╪п ╪и╪з╪┤╪п."},{"question":"╪г╪╣╪╖┘Ж┘К ┘Е╪л╪з┘Д╪з┘Л ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╣┘Д┘И┘Е╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪╣╪з┘Е╪й ┘Б┘К ┘З╪░┘З ╪з┘Д┘Б╪ж╪й: ╪з┘Д╪г┘Б┘Д╪з┘Е","answer":"┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ╪г╪╖┘И┘Д ┘Б┘К┘Д┘Е ╪н╪з╪ж╪▓ ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪м╪з╪ж╪▓╪й ╪з┘Д╪г┘И╪│┘Г╪з╪▒╪Я War and Peace"},{"question":"Odpowiedz na nast─Щpuj─Еce pytanie: w jakim kraju uprawia si─Щ najwi─Щcej kawy na ┼Ыwiecie?","answer":"W Brazylii."},{"question":"риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риХри░риХрйЗ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐ри╕риери╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ ри╣рйЗриари╛риВ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗ рижри╛ риХрйА риЕри░рие ри╣рйИред\\"риЖри╕ри╛ риори╣ри▓ри╛ рйй реери╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░ ри╡ри┐риЪри┐ ри╡рибрйА ри╡рибри┐риЖриИ реериЪри┐ри░рйА ри╡ри┐риЫрйБрй░риирйЗ риорйЗри▓ри┐ риори┐ри▓ри╛риИ реериЖрикрйЗ риорйЗри▓рйЗ риорйЗри▓ри┐ риори┐ри▓ри╛риП реериЖрикригрйА риХрйАриоридри┐ риЖрикрйЗ рикри╛риП реерйзреери╣ри░ри┐ риХрйА риХрйАриоридри┐ риХри┐рии римри┐ризри┐ ри╣рйЛриЗ реери╣ри░ри┐ риЕрикри░рй░рикри░рйБ риЕриЧрио риЕриЧрйЛриЪри░рйБ риЧрйБри░ риХрйИ ри╕римрижри┐ риори┐ри▓рйИ риЬриирйБ риХрйЛриЗ реерйзрее ри░ри╣ри╛риЙ реериЧрйБри░риорйБриЦри┐ риХрйАриоридри┐ риЬри╛ригрйИ риХрйЛриЗ реери╡ри┐ри░ри▓рйЗ риХри░риори┐ рикри░ри╛рикридри┐ ри╣рйЛриЗ реериКриЪрйА римри╛ригрйА риКриЪри╛ ри╣рйЛриЗ реериЧрйБри░риорйБриЦри┐ ри╕римрижри┐ ри╡риЦри╛ригрйИ риХрйЛриЗ реерйиреери╡ри┐ригрйБ риири╛ри╡рйИ рижрйБриЦрйБ рижри░рижрйБ ри╕ри░рйАри░ри┐ реери╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░рйБ ринрйЗриЯрйЗ ридри╛ риЙридри░рйИ рикрйАри░ рееримри┐риирйБ риЧрйБри░ ринрйЗриЯрйЗ рижрйБриЦрйБ риХриори╛риЗ реериориириорйБриЦри┐ римри╣рйБридрйА риори┐ри▓рйИ ри╕риЬри╛риЗ реерййреери╣ри░ри┐ риХри╛ риири╛риорйБ риорйАриари╛ риЕридри┐ ри░ри╕рйБ ри╣рйЛриЗ реерикрйАри╡рид ри░ри╣рйИ рикрйАриЖриП ри╕рйЛриЗ реериЧрйБри░ риХри┐ри░рикри╛ ридрйЗ ри╣ри░ри┐ ри░ри╕рйБ рикри╛риП реериири╛риириХ риири╛риори┐ ри░ридрйЗ риЧридри┐ рикри╛риП реерйкреерййреерйкрйирее\\"","answer":"риЗри╣ ри╕рйНри░рйА риЧрйБри░рйВ риЧрйНри░рй░рие ри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐рим риЬрйА рижрйЗ рикрй░риири╛ 361 ридрйЛриВ ри▓ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риЧрйБри░рйВ риЕриори░рижри╛ри╕ риЬрйА риЗриирйНри╣ри╛риВ ри╡ри╛ри░ри╛риВ рижрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЦри╛ри░рйА ри╕рииредриЗри╕ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйЗриа ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ риЕриирйБри╕ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЦри┐риЖрии риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ,\\"(ри╣рйЗ ринри╛риИ!) ри╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░рйВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЗри╣ ри╡рй▒рибри╛ ринри╛ри░ри╛ риЧрйБриг ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЙри╣ риЕриирйЗриХри╛риВ риЬриириори╛риВ рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЫрйБрйЬрйЗ ри╣рйЛриП риЬрйАри╡ри╛риВ риирйВрй░ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйЗ риЪри░риири╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬрйЛрйЬ рижрйЗриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред  рикрйНри░ринрйВ риЖрик ри╣рйА (риЧрйБри░рйВ) риори┐ри▓ри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ, риЧрйБри░рйВ риори┐ри▓ри╛ риХрйЗ риЖрикригрйЗ риЪри░риири╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬрйЛрйЬрижри╛ ри╣рйИридрйЗ (риЗри╕ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риЬрйАри╡ри╛риВ рижрйЗ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ) риЖрикригрйЗ риири╛рио рижрйА риХрижри░ риЖрик ри╣рйА рикрйИрижри╛ риХри░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйзред(ри╣рйЗ ринри╛риИ!) риХри┐ри╕ ридри░рйАриХрйЗ риири╛ри▓ (риориирйБрй▒риЦ рижрйЗ риории ри╡ри┐риЪ) рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ (рижрйЗ риири╛рио) рижрйА риХрижри░ рикрйИрижри╛ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗ? рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рикри░рйЗ ридрйЛриВ рикри░рйЗ ри╣рйИ, рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ риЕрикри╣рй░рйБриЪ ри╣рйИ, рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ ридриХ риЧри┐риЖрии-риЗрй░рижрйНри░ри┐риЖриВ рижрйА ри░ри╛ри╣рйАриВ рикри╣рй░рйБриЪ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйЛ ри╕риХрижрйА ред (римрй▒ри╕!) риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйЗ ри╢римриж рижрйА ри░ри╛ри╣рйАриВ (ри╣рйА) риХрйЛриИ ри╡ри┐ри░ри▓ри╛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ рикрйНри░ринрйВ риирйВрй░ риори┐ри▓рижри╛ ри╣рйИ (ридрйЗ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ риЕрй░рижри░ рикрйНри░ринрйВ рижрйЗ риири╛рио рижрйА риХрижри░ рикрйИрижри╛ ри╣рй░рйБрижрйА ри╣рйИ) редрйзредри░ри╣ри╛риЙредриХрйЛриИ ри╡ри┐ри░ри▓ри╛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйА ри╕ри░рии рикрйИ риХрйЗ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйЗ риири╛рио рижрйА риХрижри░ ри╕риориЭрижри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ри╕рйЗ ри╡ри┐ри░ри▓рйЗ риирйВрй░ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйА риорйЗри╣ри░ риири╛ри▓ (рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижри╛ риири╛рио) риори┐ри▓рижри╛ ри╣рйИ редри╕рин ридрйЛриВ риЙрй▒риЪрйЗ рикрйНри░ринрйВ рижрйА ри╕ри┐рйЮридри┐-ри╕ри╛ри▓ри╛ри╣ рижрйА римри╛ригрйА рижрйА римри░риХридри┐ риири╛ри▓ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риЙрй▒риЪрйЗ риЬрйАри╡рии ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ римриг риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред риХрйЛриИ (ри╡ри┐ри░ри▓ри╛ ринри╛риЧри╛риВ ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ) риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйА ри╕ри░рии рикрйИ риХрйЗ риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйЗ ри╢римриж рижрйА ри░ри╛ри╣рйАриВ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижри╛ риири╛рио ри╕ри┐риори░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйиредрикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижри╛ риири╛рио ри╕ри┐риори░рии ридрйЛриВ римри┐риири╛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ рижрйЗ ри╕ри░рйАри░ ри╡ри┐риЪ (ри╡ри┐риХри╛ри░ри╛риВ рижри╛) рижрйБрй▒риЦ ри░рйЛриЧ рикрйИрижри╛ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ,  риЬрижрйЛриВ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риирйВрй░ риЧрйБри░рйВ риори┐ри▓рижри╛ ри╣рйИ, ридрижрйЛриВ риЙри╕ рижри╛ риЗри╣ рижрйБрй▒риЦ рижрйВри░ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редриЧрйБри░рйВ риирйВрй░ риори┐ри▓риг ридрйЛриВ римри┐риири╛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риЙри╣рйА риХри░рио риХриори╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ риЬрйЛ рижрйБрй▒риЦ рикрйИрижри╛ риХри░рии, (риЗри╕ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ) риЖрикригрйЗ риории рижрйЗ рикри┐риЫрйЗ ридрйБри░рии ри╡ри╛ри▓рйЗ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риирйВрй░ ри╕рижри╛ римри╣рйБрид ри╕рйЫри╛ риори┐ри▓рижрйА ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижрйА ри╣рйИ редрййред(ри╣рйЗ ринри╛риИ!) рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижри╛ риири╛рио (риЗриХ риРри╕ри╛ риЕрй░риорйНри░ри┐рид ри╣рйИ риЬрйЛ) риори┐рй▒риари╛ ри╣рйИ, римрйЬрйЗ ри░ри╕ ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ ри╣рйИ редрикри░ риЙри╣рйА риориирйБрй▒риЦ риЗри╣ риири╛рио-ри░ри╕ рикрйАриВрижри╛ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ, риЬри┐ри╕ риирйВрй░ риЙри╣ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ риЖрик рикри┐ри▓ри╛риП ред риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйА риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риири╛ри▓ ри╣рйА риориирйБрй▒риЦ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйЗ риири╛рио-риЬри▓ рижри╛ риЖриирй░риж риори╛ригрижри╛ ри╣рйИ, ри╣рйЗ риири╛риириХ! риири╛рио-ри░рй░риЧри┐ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░рй░риЧрйАриЬ риХрйЗ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риЙрй▒риЪрйА риЖридриориХ риЕри╡ри╕риери╛ ри╣ри╛ри╕ри▓ риХри░ ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйкредрййредрйкрйиред\\""},{"question":"Mene ne Wasan Kwaikwayo?","answer":"Kamar yadda sunan ya nuna; Wasan Kwaikwayo wasa ne da ake kwaikwayar wani abu wanda ka iya zama hali, ko wani aiki da wani mutum, jamaтАЩa, ko wata alтАЩumma ke yi. Masana da dama sun yi rubutu a wannan fage na wasan kwaikwayo.Yahaya I.Y., Zariya M.S., Gusau S.M., da тАШYarтАЩaduwa T.M (1992), sun fassara shi da cewa, тАЬWasan kwaikwayo kamance ne na halaye ko yanayin rayuwa da mutane masu hikima su ke shirya gudanar da shi don jamaтАЩa su gani da idonsu, su samu nisha╔Чi da jin da╔ЧiтАЭ.Wato shi wasan kwaikwayo wasa ne da ake shirya shi ta hanyar kwaikwayar yadda wasu jamaтАЩa ke yin wani abu, ko dai da nufin shi wasan ya zama hanyar garga╔Чar mutane dangane da wani abu da zai cutar da su, ko kuma ya nisha╔Чantar da su, ko kuma ya ilimantar da su game da wani abu. Misali, idan muka ╔Чauki littafin wasan marafa na Abubakar Tunau, za mu ga cewa yana karantar da tsafta ne; wanda a ciki aka bayyana muhimmancin tsafta da kuma hatsarin rashin tsafta."},{"question":"Ngelinye ilanga ubaba wagqoka ihembe lakhe lishwabene ngobaengenakulilungiselwa noma engenakunikwa insimbi alilungise. Kwala noma ethi ucelaindodana yakhe ukuba imcelele umakoti amlungiselele, wathi usejahe emsebenziniyena. Uma ephumela ngaphandle abantu bayamangala ukubona uyise wabantuabagwilike kangaka, abahlala bebahle ngaso sonke isikhathi, engcole ngalolu hlobo.Abanye babaze bazibuze ukuthi ngabe akaqambi yini amanga uma ethi unguyisewabo na. Bayambona futhi ukuthi lo muntu uya ngokuya eguga kube sengathi akasadlinakudla lapho ehlala khona.Ngelinye ilanga ubaba ezihambela nje emgwaqeni bude buduze nalapho ehlala khonaedolobheni laseThekwini, abonwe omunye umuntu ohlala ngalapho ehlala khona,ambingelele maqede bese ethi wamuzwa exoxa indaba yakhe, wasecabanga ukuthiamfundise ukudlala ilotho.Wabe esemcela ukuba ake afike kuyena. Lavuma-ke leli khehla, wayeselinikainombolo yomuzi wakhe. Ngemuva kwezinsuku ezine, babonana. Baxoxa.Bavumelana. Wameluleka ukuthi idlalwa kanjani ilotho nokuthi kusetshenziswa maliniuma ufakela izinombolo ezingaki nokuthi idlalelwaphi.Wabuye wamtshela ukuthi kuvulwa nini kuvalwe nini nezinsuku okudlalwa ngazo.Wambuza ukuthi wake wawadlala yini amahhashi, waphendula ngokuthi: Qha! Kwasekusho ukuthi kufanele adlale naye izinsukwana ezimbalwa aze afunde kahle impela. 1. Kungani umlungu omkhulu athatha isinqumo sokufaka amakhamera efeminiuThusheleni ayengunogada kuyo?","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo:тАв UThusheleni wabamba imenenja ihamba nezimpahla ngaphandlekwemvume yomlungu omkhulu.тИЪтИЪ/тАв Umlungu omkhulu wayefuna ukubamba izisebenzi ezingamasela."},{"question":" ро╡ро┐ройро╛: родрооро┐ро┤рпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН ро╡ро╛ро▓рпНроЯро░рпНро╕рпНроХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роОройрпНро▒рпБ роЕро┤рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБрокро╡ро░рпН.","answer":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: родрооро┐ро┤рпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН ро╡ро╛ро▓рпНроЯро░рпНро╕рпНроХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роОройрпНро▒рпБ роЕро┤рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБрокро╡ро░рпН роХро▓рпНроХро┐.роХро▓рпНроХро┐: роХро▓рпНроХро┐ (9 роЪрпЖрокрпНроЯроорпНрокро░рпН 1899 тАУ 5 родро┐роЪроорпНрокро░рпН 1954) рокрпБроХро┤рпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ родрооро┐ро┤рпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродро╛ро│ро░рпН роЖро╡ро╛ро░рпН. роЗро░ро╛. роХро┐ро░рпБро╖рпНрогроорпВро░рпНродрпНродро┐ роОройрпНро▒ роЗропро▒рпНрокрпЖропро░рпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роЗро╡ро░рпН 35 роЪро┐ро▒рпБроХродрпИродрпН родрпКроХрпБродро┐роХро│рпН, рокрпБродро┐ройроЩрпНроХро│рпН, роХроЯрпНроЯрпБро░рпИроХро│рпН, рокропрогроХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯрпБро░рпИроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИ ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпБ роирпВро▓рпНроХро│рпИ роОро┤рпБродро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│ро╛ро░рпН. роОройро┐ройрпБроорпН, рооро┐роХроЪрпН роЪро┐ро▒роирпНрод роЪроорпВроХ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпБрокрпН рокрпБродро┐ройроЩрпНроХро│рпИ роОро┤рпБродро┐ропродро▒рпНроХро╛роХ рокро░ро╡ро▓ро╛роХ роЕро▒ро┐ропрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН. роЗро╡ро░рпН роОро┤рпБродро┐роп рокрпКройрпНройро┐ропро┐ройрпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро╡ройрпН рокрпБродро┐ройроорпН рооро┐роХрокрпН рокрпБроХро┤рпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒родро╛роХрпБроорпН. родройрпН рокроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН роорпВро▓роорпН роЗроирпНродро┐роп родрпЗроЪро┐роп ро╡ро┐роЯрпБродро▓рпИ рокрпЛро░ро╛роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБроорпН рокроЩрпНроХро│ро┐родрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН. родро┐ропро╛роХрокрпВрооро┐ рокрпБродро┐ройроорпН родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯрооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роОроЯрпБроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ.ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокрпБроХро▓рпНроХро┐ 1899-роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роЪрпЖрокрпНроЯроорпНрокро░рпН рооро╛родроорпН 9-роорпН родрпЗродро┐ рокро┤рпИроп роЪрпЖройрпНройрпИ рооро╛роХро╛рогродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роТройрпНро▒ро┐рогрпИроирпНрод родроЮрпНроЪро╛ро╡рпВро░рпН рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ рооропро┐ро▓ро╛роЯрпБродрпБро▒рпИ роЕро░рпБроХрпЗ роЕроорпИроирпНрод рокроЯрпНроЯроороЩрпНроХро│роорпН роОройрпБроорпН роКро░ро┐ро▓рпН роТро░рпБ рокро┐ро░ро╛роорогроХрпН роХрпБроЯрпБроорпНрокродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рокро┐ро▒роирпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЖро░роорпНрокрокрпНрокро│рпНро│ро┐рокрпН рокроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпИродрпН родройродрпБ роХро┐ро░ро╛роородрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роорпБроЯро┐родрпНрод рокро┐ро▒роХрпБ роЕро╡ро░рпН родро┐ро░рпБроЪрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ родрпЗроЪро┐роп роЙропро░рпНроиро┐ро▓рпИрокрпН рокро│рпНро│ро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЗро░рпНроирпНродро╛ро░рпН. 1921-роЗро▓рпН роороХро╛родрпНрооро╛ роХро╛роирпНродро┐ропроЯро┐роХро│рпН роТродрпНродрпБро┤рпИропро╛роорпИ роЗропроХрпНроХродрпНродрпИродрпН родрпБро╡роХрпНроХро┐роп рокрпЛродрпБ, роЕро╡ро░родрпБ роХро░рпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роИро░рпНроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБ роХро▓рпНроХро┐ родройродрпБ рокро│рпНро│ро┐рокрпНрокроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпИрокрпН рокро╛родро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН родрпБро▒роирпНродрпБ роЗроирпНродро┐роп родрпЗроЪро┐роп роХро╛роЩрпНроХро┐ро░роЪрпБ роХроЯрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЗро░рпНроирпНродро╛ро░рпН. 1922-роЗро▓рпН роЪрпБродроирпНродро┐ро░рокрпН рокрпЛро░ро╛роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рокроЩрпНроХрпБ рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒родро▒рпНроХро╛роХ роУро░ро╛рогрпНроЯрпБ роЪро┐ро▒рпИродрпН родрогрпНроЯройрпИ роЕройрпБрокро╡ро┐родрпНродро╛ро░рпН. 1923-роЗро▓рпН роЕро╡ро░рпН роиро╡роЪроХрпНродро┐ роОройрпНройрпБроорпН рокродрпНродро┐ро░ро┐роХрпИропро┐ройрпН родрпБрогрпИ роЖроЪро┐ро░ро┐ропро░ро╛роХрокрпН рокрогро┐ропро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройро╛ро░рпН. роЕро╡ро░рпБроЯрпИроп роорпБродро▓рпН рокрпБродрпНродроХроорпН роПроЯрпНроЯро┐роХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ 1927-роЗро▓рпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро╛ройродрпБ.тАШроХро▓рпНроХро┐тАЩропро┐ройрпН рокроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроЯрпИроорпИ роЖроХро┐ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯроорпИропро╛ро▓рпН, роЕро╡ро░рпБроЯрпИроп рокро▓ рокроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН роЗрогрпИропродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рокро▓ родро│роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роХро┐роЯрпИроХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.родрооро┐ро┤ро┐роЪрпИ ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐роХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокроЩрпНроХрпБ:роЪроороЪрпБроХро┐ро░рпБродроорпБроорпН родро┐ропро╛роХро░ро╛роЬро░ро┐ройрпН родрпЖро▓рпБроЩрпНроХрпБ роХрпАро░рпНродрпНродройрпИроХро│рпБроорпН рокро┐ро░рокро▓рооро╛роХ роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБ ро╡роирпНрод роЕроХрпНроХро╛ро▓роХроЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родрооро┐ро┤ро┐роЪрпИроХрпНроХро╛роХроХрпН роХро▓рпНроХро┐ роЪродро╛роЪро┐ро╡роорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роОроорпН. роОро╕рпН. роЪрпБрокрпНрокрпБро▓роЯрпНроЪрпБрооро┐ропрпБроЯройрпН роЗрогрпИроирпНродрпБ рокро╛роЯрпБрокроЯрпНроЯро╛ро░рпН роХро▓рпНроХро┐. родрооро┐ро┤рпН роЗроЪрпИ роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНрод роХро▓рпНроХро┐ропро┐ройрпН роЪро┐роирпНродройрпИроХро│рпИродрпН \\"родро░роорпН роХрпБро▒рпИропрпБрооро╛\\" роОройрпБроорпН рокрпБродрпНродроХ ро╡роЯро┐ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро╛ройродро┐ рокродро┐рокрпНрокроХроорпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.рокроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН:рокрпБродро┐ройроЩрпНроХро│рпН:ро╡ро┐роХрпНроХро┐роорпВро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рокро┐ройрпНро╡ро░рпБроорпН родро▓рпИрокрпНрокро┐ро▓ро╛рой роОро┤рпБродрпНродро╛роХрпНроХроорпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ:роХро▓рпНроХро┐ропро┐ройрпН рокроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН:роХро│рпНро╡ройро┐ройрпН роХро╛родро▓ро┐ (1937)родро┐ропро╛роХрокрпВрооро┐ (1938-1939)роороХрпБроЯрокродро┐ (1942)роЕрокро▓рпИропро┐ройрпН роХрогрпНрогрпАро░рпН (1947)роЪрпЛро▓рпИрооро▓рпИ роЗро│ро╡ро░роЪро┐ (1947)роЕро▓рпИ роУроЪрпИ (1948)родрпЗро╡роХро┐ропро┐ройрпН роХрогро╡ройрпН (1950)роорпЛроХро┐ройро┐родрпНродрпАро╡рпБ (1950)рокрпКропрпНрооро╛ройрпН роХро░роЯрпБ (1951)рокрпБройрпНройрпИро╡ройродрпНродрпБрокрпН рокрпБро▓ро┐ (1952)роЕрооро░родро╛ро░ро╛ (1954)ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпБ рокрпБродро┐ройроЩрпНроХро│рпНроЪро┐ро╡роХро╛рооро┐ропро┐ройрпН роЪрокродроорпН (1944 тАУ 1946)[1]рокро╛ро░рпНродрпНродро┐рокройрпН роХройро╡рпБ (1941 - 1943)рокрпКройрпНройро┐ропро┐ройрпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро╡ройрпН (1951 тАУ 1954)[2]роЪро┐ро▒рпБроХродрпИроХро│рпН:роЪрпБрокродрпНродро┐ро░рпИропро┐ройрпН роЪроХрпЛродро░ройрпНроТро▒рпНро▒рпИ ро░рпЛроЬро╛родрпАрокрпНрокро┐роЯро┐родрпНрод роХрпБроЯро┐роЪрпИроХро│рпНрокрпБродрпБ роУро╡ро░рпНроЪро┐ропро░рпНро╡ро╕рпНродро╛родрпБ ро╡рпЗрогрпБроЕрооро░ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпБроЪрпБрогрпНроЯрпБро╡ро┐ройрпН роЪроирпНроиро┐ропро╛роЪроорпНродро┐ро░рпБроЯройрпН роороХройрпН родро┐ро░рпБроЯройрпНроЗрооропрооро▓рпИ роОроЩрпНроХро│рпН рооро▓рпИрокрпКроЩрпНроХрпБрооро╛роЩрпНроХроЯро▓рпНрооро╛ро╕рпНроЯро░рпН роорпЖродрпБро╡роЯрпИрокрпБро╖рпНрокрокрпН рокро▓рпНро▓роХрпНроХрпБ"},{"question":"Trс║г lс╗Эi c├вu hс╗Пi sau, sс╗С ─Сс╗Сi cс╗зa 8 l├а:A. тАУ 8B. 0C. 8D. 16","answer":"Lс╗Эi giс║гiTa c├│ sс╗С ─Сс╗Сi cс╗зa 8 l├а тАУ 8.Chс╗Нn ─С├бp ├бn A."},{"question":"щЧощвШя╝ЪхЖ░хЭЧцШпхжВф╜ХхИ╢ф╜ЬчЪДя╝Я","answer":"хЫЮчнФя╝ЪхЖ░хЭЧхПпф╗ещАЪш┐Зх░Жц░┤хАТхЕехЖ░чЫТцИЦхЖ░ца╝ф╕ня╝МчД╢хРОцФ╛хЕехЖ░чо▒хЖ╖хЖ╗шАМхИ╢ф╜ЬуАВ"},{"question":"Ci ban kembaar la r├йwum Togo n├йkk","answer":"R├йwum Tchad mu ngi n├йkk ci kembaar bi ├▒uy wakh Afrique"},{"question":"ркирлАркЪрлЗркирк╛ рк╢ркмрлНркжрк╕ркорлВрк╣ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркПркХ рк╢ркмрлНркж ркЖрккрлЛ:ркЖркВркЦ рк╕рк╛ркерлЗ ркЖркВркЦ ркорк│рлА ркеркдрлА рккрлНрк░рлАркдрк┐","answer":"ркдрк╛рк░рк╛ркорлИркдрлНрк░ркХ "},{"question":"цЦЗчлауБЛуВЙуВнуГ╝уГпуГ╝уГЙуВТщБ╕уБ│уАБуБЭуБошзгщЗИуВТш┐░уБ╣уБкуБХуБДуАВ цЬАф╜Ош│ГщЗСуБпуАБф╝Ъчд╛уБкуБйуБМхГНуБПф║║уБлцЙХуБЖуБДуБбуБ░уВУф╜ОуБДш│ГщЗСуБзуБЩуАВхОЪчФЯхК┤хГНчЬБуБоф╝Ъшн░уБз7цЬИуАБ1цЩВщЦУуБоцЬАф╜Ош│ГщЗСуВТщГ╜щБУх║ЬчЬМуБох╣│хЭЗуБз41хЖЖф╕КуБТуВЛчЫоциЩуБМц▒║уБ╛уВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуБУуБоф╝Ъшн░уБоуБВуБиуАБщГ╜щБУх║ЬчЬМуБпф╝Ъшн░уВТщЦЛуБДуБжуАБхГНуБПф║║уБиф╝Ъчд╛уБоф╗гшбиуБкуБйуБМцЬАф╜Ош│ГщЗСуБлуБдуБДуБжшй▒уБЧхРИуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВцЭ▒ф║мщГ╜уБп7цЧеуБлф╝Ъшн░уВТщЦЛуБДуБжуАБцЬАф╜Ош│ГщЗСуВТ41хЖЖф╕КуБТуБжуАБя╝СцЩВщЦУ1113хЖЖуБлуБЩуВЛуБУуБиуВТц▒║уВБуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ41хЖЖф╕КуБМуВЛуБоуБпуАБцЭ▒ф║мщГ╜уБзхИЭуВБуБжуБзуБЩуАВф╗Кх╣┤уБо10цЬИуБЛуВЙф╕КуБМуВЛф║ИхоЪуБзуБЩуАВуБУуБоф╝Ъшн░уБоф╝ЪщХ╖уБпуАМцЬАф╜Ош│ГщЗСуБзхГНуБПф║║уБЯуБбуБочФЯц┤╗уБоуБЯуВБуБлуАБф╕КуБТуВЛх┐ЕшжБуБМуБВуВЛуБишАГуБИуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВцЙХуБЖш│ГщЗСуБМхвЧуБИуБжхЫ░уВЛф╝Ъчд╛уБоуБУуБиуВТцЭ▒ф║мщГ╜уБМхКйуБСуБжуБ╗уБЧуБДуБицАЭуБДуБ╛уБЩуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ","answer":"уБУуБоцЦЗчлауБлхРлуБ╛уВМуВЛуВнуГ╝уГпуГ╝уГЙуБиуБЭуБошзгщЗИуБпф╗еф╕ЛуБзуБЩуАВ- ш│ГщЗС: 1я╝ЙхГНуБДуБЯф║║уБМуАБуБЭуБохГНуБНуБлхп╛уБЧуБжуВВуВЙуБЖуБКщЗСуАВ- хОЪчФЯхК┤хГНчЬБ: 1я╝ЙхЫ╜ц░СуБохБех║╖уВДчФЯц┤╗уВТхоИуВЛф╗Хф║ЛуВДуАБхК┤хГНшАЕуБМф╗Хф║ЛуВТшжЛуБдуБСуВЛуБоуВТхКйуБСуБЯуВКуАБхК┤хГНшАЕуВТф┐Эшн╖уБЧуБЯуВКуБЩуВЛхЫ╜уБох╜╣цЙАуАВхОЪхК┤чЬБуАВ- щГ╜щБУх║ЬчЬМ: 1я╝ЙхЕихЫ╜уВТ47уБлхИЖуБСуБЯхМ║чФ╗уАВцЭ▒ф║мщГ╜уГ╗хМЧц╡╖щБУуГ╗хдзщШкх║ЬуГ╗ф║мщГ╜х║ЬуБиуАБ43уБочЬМуАВ- х╣│хЭЗ: 1я╝ЙхдЪуБДх░СуБкуБДуВДщлШуБДф╜ОуБДуБкуБйуБох╖оуБМуБкуБДуВИуБЖуБлуБЩуВЛуБУуБиуАВ2я╝Йф║МуБдф╗еф╕КуБоцХ░уВДщЗПуБоф╕нщЦУуБоцХ░уВДщЗПуАВ3я╝ЙуБдуВКхРИуБДуБМуБиуВМуВЛуБУуБиуАВуГРуГйуГ│уВ╣уАВ- чЫоциЩ: 1я╝ЙуВВуБоуБФуБиуВТуБкуБЧуБиуБТуВЛуБЯуВБуБочЫох╜УуБжуАВ2я╝ЙшбМуБНуБдуБПуБЯуВБуБочЫоуБШуВЛуБЧуАВ- ф╗гшби: 1я╝ЙхдЪуБПуБоф║║уБлф╗гуВПуБгуБжф╜ХуБЛуВТуБЩуВЛуБУуБиуАВуБ╛уБЯуАБуБЭуБоф║║уАВ2я╝Йф╕АщГихИЖуБзхЕиф╜УуБочЙ╣шЙ▓уВТшбиуБЩуБУуБиуАВуБ╛уБЯуАБуБЭуБоуВВуБоуАВ- шй▒уБЧхРИуБг: 1я╝ЙуБЯуБМуБДуБлшй▒уБЩуАВуБКуБЯуБМуБДуБлчЫ╕цЙЛуБошй▒уВТшБЮуБНуАБшЗкхИЖуВВшй▒уБЩуАВ2я╝ЙцДПшжЛуВТхЗ║уБЧхРИуБЖуАВ- ф╝ЪщХ╖: 1я╝Йф╝ЪуВТф╗гшбиуБЩуВЛф║║уАВ- хКйуБС: 1я╝ЙхН▒уБкуБДуБУуБиуВДшЛжуБЧуБДуБУуБиуБЛуВЙцХСуБЖуАВ2я╝ЙхКЫуВТш▓╕уБЩуАВцЙЛф╝ЭуБЖуАВ"},{"question":"H├гy ─Сс║╖t mс╗Щt ti├кu ─Сс╗Б ph├╣ hс╗гp vс╗Ыi ─Сoс║бn v─Гn sau: Ng├аy 31/7, C╞б quan CS─РT C├┤ng an tс╗Йnh C├а Mau khс╗Яi tс╗С bс╗Л can, bс║пt tс║бm giam ─Рс║╖ng Hс║гi ─Р─Гng (sinh n─Гm 1966, Gi├бm ─Сс╗Сc CDC C├а Mau); Hс╗У Quang Nhu, Ph├│ tr╞░с╗Яng Ph├▓ng Kс║┐ hoс║бch тАУ Nghiс╗Зp vс╗е thuс╗Щc CDC C├а Mau v├а L├к Ngс╗Нc ─Рс╗Лnh, Tr╞░с╗Яng Ph├▓ng Kс║┐ hoс║бch - T├аi ch├нnh, Sс╗Я Y tс║┐ C├а Mau ─Сс╗Г ─Сiс╗Бu tra vс╗Б h├аnh vi \\"Vi phс║бm quy ─Сс╗Лnh vс╗Б ─Сс║еu thс║зu g├вy hс║нu quс║г nghi├кm trс╗Нng\\" quy ─Сс╗Лnh tс║бi khoс║гn 3 ─Рiс╗Бu 222 BLHS. Theo C├┤ng an C├а Mau, tс╗л th├бng 1/2020 ─Сс║┐n th├бng 10/2021, Sс╗Я Y tс║┐, CDC C├а Mau v├а Bс╗Зnh viс╗Зn ─Сa khoa tс╗Йnh thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn 11 g├│i thс║зu mua kit x├йt nghiс╗Зm COVID-19, m├бy t├бch chiс║┐t DNA/RNA tс╗▒ ─Сс╗Щng, h├│a chс║еt, sinh phс║йm v├а thiс║┐t bс╗Л phс╗еc vс╗е c├┤ng t├бc ph├▓ng chс╗Сng dс╗Лch COVID-19 cс╗зa C├┤ng ty Viс╗Зt ├Б, vс╗Ыi sс╗С tiс╗Бn h╞бn 49 tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng. Qu├б tr├мnh thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn hс╗У s╞б ─Сс║еu thс║зu, L├к Ngс╗Нc ─Рс╗Лnh, ─Рс║╖ng Hс║гi ─Р─Гng v├а Hс╗У Quang Nhu thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn kh├┤ng ─С├║ng quy ─Сс╗Лnh vс╗Б ─Сс║еu thс║зu \\"kh├┤ng bс║гo ─Сс║гm c├┤ng bс║▒ng, minh bс║бch\\", vi phс║бm c├бc h├аnh vi bс╗Л cс║еm trong ─Сс║еu thс║зu quy ─Сс╗Лnh tс║бi khoс║гn 6 ─Рiс╗Бu 89 Luс║нt ─Рс║еu thс║зu; g├вy thiс╗Зt hс║бi cho ng├вn s├бch nh├а n╞░с╗Ыc. Trong ─С├│, Sс╗Я Y tс║┐ C├а Mau mua kit x├йt nghiс╗Зm COVID-19 cс╗зa C├┤ng ty Viс╗Зt ├Б cao h╞бn so vс╗Ыi chi ph├н sс║гn xuс║еt (─С├г bao gс╗Уm 5% lс╗гi nhuс║нn v├а chi ph├н kh├бc), dс║лn ─Сс║┐n thiс╗Зt hс║бi khoс║гng h╞бn 9,1 tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng. CDC C├а Mau mua kit x├йt nghiс╗Зm COVID-19 cс╗зa C├┤ng ty Viс╗Зt ├Б cao h╞бn so vс╗Ыi gi├б cс╗зa chi ph├н sс║гn xuс║еt (─С├г bao gс╗Уm 5% lс╗гi nhuс║нn v├а chi ph├н kh├бc), dс║лn ─Сс║┐n thiс╗Зt hс║бi khoс║гng h╞бn 3 tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng. Hiс╗Зn vс╗е ├бn ─Сang ─С╞░с╗гc C├┤ng an tс╗Йnh C├а Mau tiс║┐p tс╗еc ─Сiс╗Бu tra l├аm r├╡.","answer":"Bс║пt tс║бm giam Gi├бm ─Сс╗Сc CDC tс╗Йnh C├а Mau"},{"question":"рокро┐ройрпНро╡ро░рпБроорпН рооро┐ройрпНройроЮрпНроЪро▓рпН ро╕рпНрокрпЗрооро╛ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЙрогрпНроорпИропро╛рой роЕроЮрпНроЪро▓ро╛ роОрой роХрогрпНроЯро▒ро┐ропро╡рпБроорпН. роЖроорпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЗро▓рпНро▓рпИ роОрой рокродро┐ро▓ро│ро┐роХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН.\\"роирпАроЩрпНроХро│рпН 100 роЖропро┐ро░роорпН роЯро╛ро▓ро░рпНроХро│рпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│рпАро░рпНроХро│рпН. роЕроирпНродродрпН родрпКроХрпИропрпИрокрпНрокрпЖро▒ роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роХро┐ро░рпЖроЯро┐роЯрпН роХро╛ро░рпНроЯрпБ роОрогрпНрогрпИ роОроЩрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЕройрпБрокрпНрокрпБроЩрпНроХро│рпН.\\"","answer":"роЖроорпН."},{"question":"Mabisa ba ang pag-ubo sa paghinto ng atake sa puso?","answer":"Hindi. Walang ebidensiya na mababawasan ng pag-ubo ang mga panganib ng atake sa puso."},{"question":"ркЧрк┐ркЬрлБркнрк╛ркИ ркмркзрлЗркХрк╛ркирлА \\"ркЖ ркдрлЗ рк╢рлА ркорк╛ркерк╛рклрлЛркб┬а!\\" рккрлБрк╕рлНркдркХркирлБ ркПркХ рк▓рлЗркЦрки ркирлАркЪрлЗ ркорлБркЬркм ркЖрккрлЗрк▓ ркЫрлЗ.\\"ркорк╛рк░рлА ркмркЪрк▓рлА ! ркХрк╛ркВркЗ ркбрк╛рк╣рлА ркЫрлЗ ркмрк╛ ! ркШрк░ркирлБркВ ркПркХ рк░ркоркХркбрлБркВркп рккрк╛ркбрлЛрк╢рлАркирлЗ ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЬрк╡рк╛ рки ркжрлЗ. ркКрк▓ркЯрлБркВ ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЧркЗ рк╣рлЛркп ркдрлЛ ркПркХрк╛ркж ркЙрккрк╛ркбрлА ркЖрк╡рлЗ !тБаркмрк╛, ркХрк╛ркВркЗ рк╣рлЛрк╢рк┐ркпрк╛рк░ ркЫрлЗ ! ркХркжрлАркпрлЗ ркШрк░ркирлА ркПркХрлЗ рк╡рк╛ркд ркХрлЛркЗ ркирлЗ рки ркХрк╣рлЗ. рккрлВркЫрлЗ ркдрлЛ ркКрк▓ркЯрлБркВ ркКркВркзрлБркВ ркХрк╣рлЗ !тБаркмрк╛ ркХрк╛ркВркЗ рк╕ркоркЬрлБ ! рккрк╛рк░ркХрк╛ркВ ркЗ рккрк╛рк░ркХрк╛ркВ ркирлЗ рккрлЛркдрк╛ркирк╛ркВ ркЗ рккрлЛркдрк╛ркирк╛ркВ. ркмрк░рк╛ркмрк░ рккрлЛркдрк╛-рккрк╛рк░ркХрк╛ркирлЛ ркнрлЗркж рк╕ркоркЬрлЗ ркЫрлЗ.тБаркмрк╛, ркХрк╛ркВркЗ ркЪркдрлБрк░ ! ркЖрккркгрлЗ ркХрк╣рлАркП ркХрлЗ ркХрк╛ркХрлАркорк╛ркирлЗ ркХрк╣рлЗркЬрлЗ ркХрлЗ ркШрк░ркорк╛ркВ ркХрлЛркЗ ркиркерлА ркдрлЛ ркПрк╡рлБркВ ркарк╛рк╡ркХрлБркВ ркорлЛркВ рк░рк╛ркЦрлАркирлЗ ркмрлЛрк▓рлЗ ркХрлЗ ркПрко ркЬ рк▓рк╛ркЧрлЗ ркХрлЗ ркмркЪрк▓рлА рк╕рк╛рк╡ рк╕рк╛ркЪрлБркВ ркмрлЛрк▓ркдрлА рк╣рк╢рлЗ !\\"ркЖркЬ рк░рлАркдркирлА \\"ркорк╛ркерк╛рклрлЛркб\\" рккрк░ ркЖрк╡рлБ ркЬ ркмрлАркЬрлБ рк▓рлЗркЦрки рк▓ркЦрлЛ. ","answer":"ркорк╛рк░рлА ркмркЪрк▓рлА ркдрлЛ ркмрк╛, рк╕рк╛рк╡ ркнрк╛рки рк╡ркЧрк░ркирлА ркЫрлЗ. ркЖркЯрк▓рк╛ркВ ркмркзрк╛ рк░ркоркХркбрк╛ркВ ркЖркгрлНркпрк╛ркВ, рккркг ркнрк╛ркЗркмркВркзрлЛркирлЗ ркЬ ркЖрккрлА ркжрлЗ ркЫрлЗ !тБаркмрк╛, ркП ркдрлЛ рк╕рк╛рк╡ ркнрлЛркЯ ркЬрлЗрк╡рлА; рк╕ркоркЬрлЗ ркЬ ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ ркХрлЗ ? ркШрк░ркорк╛ркВ ркЬрлЗ ркерк╛ркп ркдрлЗ ркмрк╣рк╛рк░ ркЬркЗркирлЗ ркХрк╣рлА ркЖрк╡рлЗ; рккрлЗркЯркорк╛ркВ рк╢рлБркВ рк░ркЦрк╛ркп, ркмрлАркЬрк╛ркирлЗ рк╢рлБркВ ркХрк╣рлЗрк╡рк╛ркп ркПркирлА ркЦркмрк░ ркЬ рккркбрлЗ ркдрлЛ ркХрлЗ ?тБаркмрк╛, ркЗ ркдрлЛ рк╕рк╛рк╡ ркЕркЬркб ркЬрлЗрк╡рлА; ркЖ ркЖрккркгрлБркВ ркирлЗ ркЖ ркирк╣рк┐, ркПркЯрк▓рлАркпрлЗ ркЦркмрк░ рки ркорк│рлЗ ! ркХрлЛ'ркХ ркЖрк╡рлЗ ркдрлЛ ркЖ рккрк╛ркерк░рлАркирлЗ ркмрлЗрк╕рлЗ ркирлЗ ркЬрлЗ ркорк╛ркЧрлЗ ркдрлЗ ркЖрккрлЗ.тБаркмрк╛, ркЗ ркдрлЛ ркдркорк╛рк░рлЗ рк╕рк╛рк╡ ркнрлЛрк│рлА ркнркЯрк╛ркХ ! ркЬрк░рк╛ ркп ркЦрлЛркЯрлБркВ тАЛркмрлЛрк▓ркдрк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡ркбрлЗ ркдрлЛ ркХрлЗ ? ркЬрлЗрк╡рлБркВ ркоркиркорк╛ркВ ркПрк╡рлБркВ ркорлЛркврлЗ. ркКрк▓ркЯрк╛ркВ ркЖрккркгркирлЗ рккрк╛ркбрлЛрк╢рлА ркЖркЧрк│ ркЦрлЛркЯрк╛ркВ рккрк╛ркбрлЗ !"},{"question":"╨Ъ╥п╥г╨│╙й╨╣","answer":"╨в╨╛╨╛╨╜╤Г╨╜ ╨║╤Г╨╜ ╤В╨╕╨╣╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤В╨░╤А╨░╨▒╤Л╨╜ ╨║╥п╥г╨│╙й╨╣ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨░╤В╨░╨╗╨░╤В"},{"question":"Cite um criatura marinha que tem a capacidade de se clonar.","answer":"├Бgua-viva. Quando as ├бguas-vivas s├гo cortadas ao meio, elas t├кm a capacidade de regenerar suas c├йlulas e criar outras ├бguas-vivas."},{"question":"Tusidee to n bс╗Н ni wс╗Нn yoo sinku с╗Нmс╗Н Baba Adeboye","answer":"Bi gbogbo nnkan ba lс╗Н bi wс╗Нn с╣гe с╣гeto rс║╣, с╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun, Tusidee, с╗Нsс║╣ to n bс╗Н ni wс╗Нn yoo sinku Pasitс╗Н Deji Adeboye, с╗Нmс╗Н Olori ijс╗Н Ridiimu, Pasitс╗Н Adejare Adeboye.Ninu atс║╣jade kan ti aburo oloogbe naa to tun jс║╣ oluranlс╗Нwс╗Н pataki fun Baba Adeboye, Leke Adeboye, fi sita lс╗Нjс╗Н с║╕ti, Furaidee, opin с╗Нsс║╣ yii, lo ti ni с╗Нjс╗Н Aiku, Sannde, с╗Нjс╗Н kс║╣san-an, oс╣гu yii, ni isin pataki yoo waye fun oloogbe naa ni City of David Youth Church, Eket, nipinlс║╣ Akwa Ibom.Ni Mс╗Нnde, с╗Нjс╗Н kс║╣waa, oс╣гu yii, kan naa ni isin pataki ati с╗Нrс╗Н iwuri nipa oloogbe yoo waye ni RCCG, House of Favour, Redemption Camp.с╗Мjс╗Н kс╗Нkanla, oс╣гu yii, ni deede aago mс║╣waa aarс╗Н, ni isin idagbere yoo waye Youth Centre, Redemption Camp, nipinlс║╣ Ogun. Lс║╣yin eyi ni wс╗Нn yoo fi eeru fun eeru, yeepс║╣ fun yeepс║╣.Leke fi с║╣mi imoore rс║╣ han fun adura, aduroti ati atilс║╣yin ti awс╗Нn eeyan n fi ranс╣гс║╣ latigba ti iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ ibanujс║╣ naa ti с╣гс║╣lс║╣. O ni awс╗Нn mс╗Н riri atilс║╣yin awс╗Нn eeyan. Ohun to si dun mс╗Н awс╗Нn ninu ni pe arakunrin awс╗Нn ti lс╗Н sс╗Нdс╗Н Olugbala lati sinmi laya с║╕ledaa rс║╣.O ni igbe aye rere ti Dare gbe ati fifi ara jin fun iс╣гс║╣ с╗Мlс╗Нrun jс║╣ ohun idunnu fun awс╗Нn."},{"question":"р╢Жр╖Ар╖Ър╢лр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢л р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╢Ьр╢н р╖Ар╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╖Гр╖Ьр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П , \\" р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ар╖Ър╢лр╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖П \\" р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢╢р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢╢р╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢ер╢║р╖П р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п ?","answer":"р╢Жр╖Ар╖Ър╢лр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢л р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╢Ьр╢н р╖Ар╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╖Гр╖Ьр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П , \\" р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ар╖Ър╢лр╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖П \\" р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢╢р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢╢р╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢ер╢║р╖П р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢Фр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Кр╢зр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ , р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Щр╢Ьр╢╗р╖Т р╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢йр╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Фр╢╕р╖П р╢║. "},{"question":"Nitori ere asapajude, ajс╗Н с║╣sс╗Н oju popo mu mс╗Нto akero marundinlogoji","answer":"Ileeс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba to n mojuto irinna с╗Нkс╗Н loju popo (FRSC), с╗Мgbс║╣ni Oluс╣гс║╣gun Ogungbemide, ti sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn mс╗Нto akero marundinlogoji (35) lс╗Нwс╗Н awс╗Нn ti ba bayii, nitori ti awс╗Нn to ni wс╗Нn ko tс║╣le aс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba nipa lilo с║╣rс╗Н to le din ere asapajude ku.Ogungbemide с╣гalaye с╗Нrс╗Н yii  fawс╗Нn oniroyin lс║╣yin ipade to с╣гe pс║╣lu awс╗Нn onimoto ti wс╗Нn n na Eko si Ibadan. O ni o с╣гe pataki fun wс╗Нn lati maa lo с║╣rс╗Н ti yoo maa с╣гadinku ere asapajude to wс╗Нpс╗Н laarin awс╗Нn onimс╗Нto ero.Ogungbemide fi kun с╗Нrс╗Н с║╣ pe aс╣гс║╣ ti ajс╗Н naa n tс║╣le bayii ni i с╣гe pelu ohun ti с╗Нga agba ajс╗Н to n ri si irinna oju popo, Dokita Boboye Oyeyс║╣mi, sс╗Н, paapaa lori akiyesi bi с╗Нpс╗Н с║╣mi с╣гe n с╣гofo latari ere isakusa lasiko ayс║╣yс║╣ с╗Нdun.O ni, тАЬA ko ni i gbe mс╗Нto yс║╣n fawс╗Нn to ni wс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn ko ba fi с║╣rс╗Н ti yoo maa din ere asapajude ku si i, koda, ki wс╗Нn sanwo itanran fun ijс╗Нba. O с╣гe pataki ki gbogbo mс╗Нto akero ni in, bс║╣с║╣ la o ni i faaye gba aitс║╣le ofin с╗Нhun latс╗Нwс╗Н с║╣nikс║╣ni.тАЭBakan naa lo rс╗Н awс╗Нn onimс╗Нto lati с╣гe pс║╣lс║╣, ki wс╗Нn si tun pa ofin ati ilana itankalс║╣ ├аr├╣n koronafairс╗Нс╗Нsi mс╗Н d├бad├бa lс║╣nu iс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn."},{"question":"Qual foi a m├║sica de estreia de Kelly Clarkson?","answer":"O single de estreia de Kelly Clarkson foi \\"A Moment Like This\\""},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ╔Чari biyu da arba'in a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 240"},{"question":"ри╣рйЗриа ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ ри╡ри╛риХ ри╡ри┐риЪрйЛриВ риири╛риВри╡ риЪрйБригрйЛ ред риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйА риХри┐ри╕рио ри╡рйА рижрй▒ри╕рйЛри╣ри░ риЪриориХриг ри╡ри╛ри▓рйА риЪрйАриЬри╝ ри╕рйЛриири╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА ред","answer":"риЪрйАриЬри╝, ри╕рйЛриири╛ ред"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪и┘К ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ┘В╪з┘Е ╪и┘Г┘Б╪з┘Д╪й ┘Е╪▒┘К┘Е ╪и┘Ж╪к ╪╣┘Е╪▒╪з┘Ж╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪м┘И╪з╪и: ┘Ж╪и┘К ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪▓┘Г╪▒┘К╪з ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д╪з┘Е."},{"question":"╨Ъ╨░╨║╨╛ ╤Б╨╡ ╨╖╨╛╨▓╨╡ ╤Б╤А╨┐╤Б╨║╨╕ ╨║╨╛╤И╨░╤А╨║╨░╤И ╨║╨╛╤Ш╨╕ ╤Ш╨╡ ╨┐╤А╨▓╨╕ ╨╛╤Б╨▓╨╛╨╕╤Ш╨╛ ╤В╨╕╤В╤Г╨╗╤Г ╨╜╨░╤Ш╨▒╨╛╤Щ╨╡╨│ ╨╕╨│╤А╨░╤З╨░ (╨Ь╨Т╨Я) ╨Э╨С╨Р ╨╗╨╕╨│╨╡?","answer":"╨Э╨╕╨║╨╛╨╗╨░ ╨И╨╛╨║╨╕╤Ы ╤Ш╨╡ ╨┐╤А╨▓╨╕ ╤Б╤А╨┐╤Б╨║╨╕ ╨║╨╛╤И╨░╤А╨║╨░╤И ╨╛╤Б╨▓╨░╤Ш╨░╤З╨░ ╨┐╤А╨╕╨╖╨╜╨░╤Ъ╨░ ╨╖╨░ ╨╜╨░╤Ш╨▒╨╛╤Щ╨╡╨│ ╨╕╨│╤А╨░╤З╨░ ╨Э╨С╨Р ╨╗╨╕╨│╨╡. ╨Ю╨╜ ╤Ш╨╡ ╨╜╨░╨│╤А╨░╨┤╤Г ╨╖╨░ ╨╜╨░╤Ш╨▒╨╛╤Щ╨╡╨│ ╨╕╨│╤А╨░╤З╨░ ╤А╨╡╨│╤Г╨╗╨░╤А╨╜╨╡ ╤Б╨╡╨╖╨╛╨╜╨╡ ╨╛╤Б╨▓╨░╤Ш╨░╨╛ ╤Г ╤Б╨╡╨╖╨╛╨╜╨░╨╝╨░ 2020-21 ╨╕ 2021-22, ╨┤╨╛╨║ ╤Ш╨╡ ╨╜╨░╨│╤А╨░╨┤╤Г ╨╖╨░ ╨╜╨░╤Ш╨▒╨╛╤Щ╨╡╨│ ╨╕╨│╤А╨░╤З╨░ ╤Д╨╕╨╜╨░╨╗╨╜╨╡ ╤Б╨╡╤А╨╕╤Ш╨╡ ╨╛╤Б╨▓╨╛╨╕╤Ш╨╛ ╤Г ╤Б╨╡╨╖╨╛╨╜╨╕ 2022-23."},{"question":"Question: The instrument which is used for the measurement of blood pressure is known as what?a. Oxymeterb. Thermometerc. Sphygmomanometerd. Glucometer","answer":"Answer:(c) SphygmomanometerFurther notes:A sphygmomanometer is used for the measurement of blood pressure."},{"question":"╨Ъ╨╕╨▒╨╡╤А ╨║╨╛╨╛╨┐╤Б╤Г╨╖╨┤╤Г╨║ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡?","answer":"╨Ъ╨╕╨▒╨╡╤А ╨║╨╛╨╛╨┐╤Б╤Г╨╖╨┤╤Г╨║ - ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨║╨╛╨╝╨┐╤М╤О╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨║ ╤В╤Г╤В╤Г╨╝╨┤╨░╤А╨┤╤Л, ╤В╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨║╤В╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨┤╨░╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨║╤Л╨╗╨╝╤Л╤И╨║╨╡╤А╨╗╨╡╤А╨┤╨╡╨╜, ╨▓╨╕╤А╤Г╤Б╤В╨░╤А╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨▒╨░╤И╨║╨░ ╨║╨╛╤А╨║╤Г╨╜╤Г╤З╤В╤Г╤Г ╨║╥п╤З╙й╤В╥п╥п╨╗╙й╤А╨┤╙й╨╜ ╨║╨╛╤А╨│╨╛╨╛ ╨╕╤И-╨░╤А╨░╨║╨╡╤В╤В╨╡╤А╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨╢╤Л╨╣╤Л╨╜╨┤╤Л╤Б╤Л.╨Ъ╨╕╨▒╨╡╤А ╨║╨╛╨╛╨┐╤Б╤Г╨╖╨┤╤Г╨║ ╤В╙й╨╝╙й╨╜╨║╥п ╨╜╨╡╨│╨╕╨╖╨│╨╕ ╤Н╨╗╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╤В╤В╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕ ╨║╨░╨╝╤В╤Л╨╣╤В:╨Ф╨░╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨║╨╛╨╜╤Д╨╕╨┤╨╡╨╜╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨┤╤Г╤Г╨╗╤Г╨│╤Г - ╨┤╨░╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╤Г╤А╤Г╨║╤Б╨░╤В╤Б╤Л╨╖ ╨║╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╨╜╤Г╤Г╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╛╤А╨│╨╛╨╛.╨Ф╨░╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨║╨╕╨╗╨╕╨║╤В╥п╥п╨╗╥п╨│╥п - ╨╝╨░╨░╨╗╤Л╨╝╨░╤В╨║╨░ ╤Г╤А╤Г╨║╤Б╨░╤В╤Л ╨▒╨░╤А ╨║╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╨╜╤Г╤Г╤З╤Г╨╗╨░╤А ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨╡ ╨░╨╗╤Л╤И╤Л╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╝╤Б╤Л╨╖ ╨║╤Л╨╗╤Г╤Г.╨Ф╨░╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤В╤Г╤А╤Г╨║╤В╤Г╤Г╨╗╤Г╨│╤Г - ╨┤╨░╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤В╨╛╨╗╤Г╨║╤В╤Г╨│╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨░╨╜╤Л╨║╤В╤Л╨│╤Л╨╜ ╤Б╨░╨║╤В╨╛╨╛.╨в╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨║╤В╤Л╨╜ ╨╕╤И╤В╨╡╨╗╨╕╨║╤В╥п╥п╨╗╥п╨│╥п - ╤В╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨║╤В╤Л╨╜ ╤Г╨╖╨░╨║╨║╨░ ╤Б╨╛╨╖╤Г╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨▒╙й╨│╙й╤В╤В╙й╤А╤Б╥п╨╖ ╨╕╤И╤В╨╡╤И╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╝╤Б╤Л╨╖ ╨║╤Л╨╗╤Г╤Г.╨Ъ╨╕╨▒╨╡╤А ╨║╨╛╨╛╨┐╤Б╤Г╨╖╨┤╤Г╨║ ╤Б╨╕╤Б╤В╨╡╨╝╨░╤Б╤Л ╨▒╤Г╨╖╤Г╤Г╤З╤Г╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╛╤А╨│╨╛╨╛ ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╤В╙й╨╝╙й╨╜╨║╥п ╤З╨░╤А╨░╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨║╨░╨╝╤В╤Л╨╣╤В: ╤Д╨░╨╡╤А╨▓╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╤А, ╨░╨╜╤В╨╕╨▓╨╕╤А╤Г╤Б╤В╤Г╨║ ╨┐╤А╨╛╨│╤А╨░╨╝╨╝╨░╨╗╨░╤А, ╨║╨╕╤А╥п╥п╨╜╥п ╨▒╨░╤И╨║╨░╤А╤Г╤Г ╤Б╨╕╤Б╤В╨╡╨╝╨░╨╗╨░╤А╤Л, ╤И╨╕╤Д╤А╨╗╙й╙й ╨╢.╨▒.╨Ъ╨╕╨▒╨╡╤А ╨║╨╛╨╛╨┐╤Б╤Г╨╖╨┤╤Г╨║ ╨╝╨░╤Б╨╡╨╗╨╡╨╗╨╡╤А╨╕ ╤Г╤З╤Г╤А╨┤╨░ ╙й╤В╙й ╨╝╨░╨░╨╜╨╕╨╗╥п╥п ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨░╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╤З╨╡╤З╥п╥п ╨╖╨░╤А╤Л╨╗."},{"question":"рдмреНрдпрд╛рдЬ рджрд░рд▓реЗ рдЕрд░реНрдерддрдиреНрддреНрд░рдорд╛ рдЙрдзрд╛рд░реЛ рд░ рдЦрд░реНрдЪрд▓рд╛рдИ рдХрд╕рд░реА рдЕрд╕рд░ рдЧрд░реНрдЫ?","answer":"рдмреНрдпрд╛рдЬ рджрд░рд╣рд░реВрдорд╛ рдкрд░рд┐рд╡рд░реНрддрдирд╣рд░реВрд▓реЗ рдЙрдзрд╛рд░реЛ рд▓рд╛рдЧрдд, рдЙрдкрднреЛрдХреНрддрд╛ рдЦрд░реНрдЪ, рд╡реНрдпрд╛рдкрд╛рд░ рд▓рдЧрд╛рдиреА, рд░ рд╕рдордЧреНрд░ рдЖрд░реНрдерд┐рдХ рдЧрддрд┐рд╡рд┐рдзрд┐рд▓рд╛рдИ рдЕрд╕рд░ рдЧрд░реНрдЫред"},{"question":"цмбуБоцо╡шР╜уБлуГЮуГГуГБуБЩуВЛуВ┐уВдуГИуГлуВТуБдуБСуБжуБПуБауБХуБДя╝Ъ уВвуГХуВмуГЛуВ╣уВ┐уГ│уБоф║║уБоуБЯуВБуБлщХ╖уБДщЦУц┤╗хЛХуБЧуБжуБДуБЯф╕нцЭСхУ▓уБХуВУуБпуАБ3х╣┤хЙНуБо12цЬИ4цЧеуАБщКГуБзцТГуБЯуВМуБжф║буБПуБкуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ73цн│уБзуБЧуБЯуАВцЭ▒ф║муБлуБВуВЛуВвуГХуВмуГЛуВ╣уВ┐уГ│хдзф╜┐щдиуБз4цЧеуАБф╕нцЭСуБХуВУуБоуБЯуВБуБлчеИуВЛх╝ПуБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВф╕нцЭСуБХуВУуБМц┤╗хЛХуБЧуБжуБДуБЯNGOуБоуАМуГЪуВ╖уГгуГпуГ╝уГлф╝ЪуАНуВДхдзф╜┐щдиуБоф║║уБкуБй70ф║║уБРуВЙуБДуБМщЫЖуБ╛уВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВх╝ПуБзуБпуАБф╕нцЭСуБХуВУуБМуВвуГХуВмуГЛуВ╣уВ┐уГ│уБоф║║уБиф╕Ач╖ТуБлуАБф╣╛уБДуБЯхЬЯхЬ░уВТчХСуБлхдЙуБИуВЛц┤╗хЛХуВТуБЧуБжуБДуВЛуГУуГЗуВкуВТшжЛуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуВвуГХуВмуГЛуВ╣уВ┐уГ│уБоуВвуГЦуГАуГкхдзф╜┐уБпуАМф╗КуАБчзБуБЯуБбуБохЫ╜уБпщЫгуБЧуБДцЩВф╗гуБлуБкуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуБМуАБф╕нцЭСуБХуВУуБоц┤╗хЛХуВТч╢ЪуБСуБкуБСуВМуБ░уБкуВКуБ╛уБЫуВУуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуВвуГХуВмуГЛуВ╣уВ┐уГ│уВТцФпщЕНуБЧуБжуБДуВЛуВ┐уГкуГРуГ│уБпуАБф╕нцЭСуБХуВУуБоф║Лф╗╢уБлуБдуБДуБжшк┐уБ╣уБжуБДуВЛуБишиАуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВуБЧуБЛуБЧуАБшк░уБМцТГуБгуБЯуБоуБЛуБ╛уБауВПуБЛуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЫуВУуАВ","answer":"ф╕нцЭСхУ▓уБХуВУуБМф║буБПуБкуБгуБж3х╣┤уААцЭ▒ф║муБохдзф╜┐щдиуБзхдЪуБПуБоф║║уБМчеИуВЛ"},{"question":"Toko-toko di dalam mallnya bagus, tapi toilet dan mushalanya sangat mengerikan. Toilet di setiap lantai hanya 1 sehingga selalu ada antrian panjang, drainase air yang buruk, toilet dan musala yang sangat kotor dan bau. Ini sangat mengecewakan untuk apa yang disebut mal kelas atas.Apakah klasifikasi sentimen dari kalimat ulasan di atas (Positif/Negatif/Netral)?Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya.Jawaban:","answer":"Kalimat tersebut dapat diklasifikasikan sebagai sentimen negatif. Alasannya adalah terdapat kata-kata bermakna negatif seperti: sangat mengerikan; buruk; kotor dan bau; mengecewakan."},{"question":"╨Ю╤В╨▓╨╡╤В╤М╤В╨╡ ╨╜╨░ ╨▓╨╛╨┐╤А╨╛╤Б: ╨║╨░╨║╨╕╨╡ ╤А╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨╕ ╨▓╤Е╨╛╨┤╨╕╨╗╨╕ ╨▓ ╤Б╨╛╤Б╤В╨░╨▓ ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨╛╨│╨╛ ╨б╨╛╤О╨╖╨░?","answer":"╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨╕╨╣ ╨б╨╛╤О╨╖ ╨▓╨║╨╗╤О╤З╨░╨╗ ╨▓ ╤Б╨╡╨▒╤П 15 ╤Б╨╛╤О╨╖╨╜╤Л╤Е ╤А╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║:- ╨а╨б╨д╨б╨а (╨а╨╛╤Б╤Б╨╕╨╣╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨д╨╡╨┤╨╡╤А╨░╤В╨╕╨▓╨╜╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨а╨╛╤Б╤Б╨╕╨╣╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨д╨╡╨┤╨╡╤А╨░╤Ж╨╕╤П,- ╨г╨║╤А╨░╨╕╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨г╨║╤А╨░╨╕╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨г╨║╤А╨░╨╕╨╜╨░,- ╨С╨╡╨╗╨╛╤А╤Г╤Б╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨С╨╡╨╗╨╛╤А╤Г╤Б╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░ ╨С╨╡╨╗╨░╤А╤Г╤Б╤М,- ╨У╤А╤Г╨╖╨╕╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨У╤А╤Г╨╖╨╕╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨У╤А╤Г╨╖╨╕╤П,- ╨Р╨╖╨╡╤А╨▒╨░╨╣╨┤╨╢╨░╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨Р╨╖╨╡╤А╨▒╨░╨╣╨┤╨╢╨░╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣ ╨Р╨╖╨╡╤А╨▒╨░╨╣╨┤╨╢╨░╨╜,- ╨Р╤А╨╝╤П╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨Р╤А╨╝╤П╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨Р╤А╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╤П,- ╨Ъ╨░╨╖╨░╤Е╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨Ъ╨░╨╖╨░╤Е╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣ ╨Ъ╨░╨╖╨░╤Е╤Б╤В╨░╨╜,- ╨г╨╖╨▒╨╡╨║╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨г╨╖╨▒╨╡╨║╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣ ╨г╨╖╨▒╨╡╨║╨╕╤Б╤В╨░╨╜,- ╨в╨░╨┤╨╢╨╕╨║╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨в╨░╨┤╨╢╨╕╨║╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╤Л╨╣ ╨в╨░╨┤╨╢╨╕╨║╨╕╤Б╤В╨░╨╜,- ╨в╤Г╤А╨║╨╝╨╡╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨в╤Г╤А╨║╨╝╨╡╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨в╤Г╤А╨║╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╤П,- ╨Ъ╨╕╤А╨│╨╕╨╖╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨Ъ╨╕╤А╨│╨╕╨╖╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨Ъ╨╕╤А╨│╨╕╨╖╨╕╤П (╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜),- ╨Ь╨╛╨╗╨┤╨░╨▓╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨Ь╨╛╨╗╨┤╨░╨▓╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨Ь╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╨▓╨░,- ╨Ы╨╕╤В╨╛╨▓╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨Ы╨╕╤В╨╛╨▓╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨Ы╨╕╤В╨▓╨░,- ╨Ы╨░╤В╨▓╨╕╨╣╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨Ы╨░╤В╨▓╨╕╨╣╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨Ы╨░╤В╨▓╨╕╤П,- ╨н╤Б╤В╨╛╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨б╨а (╨н╤Б╤В╨╛╨╜╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╨▓╨╡╤В╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨б╨╛╤Ж╨╕╨░╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨║╨░╤П ╨а╨╡╤Б╨┐╤Г╨▒╨╗╨╕╨║╨░) - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╜╨░╤П ╨н╤Б╤В╨╛╨╜╨╕╤П."},{"question":"Ny тАЬtendryтАЭ dia baiko na didy manondro olona hanatanteraka asa mazava iray, na manondro andraikitra horaisina, na manondro toerana haleha. Anjara manokana azonтАЩny olona ka mahatonga azy hiavaka aminтАЩny hafa ao anaty fiarahamonina.  Avy aminтАЩAndriamanitra ny tendry; antso manokana mba hanatanterahana andraikitra. Eo aminтАЩny fiarahamonina ankehitriny: dia hita ihany fa misy ny fanendrena ataonтАЩny manam-pahefana eo aminтАЩireo ambany fifehezany.  Na ihany koa avy aminтАЩny feonтАЩny vahoaka ny tendry.Misy hevi-dehibe roa ao amin'io lahatsoratra io , inona  avy izany ?","answer":"Ireto avy ny hevi-dehibe roa ao amin'io lahatsoratra io : 1) Famaritana ny atao hoe Tendry. 2) Ny loharano nipoirany Tendry ."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е╪з ╪з┘Д┘Б╪▒┘В ╪и┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘В╪з╪╣╪п╪к┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪│╪з╪и┘В╪к┘К┘Ж╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪з┘Д╪┤╪о╪╡ ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ┘К┘В╪╣ ┘Б┘К ╪║┘Д╪╖ ╪и╪з┘Д┘В╪з┘Ж┘И┘Ж ┘К╪▒┘К╪п ╪к╪╖╪и┘К┘В ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡ ╪з┘Д┘В╪з┘Ж┘И┘Ж┘К ┘Д┘Г┘Ж┘З ╪г╪о╪╖╪г ╪и╪з┘Д╪н┘Г┘Е ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н┘К╪н ╪и╪│╪и╪и ╪к┘И┘З┘Е╪М ╪и┘К┘Ж┘Е╪з ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ┘К╪п┘Б╪╣ ╪и╪з┘Д╪м┘З┘Д ╪и╪з┘Д┘В╪з┘Ж┘И┘Ж ┘К╪▒┘К╪п ╪з╪│╪к╪и╪╣╪з╪п ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡ ╪з┘Д┘В╪з┘Ж┘И┘Ж┘К ┘И╪╣╪п┘Е ╪к╪╖╪и┘К┘В┘З ╪и╪н╪м╪й ┘Г┘И┘Ж┘З ┘К╪м┘З┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡."},{"question":"\\"рдПрдХ рдЪрд┐рд╣рд╛рди\\" рдЙрдкрдиреНрдпрд╛рд╕рдХрд╛ рдЖрдзрд╛рд░рдорд╛ рджрд┐рдЗрдПрдХрд╛ рдкрд╛рддреНрд░рдХреЛ рдЪрд░рд┐рддреНрд░ рдЪрд┐рддреНрд░рдг рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реН : рдирд╛рдиреАрдердХреБрдБред","answer":"рдирд╛рдиреАрдердХреБрдБ рдЙрдкрдиреНрдпрд╛рд╕рдорд╛ рдкреНрд░рдореБрдЦ рдирд╛рд░реА рдкрд╛рддреНрд░рдХрд╛ рд░реБрдкрдорд╛ рдкрд░рд┐рдЪрд┐рдд рдЫреЗ ред рдК рдЕрд╖реНрдЯрдирд╛рд░рд╛рдирдХреА рдЫреЛрд░реА рд░ рд╢рд┐рд╡рдирд╛рд░рд╛рдирд╣рд░реБрдХреА рдмрд╣рд┐рдиреА рд╣реЛред рдЧреЛрд░реЛ рдЕрдиреБрд╣рд╛рд░ резрен рд╡рд░реНрд╖реЗ рд╕рд╛рд░реИ рд╣рд┐рд╕реА рдкрд░реЗрдХреА рдмреИрдВрд╕рд▓реЗ рдзрдкреНрдк рдмрд▓реЗрдХреА рд╕реБрдиреНрджрд░реА рдЫреЗред рд╕рд░рд▓ рд░ рдирд┐рд╢реНрдЪрд▓ рднрдПрдХреАрд▓реЗ рдбрд╛. рдЧреЛрджрддреНрддрдкреНрд░рд╕рд╛рджрдХреЛ рдмрд▓рд╛рддреНрдХрд╛рд░рдХреЛ рд╕рд┐рдХрд╛рд░ рднрдПрдХреА рдЫреЗред рдК рд╕рдХрд╛рд░рд╛рддреНрдордХ рдЫреЗред рдЙрд╕рд▓реЗ рддрд░рд╛рдИрдмрд╛рд╕реА рдЦреЗрд▓рд╛рд╡рди рд░рд╛рдЙрддрд╕рдБрдЧ рдЕрдиреНрддрд░ рдЬрд╛рддреАрдп рд╡рд┐рд╡рд╛рд╣ рдЧрд░реНрдЫреЗред рдК рдмрд▓рд╛рддреНрдХреГрдд рднрдИ рдХреБрдорд╛рд░реАрддреНрд╡рдмрд╛рдЯ рдирд╛рдиреАрдердХреБрдБ рдмрдЮреНрдЪрд┐рдд рднрдПрдХреА рдЫред"},{"question":"р╢Ьр╢Яр╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢пр╢з р╖Ар╖Рр╢зр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║  р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╢нр╢▒р╖Т р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╢╕р╖Эр╢║ "},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐ : роиро░ро┐, роорпБродро▓рпИропро┐роЯроорпН роОройрпНрой роХрпВро▒ро┐ропродрпБ?","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН :  1. тАЬроЗродро▒рпНроХрпБ роорпБройрпН роТро░рпБ роорпБродро▓рпИ, ро╡ро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХрпБроХро│рпИроЪрпН роЪро╛рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпНроЯродро╛ро▓рпН роЪрпЖро░ро┐рооро╛ройроорпН роЖроХро╛рооро▓рпН роЗро▒роирпНродрпБро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпБ.тАЭ2. тАЬро╡ро┐ро╖ роорпБро▒ро┐ро╡рпБроЪрпН роЪрпЖроЯро┐роХро│рпИ роиро╛роЩрпНроХро│рпН родро┐ройрпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│родро╛ро▓рпН, роОроЩрпНроХро│рпИ ропро╛ро░рпН роХроЯро┐родрпНродро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЗро▒роирпНродрпБро╡ро┐роЯрпБро╡ро░рпНтАЭ роОройрпНро▒рпБ роиро░ро┐ роорпБродро▓рпИропро┐роЯроорпН роХрпВро▒ро┐ропродрпБ."},{"question":"Ho├аn thiс╗Зn ─Сoс║бn v─Гn sau: Sau khi lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng Bс║пc Triс╗Бu Ti├кn tс║еn c├┤ng xuс╗Сng l├гnh thс╗Х Nam Triс╗Бu Ti├кn v├аo ng├аy 25 th├бng 6 n─Гm 1950, khiс║┐n","answer":"xung ─Сс╗Щt b├╣ng nс╗Х, Hoa Kс╗│ v├а c├бc n╞░с╗Ыc ─Рс╗Уng Minh ─С├г can thiс╗Зp nh├вn danh lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng Li├кn Hс╗гp Quс╗Сc. Sau khi bс╗Л bс║еt ngс╗Э, Tс╗Хng thс╗Сng Harry S. Truman ─С├г nhanh ch├│ng phс║гn с╗йng, ra lс╗Зnh gс╗нi lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng v├а ph╞░╞бng tiс╗Зn ─Сang tr├║ ─С├│ng tс║бi Nhс║нt Bс║гn ─Сс║┐n gi├║p ─Сс╗б lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng Nam Triс╗Бu Ti├кn, c├╣ng vс╗Ыi mс╗Щt lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng hс║гi qu├вn lс╗Ыn ─Сс║┐ khu vс╗▒c ─Сс╗Г hс╗Ч trс╗г. Nh╞░ mс╗Щt phс║зn cс╗зa viс╗Зc huy ─Сс╗Щng lс╗▒c l╞░с╗гng hс║гi qu├вn, \\"Iowa\\" ─С╞░с╗гc cho hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng trс╗Я lс║бi v├аo ng├аy 14 th├бng 7 n─Гm 1951 v├а ch├нnh thс╗йc nhс║нp bi├кn chс║┐ v├аo ng├аy 25 th├бng 8 n─Гm 1951 d╞░с╗Ыi quyс╗Бn chс╗Й huy cс╗зa Hс║бm tr╞░с╗Яng, ─Рс║бi t├б hс║гi qu├вn William R. Smedberg, III. Chiс║┐c thiс║┐t gi├бp hс║бm ─Сi ─Сс║┐n v├╣ng biс╗Гn Triс╗Бu Ti├кn v├аo th├бng 3 n─Гm 1952, n╞бi n├│ thay phi├кn cho t├аu chс╗Л em v├аo ng├аy 1 th├бng 4, v├а trс╗Я th├аnh so├бi hс║бm cho Ph├│ ─С├┤ ─Сс╗Сc Robert P. Briscoe, T╞░ lс╗Зnh ─Рс╗З Thс║еt hс║бm ─Сс╗Щi."},{"question":"чммф╕АхПе:хоГцШпч┤лшЙ▓чБпхЕЙхТМцИПхЙзцАзчЪДщШ│хЕЙчЪДч▓╛х╜йц╝ФхПШ. чммф║МхПе:ш┐ЩцШпч┤лшЙ▓чБпхЕЙхТМ<unk>чГВчЪДщШ│хЕЙчЪДцИПхЙзцАзхдНхИ╢. щЧощвШ:чммф╕АхПехТМчммф║МхПешбиш╛╛чЫ╕хРМчЪДцДПф╣ЙхРЧ? чЫ╕хРМш┐ШцШпф╕НхРМ?","answer":"ф╕НхРМ"},{"question":"Iza no nahazo Loka Oscar tamin'ny alalan'ny African Queen ? ","answer":"I Bogart no nahazo ny loka oscar tamin'ny alalan'ny african queen. "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ayam pemikat\\"?","answer":"Orang yang dijadikan sebagai umpan"},{"question":"Zer dira antiossidanteak eta zein da beren funtzioa?","answer":"Antiossidanteak kimika konposatuak dira, zelula kaltetuei erresistentzia ematen dutenak. Hauen funtzio nagusia radikal libreak neutralizatzea da, gaixotasun batzuk prebenitzeko."},{"question":"р░╡р▒Жр░Ьр░┐р░Яр░мр▒Бр░▓р▒Н р░░р▒Ир░╕р▒Н р░др░пр░╛р░░р▒А р░кр▒Нр░░р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр░ир▒Б р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░╡р▒Жр░Ьр░┐р░Яр░мр▒Бр░▓р▒Н р░░р▒Ир░╕р▒Н р░Хр░┐ р░Хр░╛р░╡р░▓р░╕р░┐р░и р░кр░жр░╛р░░р▒Нр░зр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░др░пр░╛р░░р▒А р░╡р░┐р░зр░╛р░ир░В:р░Хр░╛р░╡р░▓р░╕р░┐р░и р░кр░жр░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░╛р░▓р▒Б : р░мр░┐р░пр▒Нр░пр░В, р░Йр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░┐р░кр░╛р░п, р░Яр░ор▒Лр░Яр░╛, р░кр░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐ р░мр░ар░╛р░ир▒Ар░▓р▒Б, р░Хр▒Нр░пр░╛р░░р▒Жр░Яр▒Н, р░жр░╛р░▓р▒Нр░Ър░┐р░и р░Ър▒Жр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░▓р░╡р░Вр░Чр░╛р░▓р▒Б, р░кр░╕р▒Бр░кр▒Б р░кр▒Кр░бр░┐, р░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░кр▒Кр░бр░┐, р░ор░╕р░╛р░▓р░╛ р░кр▒Кр░бр░┐, р░Хр▒Кр░др▒Нр░др░┐р░ор▒Ар░░, р░ир▒Вр░ир▒Ж, р░ир▒Жр░пр▒Нр░пр░┐, р░Йр░кр▒Нр░кр▒Б р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░ир▒Ар░░р▒Б.р░др░пр░╛р░░р▒А р░╡р░┐р░зр░╛р░ир░В :1. р░мр░┐р░пр▒Нр░пр░В р░Хр░бр░┐р░Чр░┐ 10 р░ир▒Бр░Вр░бр░┐ 15 р░ир░┐р░ор░┐р░╖р░╛р░▓р▒Б р░ир░╛р░ир░мр▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░Вр░бр░┐.2. р░ор░Вр░Я р░ор▒Ар░ж р░кр░╛р░др▒Нр░░р░ир▒Б р░Йр░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐. р░Ер░Вр░жр▒Бр░▓р▒Л р░░р▒Жр░Вр░бр▒Б р░Ър▒Жр░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓ р░ир▒Жр░пр▒Нр░пр░┐, р░ир▒Вр░ир▒Ж р░кр▒Лр░пр░╛р░▓р░┐.3. р░жр░╛р░▓р▒Нр░Ър░┐р░и р░Ър▒Жр░Хр▒Нр░Х, р░▓р░╡р░Вр░Чр░В р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░Йр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░┐р░кр░╛р░п р░╡р▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░Чр▒Лр░зр▒Бр░о р░░р░Вр░Чр▒Б р░╡р░Ър▒Нр░Ър▒Зр░╡р░░р░Хр▒Б р░╡р▒Зр░бр░┐ р░Ър▒Зр░пр░╛р░▓р░┐.4. р░др░░р░┐р░Чр░┐р░и р░Яр░ор▒Лр░Яр░╛, р░Чр▒Нр░░р▒Ар░ир▒Н р░мр░ар░╛р░ир▒Ар░▓р▒Б, р░Хр▒Нр░пр░╛р░░р▒Жр░Яр▒Н р░Ьр▒Лр░бр░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.5. р░Хр░жр░┐р░▓р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░░р▒Жр░Вр░бр▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░жр░╛ р░ор▒Вр░бр▒Б р░ир░┐р░ор░┐р░╖р░╛р░▓р▒Б р░╡р▒Зр░пр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░┐.6. р░ир░╛р░ир░мр▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░┐р░и р░мр░┐р░пр▒Нр░пр░В, р░Чр░░р░В р░ор░╕р░╛р░▓р░╛ р░кр▒Кр░бр░┐, р░кр░╕р▒Бр░кр▒Б р░кр▒Кр░бр░┐, р░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░кр▒Кр░бр░┐ р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░Йр░кр▒Нр░кр▒Б р░Хр░▓р░кр░Вр░бр░┐.7. р░Хр░жр░┐р░▓р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒В 2 р░▓р▒Зр░жр░╛ 3 р░ир░┐р░ор░┐р░╖р░╛р░▓р▒Б р░╡р▒Зр░пр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░┐.8. р░др░░р▒Бр░╡р░╛р░д 1 р░▓р▒Зр░жр░╛ 2 р░Хр░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░ир▒Ар░░р▒Б р░╡р▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░мр░╛р░Чр░╛ р░Хр░▓р░кр░╛р░▓р░┐.9. р░Хр▒Бр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░░р▒Н р░ир▒Б р░ор▒Вр░др░др▒Л р░ор▒Вр░╕р░┐р░╡р▒Зр░╕р░┐, 2 р░╡р░┐р░Ьр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░╕р▒Н р░Хр▒Лр░╕р░В р░ор▒Ар░бр░┐р░пр░В р░ор░Вр░Я р░ор▒Ар░ж р░Йр░бр░┐р░Хр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░┐.10. р░ор░Вр░Яр░ир▒Б р░Жр░кр░┐р░╡р▒Зр░пр░Вр░бр░┐. р░Чр░жр░┐ р░Йр░╖р▒Нр░гр▒Лр░Чр▒Нр░░р░д р░╡р░жр▒Нр░ж р░Ър░▓р▒Нр░▓р░мр░░р░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.11. р░ор▒Вр░д р░Ьр░╛р░Чр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░др░Чр░╛ р░др▒Жр░░р░┐р░Ър░┐, р░╡р░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Вр░Ър▒З р░Чр░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир▒Жр░Хр▒Б р░мр░жр░┐р░▓р▒А р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐, р░др░╛р░Ьр░╛ р░Хр▒Кр░др▒Нр░др░┐р░ор▒Ар░░р░др▒Л р░Ер░▓р░Вр░Хр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐."},{"question":"р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╜р╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢║р╖Пр╢╜р╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖П  р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Ър╢п? ","answer":"р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╜р╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢║р╖Пр╢╜р╢║ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢Вр╖Бр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖П  р╢Зр╢н."},{"question":"2022 р╢йр╖Т р╖Ар╖Ыр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╢р╖Щр╢╜р╖К р╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╢║ р╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╢Ьр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢п?","answer":"Svante P├д├дbo р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢ер╢║р╖П"},{"question":"р░Хр░┐р░Вр░ж р░Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐р░и р░нр░╛р░╡р░В р░╡р░Ър▒Нр░Ър▒Зр░▓р░╛р░Чр░╛ р░кр░жр▒Нр░пр░В р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐:р░Ър▒Вр░╕р▒Зр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Б р░нр░пр░кр░бр▒Зр░Яр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░ир▒Ар░Яр░┐р░▓р▒Л р░нр░пр░Вр░Хр░░р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Тр░Х р░ор▒Кр░╕р░▓р░┐ р░Хр░Вр░Яр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░Хр░ир░кр░бр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░╡р░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐ р░╢р░┐р░╖р▒Нр░пр▒Бр░▓р░Вр░др░╛ р░мр▒Жр░жр░┐р░░р▒Зр░Яр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░жр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░гр▒Бр░ир░┐ р░кр░┐р░Хр▒Нр░Хр░ир▒Б р░╡р▒Жр░Вр░Яр░ир▒З р░кр░Яр▒Нр░Яр▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐.","answer":"р░Х. р░╡р▒Жр░▒р░Ър░▒р░╡ р░ир▒Ар░░р░┐р░▓р▒Л р░ир░╛р░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Ж р░ир▒Кр░Х р░ор▒Кр░╕р░▓р░┐ р░Ър▒Вр░бр▒Нр░Хр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░ир░Чр▒Лр░Ър░░ р░ор▒Ир░кр░▒р░др▒Жр░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Хр▒Бр░Вр░нр░╕р░Вр░нр░╡р▒Бр░Ър░┐р░▒р▒Бр░др▒Кр░б р░╡р░бр░┐р░Б р░мр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░┐р░Б р░Хр▒Кр░ир░┐р░пр▒Ж р░╢р░┐р░╖р▒Нр░пр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░мр▒Жр░жр░░р░ир▒Н."},{"question":"рж╕ржмрзБржЬ ржЖрж▓рзЛрждрзЗ рж╣рж▓рзБржж ржлрзБрж▓рзЗрж░ рж░ржЩ ржХрж┐?","answer":"ржПржХржЯрж┐ рж╣рж▓рзБржж ржлрзБрж▓ рж╣рж▓рзБржж ржжрзЗржЦрж╛ржпрж╝ ржХрж╛рж░ржг ржПржЯрж┐ рж╢рзБржзрзБржорж╛рждрзНрж░ рж╣рж▓рзБржж ржЖрж▓рзЛ ржкрзНрж░рждрж┐ржлрж▓рж┐ржд ржХрж░рзЗ ржПржмржВ ржЕржирзНржп рж╕ржм рждрж░ржЩрзНржЧржжрзИрж░рзНржШрзНржпрзЗрж░ ржЖрж▓рзЛ рж╢рзЛрж╖ржг ржХрж░рзЗред рждрж╛ржЗ ржпржжрж┐ рж╕ржмрзБржЬ ржЖрж▓рзЛ ржПржЯрж┐рж░ ржЙржкрж░ ржкржбрж╝рзЗ рждржмрзЗ ржПржЯрж┐ рж╕ржмрзБржЬ ржЖрж▓рзЛржХрзЗ рж╢рзЛрж╖ржг ржХрж░ржмрзЗ ржПржмржВ ржХрзЛржи рждрж░ржЩрзНржЧржжрзИрж░рзНржШрзНржпрзЗрж░ ржЖрж▓рзЛ ржкрзНрж░рждрж┐ржлрж▓рж┐ржд ржХрж░ржмрзЗ ржирж╛ рждрж╛ржЗ рж╕ржмрзБржЬ ржЖрж▓рзЛрж░ ржирзАржЪрзЗ ржПржХржЯрж┐ рж╣рж▓рзБржж ржлрзБрж▓ ржХрж╛рж▓рзЛ ржжрзЗржЦрж╛ржмрзЗред"},{"question":"Bel├йm ├й capital de qual estado brasileiro?","answer":"Par├б."},{"question":"р╢пр╖Щр╖Гр╖Рр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К 27 р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒ р╢Ър╢ор╖П р╢Ър╢╗р╢╕р╖Ф.","answer":"р╢пр╖Щр╖Гр╖Рр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К 27, р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Щр╢Ьр╢╗р╖Т р╢пр╖Тр╢▒ р╢пр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╢з р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖А р╢Ер╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢пр╖Ъ 361 р╖Ар╢▒ р╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖Ъ (р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Ер╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢пр╢Ъ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К 362 р╖Ар╢▒ р╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╢║). р╢Ер╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢п р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢пр╖Тр╢▒ р╖Гр╢нр╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢н."},{"question":"с╣вe ├аpilс║╣╠Аkс╗Н ├аyс╗Нk├а f├║n ├аk├▓r├н y├м├н: T.B Joshua: с╗Мjс╗Н╠Б ├мb├н ayс╗Н╠А f├║n mi ├аmс╗Н╠Б ┼Д k├▓ n├н l├и с╣гe ayс║╣yс║╣ с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б ├мb├н n├б├а.","answer":"с╗Мjс╗Н╠Б kej├мl├б, oс╣г├╣ ├Тkud├╣, l├│ yс║╣ k├н W├▓l├н├м T├иm├нtс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б Bal├│gun Joshua с╣гe с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б ├мb├н с╗Нd├║n m├йj├мd├нnlс╗Н╠Бgс╗Н╠Бta rс║╣╠А l├│k├и e├иpс║╣╠А. с╣в├╣gbс╗Н╠Бn ├│ с╣гeni l├б├аn├║ p├й ├│ k├║ n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kar├╣n-├║n, oс╣г├╣ ├Тkud├╣, с╣г├б├бj├║ с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б n├б├а, n├нgb├а t├│ ku с╗Н╠Аsс║╣╠А kan p├йr├й k├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б n├б├а k├▓. ├Аmс╗Н╠Б ╟╣kan t├│ t├║n jс║╣╠Б ├мy├аlс║╣╠Бnu ni p├й, w├▓l├н├м n├б├а ti sс╗Н n├нpa с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б-├мb├н rс║╣╠А p├й ├▓un k├▓ n├н с╣гe ayс║╣yс║╣ kankan n├н с╗Нd├║n y├м├н. N├нnu f├нd├н├▓ kan t├│ j├бde s├│r├н ay├йluj├бra lс║╣╠Бy├мn ik├║ rс║╣╠А, Joshua ┼Д kс╗Н orin с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б ├мb├н f├║n ara rс║╣╠А p├й \\"Happy Birthday to you....\\" N├нbс║╣╠А n├б├а l├│ s├м ti k├йde p├й ├▓un k├▓ n├н с╣гe ayс║╣yс║╣ с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б-├мb├н kankan n├н с╗Нd├║n y├м├н n├нtor├н p├й ├аwс╗Нn ├мс╣гс║╣╠Аlс║╣╠А t├│ ┼Д w├бy├й n├н ├аgb├бy├й k├▓ d├╣n mс╗Н╠Б ├▓un n├нn├║. ├У n├н \\"k├▓ n├н rс╗Нr├╣n f├║n mi l├бti с╣гe ├аjс╗Нyс╗Н╠А с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б-├мb├н mi, n├нtor├н p├й с╗Н╠Аpс╗Н╠А ├и├иy├аn t├│ fс║╣╠Бс║╣╠А w├а n├н w├аh├бl├а ├аti ├мd├аm├║ t├│ ┼Д с╣гс║╣lс║╣╠А n├н ├аgb├бy├й ┼Д bani n├нn├║ jс║╣╠Б. ├Мb├аn├║jс║╣ ├аti ├мbс║╣╠Аr├╣ wс╗Н╠Бn k├аn m├н. N├нtor├н n├б├а, с║╣ jс║╣╠Б k├н ├б fi с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б n├б├а с╣гe с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б ├аwс║╣╠А ├аti ├бd├╣r├б, kс║╣╠Бс║╣ m├б s├м gb├аgb├й ├аwс╗Нn al├б├мn├н.\\" ├У n├н \\"l├бgb├бra с╗Мlс╗Н╠Бrun, с╗Н╠Аpс╗Н╠А ayс║╣yс║╣ с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б-├мb├н s├м w├а n├нw├бj├║ f├║n mi t├бa m├бa с╣гe.\\" B├│ tilс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б p├й ├│ kс╗Н orin с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б-├мb├н f├║n ara rс║╣╠А n├нnu f├нd├н├▓ n├б├а, ol├│├▓gb├й T.B Joshua sс╗Н p├й с╗Н╠Аpс╗Н╠Аlс╗Нpс╗Н╠А с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б-├мb├н l├│ s├м w├а n├нw├бj├║ l├бti с╣гe. N├нgb├а ay├й rс║╣╠А, с║╣lс║╣╠Бyinj├║ ├а├бn├║, ol├│ore ├аti ol├╣fif├║nni ni с╗Н╠Аpс╗Н╠А ├и├иy├аn mс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Б s├н, p├а├бp├а├б ├аwс╗Нn ol├│l├╣fс║╣╠Б rс║╣╠А. ╟╕kan y├м├н n├б├а s├м ni ├аwс╗Нn ├и├иy├аn kan ┼Д sс╗Н n├нpa rс║╣╠А l'├│r├н ay├йluj├бra."},{"question":"Qual foi o maior goleador do Brasileir├гo no ano de 2022?","answer":"No Campeonato Brasileiro de 2022, o maior goleador foi Germ├бn Cano conhecido como Cano, do Fluminense. Ele marcou um total de 26 gols durante o torneio."},{"question":"р╕Яр╣Йр╕▓р╕Ьр╣Ир╕▓р╣Ар╕Бр╕┤р╕Фр╕Ир╕▓р╕Бр╕нр╕░р╣Др╕г","answer":"р╣Ар╕Бр╕┤р╕Фр╕Ир╕▓р╕Бр╕Бр╕▓р╕гр╕Ыр╕ер╕Фр╕Ыр╕ер╣Ир╕нр╕вр╕Ыр╕гр╕░р╕Ир╕╕р╣Др╕Яр╕Яр╣Йр╕▓р╕нр╕нр╕Бр╕Ир╕▓р╕Бр╣Ар╕бр╕Жр╕Эр╕Щр╕Яр╣Йр╕▓р╕Др╕░р╕Щр╕нр╕З р╕лр╕гр╕╖р╕н р╣Ар╕бр╕Жр╕Др╕┤р╕зр╕бр╕╣р╣Вр╕ер╕Щр╕┤р╕бр╕Ър╕▒р╕к (cumulonimbus)"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛ : роХрпАро┤рпНроХрпНроХроЯро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпН роЖро╡ро┐ роОройрпНро▒ роЪрпКро▓рпНро▓ро┐ройрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН ропро╛родрпБ? роЕ) роЙропро┐ро░рпНроЖ) рооро░роорпНроЗ) роХрпБродро┐ро░рпИроИ) роЙроЯро▓рпН","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ : роЕ) роЙропро┐ро░рпН"},{"question":"р░Ер░др░┐р░╢р░пр▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др▒Нр░пр░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░гр░▓р▒Б р░Зр░╡р▒Нр░╡р░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░Ер░др░┐р░╢р░пр▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др▒Нр░пр░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░В :р░▓р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░гр░В :р░Тр░Х р░╡р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░╡р▒Б р░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Чр░╛р░ир░┐, р░Тр░Х р░╕р░Вр░жр░░р▒Нр░нр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Чр░╛р░ир░┐, р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░жр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░Вр░Яр▒З р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡р░Чр░╛ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░┐р░ир░Яр▒Нр░▓р░пр░┐р░др▒З р░жр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ тАШр░Ер░др░┐р░╢р░пр▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др▒Нр░пр░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░ВтАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░Ер░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░г 1:р░ир░Чр░░р░Вр░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐ р░нр░╡р░ир░╛р░▓р▒Б р░ир░Хр▒Нр░╖р░др▒Нр░░р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░др░╛р░Хр▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░┐.р░╕р░ор░ир▒Нр░╡р░пр░В :р░кр▒И р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░г р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░ир░Чр░░р░Вр░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐ р░ор▒Зр░бр░▓р▒Б р░ор░┐р░Хр▒Нр░Хр░┐р░▓р░┐ р░Ор░др▒Нр░др░пр░┐р░ир░╡р░┐ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░бр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░мр░жр▒Бр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░ир░Хр▒Нр░╖р░др▒Нр░░р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░др░╛р░Хр▒Бр░Ър▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░ир░┐ р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡р░Чр░╛ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░бр░В р░Ьр░░р░┐р░Чр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ер░Вр░жр▒Бр░╡р░▓р▒Нр░▓ р░жр▒Ар░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ тАШр░Ер░др░┐р░╢ р░пр▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др▒Нр░пр░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░ВтАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░Ер░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░г 2:р░ор░╛ р░Ър▒Жр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Жр░▓р▒Б р░др░╛р░Яр░┐р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░Вр░д р░кр▒Кр░бр░╡р▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐.р░жр▒Зр░╡р░╛р░▓р░п р░Чр▒Лр░кр▒Бр░░р░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Жр░Хр░╛р░╢р░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░┐.р░кр▒И р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Л р░Ър▒Жр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Ж р░Ор░др▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Б, р░Чр▒Лр░кр▒Бр░░р░╛р░▓ р░Ор░др▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р░ир▒Б р░Йр░ир▒Нр░и р░Ор░др▒Нр░др▒Б р░Хр░Вр░Яр▒З р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░бр░В р░Ьр░░р░┐р░Чр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░Хр░жр░╛! р░Ер░Вр░Яр▒З р░Ер░др░┐р░╢р░пр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░бр░В р░Ер░ир▒Нр░ир░ор░╛р░Я. р░Зр░▓р░╛ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░Яр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Ер░др░┐р░╢р░пр▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐ р░Ер░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░г 3 :р░Хр░В. р░Ър▒Бр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░▓р▒Б р░др░▓ р░кр▒Вр░╡р▒Бр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛р░Ер░Хр▒Нр░Хр░Ьр░ор▒Бр░Ч р░ор▒Зр░ир▒Бр░кр▒Жр░Вр░Ър░┐ р░пр░Вр░мр░░ р░╡р▒Ар░зр░┐р░ир▒Н р░╡р▒Жр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░╕р░ор▒И р░Ър▒Вр░кр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░┐р░ир░Ер░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Лр░ор░▓р░┐ р░ор▒Бр░жр░ор▒Б р░ир▒Кр░Вр░жр▒Ж р░Жр░др▒Нр░ор░╕р▒Нр░ер░┐р░др░┐р░▓р▒Лр░ир▒Н.р░Зр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░б р░Ър▒Бр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░▓р░ир▒Б р░др░▓ р░кр▒Вр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Бр░Хр▒Кр░ир░┐, р░Жр░Хр░╛р░╢р░ор░Вр░д р░Ор░др▒Нр░др▒Б р░кр▒Жр░░р░┐р░Чр░╛р░бр░ир░┐, р░╣р░ир▒Бр░ор░Вр░др▒Бр░бр░┐р░ир░┐ р░Чр▒Вр░░р▒Нр░Ър░┐ р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡р░Чр░╛р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░бр░В р░Ьр░░р░┐р░Чр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ер░Вр░жр▒Бр░╡р░▓р▒Нр░▓ р░Зр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░б р░Ер░др░┐р░╢р░пр▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐ р░Ер░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░жр░┐.р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░г 4:р░ор░╛ р░кр▒Кр░▓р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░мр░Вр░Чр░╛р░░р░В р░кр░Вр░бр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. р░╕р░╛р░зр░╛р░░р░гр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░кр▒Кр░▓р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░кр░Вр░Я р░кр░Вр░бр▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Хр░╛р░ир░┐ р░мр░╛р░Чр░╛ р░кр░Вр░Я р░кр░Вр░бр░┐р░Вр░жр░ир▒З р░╡р░┐р░╖р░пр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░др▒Жр░▓р░┐р░п р░Ьр▒Зр░пр░бр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░мр░Вр░Чр░╛р░░р░В р░кр░Вр░бр░┐р░Вр░жр░ир░┐ р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡р░Чр░╛ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░бр░В р░Ьр░░р░┐р░Чр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ер░Вр░жр▒Бр░╡р░▓р▒Нр░▓ р░Зр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░б р░Ер░др░┐р░╢р░пр▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐ р░Ер░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░жр░┐."},{"question":"Mubvunzo: zita guru remapfupa ose ari mumusoro nderekuti Mhinduro:","answer":"dehenya"},{"question":"р╢▒р╖Тр╢пр╖Др╖Гр╖К р╢Ер╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢┤р╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╢▒р╖Тр╢пр╖Др╖Гр╖К р╢Ер╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢┤р╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖П р╖Гр╖У. р╢йр╢╢р╖Кр╢╜р╖Тр╖Ар╖К. р╢йр╢╢р╖Кр╢╜р╖Тр╖Ар╖К. р╢Ър╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╢╗ р╢╕р╖Др╢нр╖Пр╢║."},{"question":"р░Хр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░╢р▒Нр░ир░Хр▒Б р░╕р░ор░╛р░зр░╛р░ир░В р░Зр░╡р▒Нр░╡р░Вр░бр░┐:р░╡р░╛р░пр▒Б р░Ер░гр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓ р░╕р▒Нр░╡р▒Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ыр░╛р░Вр░╢ р░Ер░ир░Чр░╛ р░Пр░ор░┐?","answer":"р░Тр░Х р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╕р▒Нр░ер░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐ р░Хр░гр░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░ор▒Кр░др▒Нр░др░ор▒Б р░Ор░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░╕р▒Нр░╡р░др░Вр░др▒Нр░░ р░кр░жр▒Нр░зр░др▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Л р░╢р░Хр▒Нр░др░┐р░ир░┐ р░Чр▒Нр░░р░╣р░┐р░Вр░Ър░Чр░▓р░╡р▒Л р░Ж р░╕р░Вр░Цр▒Нр░пр░ир▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░╡р▒Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ыр░╛р░Вр░╢р░▓р▒Б р░Ер░ир░┐ р░Ер░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Йр░жр░╛: р░Ер░Вр░др░░р░╛р░│р░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Л р░╕р▒Нр░╡р▒Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ыр░Чр░╛ р░Ър░▓р░┐р░Вр░Ър░Чр░▓ р░Хр░гр░ор▒Бр░ир░Хр▒Б 3 р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░ир░╛р░Вр░др░░ р░╕р▒Нр░╡р▒Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ыр░╛р░Вр░╢р░▓р▒Б р░Йр░Вр░бр▒Бр░ир▒Б.р░Пр░Х р░кр░░р░ор░╛р░гр▒Бр░Х р░╡р░╛р░пр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓ р░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐ р░Ер░гр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б 3 р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░ир░╛р░Вр░др░░ р░╕р▒Нр░╡р▒Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ыр░╛р░Вр░╢р░▓р▒Б р░ор░╛р░др▒Нр░░р░ор▒З р░Йр░Вр░бр▒Бр░ир▒Б. р░жр▒Нр░╡р░┐р░кр░░р░ор░╛р░гр▒Бр░Х р░╡р░╛р░пр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐ р░Ер░гр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б 3 р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░ир░╛р░Вр░др░░, 2 р░нр▒Нр░░р░ор░г р░Ър░▓р░и р░Ер░ир░Чр░╛ р░ор▒Кр░др▒Нр░др░ор▒Б 5 р░╕р▒Нр░╡р▒Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ыр░╛р░Вр░╢р░▓р▒Б р░Йр░Вр░бр▒Бр░ир▒Б."},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay fiara be mpividy izay tsy maintsy novaina ny anarany vao afaka novarotana tao espana noho ny dikan'ilay anarana amin'ny fiteny tany ?","answer":"Ny anaran'ilay fiara nalaza sy be mpividy izay tsy maintsy novaina ny anarany vao afaka novarotana tao espana dia ny 'Nova' izay midika hoe tsy mandeha raha adika amin'ny fiteny espaniola. "},{"question":"┘Е╪з ┘З┘К ╪з┘Д╪│┘И╪▒╪й ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪к╪│┘Е┘Й (╪з┘Д╪│╪з┘З╪▒╪й) ╪г┘И (╪з┘Д╪╖╪з┘Е╪й)╪Я","answer":"╪│┘И╪▒╪й ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪з╪▓╪╣╪з╪к"},{"question":"Quelle est une astuce pour mieux dormir la nuit ?","answer":"Manger des noix, du miel ou un yogourt ! Ces aliments ont des composantes qui favorisent le sommeil."},{"question":"┬┐Cu├бl es la capital de Caldas, Colombia?","answer":"La capital del departamento de Caldas es la ciudad de Manizales."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:родро╛ройрпН роЕро▒ро┐ропро╛род роТройрпНро▒рпИ роЕро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро╡родро▒рпНроХро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ройро╡рпБро╡родрпБ тАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАж..роЕ) роЕро▒ро┐ро╡ро┐ройро╛роЖ) роЕро▒ро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройро╛роЗ) роРропро╡ро┐ройро╛роИ) роПро╡ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ройро╛","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ :роЖ) роЕро▒ро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройро╛"},{"question":"Milloin jogurttia saa mainostaa kreikkalaiseksi?","answer":"Jogurttia saa mainostaa kreikkalaiseksi, josjogurtti on valmistettu Kreikassa, jolloin se kuvaa elintarvikkeen alkuper├дmaata taijogurtin ainesosan koostumus ja maku muistuttaa kyseisess├д maassa yleisesti valmistettua ja nautittua jogurttia. T├дll├╢in esimerkiksi kreikkalaisenjogurtin nimi on yleiseen k├дytt├╢├╢n vakiintunut nimi, jonka valmistukseen on k├дytetty mikrobiviljelm├д├д, hapatetta, joka antaa kyseisen maan jogurtille ominaisen luonteen."},{"question":"SuтАЩaal: Sheeg Salaada Faralka (Waajib) Ah Oo Haweenka Waajib Ku Ahayn?","answer":"Jawaab: Waa Salaada Jimcaha Ah."},{"question":"р░╡р░░р▒Нр░др░Хр░ор▒Б р░Ер░Вр░Яр▒З р░Пр░ор░┐р░Яр░┐?","answer":"р░╡р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓ р░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Бр░Чр▒Лр░▓р▒Б, р░Ер░ор▒Нр░ор░Хр░╛р░▓ р░кр▒Нр░░р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░пр░ир▒Б р░╡р░░р▒Нр░др░Хр░ор▒Б р░Ер░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б. р░╡р░░р▒Нр░др░Хр░ор▒Б р░╡р░╛р░гр░┐р░Ьр▒Нр░пр░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Л р░кр▒Нр░░р░зр░╛р░и р░нр░╛р░Чр░ор▒Б. р░╡р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Б р░╕р▒Зр░╡р░▓ р░Йр░др▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐р░жр░╛р░░р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░╡р░╛р░Яр░┐р░ир░┐ р░╡р░┐р░ир░┐р░пр▒Лр░Чр░┐р░Вр░Ър▒З р░╡р░┐р░ир░┐р░пр▒Лр░Чр░жр░╛р░░р▒Бр░▓ р░╡р░жр▒Нр░жр░Хр▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░░р▒Нр░Ър░┐ р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐ р░ор░зр▒Нр░п р░╕р░Вр░мр░Вр░зр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░ир▒Жр░▓р░Хр▒Кр░▓р▒Нр░кр▒Зр░Яр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ер░ир░Чр░╛ р░Йр░др▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐р░ир░┐ р░╡р░┐р░ир░┐р░пр▒Лр░Чр░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Лр░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░др▒Зр░╡р░Яр░ор▒З р░╡р░░р▒Нр░др░Хр░ор▒Б, р░╡р░╛р░гр░┐р░Ьр▒Нр░п р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░пр░Хр░▓р░╛р░кр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Нр░ир▒А р░╡р░░р▒Нр░др░Хр░ор▒Б р░Ър▒Бр░Яр▒Нр░Яр▒В р░др░┐р░░р▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░др░╛р░пр░┐."},{"question":"р░Хр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░ор▒Бр░ир░┐ р░╕р░Вр░пр▒Бр░Хр▒Нр░д  р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░ор░╛р░░р▒Нр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.р░Жр░пр░и р░Хр░╡р░┐. р░Жр░пр░и р░Чр░╛р░пр░Хр▒Бр░бр▒Б. р░Жр░пр░и р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╡р▒Зр░др▒Нр░д.","answer":"р░Жр░пр░и р░Хр░╡р░┐, р░Чр░╛р░пр░Хр▒Бр░бр▒Б р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╡р▒Зр░др▒Нр░д. р░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░др░╛р░жр░┐ р░╕р░Вр░зр░┐"},{"question":"Aarс║╣ Buhari ko gbс╗Нdс╗Н pa SARS rс║╣, gbс╗Нn-in gbс╗Нn-in la wa lс║╣yin wс╗Нn-Awс╗Нn gomina ilс║╣ Hausa","answer":"Lasiko ti gbogbo araalu n pariwo, to fi mс╗Н awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н Naijiria ti wс╗Нn wa loke okun, pe ki wс╗Нn fopin si с║╣ka ileeс╣гс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ti wс╗Нn ya sс╗Нtс╗Н lati maa gbogun ti idigunjale ati iwa с╗Нdaran gbogbo ti wс╗Нn n pe ni SARS, с╗Нtс╗Н ni ibi ti awс╗Нn gomina ilс║╣ Hausa sun, ti wс╗Нn dori kс╗Н. Awс╗Нn gomina to wa lawс╗Нn ipinlс║╣ kaakiri ilс║╣ Hausa ti sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn fara mс╗Н SARS ni tawс╗Нn, wс╗Нn ni ko maa lс╗Н bс║╣с║╣, ijс╗Нba ko gbс╗Нdс╗Н fagi le e.Nile ijс╗Нba, niluu Abuja, lawс╗Нn gomina ilс║╣ Hausa с╗Нhun kora wс╗Нn lс╗Н lтАЩс╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, с╗Нsс║╣ yii, ohun ti wс╗Нn si lawс╗Нn n fс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н ijс╗Нba Buhari ni pe ko da ajс╗Н SARS pada, ko ma с╣гe da awс╗Нn to n с╣гewс╗Нde kiri pe awс╗Нn ko fс║╣ wс╗Нn mс╗Н lohun rara.Bi wс╗Нn с╣гe pari ipade wс╗Нn pс║╣lu Aarс║╣ ni alaga awс╗Нn gomina Hausa yii Gomina Lalong, ba awс╗Нn oniroyin sс╗Нrс╗Н, ohun to si sс╗Н ni pe ipa nla ni awс╗Нn с║╣с╣гс╗Н с╗Нhun n ko ti a ba n sс╗Н nipa eto idaabobo awс╗Нn eeyan ati dukia lagbegbe awс╗Нn.Lalong fi kun с╗Нrс╗Н с║╣ pe ki i с╣гe gbogbo awс╗Нn с║╣с╣гс╗Н to wa ninu SARS naa ni iwa wс╗Нn ko dara, ati pe awс╗Нn kan wa ninu wс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn wulo gidi, ti wс╗Нn si n с╣гiс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn bo ti yс║╣.Gomina yii waa kadii с╗Нrс╗Н с║╣ nilс║╣ pс║╣lu alaye pe bo tilс║╣ jс║╣ pe awс╗Нn eeyan kan lorile-ede yii fara mс╗Н ki wс╗Нn fagi le awс╗Нn с║╣с╣гс╗Н с╗Нhun, sibс║╣, ohun ti с║╣ka agbofinro с╗Нhun nilo ni atunto gidi, eyi ti yoo jс║╣ ki wс╗Нn le jawс╗Н ninu iwa ibajс║╣, ti wс╗Нn yoo si mu iс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn bii iс╣гс║╣."},{"question":"рджрд┐рдЗрдПрдХреЛ рдЯреБрдХреНрдХрд╛рдХреЛ рдЕрд░реНрде рдкрд╣рд┐рд▓реНрдпрд╛рдИ рддреЗрд╕реНрд▓рд╛рдИ рд╡рд╛рдХреНрдпрдорд╛ рдкреНрд░рдпреЛрдЧ рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реН :рдЖрдБрдЦрд╛ рдЪрд┐рдореНрд▓рд┐рдиреБ ","answer":"рдЖрдБрдЦрд╛ рдЪрд┐рдореНрд▓рд┐рдиреБ : рджреЗрдЦреЗрдХреЛ рдирджреЗрдЦреА рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╕рдВрд╡рд┐рдзрд╛рдирдХреЛ рд╕рдВрд░рдХреНрд╖рдХ рд░рд╛рд╖реНрдЯреНрд░рдкрддрд┐рд▓реЗ рдЖрдБрдЦрд╛ рдЪрд┐рдореНрд▓рд┐рдиреБ рд╡рд┐рдбрдореНрдмрдирд╛ рдХреБрд░рд╛ рдЫ ред "},{"question":"Velona tsy misy fofonaina aho, ary mangatsiaka toy ny fahafatesana. Tsy mangetaheta mihitsy aho fa misotro foana. Inona moa aho?","answer":" trondro. Velona tsy mifoka rivotra,, miaina anaty rano ary \\"misotro\\" rano amin'ny osmosis."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagaimana ditanam, begitulah dituai\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud tiap-tiap kejahatan itu, kejahatan jugalah akan balasannya."},{"question":"сКе.сКа.сКа сЙа1927 сКесИ╡сИн сИ╡сЛ╡сИ╡сЙ╡ сЛисИЭсИ╡сИН сМИсМ╜сЙ│сЛОсЙ╜сКХ сЙасКасКХсЛ╡ сИ░сКисКХсЛ╡ сКисЛЛсИ╜сКХсМНсЙ░сКХ сЛ▓сИ▓ сЛИсЛ░ сКТсЛНсЛосИнсКн сКисЙ░сИЫ сЙасИ╜сЙж сЛисИЛсКисЛН сК╕сИнсЙасИнсЙ╡ сКасЛнсЙнсИ╡ сЛисЛисЙ╡сКЫсЛН сЛ╡сИнсМЕсЙ╡ сИ░сИлсЙ░сКЫ сКРсЙасИн?","answer":"сЛисЙдсИН сИЛсЙесИлсЙ╖сИн(сИЛсЙжсИлсЙ╢сИк)"},{"question":"рд╡рд╛рдЪреНрдпрдВ рд╢реНрд░рджреНрдзрд╛рд╕рдореЗрддрд╕реНрдп рдкреГрдЪреНрдЫрдХрд╕реНрдп рд╡рд┐рд╢реЗрд╖рддрдГ |рдкреНрд░реЛрдХреНрддрдВ рд╢реНрд░рджреНрдзрд╛рд╡рд┐рд╣реАрдирд╛рдп рд╣реНрдпрд░рдгреНрдпрд░реБрджрд┐рддрдВ рднрд╡реЗрддреНтАМ ||","answer":"рдЕрд░реНрде : рдЬреНрдпрд╛рдЪрд╛ [рдЖрдкрд▓реНрдпрд╛рд╡рд░] рд╡рд┐рд╢реНрд╡рд╛рд╕ рдЖрд╣реЗ рдЖрдгрд┐ рдЬрд╛рд╕реНрддрдХрд░реВрди рдЬреНрдпрд╛рдиреЗ рдЖрдкрд▓реНрдпрд╛рд▓рд╛ [рддреНрдпрд╛рдмрджреНрджрд▓] рд╡рд┐рдЪрд╛рд░рд▓реЗрд▓реЗ рдЖрд╣реЗ рдЕрд╢рд╛ [рдорд╛рдгрд╕рд╛рд▓рд╛рдЪ рдЙрдкрджреЗрд╢] рд╕рд╛рдВрдЧрд╛рд╡рд╛ рдкрдг рд╡рд┐рд╢реНрд╡рд╛рд╕ рдирд╕рдгрд╛рд▒реНрдпрд╛рд▓рд╛ рд╕рд╛рдВрдЧрд┐рддрд▓реЗ рддрд░ рддреЗ рдХрд╖реНрдЯ рд╡реНрдпрд░реНрде рдЬрд╛рддреАрд▓."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ╪з┘Д╪┤╪ж ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ┘Г╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪и┘К ╪╡┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ┘И╪│┘Д┘Е ┘Д╪з ┘К╪▒╪п┘З╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪╖┘К╪и "},{"question":"Imaamu ilс║╣ Ibadan tako aс╣гс║╣ awс╗Нn olori Islam, o kirun yidi lтАЩAgodi","answer":"Pс║╣lu bi igbimс╗Н National Supreme Council for Islamic Affairs (NSCIA) с╣гe kede pe aawс║╣ Ramadan gbс╗Нdс╗Н tс║╣siwaju lтАЩс╗Мjс╗Нruu, с╗Нjс╗Н kejila, oс╣гu karun-un, с╗Нdun 2021, nitori awс╗Нn ko ti i ri oс╣гu Shawal to kan lс║╣yin Lamulana yii, Imaamu Ilс║╣ Ibadan, Alaaji AbdulGaniu Abubakry Agbс╗Нtс╗Нmс╗Нkekere, ti с╣гaaju irun yidi fawс╗Нn eeyan lтАЩAgodi, wс╗Нn ni aawс║╣ tawс╗Нn ti pari lс╗Нdun yii na.Olubadan ilс║╣ Ibadan, с╗Мba Saliu Adetunji, naa wa lara awс╗Нn to kirun lс║╣yin Imaamu yii, bс║╣с║╣ ni Igbakeji gomima ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н, Alaaji Rauf с╗Мlaniyan, naa kirun Yidi laaarс╗Н oni, lс║╣yin Imaamu Agbс╗Нtс╗Нmс╗Нkekere.Ana ode yii ti i с╣гe с╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun ni Imaamu ilс║╣ Ibadan ti kede loju opo Fesibuuku rс║╣, pe oun yoo kirun lowurс╗Н с╗Мjс╗Нruu, nitori mс╗Нkandinlс╗Нgbс╗Нn laaawс║╣, o si ti pe.Bo tilс║╣ jс║╣ pe Yidi Agodi naa ko kun to bo с╣гe maa n kun tс║╣lс║╣, nitori с╗Нpс╗Н eeyan с╣гi n gbaawс║╣ Ramadan gс║╣gс║╣ bii aс╣гс║╣ awс╗Нn olori с║╣sin Islam, sibс║╣, awс╗Нn araalu kс╗Нс╗Нkan naa ti wс╗Нn lawс╗Нn ko gbaawс║╣ mс╗Н, darapс╗Н mс╗Н wс╗Нn lтАЩAgodi, wс╗Нn si kirun.с║╕ oo ranti pe lс╗Нdun kс║╣ta sс║╣yin, nigba ti wс╗Нn ni с╗Нgbс╗Нn (30) ni aawс║╣ с╗Нdun naa, Imaamu Agbс╗Нtс╗Нmс╗Нkekere ko duro gba с╗Нgbс╗Нn, lс║╣yin с╗Нjс╗Н kс╗Нkandinlс╗Нgbс╗Нn lo с╣гiwaju irun yidi fawс╗Нn to tс║╣le e."},{"question":"Bendera Pusaka Sang Saka Merah Putih adalah Bendera Merah-Putih yang pertama kali dikibarkan adalah bendera yang dijahit oleh Ibu Fatmawati pada proklamasi Kemerdekaan Indonesia tanggal 17 Agustus 1945.Apakah bendera yang dikibarkan pada upacara kemerdekaan Republik Indonesia ke-78, 17 Agustus 2023, adalah Bendera Pusaka Sang Saka Merah Putih? Berikan jawaban beserta alasannya.Jawaban:","answer":"Tidak. Bendera Pusaka Sang Saka Merah Putih terus dikibarkan pada upacara peringatan hari kemerdekaan Indonesia di Istana Merdeka hingga tahun 1968, kemudian diganti dengan bendera replika dari bahan sutera. Bendera replika itulah yang terus dikibarkan hingga kini, sementara Bendera Pusaka yang asli disimpan di Monumen Nasional karena sudah pudar dan rapuh."},{"question":"┘Б┘К ╪г┘К ┘В╪з╪▒╪й ┘К┘И╪м╪п ╪м┘Ж┘И╪и ┘Г┘И╪▒┘К╪з╪Я","answer":"┘К┘И╪м╪п ╪м┘Ж┘И╪и ┘Г┘И╪▒┘К╪з ┘Б┘К ┘В╪з╪▒╪й ╪в╪│┘К╪з."},{"question":"Shin batun me ake a wannan jumlar mai zuwa? \\"Ana sa ran mahaukaciyar guguwar teku ta maria zata ratsa a martinique da kuma dominica\\":(a) Lafiya(b) Najeriya(c) Duniya(d) Siyasa(e) Afirka","answer":"Jumlar \\"Ana sa ran mahaukaciyar guguwar teku ta maria zata ratsa a martinique da kuma dominica\\" na batu ne a kan (c) Duniya."},{"question":"Midika inona ny vodiondry eo amin'ny fanambadiana Malagasy?","answer":"Ny dikan'ny vodiondry eo amin'ny fanambadiana Malagasy dia : -Fatoram-panam-badiana.-Fanajana ny ray aman-dreny sy ny fianakaviana"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira da Venezuela.","answer":"A bandeira da Venezuela ├й composta por tr├кs faixas horizontais: amarela na parte superior, azul no meio e vermelha na parte inferior, com sete estrelas brancas no meio da faixa azul."},{"question":"родрооро┐ро┤рпНродро╛ропрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНродрпНродрпБ роОро┤рпБродро┐ропро╡ро░рпН ропро╛ро░рпН?","answer":"родрооро┐ро┤рпНродро╛ропрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНродрпНродрпБ роОро┤рпБродро┐ропро╡ро░рпН рооройрпЛройрпНроорогро┐ропроорпН роЪрпБроирпНродро░роорпН рокро┐ро│рпНро│рпИ ."},{"question":"Waa maxay macnaha  \\"lihid\\" ee Af-soomaaliga? ","answer":" Lihid:macnaheedu waa eray ku tusaya kuuna sheegaya qof walax leh."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ╪г┘Г╪и╪▒ ┘Е╪н┘К╪╖ ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪╣╪з┘Д┘Е╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪з┘Д┘Е╪н┘К╪╖ ╪з┘Д┘З╪з╪п┘К"},{"question":"Apakah soalan kepada: \\"Pada 11 Mei 2012, siri ini diperbaharui untuk musim kesembilan, yang ditayangkan pada 27 September 2012\\"? Topiknya ialah Anatomi Grey.","answer":"\\"berapakah musim Grey's Anatomy?\\""},{"question":"р╖Ар╢В р╢Зр╢┤р╢╜ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"\\"р╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П \\" р╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢нр╖К \\"р╖Ар╢В р╢Зр╢┤р╢╜\\" р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Др╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢Лр╢┤ р╢╕р╖Др╖Пр╢пр╖Кр╖Ар╖Ур╢┤р╢║р╖Ъ р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э  р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╖Ар╢╜ р╖Ар╖Рр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒ р╢Цр╖Вр╢░р╖Ур╢║ р╖Бр╖Пр╢Ър╢║р╢Ър╖Т.р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╖Бр╖Пр╢Ър╢║ р╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П, р╖Ар╢В р╢Зр╢┤р╢╜, р╢Ер╢Ьр╢╜р╖К р╢Ер╖Пр╢пр╖Пр╢╗ р╖Др╖П р╢┤р╖Пр╖Ар╢зр╖Кр╢зр╖П р╖Ар╢▒ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢░ р╢┤р╢╜р╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢╜р╢пр╖У р╖Др╖Рр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢╕р╖Щр╢║ р╢Ер╢йр╖Т 3-10 р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖П р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Лр╖Гр╢з р╖Ар╖Рр╢йр╖Щр╢▒ р╢╢р╖Др╖Фр╖Ар╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Вр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢┤р╢│р╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╖Бр╖Пр╢Ър╢║ р╢╢р╖Щр╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Др╢нр╢╗р╢з р╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╖Ер╖Т р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╖Ар╢╜р╢║р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╖Бр╖Пр╢Ър╢║ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╖Др╖П р╢╕р╢╜р╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ър╢п р╖Ар╖Рр╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П р╢Ър╖Щр╖Пр╖Ер╢║ р╢Ер╢Яр╢╜р╖К 6-12 р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖П р╢пр╖Тр╢Ьр╖Рр╢нр╖Тр╢║. р╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢║. р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢Ър╖Щр╢╜р╖Ар╢╗ р╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Фр╢лр╖Фр╢║. р╢Ър╖Щр╢зр╖Т р╖Др╖П р╢пр╖Рр╢йр╖Т р╢Ър╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Тр╢║ р╖Бр╖Фр╢Ър╖Тр╖Ар╢╜ р╢Ър╖Фр╢йр╖П р╖Гр╖Фр╢пр╖Ф р╢╕р╢╜р╖К р╖Др╢зр╢Ьр╢▒р╖У. р╢▒р╖Тр╢┤р╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗ р╢Ер╢Яр╢╜р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╢╕р╢л р╢пр╖Тр╢Ьр╢║. р╢╕р╢╜р╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Фр╢Ър╖Фр╢зр╢║ р╢пр╖Кр╖Ар╖Ур╢Ър╖Эр╖Вр╖Кр╢зр╖Ур╢║ р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢╕р╢╜р╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢йр╖Т р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╢зр╢Ьр╢▒р╖Фр╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К р╖Др╖П р╢пр╖Щр╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К р╢║р╢▒ р╢╕р╖Пр╖Г р╖Ар╢╜р╢║р╖Т. р╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П р╢╡р╢╜р╢║ р╖Гр╖Кр╢╡р╖Эр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖Т. р╢Ср╢║ р╢Ер╢Яр╢╜р╖К 3/4 р╢┤р╢╕р╢л р╢пр╖Тр╢Ьр╢║.р╢Цр╖Вр╢░р╖Ур╢║ р╖Ар╢зр╖Тр╢▒р╖Пр╢Ър╢╕р╢Ср╢║ р╖Гр╖Щр╢╕р╖К р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь, р╢╗р╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь, р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖Гр╢▒ р╢Ер╢┤р╖Др╖Гр╖Фр╢нр╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╖Ар╢▒ р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь, р╢Лр╢л, р╖Ар╢╕р╢▒р╢║, р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕р╖Ър╖Д р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь р╖Др╖П р╢Ър╖Фр╖Вр╖Кр╢з р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь р╢▒р╖Гр╢║р╖Т. р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╖Ур╢║ р╖Ар╖Ыр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║ р╢Ър╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Ар╢╜р╢пр╖У р╢нр╖Рр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╖Фр╢╕р╖К, р╢╕р╖Рр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Фр╢╕р╖К, р╢┤р╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ф, р╢Йр╖Гр╢Ър╖Фр╢йр╖Тр╢ар╖К р╖Др╖П р╢Ър╖Вр╖Пр╢║ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Е р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Ъ. р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╖Ар╖Тр╢з тАЬр╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П р╢┤р╢Вр╢ар╖Пр╢Вр╢Ьр╢║тАЬ р╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Е, р╢╕р╖Фр╢╜р╖К, р╢╕р╢╜р╖К, р╢┤р╖Ьр╢нр╖Ф р╖Др╖П р╢▒р╖Рр╢зр╖Т р╢║р╢▒ р╢┤р╖Гр╖К р╢┤р╢Вр╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢╕ р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Ъ. р╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П р╢║р╖Ьр╢пр╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢▒р╖Тр╢┤р╢пр╖Ар╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╢╢р╢▒ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢Ър╢з р╢Цр╖Вр╢░ р╢╗р╖Рр╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢н. р╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╖Пр╖Ар╢╜р╖Ър╖Др╢║, р╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╖Пр╖Др╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╢Ър╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢пр╖У р╢╜р╖Ър╖Др╢║, р╖Ар╖Пр╖Др╢Ъ р╢┤р╢Вр╢ар╖Пр╢Вр╢Ьр╢║, р╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Тр╖Вр╖Кр╢зр╢║ р╢Йр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗р╢Ър╖Кр╢║. р╢╕р╖Ър╖Ар╖П р╢╗р╢нр╖Кр╢┤р╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь, р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢║ р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь р╖Гр╖Д р╖Бр╖Кр╖Ар╖Гр╢▒ р╢╗р╖Эр╢Ь р╖Ар╢╜р╢пр╖У р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╢Ър╖Щр╢╗р╖Ъ. р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╢▒р╖К тАЬр╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╢ЪтАЬ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢пр╢▒ р╢Жр╢йр╢нр╖Эр╢йр╖П р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢н р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢║р╖Т."},{"question":"\\"р╢╕р╢╜р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Фр╢йр╖Т р╢пр╖Ар╖Гр╖К\\" р╖Др╖Т р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢ар╖Кр╢бр╖Ър╢п р╢╜р╖Рр╢║р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Фр╢Ьр╢н р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╢Жр╢╗р╖К р╢Ър╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Пр╢╗р╖Пр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╗р╢ар╖Тр╢н \\"р╢╕р╢╜р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Фр╢йр╖Т р╢пр╖Ар╖Гр╖К\\" р╖Др╖Т р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢ар╖Кр╢бр╖Ър╢п р╢╜р╖Рр╢║р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Фр╖А р╢╕р╖Щр╖Гр╖Ър╢║:1. \\"р╢вр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ьр╢нр╖Тр╖Вр╖Ар╖Ър╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖Фр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╢║\\"2. \\"р╢Ер╢нр╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Др╢▒р╖К р╢нр╖Рр╢┤р╖Ср╢╜\\"3. \\"р╖Ар╖Ыр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║\\"4. \\"р╢Ьр╖Ър╢зр╖Кр╢╕р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢нр╖Ср╢Ьр╖Кр╢Ь\\"5. \\"р╢Ер╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╢╢р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖П\\"6. \\"р╖Гр╖Др╖Шр╢п р╖Др╖Рр╢Яр╖Ур╢╕\\"7. \\"р╢Ър╖Ьр╢зр╖Т р╢▒р╖Тр╢║\\"8. \\"р╢Кр╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╗р╢▒р╖К\\"9. \\"р╢Ср╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢┤р╖Цр╢╗р╖Кр╢лр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║\\"10. \\"р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Лр╢пр╖Ар╖К\\"11. \\"р╖Гр╢╗р╖Кр╢┤-р╢Ьр╖Ур╢нр╢║\\"12. \\"р╢Ср╢▒р╖Кр╢вр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢пр╢╗\\"13. \\"р╢╕р╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╢Ър╢з р╖Др╢нр╖Ер╖Тр╖Гр╖К р╢┤р╖Др╢Ър╖К\\"14. \\"р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢┤р╖Пр╢╗р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Рр╖Др╖Рр╢╗\\"15. \\"р╢Зр╢зр╖Тр╢╜р╖П\\"16. \\"The Axe\\"17. \\"р╢╜р╖Эр╢╜р╖Т р╢┤р╖Пр╢╗\\"18. \\"р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Кр╢╜р╖Ър╖Гр╢╗р╖К р╢зр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ър╢╜р╖К\\"19. \\"р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Пр╢л р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Тр╢Ър╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ьр╢▒\\"20. \\"р╢╢р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢│р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╖Пр╢йр╖Фр╖А\\"21. \\"р╖Гр╖Щр╖Ар╢лр╖Рр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╢Ър╖К\\"22. \\"р╢Ър╖Рр╢╕р╖Рр╢нр╖Кр╢н р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Др╢╜р╖Щр╢Ър╖К\\"23. \\"р╢╜р╖Ур╢╜р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╢╗р╖П\\"24. \\"р╢╕р╖А р╖Гр╖Д р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╖П\\"25. \\"р╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╖П\\"26. \\"р╖Гр╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╖Ар╖Т\\"27. \\"р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╢▒ р╢╕р╢нр╢║\\"28. \\"Cat Within\\"29. \\"р╢п р╢Ср╢вр╖К\\"30. \\"р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Д р╢Ър╖Ьр╢╢р╖Кр╢╜р╢╗р╖К\\"31. \\"р╢╢р╢йр╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖Т р╢пр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖П\\"32. \\"р╢Зр╢╕р╖Кр╢йр╢▒р╖К\\""},{"question":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢┤р╖Пр╢пр╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Пр╢║р╢Ъ р╢░р╖Фр╢╗р╢║р╢з р╢┤р╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╖Ц , р╢┤р╖Ер╢╕р╖Фр╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╢╕р╖Ур╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п ?","answer":"р╢╕р╢йр╢Ьр╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╢▒ р╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╢лр╖Ър╢╗ р╖Др╖Тр╢╕р╖Т "},{"question":"Awс╗Нn janduku kс╗Н lu e├йgu╠Бn Ol├│├▓l├╣ nтАЩIbadan, eeyan marun-un ni wс╗Нn pa","answer":"Eeyan marun-un ni wс╗Нn pa n├нfс╗Нnn├б-fс╗Нnс╣гu nigba tawс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н iс╣гс╗Нta kс╗Н lu Ol├│├▓l├╣, ├аgb├а e├йg├║n ilu Ibadan, nirс╗Нlс║╣ с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, to kс╗Нja.ALAROYE gbс╗Н pe lasiko ti e├йg├║n n├б├а n с╣гe ├иt├╣t├╣ с╗Нlс╗Нdс╗Нс╗Нdun to m├бa n с╣гe lс╗Нwс╗Н lawс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi ya bo oun atawс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣y├мn с║╣╠А laduugbo ├Тj├й, nтАЩIbadan.O ti fс║╣с║╣ pari etutu с╗Нh├║n lawс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н iс╣гс╗Нta naa ti wс╗Нn fс║╣с║╣ t├│ с╗Нgс╗Нrin (80) niye ya d├й pс║╣lu ibс╗Нn ada, k├╣mс╗Н╠А, eegun с║╣ran nla nla ati oriс╣гiiriс╣гii awс╗Нn nnkan ├мj├аmb├б mi-in, t├н с╗Нrс╗Н s├м di b├│-├▓-lс╗Н, y├аg├▓ lс╗Н╠Бn├а.Yatс╗Н sтАЩawс╗Нn marun-un ti awс╗Нn ipata wс╗Нnyi y├мn nibс╗Нn, ti wс╗Нn s├м k├║ loju с║╣sс║╣, с╗Мlс╗Нrun lo mс╗Н iye ├и├иy├аn t├│ с╣гee с╣гe k├│ t├║n pad├а gbс║╣╠Бm├м-in mi lс║╣yin ikс╗Нlu с╗Нhun ninu awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣yin eegun naa.├Мd├н ni p├й с╗Нpс╗Н eeyan lo fara gbс╗Нgbс║╣ nla, ti wс╗Нn s├м n ti ileewosan kan gbe lс╗Н s├н ├▓m├н-├мn, с╣гugbс╗Нn ti ko s├н с║╣ni t├│ l├и sс╗Н с║╣ni t├│ m├бa k├║ tabi y├и ninu wс╗Нn.Nigba to n sс╗Нrс╗Н lori iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ yii, Aarс║╣ с║╣gbс║╣ ├аwс╗Нn с╗Нdс║╣ Sс╗Н╠Аl├║dс║╣╠Аrс╗Н╠А jake-jado ilс║╣ Yor├╣b├б, с╗Мba Wahab Ajijс╗Нla-Anabi, с║╣ni t├н ├мс╣гс║╣╠Аlс║╣╠А naa с╣гoju с║╣╠А f├мd├н с║╣╠А mulс║╣ pe wс╗Н╠Бс╗Н╠Бrс╗Н╠Бwс╗Н╠Б leto ti agba eegun naa n с╣гe n lс╗Н ko too di pe awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н iс╣гс╗Нta naa ya de toguntogun lai jс║╣ pe eegun tabi awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣yin с║╣ kankan tс╗Н wс╗Нn.Gс║╣gс║╣ bo с╣гe sс╗Н, тАЬLс╗Нdс╗Нс╗Нdun lтАЩOl├│├▓l├╣ m├бa n с╣г├иt├╣t├╣ yс║╣n, to m├бa n gbс║╣╠Бbс╗Н kaakiri igboro Ibadan lati w├║re f├║n gbogbo ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н pe k├н ilu le m├бa r├│j├║, ki alaafia s├н m├бa jс╗Нba. Lс║╣yin ├иt├╣t├╣ yс║╣n ni wс╗Нn с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ m├бa m├║ с╗Нjс╗Н ti с╗Нdun e├йg├║n m├бa bс║╣rс║╣ nтАЩIbadan. Eegun Ol├│├▓l├╣ naa lo maa n jade gbс║╣yin lс║╣yin ti gbogbo eegun ba jade tan lasiko odun e├йg├║n.тАЬPс║╣lu bi mo с╣гe foju wo awс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi yс║╣n, wс╗Нn t├│ с╗Нgс╗Нrin (80). Ol├│├▓l├╣ ti lс╗Н kaakiri gbogbo ibi to yс║╣ k├│ d├й gс║╣gс║╣ b├нi iс╣гe с║╣╠А lс╗Нdс╗Нс╗Нdun. O ku diс║╣ ko pari eto yс║╣n lawс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi yс║╣n kс╗Н lu u laduugbo ├Тj├й, nтАЩIbadan, pс║╣lu с╗Нpс╗Нlс╗Нpс╗Н ibс╗Нn, ada, ├аp├│l├а igi atawс╗Нn nnkan ija oloro mi-in.тАЬс╗Мmс╗Нk├╣nrin kan ti wс╗Нn n pe ni Star Boy lo с╣гaaju awс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi yс║╣n. Niс╣гe ni wс╗Нn n yinbс╗Нn l├бkс╗Нl├бkс╗Н, ti wс╗Нn s├м t├║n ju ├▓k├▓ ati igi, с╣гugbс╗Нn k├▓ s├н nnkan kan to de с╗Нdс╗Н Ol├│├▓l├╣ ninu gbogbo nnkan ├мj├а wс╗Нnyс║╣n.тАЬO pс║╣ ti с╗Нmс╗Нk├╣nrin ti wс╗Нn n pe ni Star Boy yii ti maa n huwa idaluru. Oun lo pa ├а├аf├б├а w├б kan nitori с╗Нrс╗Н t├нkс║╣╠Бс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Аt├м mс╗Н╠Бt├▓ nitori с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣yin Auxiliary (с╗Нga с║╣gbс║╣ awс╗Нn awakс╗Н ni ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н) ni.тАШтАШLanaa (с╗Нjс╗Н keji ikс╗Нlu akс╗Нkс╗Н lawс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi yс║╣n tun bс║╣rс║╣ si i lс╗Нс╗Н ka awс╗Нn eeyan mс╗Нle. Wс╗Нn lс╗Нс╗Н ka Iyalс╗Нja Oje mс╗Н с╣гс╗Нс╗Нbu с║╣, wс╗Нn ni awс╗Нn maa dana sun un.тАЬEmi ni mo pe awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ti wс╗Нn fi waa k├▓├▓r├й ├а╟╣b├нl├н├м.  с╗Мpс║╣lс╗Нpс║╣ DPO Agugu ni ko jс║╣ ki wс╗Нn r├н iya yс║╣n dana sun. Koda, awс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi yii tun lс║╣ko mс╗Н awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa.тАЭALAROYE gbс╗Н pe awс╗Нn eleto aabo ijс╗Нba ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н ta a mс╗Н si Operation Burst naa sare lс╗Нс╗Н kun awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa lс╗Нwс╗Н ninu akitiyan wс╗Нn lati pс║╣tu s├н l├а├бs├мgb├▓ naa.Meji ninu awс╗Нn afurasi с╗Нdaran с╗Нhun la gbс╗Н pe awс╗Нn Operation Burst ri mu ninu wс╗Нn. ├Аh├бmс╗Н╠Б awс╗Нn Operation Burst ni wс╗Нn w├а titi ta a fi par├н akojс╗Н iroyin yii."},{"question":"ЁЯЗ░ЁЯЗм ╨Ь╨░╨╜╨░╤Б ╤Н╨┐╨╛╤Б╤Г ЁЯУЪ ╨г╨╣╨│╤Г╤А ╨╝╨░╨╜╨░╤Б╤З╤Л ╨║╨░╨╣╤Б╤Л ╤Н╨╗╨┤╨╡ ╨╢╨░╤И╨░╨╣╤В? ╨░) ╨Ю╨╛╨│╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А╨┤╨░ ╨▒) ╨Ъ╤Л╤В╨░╨╣╨┤╨░ ╨▓) ╨в╤Г╤А╨║╨╕╤П╨┤╨░ ╨│) ╨Т╨╡╨╜╨│╤А╨╕╤П╨┤╨░","answer":"ЁЯЗ░ЁЯЗм ╨Ь╨░╨╜╨░╤Б ╤Н╨┐╨╛╤Б╤Г ЁЯУЪ╨▒) ╨Ъ╤Л╤В╨░╨╣╨┤╨░"},{"question":"T├│m tс║пt ─Сoс║бn v─Гn bс║гn sau: 14% thu nh├в╠гp cс╗зa Samsung l├а tс╗л thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng Trung Quс╗СcPh├│ng sс╗▒ chiс║┐u tr├кn truyс╗Бn h├мnh Trung ╞░╞бng Trung Quс╗Сc n├│i c├бc ─Сi├к╠гn thoс║бi lс╗Чi bс╗Л hс╗Пng chip ─Сi├к╠гn tс╗н, ─Сс╗Уng thс╗Эi chс╗Й tr├нch ch├нnh s├бch bс║гo h├аnh cс╗зa Samsung.14% thu nh├в╠гp cс╗зa h├гng ─Сi├к╠гn tс╗н n├аy l├а tс╗л Trung Quс╗Сc. Samsung nay n├│i sс║╜ sс╗нa chс╗пa miс╗Еn ph├н bс║гy model ─Сi├к╠гn thoс║бi m├а ph├│ng sс╗▒ truyс╗Бn h├мnh nhс║пc ─Сс║┐n.Samsung l├а m├┤╠гt trong c├бc h├гng n╞░с╗Ыc ngo├аi mс╗Ыi ─С├вy bс╗Л truyс╗Бn th├┤ng Trung Quс╗Сc c├┤ng k├нch.H├гng n├аy ra th├┤ng c├бo vс╗Ыi lс╗Эi 'xin lс╗Чi ch├вn th├аnh' tс╗Ыi ng╞░с╗Эi ti├кu d├╣ng Trung Quс╗Сc v├м nhс╗пng sс╗▒ bс║еt ti├к╠гn m├а c├бc \\"vс║еn ─Сс╗Б quс║гn l├╜\\" cс╗зa h├гng g├вy ra; v├а hoan ngh├кnh truyс╗Бn th├┤ng tiс║┐p tс╗еc theo d├╡i hoс║бt ─С├┤╠гng cс╗зa h├гng.Trong c├бc model ─Сi├к╠гn thoс║бi di ─С├┤╠гng m├а k├кnh truyс╗Бn h├мnh CCTV n├│i l├а bс╗Л lс╗Чi, c├│ c├бc loс║бi Galaxy S3 v├а Note2.'Ngс║бo mс║бn'Trung Quс╗Сc l├а nс╗Бn kinh tс║┐ ─Сс╗йng thс╗й hai thс║┐ giс╗Ыi, c┼йng l├а quс╗Сc gia ─С├┤ng d├вn nhс║еt hi├к╠гn nay.Nс╗Бn kinh tс║┐ t─Гng tr╞░с╗Яng mс║бnh, mс╗йc thu nh├в╠гp ─Сi l├кn v├а l╞░с╗гng ng╞░с╗Эi ti├кu d├╣ng lс╗Ыn ─С├г khiс║┐n Trung Quс╗Сc trс╗Я th├аnh thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng chс╗з chс╗Сt cho c├бc h├гng sс║гn xuс║еt h├аng ti├кu d├╣ng tr├кn to├аn cс║зu.Tuy nhi├кn, trong qu├б tr├мnh mс╗Я r├┤╠гng kinh doanh с╗Я Trung Quс╗Сc, c├бc h├гng n╞░с╗Ыc ngo├аi c┼йng ng├аy c├аng bс╗Л soi m├│i.Hс╗Уi ─Сс║зu tuс║зn n├аy, m├┤╠гt ph├│ng sс╗▒ kh├бc tr├кn CCTV cho hay Starbucks, mс║бng l╞░с╗Ыi cс╗нa h├аng c├а ph├к lс╗Ыn nhс║еt thс║┐ giс╗Ыi, n├вng gi├б b├бn с╗Я Trung Quс╗Сc cao h╞бn с╗Я c├бc n╞░с╗Ыc kh├бc.CCTV n├│i Starbucks thu l├гi nhiс╗Бu h╞бn с╗Я Trung Quс╗Сc ch├нnh v├м gi├б mс║пc.Th├бng T╞░ n─Гm nay, Tс╗Хng gi├бm ─Сс╗Сc ─Сiс╗Бu h├аnh cс╗зa t├в╠гp ─Сo├аn Apple, Tim Cook, ─С├г phс║гi xin lс╗Чi ng╞░с╗Эi ti├кu d├╣ng Trung Quс╗Сc sau hai tuс║зn liс╗Бn h├гng n├аy bс╗Л truyс╗Бn th├┤ng nh├а n╞░с╗Ыc ─Сс║г ph├б vс╗Б dс╗Лch vс╗е bс║гo h├аnh.B├бo ch├н Trung Quс╗Сc c├бo bu├┤╠гc Apple l├а ngс║бo mс║бn v├а tham lam.","answer":"Mс╗Щt ph├│ng sс╗▒ tr├кn truyс╗Бn h├мnh Trung Quс╗Сc ─С├г tiс║┐t lс╗Щ rс║▒ng ─Сiс╗Зn thoс║бi cс╗зa Samsung gс║╖p sс╗▒ cс╗С vс╗Б chip ─Сiс╗Зn tс╗н, v├а chс╗Й tr├нch ch├нnh s├бch bс║гo h├аnh cс╗зa h├гng. amsung ─С├г cam kс║┐t sс╗нa chс╗пa miс╗Еn ph├н bс║гy model ─Сiс╗Зn thoс║бi bс╗Л lс╗Чi nh╞░ ─С╞░с╗гc ─Сс╗Б cс║нp trong ph├│ng sс╗▒. C├бc h├гng n╞░с╗Ыc ngo├аi, trong ─С├│ c├│ Samsung, ─Сang gс║╖p ├бp lс╗▒c tс╗л truyс╗Бn th├┤ng Trung Quс╗Сc khi mс╗Я rс╗Щng kinh doanh с╗Я ─С├вy. T╞░╞бng tс╗▒, Starbucks c┼йng bс╗Л chс╗Й tr├нch v├м n├вng gi├б b├бn c├а ph├к с╗Я Trung Quс╗Сc. ─Р├вy l├а dс║еu hiс╗Зu cho thс║еy sс╗▒ gia t─Гng cс╗зa truyс╗Бn th├┤ng nh├а n╞░с╗Ыc Trung Quс╗Сc trong viс╗Зc kiс╗Гm so├бt hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng cс╗зa c├бc c├┤ng ty n╞░с╗Ыc ngo├аi tr├кn thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng cс╗зa hс╗Н."},{"question":"с╗Мmс╗Н с╗Нdu╠Бn me╠Бlo╠Аo╠Б ni Noam Chomsky?","answer":"с╗Мmс╗Н с╗Нdu╠Бn mс║╣╠Бrinle╠Бla╠Бa╠Аdс╗Н╠Бru╠Аn-u╠Бn"},{"question":"Qual o nome do est├бdio do Morumbi?","answer":"O nome do est├бdio do Morumbi ├й C├нcero Pompeu de Toledo."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛ :родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ роорпКродрпНрод роиро╛роЯро╛ро│рпБрооройрпНро▒ родрпКроХрпБродро┐роХро│рпНA. 21B. 20C. 25D. 39","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ : D. 39"},{"question":"Apa yang berlaku apabila Beneden Merwede bercabang? Berdasarkan soalan sebelumnya, tulis konteks yang mengandungi jawapannya. Konteks boleh mengandungi 1 - 20 ayat. Konteks:","answer":"Dua pertiga daripada jumlah aliran air Rhine mengalir ke barat, melalui Waal dan kemudian, melalui Merwede dan Nieuwe Merwede (De Biesbosch), bergabung dengan Meuse, melalui muara Hollands Diep dan Haringvliet, ke Laut Utara. Beneden Merwede bercabang, berhampiran Hardinxveld-Giessendam dan terus sebagai Noord, untuk menyertai Lek, berhampiran kampung Kinderdijk, untuk membentuk Nieuwe Maas; kemudian mengalir melepasi Rotterdam dan meneruskan melalui Het Scheur dan Nieuwe Waterweg, ke Laut Utara. Percabangan Oude Maas, berhampiran Dordrecht, lebih jauh ke bawahnya bergabung dengan Nieuwe Maas untuk membentuk Het Scheur."},{"question":"Quem foi o l├нder pacifista indiano que desempenhou um papel fundamental na conquista da independ├кncia da ├Нndia do dom├нnio brit├вnico?","answer":"O l├нder pacifista indiano que desempenhou um papel fundamental na conquista da independ├кncia da ├Нndia do dom├нnio brit├вnico foi Mahatma Gandhi."},{"question":"риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риХри░риХрйЗ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐ри╕риери╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ ри╣рйЗриари╛риВ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗ рижри╛ риХрйА риЕри░рие ри╣рйИред\\"риориГ рйк реери╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░ ри╕рйЗридрйА риЧригрид риЬри┐ ри░риЦрйИ ри╣ри▓ридрйБ рикри▓ридрйБ ри╕ринрйБ ридри┐ри╕ риХри╛ риЧриЗриЖ реериири┐рид риЭри╣рйАриЖ рикри╛риП риЭриЧрйВ ри╕рйБриЯрйЗ риЭриЦрижри╛ риЭриЦрижри╛ риЭрйЬри┐ рикриЗриЖ реериири┐рид риЙрикри╛ри╡ риХри░рйИ риори╛риЗриЖ ризрии риХри╛ри░ригри┐ риЕриЧри▓ри╛ ризриирйБ ринрйА риЙрибри┐ риЧриЗриЖ реериХри┐риЖ риУри╣рйБ риЦриЯрйЗ риХри┐риЖ риУри╣рйБ риЦри╛ри╡рйИ риЬри┐ри╕рйБ риЕрй░рижри░ри┐ ри╕ри╣ри╕ри╛ рижрйБриЦрйБ рикриЗриЖ реериири┐ри░ри╡рйИри░рйИ риири╛ри▓ри┐ риЬри┐ ри╡рйИри░рйБ ри░риЪри╛риП ри╕ринрйБ рикри╛рикрйБ риЬриЧридрйИ риХри╛ ридри┐риири┐ ри╕ри┐ри░ри┐ ри▓риЗриЖ реериУри╕рйБ риЕриЧрйИ рикри┐риЫрйИ риврйЛриИ риири╛ри╣рйА риЬри┐ри╕рйБ риЕрй░рижри░ри┐ риири┐рй░рижри╛ риорйБри╣ри┐ риЕрй░римрйБ рикриЗриЖ реериЬрйЗ ри╕рйБриЗриирйЗ риирйЛ риУри╣рйБ ри╣риерйБ рикри╛риП ридри╛ риЦрйЗри╣рйВ ри╕рйЗридрйА ри░ри▓ри┐ риЧриЗриЖ реериЬрйЗ риЧрйБри░ риХрйА ри╕ри░ригрйА рилри┐ри░ри┐ риУри╣рйБ риЖри╡рйИ ридри╛ рикри┐риЫри▓рйЗ риЕриЙриЧриг римриЦри╕ри┐ ри▓риЗриЖ реериЬрии риири╛риириХ риЕриирижри┐риирйБ риири╛риорйБ ризри┐риЖриЗриЖ ри╣ри░ри┐ ри╕ри┐риори░рид риХри┐ри▓ри╡ри┐риЦ рикри╛рик риЧриЗриЖ реерйирее\\"","answer":"риЗри╣ ри╕рйНри░рйА риЧрйБри░рйВ риЧрйНри░рй░рие ри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐рим риЬрйА рижрйЗ рикрй░риири╛ 307 ридрйЛриВ ри▓ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риЧрйБри░рйВ ри░ри╛риорижри╛ри╕ риЬрйА риЗри╣риири╛риВ римри╛ригрйАриЖриВ рижрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЦри╛ри░рйА ри╕рииредриЗри╕ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйЗриа ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ риЕриирйБри╕ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЦри┐риЖрии риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ,\\"риЬрйЛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ ри╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░рйВ риири╛ри▓ риХри┐рйЬ ри░рй▒риЦрижри╛ ри╣рйИ, риЙри╕ рижри╛ ри▓рйЛриХ ридрйЗ рикри░ри▓рйЛриХ ри╕риорйБрй▒риЪрйЗ ри╣рйА ри╡ри┐риЕри░рие риЬри╛риВрижрйЗ ри╣рии (риЙри╕ рижрйА рикрйЗри╢ ридри╛риВ риЬри╛риВрижрйА риири╣рйАриВ, риЗри╕ риХри░риХрйЗ риЙри╣) ри╕рижри╛ риХриЪрйАриЪрйАриЖриВ ри╡рй▒риЯрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ридрйЗ рижрй░риж рикрйАриВри╣рижри╛ ри╣рйИ (ридрйЗ риЕрй░рид риирйВрй░) риЦрикрижри╛ риЦрикрижри╛ риири╢риЯ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ (риЖридриориХ риорйМрид ри╕ри╣рйЗрйЬ ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ) ред:тАФ(ри╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░рйВ рижри╛ риЙри╣ рижрйЛриЦрйА) ри╕рижри╛ риори╛риЗриЖ ри▓риИ ри╡ри┐риУриВридри╛риВ риХри░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ, рикри░ риЙри╕ рижри╛ риЕриЧри▓ри╛ (риХриори╛риЗриЖ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ) ринрйА ри╣рй▒риерйЛриВ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ риЬри┐ри╕ риориирйБрй▒риЦ рижрйЗ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЭрйЛри░ри╛ ридрйЗ ри╕ри╛рйЬри╛ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗ, риЙри╕ риирйЗ риЦрй▒риЯригри╛ риХрйАри╣ ридрйЗ риЦри╛ригри╛ риХрйАри╣? (ринри╛ри╡, риЙри╣ риири╛ риХрйБриЭ риЦрй▒риЯ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ридрйЗ риири╛ риЦрй▒риЯрйЗ ри╣рйЛриП рижри╛ риЖриирй░риж ри▓рйИ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ) риЬрйЛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риири┐ри░ри╡рйИри░ риири╛ри▓ ри╡рйИри░ риХри░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ риЙри╣ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ ри╕рй░ри╕ри╛ри░ рижрйЗ рикри╛рикри╛риВ (рижри╛ ринри╛ри░) риЖрикригрйЗ ри╕ри┐ри░ ридрйЗ ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ, риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ ри▓рйЛриХ рикри░ри▓рйЛриХ ри╡ри┐риЪ риХрйЛриИ риЖри╕ри░ри╛ риири╣рйАриВ рижрйЗриВрижри╛ ред риЬри┐ри╕ рижрйЗ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ ридри╛риВ риири┐рй░рижри╛ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗ, рикри░ риорйВрй░ри╣ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЕрй░рим рикри┐риЖ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗ (ринри╛ри╡, риЬрйЛ риорйВрй░ри╣рйЛриВ риори┐рй▒риари╛ римрйЛри▓рйЗ),  риЗри╣рйЛ риЬри┐ри╣ри╛ риЦрйЛриЯри╛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риЬрйЗ ри╕рйЛриирйЗ риирйВрй░ ри╣рй▒рие рикри╛риП риЙри╣ ринрйА ри╕рйБриЖри╣ риири╛ри▓ ри░ри▓ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрилри┐ри░ ринрйА (ринри╛ри╡, риЗри╣рйЛ риЬри┐ри╣ри╛ рикри╛рикрйА ри╣рйБрй░рижри┐риЖриВ ринрйА) риЬрйЗ риЙри╣ ри╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйА риЪри░риирйАриВ риври╣ри┐ рикри╡рйЗ ридри╛риВ ри╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░рйВ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ рикри┐риЫри▓рйЗ риЕриЙриЧрйБригри╛риВ риирйВрй░ римрйЩри╢ рижрйЗриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ри╣рйЗ риири╛риириХ! риЬрйЛ риориирйБрй▒риЦ (ри╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйА ри╕ри░ригри┐ рикрйИ риХрйЗ) ри╣ри░ ри░рйЛрйЫ риири╛рио риЬрикрижри╛ ри╣рйИ, рикрйНри░ринрйВ риирйВрй░ ри╕ри┐риори░рижри┐риЖриВ риЙри╕ рижрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ рикри╛рик рижрйВри░ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижрйЗ ри╣рии редрйиред\\""},{"question":"тАШроЗро│рпИродро╛роХ роорпБро│рпНрооро░роорпНтАЩ роОройродрпН родрпКроЯроЩрпНроХрпБроорпН роХрпБро▒ро│ро┐ро▓рпН роИро▒рпНро▒роЯро┐ роИро▒рпНро▒рпБроЪрпНроЪрпАро░рпН, роОройрпНройрпБроорпН ро╡ро╛рокрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпН роорпБроЯро┐роирпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.роЕ) роиро╛ро│рпНроЖ) рооро▓ро░рпНроЗ) роХро╛роЪрпБроИ) рокро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБ","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: тАШроЗро│рпИродро╛роХ роорпБро│рпНрооро░роорпНтАЩ роОройродрпН родрпКроЯроЩрпНроХрпБроорпН роХрпБро▒ро│ро┐ро▓рпН роИро▒рпНро▒роЯро┐ роИро▒рпНро▒рпБроЪрпНроЪрпАро░рпН, роОройрпНройрпБроорпН ро╡ро╛рокрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпН роИ) рокро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБ роорпБроЯро┐роирпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ."},{"question":"хМЧцЬЭщооуБоца╕хЕ╡хЩищЦЛчЩ║уВТщШ▓уБРуБЯуВБуБлшинуБСуВЙуВМуБЯуАМцЬЭщоохНКх│╢уВиуГНуГлуВоуГ╝щЦЛчЩ║цйЯцзЛуАНуВТуВвуГлуГХуВбуГЩуГГуГИя╝ФцЦЗхнЧуБзф╜ХуБиуБДуБЖуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"я╝ля╝ея╝дя╝п"},{"question":"Iza no nanoratra an'ilay boky mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Twilight\\"?","answer":"Ny mpanoratra an'ilay boky mitondra ny lohateny hoe \\"Twilight\\" dia i Stephenie Meyer."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: рооро┐ройрпНроЪро╛ро░родрпНродрпИроХрпН роХроЯродрпНродрпБроорпН роЕро▓рпЛроХроорпН роОродрпБ ?1.роХро┐ро░ро╛рокрпИроЯрпН2.роорпЖроХрпНройрпАроЪро┐ропроорпН роЪро▓рпНрокрпЗроЯрпН3.рокро╛ро▓ро┐ропрпЖро╕рпНроЯро░рпН4.роирпИро▓ро╛ройрпН","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ:1.роХро┐ро░ро╛рокрпИроЯрпН"},{"question":"цмбуБоцЦЗчлауБлцЫ╕уБЛуВМуБжуБДуВЛхЖЕхо╣уБлхЯ║уБеуБДуБжуАБх░СуБкуБПуБиуВВ200шкЮуБоцо╡шР╜уВТцЫ╕уБДуБжуБПуБауБХуБДуАВя╝Ъ чБ╜хо│уБоуБиуБНх╜╣уБлчлЛуБдуААц░┤щБУуВДщЫ╗ц░ЧуВТф╜┐уВПуБкуБДцЦЩчРЖуВТч┤╣ф╗Л","answer":"ф╗Кх╣┤уБпщЦвцЭ▒хдзщЬЗчБ╜уБЛуВЙ100х╣┤уБзуБЩуАВщжЦщГ╜чЫ┤ф╕ЛхЬ░щЬЗуБкуБйуБохдзуБНуБкхЬ░щЬЗуВВуБУуВМуБЛуВЙш╡╖уБУуВЛуБишиАуВПуВМуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВуВпуГГуВпуГСуГГуГЙуБиуБДуБЖф╝Ъчд╛уБпуАБчБ╜хо│уБзц░┤щБУуВДщЫ╗ц░ЧуАБуВмуВ╣уБкуБйуБМцнвуБ╛уБгуБЯуБиуБНуБзуВВф╜ЬуВЛуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуВЛцЦЩчРЖуВТуВжуВзуГЦуВ╡уВдуГИуБзч┤╣ф╗ЛуБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВцЦЩчРЖуБп250ф╗еф╕КуБВуВКуБ╛уБЩуАВхо╢уБлчФицДПуБЧуБжуБКуБДуБЯц░┤уВДуВлуВ╗уГГуГИуВ│уГ│уГнуАБчЖ▒уБлх╝╖уБДуГЭуГкуВиуГБуГмуГ│уБошвЛуВТф╜┐уБгуБжуБФуБпуВУуВТчВКуБП цЦ╣ц│ХуВДуАБч╝╢шй░уВТф╜┐уБгуБЯуГСуВ╣уВ┐уБкуБйуВТч┤╣ф╗ЛуБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВф╝Ъчд╛уБпуАМщгЯф║ЛуБпчФЯц┤╗уБоф╕нуБзуБиуБжуВВхдзхИЗуБзуБЩуАВчБ╜хо│уБоуБиуБНуВВуАБх░СуБЧуБзуВВхоЙх┐ГуБзуБНуВЛуВИуБЖуБлуАБуБКуБДуБЧуБДщгЯф║ЛуВТф╜ЬуБгуБжуБ╗уБЧуБДуБзуБЩуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВ"},{"question":"Apakah tema sambutan Hari Kebangsaan 2017?","answer":"Tema sambutan Hari Kebangsaan 2017 ialah Negaraku Sehati Sejiwa."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada umur ada rezeki\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud asal masih hidup, tentu akan beroleh rezeki"},{"question":"Wace jam'iyar siyasa ce mafi girma a Amruka?","answer":"Democratic Party da Republican Party"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai bersahabat dengan ular bisa\\"?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini adalah berkawan dengan orang jahat."},{"question":"audio blog-родрооро┐ро┤ро┐ро▓рпН роорпКро┤ро┐рокрпЖропро░рпНроХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН","answer":"роТро▓ро┐родрокрпНрокродро┐ро╡рпБ"},{"question":"\\"╨Ь╨╡╨╖╨│╨╕╨╗ ╤Г╤З╨░╤В\\" ╨┐╨╛╨▓╨╡╤Б╤В╨╕ ╨║╨╕╨╝╨│╨╡ ╤В╨░╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║?\\"╨Ь╨╡╨╖╨│╨╕╨╗ ╤Г╤З╨░╤В\\" ╨┐╨╛╨▓╨╡╤Б╤В╨╕ ╨║╨╕╨╝ ╨╢╙й╨╜╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨╗╨│╨░╨╜?","answer":"\\"╨Ь╨╡╨╖╨│╨╕╨╗ ╤Г╤З╨░╤В\\" ╨┐╨╛╨▓╨╡╤Б╤В╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨░╨▓╤В╨╛╤А╤Г ╨Р╨░╨╗╤Л ╨в╨╛╨║╨╛╨╝╨▒╨░╨╡╨▓.\\"╨Ь╨╡╨╖╨│╨╕╨╗ ╤Г╤З╨░╤В\\" ╨┐╨╛╨▓╨╡╤Б╤В╨╕╨╜╨┤╨╡╨│╨╕ ╨▒╨░╤И╨║╤Л ╨║╨░╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨╜ ╨Ц╨░╨┐╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨┐╤А╨╛╤В╨╛╤В╨╕╨▒╨╕ тАФ ╨У╨░╨┐╨░╤А ╨Р╨╣╤В╨╕╨╡╨▓. ╨Ц╨░╨┐╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨░╤В╨░╤Б╤Л ╨Р╨╣╤В╨╕╨║╨╡ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛ ╨У╨░╨┐╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨░╤В╨░╤Б╤Л ╨Р╨╣╤В╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨┐╤А╨╛╤В╨╛╤В╨╕╨▒╨╕. ╨С╤Г╨╗ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨╜╤Л ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Г╤Г╨┤╨░ ╨░╨▓╤В╨╛╤А ╨У╨░╨┐╨░╤А ╨Р╨╣╤В╨╕╨╡╨▓ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨║╙й╨┐ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г ╤Б╥п╨╣╨╗╙й╤И╨║╙й╨╜, ╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╨╗╤Л╨│╤Л, ╨╢╨░╤И╤В╤Л╨│╤Л, ╨░╤В╨░-╤Н╨╜╨╡╤Б╨╕, ╨╢╨░╨║╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╤А╤Л, ╨║╤Л╤Б╨║╨░╤Б╤Л, ╨░╤В╨░╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╤Б╥п╤А╙й╤В╤З╥п ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜╨│╨╛ ╤З╨╡╨╣╨╕╨╜╨║╨╕ ╨▒╨░╤Б╤Л╨┐ ╙й╤В╨║╙й╨╜ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╜ ╙й╨╖ ╨╛╨╛╨╖╤Г╨╜╨░╨╜ ╤Г╨║╨║╨░╨╜, ╨░╤А╤Е╨╕╨▓╨┤╨╕╨║-╨┤╨╛╨║╤Г╨╝╨╡╨╜╤В╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╨║ ╨╝╨░╨░╨╗╤Л╨╝╨░╤В╤В╨░╤А ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╤В╨░╨░╨╜╤Л╤И╨║╨░╨╜, ╨▒╨░╨╗╨║╨╕╨╝, ╨║╨╕╤В╨╡╨┐ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░ ╤Н╨╗╨╡╨║ ╨║╨╡╨╖╨┤╨╡ ╨┐╤А╨╛╤В╨╛╤В╨╕╨┐╤В╨╕╨╜ ╙й╨╖╥п╨╜╙й ╨┤╨░ ╨╛╨║╤Г╤В╤Г╨┐ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╤А."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na to pytanie: Ed Oxenbould gra Tylera w filmie re┼╝yserowanym przez jakiego s┼Вynnego re┼╝ysera?","answer":"Przez M. Night Shyamalana"},{"question":"Awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ pariwo: с║╕ gba wa o, Oluwoo ti dс║╣ awс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi si wa","answer":"с╗Мjс╗Нruu, Wс║╣sidee, to kс╗Нja, ni ina с╗Нrс╗Н с╗Нhun ru jade, с╗Нjс╗Н yс║╣n ni mejila lara awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ ilu Iwo fi с╗Нwс╗Н si iwe kan, wс╗Нn si mu un lс╗Н sс╗Нdс╗Н gomina ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun, Alhaji Gboyega Oyetс╗Нla.Ohun to wa ninu lс║╣ta naa ni pe ki gomina ba awс╗Нn yс╗Н Oluwoo, с╗Мba Abdulrasheed Adewale, lori oye. с║╕sun mс╗Нkanla ni wс╗Нn ka si с╗Нba yii lс║╣sс║╣, wс╗Нn ni с╗Нba naa ko yс║╣ nipo nitori oniruuru iwa idojuti to n hu kaakiri, eyi to n ba orukс╗Н ilu naa jс║╣.Lara awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn fс╗Нwс╗Н si iwe naa ni Oloye Raufu Murana Olorunlampe (Balogun), Oloye Fatai Alani Olaoye (Onto), Oloye Yekeen Bello Orobimpe (Oosa), Oloye Sunday Oyetunde Oyeniyi (Olosi), Oloye Ganiyu Kazeem Ayinde (Jagun) ati Oloye Moses Akanmu Ajao (с╗Мlс╗Нya).Awс╗Нn to ku ni Oloye Baс╣гiru Ajani Akinс╣гс╗Нla (Olukс╗Нtun), Oloye Lamidi Mс╗Нrufu Oyeleke (с╗Мс╕Нс╗Нfin), Oloye Suraju Bello (Onju), Oloye Lateef Ishс╗Нla (Agoro), Oloye Moshood Amс╗Нo (Aс╣гape), Oloye Rasaki Akanmu Tijani (Olukosi) ati Oloye Amao с╗Мlaoс╣гebikan Taiwo (Aro).Lara awс╗Нn с║╣sun ti wс╗Нn fi kan с╗Мba Adewale ni pe o ba с╗Нba с║╣gbс║╣ rс║╣ ja titi ti igbimс╗Н lс╗Нbalс╗Нba ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun fi da a duro fodidi oс╣гu mс║╣fa. Wс╗Нn ni Oluwoo ti Iwo-Oke tun ti figba kan gbe e lс╗Н sile-с║╣jс╗Н, с╣гugbс╗Нn ti ko lс╗Н, to si jс║╣ pe awс╗Нn eeyan bii Oloye Oluс╣гс║╣gun с╗Мbasanjс╗Н lo yс╗Н с╗Н lс╗Нwс╗Н aс╣гс║╣ ti kootu pa.Wс╗Нn ni lс╗Нdun 2016, с╗Мba Adewale tun sс╗Н pe gbogbo с╗Нmс╗Н Yoruba lo le di с╗Мс╗Нni ti Ifс║╣, eleyii to le da wahala silс║╣ nilс║╣ Yoruba. Bakan naa lo tun gba iс╣гс║╣ Imaamu Agba ilu Iwo с╣гe lс╗Нjс╗Н с╗Нdun Ileya lс╗Нdun naa.Awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ fi kun с╗Нrс╗Н wс╗Нn pe Oluwoo tun ti figba kan sс╗Нrс╗Н to le da wahala silс║╣ niluu Ibadan, nipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н. Wс╗Нn lo sс╗Н ninu ifс╗Нrс╗Нwerс╗Н kan pe ilu Iwo lo maa n yan с║╣ni ti yoo jс║╣ Olubadan.Wс╗Нn ni ija igboro wa ninu с║╣jс║╣ Oluwoo, ko si si eeyan nla nla ti ko ti i ba ja tan. Lara wс╗Нn ni с╗Мс╗Нni ti Ifс║╣, Alaafin ti с╗Мyс╗Н, с╗Мrangun ti Ila, Oloye Abiс╗Нla Ogundokun, Imrah Adio ati bс║╣с║╣ bс║╣с║╣ lс╗Н.Ju gbogbo rс║╣ lс╗Н, awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ yii sс╗Н pe o jс║╣ nnkan ibanujс║╣ fun awс╗Нn pe с║╣ni to ti с╣гс║╣wс╗Нn ri lorileede United States of America (USA) ati Canada ni Oluwoo.Wс╗Нn ni ki Gomina Oyetс╗Нla gba ilu Iwo lс╗Нwс╗Н idojuti ti с╗Мba Adewale n mu ba a nipa yiyс╗Н с╗Н nipo с╗Нba to wa ko too di pe yoo ba ilu Iwo jс║╣.с╣вugbс╗Нn с╗Нrс╗Н naa ko ti i balс║╣ ti Akс╗Нwe iroyin с╗Мba Adewale, Alli Ibrahim, fi fun awс╗Нn baba naa lesi. O ni atamс╗Н lasan ni с╗Нrс╗Н awс╗Нn baba naa ati pe ariwo с╗Нja lasan ni wс╗Нn n pa, eleyii ti ko si le tu irun kankan lara Oluwoo.Alli с╣гalaye pe с╗Нmс╗Нс╗Нba kan to du ipo Oluwoo pс║╣lu с╗Мba Adewale Akanbi lo wa nidii wahala naa, o ni wс╗Нn n с╣гe bс║╣с║╣ lati le jс║╣ ki awс╗Нn eeyan ro pe ko si alaafia niluu Iwo, с╣гugbс╗Нn ero wс╗Нn ko le jс╗Н.O ni ko si bi idunkukulaja naa с╣гe le le to, ko le di awс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣ rere ti Oluwoo n с╣гe fun awс╗Нn eeyan ilu naa lс╗Нwс╗Н rara, ati pe с║╣ni to n lo awс╗Нn oloye oun lati с╣гiс╣гс║╣ tako oun kan n с╣гe e lasan ni, с╣гe ni ko lс╗Н gba fun с╗Мlс╗Нrun.Lс╗Нjс╗Н keji, iyс║╣n с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, Igbakeji Oluwoo, to si jс║╣ olori awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ niluu Iwoo, Oosa ti ilu Iwo, Oloye Yekeen Bello, ba ALAROYE sс╗Нrс╗Н nile rс║╣, o ni с╗Нrс╗Н rirun gbaa ni Alli sс╗Н lorukс╗Н Oluwoo, ati pe ti awс╗Нn ba fс║╣с║╣ gba owo lс╗Нwс╗Н с║╣nikс║╣ni lati lo awс╗Нn tako Oluwoo, с╗Нrс╗Н naa ko ni i le to bayii.Oloye Bello ni тАЬNitori iwa ati iс╣гe Oluwoo lo jс║╣ ka kс╗Н iwe с║╣honu naa si gomina. Ihuwasi rс║╣ ti n ko idojuti ba ilu Iwo, ti с║╣ ba ri nnkan ti awс╗Нn eeyan maa n sс╗Н nipa rс║╣ lori с║╣rс╗Н ayelujara, с║╣ maa mс╗Н pe o buru jai.тАЬNigba ti с╗Нba ko ba ka awс╗Нn ijoye si, ti ko ka awс╗Нn agbaagba si, ki lс║╣ ro pe o le с╣гс║╣lс║╣? A ti gbiyanju pupс╗Н lati mu iwa rс║╣ mс╗Нra, с╣гugbс╗Нn a ko le tс║╣siwaju mс╗Н bayii, a ti gba a nimс╗Нran, a pe e jokoo, sibс║╣, ko ni i gbс╗Н, idi niyс║╣n ti awa afс╗Нbajс║╣ fi pinnu pe a gbс╗Нdс╗Н gbe igbesс║╣ kan.тАЬFun apс║╣rс║╣, с╗Мlaoluwa ati Ayedire wa labс║╣ ilс║╣ Iwo, с╣гugbс╗Нn awс╗Нn da loni-in? с╣вe ohun to bojumu ni ki awс╗Нn igbimс╗Н lс╗Нbalс╗Нba da с╗Нba duro gс║╣gс║╣ bo с╣гe с╣гс║╣lс║╣ si Oluwoo? Aanu Alli с╣гe mi pс║╣lu irс╗Н buruku to n pa kaakiri, a si ti fun un ni с╗Нjс╗Н meje lati sс╗Н с║╣ni to sс╗Н pe o gbe owo fun wa lati maa daamu Oluwoo, lai jс║╣ bс║╣с║╣, yoo ba wa ni kootu.тАЬDipo ko fun awa oloye ni с║╣tс╗Н wa ninu alokesan to n gba loс╣гooс╣гu, с╣гe lo sс╗Н pe ka lс╗Нс╗Н wa iс╣гс║╣ с╣гe. O ni с╗Нba nikan lo ni alokesan, с║╣rin pa mi, с╣гe ara-oko lo pe wa ni? Ki odidi oloye maa mu с║╣gbс║╣run mс║╣ta, с║╣gbс║╣run mс║╣rin lс╗Н sile loс╣гooс╣гu, o с╣гe ni laaanu.тАЬKo too di pe a fi Adewale jс╗Нba, yatс╗Н si pe ko gbe ninu ilu, с╣гe lo dibс╗Нn fun wa, iwa oniwa lo n hu, o fiwa pamс╗Н fun wa, с╣гugbс╗Нn nitori pe с╗Нrс║╣ lemi ati baba rс║╣, mo ti i lс║╣yin. Nigba to fс║╣с║╣ joye, mo ti ra bulс╗Нс╗Нku ti mo fс║╣с║╣ fi kс╗Нle silс║╣, с╣гugbс╗Нn mo na owo yс║╣n lori с╗Нrс╗Н oye с╗Нba yii ni, ti bulс╗Нс╗Нku si с╣гofo, с╣гugbс╗Нn bayii, emi ni olori awс╗Нn с╗Нta rс║╣.тАЬAwa mс║╣rinla ni afс╗Нbajс║╣, с║╣ni kan ti с╣гalaisi laarin wa, a ko si mu iwe lс╗Н sс╗Нdс╗Н с║╣ni kс║╣tala nitori idi pataki to han si wa. Ohun ti a fс║╣ bayii ni pe ki gomina ba wa yс╗Н с╗Мba Adewale nipo, с╗Нrс╗Н rс║╣ ti su waтАЭALAROYE gbiyanju lati ba с║╣ni ti Oluwoo sс╗Н pe o ba oun du ipo с╗Нba, Alhaji Abdulazeez Inaс╗Нlaji, sс╗Нrс╗Н lori с║╣sun ti Oluwoo fi kan an pe oun lo wa nidii igbesс║╣ awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ sс╗Нrс╗Н, с╣гugbс╗Нn pabo lo ja si. Awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn sun mс╗Н baba naa jс║╣ ko di mimс╗Н pe o с╣гee с╣гe ko jс║╣ nitori с║╣jс╗Н to wa ni kootu ni baba naa ko с╣гe fс║╣с║╣ ba awс╗Нn oniroyin sс╗Нrс╗Н.с╣вugbс╗Нn Oloye Sunday Oyeniyi, Olosi ti ilu Iwo, с║╣ni to jс║╣ afс╗Нbajс║╣ kс║╣tala ti ko sс╗Нrс╗Н ni tiс║╣ sс╗Н pe ko с╣гee с╣гe lati rin ki ori ma mi. O ni oun gbagbс╗Н pe с╗Мlс╗Нrun nikan lo le fi с╗Нba jс║╣, Oun nikan naa si lo le yс╗Н с╗Нba loye, ati pe oun ko mс╗Н nnkan kan nipa iwe ti awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ yooku mu lс╗Н sс╗Нdс╗Н gomina.Oloye Oyeniyi waa rс╗Н Oluwoo lati tubс╗Н ni ikomс╗Нra, ko yago fun nini с╗Нta kun с╗Нta, bс║╣с║╣ lo si ni с╗Мlс╗Нrun nikan ni gbogbo ilu gbс╗Нdс╗Н ke pe bayii lati da si с╗Нrс╗Н naa.Bo с╣гe di с╗Нjс╗Н с║╕ti, Furaidee, ni awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ mejila yii gba ile-с║╣jс╗Н giga ipinlс║╣ с╗Мс╣гun lс╗Н, wс╗Нn wс╗Н Oluwoo lс╗Н si kootu, wс╗Нn ni ko gbс╗Нdс╗Н yс╗Н awс╗Нn, bс║╣с║╣ ni ko gbс╗Нdс╗Н fi с║╣lomi-in rс╗Нpo awс╗Нn gс║╣gс║╣ bii afс╗Нbajс║╣ ati oloye.Ninu iwe ipс║╣jс╗Н naa to ni nс╗Нmba HIW/M.18/2020, eleyii ti Oosa с╣гebura le lori pс║╣lu agbс║╣jс╗Нro wс╗Нn, John Enworo, ti ALAROYE si ri lс╗Нjс╗Н Aiku, Sannde, ni wс╗Нn ti sс╗Н pe lс║╣yin ti awс╗Нn kс╗Н iwe iyс╗Нnipo Oluwoo si gomina ni с╗Нba naa dс║╣ awс╗Нn tс╗Нс╗Нgi si awс╗Нn, inu ibс║╣rubojo ni gbogbo awс╗Нn si wa latigba naa.Oosa fi kun с╗Нrс╗Н rс║╣ ninu iwe ipс║╣jс╗Н naa pe Oluwoo ti ranс╣гс║╣ si gbogbo awс╗Нn agboole awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ naa lati fi orukс╗Н с║╣lomi-in ranс╣гс║╣, eleyii ti yoo fi rс╗Нpo awс╗Нn afс╗Нbajс║╣ ti wс╗Нn fс║╣ yс╗Н с╗Н nipo.Idi niyi ti wс╗Нn fi sa di kootu lati da Oluwoo duro ninu igbesс║╣ to fс║╣с║╣ gbe. Bi с║╣jс╗Н naa ba si с╣гe n lс╗Н si, ALAROYE yoo maa fi to yin leti."},{"question":"р╢пр╖Щр╖Гр╖Рр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢пр╖Щр╖Гр╖Рр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Щр╢Ьр╢╗р╖Т р╢пр╖Тр╢▒ р╢пр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒ р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖А р╢Ер╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢пр╖Ъ р╢пр╖Ьр╖Ер╖Ьр╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т (р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖К) р╢╕р╖Пр╖Гр╢║ р╖Ар╖Ъ."},{"question":"┘Г┘Е ╪╣╪п╪п ╪о┘Д┘Б╪з╪б ╪з┘Д╪п┘И┘Д╪й ╪з┘Д╪╣╪и╪з╪│┘К╪й╪Я","answer":"(37 ╪о┘Д┘К┘Б╪й)"},{"question":"Najite Dede","answer":"Najite Dede jс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├йb├мnrin ├аti adar├н f├н├мm├╣ n├н or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а. ├У jс║╣╠Б ar├бb├мnrin Michelle Dede ├аti Richard Mofe Damijo, ├аwс╗Нn mс║╣╠Бtс║╣╠Аta jс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├й.Or├║kс╗Н b├аb├б Najite ni Ogbeni Brownson Dede, aс╣гoj├║ N├а├мj├нr├н├а tс║╣╠Бlс║╣╠Аr├н s├н or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и Ethiopia."},{"question":"цЭ▒ц╡╖щБУф║ФхНБф╕ЙцмбуБзуАБхооуБЛуВЙцбСхРНуБ╛уБзуБоуБВуБДуБац╡╖уБоц╕буВЛщБУуБоуВКуВТуАБуБЭуБош╖ЭщЫвуБЛуВЙуАМф╜ХуБоц╕буБЧуАНуБиуБДуБЖуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"я╝Иц╡╖ф╕Кя╝Йф╕ГщЗМуБоц╕буБЧуБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"How does MLOps support the monitoring of model inference latency and response times?","answer":"MLOps monitors model inference latency by tracking the time it takes for models to process requests, ensuring that response times meet predefined performance criteria."},{"question":"Marina sa diso: tsy mety maty ny olona ","answer":"Tsia, diso io fanambarana io. Ny olona dia mety maty."},{"question":"р┤Ър╡Лр┤жр╡Нр┤пр┤В: р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤др┤┐р┤ир┤┐р┤зр┤┐р┤╕р┤нр┤пр┤┐р┤▓р╡Ж р┤Пр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р┤╡р╡Бр┤В р┤жр╡Ир╡╝р┤Шр╡Нр┤пр┤ор╡Зр┤▒р┤┐р┤п р┤Ер┤Вр┤Чр┤В р┤Жр┤░р┤╛р┤гр╡Н? р┤Йр┤др╡Нр┤др┤░р┤В:","answer":"р┤╣р╡Мр┤╕р╡Н р┤Ур┤лр╡Н р┤▒р╡Жр┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤╕р┤ир╡Нр┤▒р╡Зр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р╡Ар┤╡р╡Нр┤╕р┤┐р┤▓р╡Ж р┤Пр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р┤╡р╡Бр┤В р┤Хр╡Вр┤Яр╡Бр┤др╡╜ р┤Хр┤╛р┤▓р┤В р┤╕р╡Зр┤╡р┤ир┤ор┤ир╡Бр┤╖р╡Нр┤ар┤┐р┤Ър╡Нр┤Ъ р┤Ер┤Вр┤Чр┤ор┤╛р┤гр╡Н р┤Ьр╡Лр╡║ р┤бр┤┐р┤Вр┤Чр╡╜"},{"question":"рдмрд┐.рд╕.резрепрепреи рдХреЛ рдПрд╕. рдПрд▓. рд╕реА рдкрд░рд┐рдХреНрд╖рд╛рдорд╛ рдХрддрд┐ рдЬрдирд╛ рдкрд╛рд╕ рднрдПрдХрд╛ рдерд┐рдП ?","answer":"рдмрд┐.рд╕.резрепрепреи рдХреЛ рдПрд╕. рдПрд▓. рд╕реА рдкрд░рд┐рдХреНрд╖рд╛рдорд╛  резреп рдЬрдирд╛ рдкрд╛рд╕ рднрдПрдХрд╛ рдерд┐рдП |"},{"question":"цИСуБМхЫ╜уБох╣┤хП╖уБзуАБуАМцДЯхоЭ(уБЛуВУуБ╜уБЖ)уАНуАМхЛЭхоЭ (уБЧуВЗуБЖуБ╗уБЖ)уАНуАМхоЭхнЧ (уБ╗уБЖуБШ)уАНуАМчеЮшн╖ (уБШуВУуБФ)уАНуБиуБДуБИуБ░уАБхЕ▒щАЪуБЧуБжф╕КуБлф╗ШуБПц╝вхнЧф║МцЦЗхнЧуБпф╜ХуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"хдйх╣│(уБжуВУуБ┤уВЗуБЖ)уБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"╨Ы╨╛╨╜╨┤╨╛╨╜, ╨Р╨╜╨│╨╗╨╕╤П ╨Ц╥п╨┤╨╛╨╜╤Г╨╜ ╥п╤З╥п╨╜╤З╥п ╤Б╨╡╤Б╤Б╨╕╤П╤Б╤Л ╨Ы╨╛╨╜╨┤╨╛╨╜╨┤╨╛╨│╤Г ExCeL ╨в╥п╨╜╨┤╥п╨║ ╨Р╤А╨╡╨╜╨░ 2╨┤╨╡ ╨╛╨╜ ╨░╨╗╤В╤Л ╤А╨░╤Г╨╜╨┤╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А╨┤╨╡╨╜ ╨╢╨╛╨║ ╨║╤Л╨╗╤Г╤Г ╤В╤Г╤А╨╜╨╕╤А╨╕ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И╤В╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л","answer":"2012-╨╢╤Л╨╗╨║╤Л ╨╢╨░╨╣╨║╤Л ╨Я╨░╤А╨░╨╗╨╕╨╝╨┐╨╕╨░╨┤╨░ ╨╛╤О╨╜╨┤╨░╤А╤Л."},{"question":"рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╛ро░ро┐ройрпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ  роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роЪро┐ро▓ро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"роРроорпНрокрпБро▓ройрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБродрпН родроЯрпНроЯрпБрокрпНрокроЯро╛род ро╡ро┐ро╖ропроорпН, рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН, роироЯрокрпНрокрпБ, роОродрпБро╡ро╛ройро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роЕродрпБ рокрпКропрпН роОройрпНрокродрпЗ рокроХрпБродрпНродро▒ро┐ро╡ро╛ро│ройро┐ройрпН роХрпКро│рпНроХрпИ.роироорпН рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпН роХрпБро▒рпИроирпНрод рокроЯрпНроЪроорпН 20 ро╡ропродрпБ ро╡ро░рпИ рокроЯро┐роХрпНроХ ро╡рпИроХрпНроХ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроХрпН роХро▓рпНро╡ро┐ропро│ро┐роХрпНроХ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ роПро▒рпНро▒ ро╡ро░рпБро╡ро╛ропрпБро│рпНро│ родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпИ роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроХрпН роХро▒рпНрокро┐роХрпНроХро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. роЕродройрпНрокро┐ройрпН роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро╛роХродрпН родроЩрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпЗро▒рпНро▒ родрпБрогрпИро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпИ роПро▒рпНро▒рпБроХрпН роХрпКро│рпНро│ роЕройрпБроородро┐роХрпНроХ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роХро╡ро▓рпИропро▒рпНро▒ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпБ ро╡ро╛ро┤ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. рооройро┐родройрпН роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН-рокроХрпБродрпНродро▒ро┐ро╡рпБро│рпНро│ро╡ройрпН роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН, роЕродро▒рпНроХрпБрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН роХро╡ро▓рпИропро▒рпНро▒рпБ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡родрпЗропро╛роХрпБроорпН.рооро╛ройроорпБроорпН роЕро▒ро┐ро╡рпБроорпН рооройро┐родройрпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЕро┤роХрпБ.рокроХрпБродрпНродро▒ро┐ро╡рпБ роОройрпНрокродрпБ рооройро┐родройрпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЙропро┐ро░рпНроиро╛роЯро┐роорпВроЯроироорпНрокро┐роХрпНроХрпИропрпБроорпН роХрпБро░рпБроЯрпНроЯрпБрокрпН рокро┤роХрпНроХроорпБроорпН роЪроорпВроХродрпНродро┐ройрпН роорпБродро▓рпН рокроХрпИро╡ройрпНро╡ро┐родро┐ропрпИ роироорпНрокро┐ роородро┐ропрпИ роЗро┤роХрпНроХро╛родрпЗ!роороХрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роТро┤рпБроХрпНроХродрпНродрпИропрпБроорпН роородро┐ропрпИропрпБроорпН роХрпЖроЯрпБрокрпНрокродрпБ роородрпБ.рооройро┐родрокрпН рокрогрпНрокрпИ ро╡ро│ро░рпНрокрпНрокродрпЗ роОройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроиро╛ро│рпН рокрогро┐.рокро┐ро▒ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБ родрпКро▓рпНро▓рпИ родро░ро╛род ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпЗ роТро┤рпБроХрпНроХ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпБ.рокроХрпНродро┐ роОройрпНрокродрпБ родройро┐роЪрпН роЪрпКродрпНродрпБ. роТро┤рпБроХрпНроХроорпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ рокрпКродрпБ роЪрпКродрпНродрпБ.рокроХрпНродро┐ роЗро▓рпНро▓ро╛ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпН роЗро┤рокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпИ. роТро┤рпБроХрпНроХроорпН роЗро▓рпНро▓ро╛ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпН рокро╛ро┤рпН."},{"question":"шлЛхЫЮчнФщАЩхАЛхХПщбМя╝ЪхКацЛ┐хдзчЪДуАМцДПхдзхИйчз╗ц░СуАНф╕╗шжБщЫЖф╕нхЬихУкф║ЫхЯОх╕Вя╝Я","answer":"чнФцбИя╝ЪхКацЛ┐хдзчЪДцДПхдзхИйчз╗ц░Сф╕╗шжБщЫЖф╕нхЬихдЪхАлхдЪуАБц║лхУешПпуАБшТЩчЙ╣хИйчИ╛хТМцДЫх╛╖шТЩщаУчнЙхЯОх╕ВуАВши▒хдЪцДПхдзхИйчз╗ц░СхЬи20ф╕Цч┤АхИЭцЬЯхТМх╛МцЬЯф╛ЖхИ░хКацЛ┐хдзя╝Мф╕жхЬищАЩф║ЫхЯОх╕Вх╗║члЛф║Жч╣БцжочЪДцДПхдзхИйчд╛хНАуАВ"},{"question":"рк╣рк░рлНрк╖ ркмрлНрк░рк╣рлНркоркнркЯрлНркЯ ркирлА \\"рк╢ркмрлНркжркорк╛ркВркерлА ркЕрк░рлНрке ркЫрлВркЯрк╛ ркерк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ\\" ркХрк╡рк┐ркдрк╛ рк▓ркЦрлЛ.","answer":"рк╢ркмрлНркжркорк╛ркВркерлА ркЕрк░рлНрке ркЫрлВркЯрк╛ ркерк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ,рк╡рлЗркжркирк╛ рк╢рлБркВ ркП рк╣рк╡рлЗ рк╕ркоркЬрк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ.ркХрлЛркг ркПркирлЗ ркЭрк╛ркВркЭрк╡рк╛ рк╕рлАркВркЪрлНркпрк╛ ркХрк░рлЗ,рк░рлЛркЬ рк░рк╛ркдрлЗ рк╕рлНрк╡рккрлНрки ркПркХ рклркгркЧрк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ.ркЖркВркЦ ркорк╛рк░рлА ркПркХ ркПрк╡рлЛ ркХрлЛркпркбрлЛ,ркЬрк╛рко ркЦрк╛рк▓рлА ркЫрлЗ ркЫркдрк╛ркВ ркЫрк▓ркХрк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ.ркорк╛рк░рлА ркнрлАркдрк░ ркХрлЗркЯрк▓рлБркВ рк╡рк░рк╕рлНркпрк╛ркВ ркдркорлЗ,ркЖркЦрлЗркЖркЦрлБркВ ркЕркВркЧ рк▓рлАрк▓рлБркВ ркерк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ.ркЪрлАрк░ рк╣рк░рккрк│ ркХрлЗркЯрк▓рк╛ ркЦрлЗркВркЪрк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ,ркХрлГрк╖рлНркгркирлЗ рккркг ркХрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркХрк╢рлБркВркпрлЗ ркерк╛ркп ркЫрлЗ."},{"question":"ркЧрлНрк░рлЗркирлА ркПркирк╛ркЯрлЛркорлАркорк╛ркВ ркХрлЗркЯрк▓рк╛ рк╕рлНрккрк┐рки-ркУркл ркЫрлЗ?","answer":"ркЧрлНрк░рлЗркирлА ркПркирк╛ркЯрлЛркорлАркорк╛ркВ ркдрлНрк░ркг рк╕рлНрккрк┐рки-ркУркл ркЫрлЗ: ркЦрк╛ркиркЧрлА рккрлНрк░рлЗркХрлНркЯрк┐рк╕ (2007-2013), рк╕рлНркЯрлЗрк╢рки 19 (2018-рк╣рк╛рк▓), ркЕркирлЗ ркЧрлНрк░рлЗркирлА ркПркирк╛ркЯрлЛркорлА: ркмрлА-ркЯрлАрко (2021-рк╣рк╛рк▓)."},{"question":"ркЭрлАркгрк╛ркнрк╛ркИ ркжрлЗрк╕рк╛ркИ тАШрк╕рлНркирлЗрк╣рк░рк╢рлНркорк┐тАЩркирлА \\"рк╕рк╛ркВркЬ рккркбрлАркирлЗ\\" ркХрк╡рк┐ркдрк╛ рк▓ркЦрлЛ.","answer":"рк╕рк╛ркВркЬ рккркбрлАркирлЗ ркШрлЗрк░ ркЬрк╡рк╛ рк╣рлБркВ рк╕рк╛рке рк░рк╣рлНркпрлЛ ркдрлЛ ркЦрлЛрк│рлАркжрлАркарлА ркорлЗркВ ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡ркдрлА рк╕рк╛ркорлЗ ркмрк╛рк│рк╛ ркПркХ ркнрлЛрк│рлАркжрлАркарк╛ркВ ркдрлЗркирк╛ ркирлЗркг рк╕рлБрк╣рк╛ркЧрлА, рк╕рлБрк╣рк╛ркЧрлА ркирлЗркг ркдрлЗркирк╛ркзрлАркорлЗ рк░рк╣рлАркирлЗ рккрлВркЫрлНркпрлБркВ ркдрлЗркирлЗ ркХрлЛркирлА ркХрк╣рлЗ ркдрлБркВ ркмрк╣рлЗркирк╛рк▓ркЬрк╛ркоркгрлАркирк╛ ркЫрлЛркб рк╕ркорлАрккрлЗ ркиркоркгрлА ркирк╛ркЬрлБркХ рк╡рлЗрк▓ркмрлЛрк▓ рк╕рлБркгрлАркирлЗ ркЖркВркЦ ркврк╛рк│рлА ркдрлЗ ркЖркВркЦ ркдрлЗ ркирк╛ ркорлЗрк▓рлАрк╕рк╛ркВркЬ рккркбрлАркирлЗ ркШрлЗрк░ ркЬрк╡рк╛ рк╣рлБркВ..ркХрк╛рк│рк╛ ркХрк╛рк│рк╛ ркХрлЗрк╢ ркдрк╛рк░рк╛, ркХрлЗрк╢ ркХрк╛рк│рк╛ ркХрк╛рк│рк╛ркжрк┐рки рк╕рк╛ркерлЗ ркмрлЗрк╕рлА рк░ркЬркирлАркП ркЧрлВркВркерлНркпрк╛ ркХрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ ркмрк╛рк│рк╛ркЧрлМрк░ ркнрк░рлЗрк▓рк╛ ркмрк╛рк│рк╛ркирлЗ ркдрлЗркирлЗ ркЧрлЛрк░рк╛ ркорлБркЧрлНркз ркЧрк╛рк▓рлЗркирк╛ркиркХркбрк╛ ркмрлЗ ркЧрлБрк▓рк╛ркм ркЦрлАрк▓рлНркпрк╛, ркЙрк╖рк╛ ркЦрлАрк▓рлА ркХркВркИ ркнрк╛рк▓рлЗрк╕рк╛ркВркЬ рккркбрлА ркирлЗ ркШрлЗрк░ ркЬрк╡рк╛ рк╣рлБркВ..ркЕрк╕рлНркерк┐рк░ ркбркЧрк▓рк╛ ркнрк░рк┐ркпрк╛ ркЖркЧрк│, ркбркЧ ркнрк░рк┐ркпрк╛ ркорлЗркВ ркЪрк╛рк░ркЙркВркЪрлА ркирлАркЪрлА ркеркдрлА ркорлЗркВ ркдрлЗркирлЗ рк╣рлИркпрлЗ ркжрлАркарлА ркорк╛рк│ркЫрк╛ркирлАркорк╛ркирлА рк╢рк░ркорк╛ркдрлА ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлА рк░рк╛ркд ркХрк╛рк│рлАрк╣рлИркпрлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлЗ ркврк│рлА рк░рк╣рлА ркорлЗркВ ркЖркдрлБрк░ ркЖркВркЦ ркнрк╛рк│рлАрк╕рк╛ркВркЬ рккркбрлА ркирлЗ ркШрлЗрк░ ркЬрк╡рк╛ рк╣рлБркВ..рк╡рлЗркгрлА ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ рклрлВрк▓ ркЧрлВркВркерлНркпрк╛ ркорлЗркВ, рклрлВрк▓ ркЧрлВркВркерлНркпрк╛ ркорлЗркВ рк╕рк╛ркдркХрк╛ркВркарлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлЗ рк░рк╣рлНркпрк╛ рк╡рлАркВркЯрк╛ркпрлА ркирк╛ркЬрлБркХ ркП ркмрлЗ рк╣рк╛рке."},{"question":" Sheeg Imisa Ayey Ahaayeen Muslimiinta Dagaalkii MuтАЩta","answer":"яГШ  Dagaalkii MuтАЩta Muslimiinta Waxay Ahaayeen 3000."},{"question":"риорйМри╕риорйА рилрйБрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ рижрйА римрйАриЬри╛риИ рижри╛ ри╕риори╛риВ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ ред","answer":"риорйМри╕риорйА рилрйБрй▒ри▓ риЗриХ ри╕ри╛ри▓ риЬри╛риВ риЗриХ риорйМри╕рио ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЖрикригри╛ риЬрйАри╡рии риЪрй▒риХри░ рикрйВри░ри╛ риХри░ ри▓рйИриВрижрйЗ ри╣рии ред риЗри╣риири╛риВ рижрйА римри┐риЬри╛риИ рижри╛ ри╕риори╛риВ риЧри░риорйА ри░рйБрй▒рид рижрйЗ рилрйБрй▒ри▓-рилри╝ри░ри╡ри░рйА-риори╛ри░риЪ, ри╡ри┐риЪ рикриирйАри░рйА ридрйЗ риЦрйЗридри╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬрижрйЛриВ рикриирйАри░рйА риЪри╛ри░ ри╣рилридрйЗ рижрйА ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛ри╡рйЗ ред римри░ри╕ри╛рид ри░рйБрй▒рид рижрйЗ рилрйБрй▒ри▓-риЬрйВрии рижрйЗ рикри╣ри┐ри▓рйЗ ри╣рилри╝ридрйЗ рикриирйАри░рйА риЕридрйЗ риЦрйЗридри╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬрйБри▓ри╛риИ рижрйЗ рикри╣ри┐ри▓рйЗ ри╣рилри╝ридрйЗ рее ри╕ри░рижрйА ри░рйБрй▒рид рижрйЗ рилрйБрй▒ри▓-ри╕ридрй░римри░ рижрйЗ риЕрй▒риз ри╡ри┐риЪ рикриирйАри░рйА ридрйЗ риЦрйЗридри╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЕриХридрйВримри░ рижрйЗ риЕрй▒риз ри╡ри┐риЪ ред"},{"question":"цмбуБоцо╡шР╜уБлуГЮуГГуГБуБЩуВЛуВ┐уВдуГИуГлуВТуБдуБСуБжуБПуБауБХуБДя╝Ъ ц╢Иш▓╗чФЯц┤╗уВ╗уГ│уВ┐уГ╝уБкуБйуБлуБпхО╗х╣┤уАБSNSуБоуГИуГйуГЦуГлуБлуБдуБДуБжуБочЫ╕шлЗуБМ6ф╕З552уБВуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуБКуБиуБиуБЧуВИуВКч┤Д1ф╕ЗхвЧуБИуБжуАБф╗КуБ╛уБзуБо10х╣┤уБзуБДуБбуБ░уВУхдЪуБПуБкуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ40цн│ф╗еф╕КуБоф║║уБЛуВЙуБочЫ╕шлЗуБМуБиуБжуВВхвЧуБИуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВчЙ╣уБл50ф╗гуБоф║║уБЛуВЙуБочЫ╕шлЗуБпуАБуБКуБиуБиуБЧуВИуВК2574хвЧуБИуБжуАБ1ф╕З2521уБзуБЧуБЯуАВхИЭуВБуБж20ф╗гуВИуВКхдЪуБПуБкуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуАМSNSуБох║ГхСКуВТшжЛуБжц│ицЦЗуБЧуБЯуБМуАБуБЖуБЭуБоуВжуВзуГЦуВ╡уВдуГИуБауБгуБЯуАНуБиуБЛуАМSNSуБзчЯеуБгуБЯф║║уБоч┤╣ф╗ЛуБзцЪЧхП╖ш│ЗчФгуВТщАБуБгуБжхПЦуВЙуВМуБЯуАНуБкуБйуБочЫ╕шлЗуБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ65цн│ф╗еф╕КуБоф║║уБЛуВЙуБпуАМхБех║╖уБлуБДуБДщгЯуБ╣чЙйуАНуБлуБдуБДуБжуБочЫ╕шлЗуБМуБДуБбуБ░уВУхдЪуБПуБжуАБх╣┤щ╜вуБМф╕КуБМуВЛуБиуАМхо╢уБоф┐очРЖуБкуБйуАНуБочЫ╕шлЗуБМхвЧуБИуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВц▓│щЗОхдзшЗгуБпуАМуГИуГйуГЦуГлуБпх╣┤щ╜вуБзщБХуБЖуБУуБиуБМуВПуБЛуВКуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВц╢Иш▓╗шАЕх║БуБпуАБуГИуГйуГЦуГлуБлуБдуБДуБжф╝ЭуБИуБжуАБц░ЧуВТуБдуБСуВЛуВИуБЖуБлшиАуБгуБжуБДуБНуБЯуБДуБишАГуБИуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ","answer":"SNSуБоуГИуГйуГЦуГлчЫ╕шлЗуААф╗КуБ╛уБзуБо10х╣┤уБзуБДуБбуБ░уВУхдЪуБД"},{"question":"Qual ├й o papel de um mec├вnico automotivo?","answer":"Um mec├вnico automotivo faz reparos e manuten├з├гo em ve├нculos, garantindo que funcionem corretamente."},{"question":"риорйИриВ ри╣риерйМрйЬрйЗ риири╛ри▓ риорйЗриЦ риЧрй▒риб рижри┐рй▒ридрйАред | рииридрйАриЬрйЗ ри╡риЬрйЛриВ риХрйА ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ? риЪрйЛриг 1 : риорйЗриЦ ри▓рй▒риХрйЬ ри╡ри┐риЪ риарйЛриХ ри╣рйЛ риЧриИред риЪрйЛриг 2 : риорйЗриЦ риирйВрй░ риЬрй░риЧри╛ри▓ ри▓рй▒риЧ риЧри┐риЖред ","answer":"риЪрйЛриг 1 : риорйЗриЦ ри▓рй▒риХрйЬ ри╡ри┐риЪ риарйЛриХ ри╣рйЛ риЧриИред"},{"question":"Ndeipi nzira yakanakisa yekutsanangura data & AI zano?","answer":"\\"Shandura bhizinesi rako nedhijitari mudhata rako uye AI chiono uye zano rinoratidza nzvimbo dzemikana mikuru inokwenenzvera bhizinesi rako razvino pamwe nemabhizinesi matsva anoshandisa AI uye data.Ziva maitiro ebhizinesi (kuvandudzwa kwechigadzirwa, kugadzira, kutengesa & kushambadzira, cheni yekugovera, mitengo, HR, mari, nezvimwewo) kwaunoda kushandisa data neAI.Nzwisisa mamiriro azvino e data rako uye kugona kweAI.Rondedzera mamiriro akatarwa ebhizinesi rako maitiro kana data uye AI kugona zvaiswa.Tsanangura bhizinesi idzva rinofambiswa nedata uye mazano echigadzirwa.Tsanangura nzira yako yekuuraya, kusanganisira mari.Ita iyo yekutanga data uye AI shandisa makesi nekugadzira yako AI playbook, yakanangana nekugadzirira kugadzira.Automate uye wedzera mashandiro\\""},{"question":"роЗроирпНродрокрпН рокродрпНродро┐ропро┐ройрпН родрпКроЯро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ропрпИ роОро┤рпБродрпБроХ:родрпЖройрпН роХрпКро░ро┐ропродрпН родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯродрпНродрпБро▒рпИ роОройрпНрокродрпБ 1945 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роорпБродро▓рпН родрпЖройрпН роХрпКро░ро┐ропро╛ роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро╛роХрпБроорпН родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН, роЕродрпИроЪрпН роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро╛ро│ро░рпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роЙро│рпНро│роЯроХрпНроХро┐роп родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯродрпНродрпБро▒рпИ роЖроХрпБроорпН. роХрпКро░ро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роЬрокрпНрокро╛ройро┐роп роЖроХрпНроХро┐ро░рооро┐рокрпНрокрпБ, роХрпКро░ро┐ропрокрпН рокрпЛро░рпН,","answer":"роЕро░роЪро╛роЩрпНроХ родрогро┐роХрпНроХрпИ, ро╡рогро┐роХродрпН родрпБро▒рпИ, роЙро▓роХрооропрооро╛роХрпНроХро▓рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН родрпЖройрпН роХрпКро░ро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роЬройроиро╛ропроХрооропрооро╛роХрпНроХро▓рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роиро┐роХро┤рпНро╡рпБроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро┐ро░роЪрпНроЪройрпИроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН родрпЖройрпН роХрпКро░ро┐роп родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯродрпНродрпБро▒рпИ рокрпЖро░ро┐родрпБроорпН рокро╛родро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│рой. 20 роЖроорпН роирпВро▒рпНро▒ро╛рогрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роироЯрпБрокрпНрокроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН родрпЖройрпН роХрпКро░ро┐ропродрпН родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯродрпНродрпБро▒рпИропро┐ройрпН рокрпКро▒рпНроХро╛ро▓роорпН роОройро▓ро╛роорпН. 1960 роХро│ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро╛рой 'родро┐ ро╣ро╡рпБро╕рпНроорпЖропрпНроЯрпН' (1960) рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН 'роУрокро▓рпНроЯройрпН' (1961) рокрпЛройрпНро▒ родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпН роОро▓рпНро▓ро╛ роХро╛ро▓роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▒роирпНрод рокроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпН роОрой роХро░рпБродрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. 1990 роХро│ро┐ройрпН рокро┐ро▒рпНрокроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роЗройрпНро▒рпБро╡ро░рпИ 'родро┐ роЕроЯрпНрооро┐ро░ро▓рпН: ро░рпЛро░ро┐роЩрпН роХро░рогрпНроЯрпНро╕рпН' (2014) рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН 'роОроХрпНро╕рпНроЯрпНро░рпАроорпН роЬро╛рокрпН' (2019) рокрпЛройрпНро▒ родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпЖройрпН роХрпКро░ро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХ ро╡роЪрпВро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНрод рокроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роХрпЛро▓рпНроЯройрпН ро▓ропройрпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБродрпБ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒ родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпН роЖроХрпБроорпН. 2012 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро╛рой 'рокро┐ропроЯрпН' роОройрпНро▒ родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯроорпН рокро╛роорпН роЯро┐ роЖро░рпН роОройрпНро▒ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБродрпБроорпН 2019 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро╛рой рокро╛ро░роЪрпИроЯрпНроЯрпБ роОройрпНро▒ родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯроорпН роЪро┐ро▒роирпНрод родро┐ро░рпИрокрпНрокроЯродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХро╛рой ро╡рпЖро│ро┐роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ рокроЯродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХро╛роХ роЕроХро╛родрооро┐ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБродрпБ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│родрпБ."},{"question":"Mс╗Щt mс║гnh v╞░с╗Эn c├│ dс║бng h├мnh vu├┤ng vс╗Ыi chiс╗Бu d├аi cс║бnh bс║▒ng 25m. Ng╞░с╗Эi ta ─Сс╗Г mс╗Щt phс║зn cс╗зa mс║гnh v╞░с╗Эn l├аm lс╗Сi ─Сi rс╗Щng 2m, phс║зn c├▓n lс║бi ─Сс╗Г trс╗Уng rau. H├гy trс║г lс╗Эi hai c├вu hс╗Пi sau:a) T├нnh diс╗Зn t├нch phс║зn v╞░с╗Эn trс╗Уng rau.b) Ng╞░с╗Эi ta l├аm h├аng r├аo xung quanh mс║гnh v╞░с╗Эn trс╗Уng rau v├а с╗Я mс╗Щt g├│c v╞░с╗Эn rau c├│ ─Сс╗Г cс╗нa ra v├аo rс╗Щng 2m. T├нnh ─Сс╗Щ d├аi cс╗зa h├аng r├аo ─С├│.","answer":"a) V├м ng╞░с╗Эi ta ─Сс╗Г mс╗Щt phс║зn cс╗зa mс║гnh v╞░с╗Эn l├аm lс╗Сi ─Сi rс╗Щng 2 m n├кn phс║зn v╞░с╗Эn trс╗Уng rau l├а mс║гnh ─Сс║еt h├мnh vu├┤ng v├а c├│ ─Сс╗Щ d├аi cс║бnh l├а: 25 тАУ 2 = 23 (m)Diс╗Зn t├нch phс║зn v╞░с╗Эn trс╗Уng rau l├а: 23 . 23 = 529 (m2) b) Chu vi cс╗зa phс║зn v╞░с╗Эn trс╗Уng rau h├мnh vu├┤ng l├а: 4 . 23 = 92 (m)─Рс╗Щ d├аi cс╗зa h├аng r├аo ch├нnh l├а chu vi cс╗зa phс║зn v╞░с╗Эn trс╗Уng rau trс╗л ─Сi phс║зn cс╗нa ra v├аo rс╗Щng 2 m. Do ─С├│ ─Сс╗Щ d├аi cс╗зa h├аng r├аo l├а: 92 тАУ 2 = 90 (m)Vс║нy diс╗Зn t├нch cс╗зa phс║зn v╞░с╗Эn trс╗Уng rau l├а 529 m2, v├а ─Сс╗Щ d├аi cс╗зa h├аng r├аo l├а 90 m."},{"question":"рдирд┐рдореНрдирд▓рд┐рдЦрд┐рдд рд╡рд╛рдХреНрдпрд╛рдВрд╢рдХреЛ рдЖрдзрд╛рд░рдорд╛, рдорд▓рд╛рдИ рдХреЗрд╣рд┐ рдкреНрд░рд╢реНрдирд╣рд░реВ рд▓реЗрдЦреНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реН:рдорд╛рдирд╡ рд╡рд┐рд╡реЗрдХрд╢реАрд▓ рдкреНрд░рд╛рдгреА рд╣реЛ ред рдорд╛рдирд╡рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рд╕рднреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рд╣реЛ ред рд╕рдордпрд╕рдБрдЧрд╕рдБрдЧреИ рдХреНрд░рдорд╢ рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рд╣реБрдБрджреИ рдЧрдЗрд░рд╣реЗрдХреЛ рдЫ ред рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛ рдорд╛рдирд╡ рдирд┐рд░реНрдорд┐рдд рдХреБрд░рд╛рд╣рд░реБ рд╣реБрдиреН ред рдЗрддрд┐рд╣рд╛рд╕рдХреЛ рдХрд╛рд▓рдЦрдгреНрдбрдорд╛ рдЬреАрд╡рди рдкрджреНрдзрддрд┐рдорд╛ рдкрд░рд┐рд╕реНрдХрд╛рд░ рдЧрд░реНрдиреЗ рдзреНрдпреЗрдпрд▓реЗ рдорд╛рдирд┐рд╕рд▓реЗ рд╡рд┐рднрд┐рдиреНрди рдзрд░реНрдорд╣рд░реБрдХреЛ рд╕реБрд░реБрд╡рд╛рдд рдЧрд░реЗрдХреЛ рдерд┐рдпреЛ ред рдпрд╣реА рдзрд░реНрдорд▓реЗ рдкрд╛рдк рд░ рдкреБрдгреНрдпрдХрд╛ рдмрд╛рд░реЗрдорд╛ рдорд╛рдирд┐рд╕рд▓рд╛рдИ рд╕рдЪреЗрдд рдЧрд░рд╛рдЙрдБрджреИ рдЧрдпреЛ рд░ рд╕рддреНрдпрдХреЛ рдмрд╛рдЯреЛрдорд╛ рд▓рд╛рдЧреНрди рдкреНрд░реЛрддреНрд╕рд╛рд╣рди рдЧрд░реНрджреИ рдЧрдпреЛ ред рдзрд░реНрдордХреЛ рдореБрдЦреНрдп рдЖрдзрд╛рд░ рднрдиреЗрдХреИ рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛ рдерд┐рдпреЛ ред рдорд╛рдирд╡ рд╕рднреНрдпрддрд╛рд▓рд╛рдИ рдЬрдЧреИрджреЗрдЦрд┐ рдмрд▓рд┐рдпреЛ рдмрдирд╛рдЙрди рдпрд┐рдиреАрд╣рд░реБрдХреЛ рдареВрд▓реЛ рдпреЛрдЧрджрд╛рди рд░рд╣реЗрдХреЛ рдЫ ред рдорд╛рдирд╡ рд╕рднреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕рдХрд╛ рд▓рд╛рдЧрд┐ рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛ рднрдиреЗрдХрд╛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕рдХрд╛ рдкреВрд░реНрд╡рд╛рдзрд╛рд░ рд╣реБрдиреН ред рдорд╛рдирд╡ рд╕рднреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕рд╕рдБрдЧреИ рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рднрдПрдХреЛ рдЫ ред ","answer":"1. рдорд╛рдирд╡рд▓реЗ рдХреЗ рдХреЗ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рдЧрд░реЗрдХреЛ рдЫ рд░ рддреА рдХрд╕рд░реА рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рдЧрд░реЗрдХреЛ рдЫ?2. рд╕рдордпрдХреЛ рд╕рд╛рдереИ рдХрд╕рд░реА рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп, рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕ рд╣реБрдБрджреИ рдЧрдЗрд░рд╣реЗрдХреЛ рдЫ?3. рдзрд░реНрдорд▓реЗ рдорд╛рдирд╡рд▓рд╛рдИ рдХрд╕рд░реА рд╕рдЪреЗрдд рдЧрд░рд╛рдЙрдБрдЫ рд░ рд╕рддреНрдпрдХреЛ рдмрд╛рдЯреЛрдорд╛ рд▓рд╛рдЧреНрди рдкреНрд░реЛрддреНрд╕рд╛рд╣рди рдЧрд░реНрджрдЫ?4. рдорд╛рдирд╡ рд╕рднреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕рдХрд╛ рд▓рд╛рдЧрд┐ рдХрд╕рд░реА рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп, рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛ рдкреНрд░рд╛рдзрд┐рдХрд░рдг рднрдиреЗрдХреЛ рдЫ?5. рдХрд╕рд░реА рдзрд░реНрдо, рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐, рд╕рд╛рдорд╛рдЬрд┐рдХ рдореВрд▓реНрдп, рд░ рдорд╛рдиреНрдпрддрд╛ рд▓реЗ рдорд╛рдирд╡ рд╕рднреНрдпрддрд╛рдХреЛ рд╡рд┐рдХрд╛рд╕рдорд╛ рдпреЛрдЧрджрд╛рди рдЧрд░реЗрдХрд╛ рдЫрдиреН?"},{"question":"SuтАЩaal: Sheeg Magaalada Ugu Qadiimsan Caalamka?","answer":"Jawaab: Magaalada Caalamka Ugu Qadiimsan Waa Magadala Arriixa Waxay-Na Ku TaalaaDalka Falastiin."},{"question":"Which was the first radio service in Asia?","answer":"The first radio service in Asia was established in India. It began as a private venture known as the \\"Indian Broadcasting Company (IBC)\\" and was initiated in Bombay (now Mumbai) on July 23, 1927. This was followed by a station in Calcutta (now Kolkata), which started broadcasting later that year. However, the IBC was not financially successful and was dissolved in 1930.Subsequently, the government of British India took over the broadcasting facilities and started the \\"Indian State Broadcasting Service\\" on April 1, 1930, which was later renamed \\"All India Radio (AIR)\\" in 1936. AIR played a significant role in the development of radio broadcasting in India and across Asia."},{"question":"р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░╡р░╛р░ир░┐р░▓р▒Л р░╣р░┐р░ор░╛р░▓р░п р░ир░жр░┐ р░Хр░╛р░ир░┐р░жр░┐.р░Чр░Вр░Чр░╛, р░╕р░┐р░Вр░зр▒Б, р░мр▒Нр░░р░╣р▒Нр░ор░кр▒Бр░др▒Нр░░, р░ор░╣р░╛р░ир░жр░┐, р░Чр░Вр░бр░Хр▒Н.","answer":"р░ор░╣р░╛р░ир░жр░┐"},{"question":"Hafiriana no matory isan'andro ny saka?","answer":"Environ 12 ├а 16 heures par jour."},{"question":"Joxeel p├йeteg waat yi ci k├аddu gii: ├Сa'y t├аxawe kaaraange ga ca dig u Polo├▒ wa d├лggal na ├▒u ne ├▒a yor kaaraange gu njiit u r├йew u ├Аfrig di Sidd ca f├лx-naaw ga la'├▒ fanaan fa Warsowi.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci k├аddu gii di \\"├Сa'y t├аxawe kaaraange ga ca dig u Polo├▒ wa d├лggal na ├▒u ne ├▒a yor kaaraange gu njiit u r├йew u ├Аfrig di Sidd ca f├лx-naaw ga la'├▒ fanaan fa Warsowi.\\" ak s├йen i p├йete ├▒oo di:├Сa: PRON'y: AUXt├аxawe: VERBkaaraange: NOUNga: DETca: ADPdig: NOUNu: ADPPolo├▒: PROPNwa: DETd├лggal: VERBna: AUX├▒u: PRONne: SCONJ├▒a: PRONyor: VERBkaaraange: NOUNgu: PRONnjiit: NOUNu: ADPr├йew: NOUNu: ADP├Аfrig: PROPNdi: ADPSidd: PROPNca: ADPf├лx-naaw: NOUNga: DETla: AUX'├▒: PRONfanaan: VERBfa: ADVWarsowi: PROPN.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Sheeg Goorma Ayuu Dhacay Dagaalkii Qandala?","answer":"Waxa uu dhacay sanadkii 8-aad ee Hijriyada."},{"question":"\\"Aquela pessoa ├й do piorio\\"O que significa \\"do piorio\\"?","answer":"A express├гo \\"do piorio\\" significa ser terr├нvel, portar-se muito mal."},{"question":"р░░р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░Хр░Хр░гр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░жр░╛ р░░р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░Хр░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░╛р░гр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Хр░▓р░┐р░Чр░┐р░и р░Ьр░ир░ир░╕р▒Нр░др░░р░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░╕р░Вр░мр░Вр░зр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╣р▒Ир░бр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░Ьр▒Лр░╡р░ир▒Нр░╕р▒Н, р░Зр░др░░ р░ир░┐р░бр▒Зр░░р░┐р░пр░ир▒Нр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░Чр░▓ р░кр▒Нр░░р░зр░╛р░и р░нр▒Зр░жр░ор▒Зр░ор░┐р░Яр░┐?","answer":"р░░р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░Хр░Хр░гр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░жр░╛ р░░р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░Х р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░╛р░гр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Ер░пр░┐р░и р░жр░Вр░╢ р░Хр░гр░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░мр░╛р░╣р▒Нр░п р░др▒Нр░╡р░Ър░ор▒Б р░ир▒Бр░Вр░бр░┐ р░Пр░░р▒Нр░кр░бр▒Бр░ир▒Б. р░ор░┐р░Чр░┐р░▓р░┐р░и р░ир░┐р░бр▒Зр░░р░┐р░пр░╛ р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Л р░мр░╛р░╣р▒Нр░пр░др▒Нр░╡р░Ър░ор▒Б р░ир▒Бр░Вр░бр░┐ р░Ер░Вр░др░╕р▒Нр░др▒Нр░╡р░Ър░В р░ир▒Бр░Вр░бр░┐ р░Пр░░р▒Нр░кр░бр▒Бр░ир▒Б."},{"question":"шЛ▒шкЮуБоуВвуГлуГХуВбуГЩуГГуГИуВТх░ПцЦЗхнЧуБочнЖшиШф╜УуБзцЫ╕уБДуБЯцЩВуАБф╕АчнЖцЫ╕уБНуБзуБНуБкуБДуБоуБпуАБя╝йуАБя╝куАБя╝┤уБиуВВуБЖя╝СуБдуБпф╜ХуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"я╝╕уБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH de Papua-Nova Guin├й? ","answer":"O IDH de Papua- Nova Guin├й em 2021 foi 0,558."},{"question":"р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░кр░жр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░╕р░░р░пр░┐р░и р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░гр░▓р░др▒Л р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.р░О) р░Пр░░р▒Лр░╕р░╛р░▓р▒Н р░мр░┐) р░╣р▒Ир░бр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░╕р░╛р░▓р▒Н","answer":"р░О) р░Пр░░р▒Лр░╕р░╛р░▓р▒Н :р░П р░Хр▒Кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░╛р░пр░┐р░бр▒Н р░жр▒Нр░░р░╛р░╡р░гр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░┐р░кр▒Нр░д р░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░╡р░╕р▒Нр░е р░Шр░ир░кр░жр░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░В р░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Зр░кр░г р░пр░╛р░ир░Хр░В р░Чр░╛р░▓р░┐ (р░╡р░╛р░пр▒Бр░╡р▒Б) р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр▒Л р░╡р░╛р░Яр░┐р░ир░┐ р░Ор░░р▒Лр░╕р░╛р░▓р▒Н р░Ер░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Йр░жр░╛ : р░кр▒Кр░Ч : р░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░┐р░кр▒Нр░др░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░╡р░╕р▒Нр░е : р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░мр░ир▒Н р░Хр░гр░╛р░▓р▒Б (р░Шр░и)р░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Зр░кр░г р░пр░╛р░ир░Хр░В : р░Чр░╛р░▓р░┐ (р░╡р░╛р░пр▒Бр░╡р▒Б)р░мр░┐) р░╣р▒Ир░бр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░╕р░╛р░▓р▒Н :р░П р░Хр▒Кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░╛р░пр░┐р░бр▒Н р░жр▒Нр░░р░╛р░╡р░гр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Зр░кр░В р░пр░╛р░ир░Хр░В р░ир▒Ар░░р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр▒Л р░╡р░╛р░Яр░┐р░ир░┐ р░╣р▒Ир░бр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░╕р░╛р░▓р▒Н р░Ер░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Йр░жр░╛ : р░кр░╛р░▓р▒Б : р░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░┐р░кр▒Нр░др░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░╡р░╕р▒Нр░е : р░жр▒Нр░░р░╡р░░р▒Вр░к р░Хр▒Нр░░р▒Кр░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Бр░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Зр░кр░г р░пр░╛р░ир░Хр░В : р░ир▒Ар░░р▒Б"},{"question":"\\tро╡ро┐ройро╛:         роХро░рпБрокрпНрокрпКро░рпБро│рпН ро╡роХрпИроХро│рпИ  ро╡ро┐ро│роХрпНроХрпБроХ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ:роРроирпНродрпБ родро┐рогрпИроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЙро░ро┐роп роиро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпБроорпН роЙропро┐ро░ро┐ройроЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпН ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХрпБроорпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпНроХро│рпБроорпН тАШроХро░рпБрокрпНрокрпКро░рпБро│рпНтАЩ роОрой ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЕроирпНродроирпНрод роиро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роПро▒рпНрок ро╡рпЗро▒рпБ ро╡рпЗро▒ро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХрпБроорпН роЕроХрпНроХро░рпБрокрпНрокрпКро░рпБро│рпНроХро│рпИ роЗро▓роХрпНроХрог роирпВро▓рпНроХро│рпН рокро▓ро╡ро╛ро▒рпБ ро╡роХрпИрокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроорпН. роироорпНрокро┐ропроХрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН 14 ро╡роХрпИропро╛рой роХро░рпБрокрпНрокрпКро░рпБро│рпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро▓рпН роЗроЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпН роХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЕро╡рпИропро╛ро╡рой1.роЖро░рогроЩрпНроХрпБ (родрпЖропрпНро╡роорпН)2.роЙропро░рпНроирпНродрпЛро░рпН3.роЙропро░рпНроирпНродрпЛро░рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓рпЛро░рпН4.рокрпБро│рпН (рокро▒ро╡рпИ)5.ро╡ро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХрпБ6.роКро░рпН7.роирпАро░рпН8.рокрпВ9.рооро░роорпН10.роЙрогро╡рпБ11.рокро▒рпИ12.ропро╛ро┤рпН13.рокрогрпН14.родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпН"},{"question":"Ibinzana 1: UYesu wachitha iintsuku ezintathu esiswini sentlanzi, uYona uza kuchitha iintsuku ezintathu engcwabeni. Ibinzana lesibini: UYona wachitha iintsuku ezintathu esiswini sentlanzi; uYesu uza kuchitha iintsuku ezintathu engcwabeni. Umbuzo: Ingaba ibinzana 1 nebinzana 2 zithetha into enye? Ewe okanye Hayi?","answer":"Hayi"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai besi dengan penempa\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya adalah orang lemah dikuasai orang kuat"},{"question":"ржПржЗ рж▓рзЗржЦрж╛ржЯрж┐ ржХрзЛржи ржЧрзБрж░рзБрждрзНржмржкрзВрж░рзНржг ржШржЯржирж╛ рж╕ржорзНржкрж░рзНржХрзЗ ?рж░рзБрж╣рзБрж▓ ржХрзБржжрзНржжрзБрж╕ рж╣рж▓рзЗржи ржмрж╛ржВрж▓рж╛ржжрзЗрж╢рзЗрж░ ржПржХржЬржи ржкрзНрж░ржЦрзНржпрж╛ржд рж░рж╛ржЬржирзАрждрж┐ржмрж┐ржжред ржорзБржХрзНрждрж┐ржпрзБржжрзНржзрзЗ ржЕржиржирзНржп рж╕рж╛ржзрж╛рж░ржг ржЕржмржжрж╛ржирзЗрж░ ржЬржирзНржп рзирзжрзжрзз рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗ рждрж╛ржХрзЗ тАЬрж╕рзНржмрж╛ржзрзАржирждрж╛ ржУ ржорзБржХрзНрждрж┐ржпрзБржжрзНржзрзЗ рж╕рзНржмрж╛ржзрзАржирждрж╛ ржкрзБрж░рж╕рзНржХрж╛рж░тАЭ ржкрзНрж░ржжрж╛ржи ржХрж░рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ред","answer":"ржмрж╛ржВрж▓рж╛ржжрзЗрж╢рзЗрж░ ржорзБржХрзНрждрж┐ржпрзБржжрзНржз |"},{"question":"р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╢зр╖К р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢йр╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢Йр╢пр╖Т р╢Ър╖Е р╢╜р╖Ьр╖А р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢ор╢╕ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢йр╖Пр╢Вр╢Ьр╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╢▒ р╢╜р╖Эр╢йр╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢йр╖Пр╢Вр╢Ьр╢▒р╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╗р╢з?","answer":"р╢Ср╢Вр╢Ьр╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢║"},{"question":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Юр╢╗р╖Пр╢лр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Ьр╖Гр╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢пр╢Ьр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Зр╢║р╖Т, р╖Гр╖Д р╢╗р╢зр╖Ъ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Др╖П  р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Лр╢╗р╖Фр╢╕р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢нр╖Фр╖Е р╢Тр╖Ар╖П  р╢Йр╢зр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢║р╢╖р╖Пр╢╗р╢║ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Рр╢╗р╢лр╖Т р╢Ьр╖Гр╖К р╢Тр╖Ар╖Пр╢║р╖Ъ р╢╜р╖Ър╢Ыр╢▒р╢Ьр╢н р╢Йр╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╢║, р╖Др╖Ьр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖К  р╢Фр╢╗р╖Ьр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ф р╢пр╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Д р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╖Рр╢пр╢Ьр╢нр╖Кр╢Ър╢╕ р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢пр╢Ьр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Ур╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П  р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Бр╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢╗р╢зр╖Ъ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Др╖П р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Лр╢╗р╖Фр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ьр╢зр╖Гр╢Ър╖Т. р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╢Ьр╖Фр╢лр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Фр╖Вр╖Кр╢Ър╢╗р╢нр╖П  р╢╕р╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Ар╖Гр╖К р╢Ьр╢лр╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖П  р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢Ьр╖Гр╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Пр╢вр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖А р╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢╗р╢зр╖Ъ р╢Ур╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╢╜р╢з р╖Гр╖Пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢║ р╖Гр╢┤р╢║р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Т."},{"question":"┬┐Qu├й es el valor absoluto de un n├║mero?","answer":"El valor absoluto de un n├║mero es el valor del n├║mero sin considerar el signo, sea este positivo o negativo."},{"question":"Inona no marika mifandray matetika amin'ny Kristianisma?","answer":"Ny lakroa no famantarana matetika mifandray amin'ny Kristianisma."},{"question":" \\"╨Ь╨╛╨╜╨░ ╨Ы╨╕╨╖╨░\\" ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ \\"╨Р╨║╤Л╤А╨║╤Л ╨║╨╡╤З╨║╨╕ ╤В╨░╨╝╨░╨║\\" ╤Б╥п╤А╙й╤В╤В╙й╤А╥п ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨╡╨╗╨│╨╕╨╗╥п╥п ╨╕╤В╨░╨╗╨╕╤П╨╗╤Л╨║ ╨▒╨╡╨╗╨│╨╕╨╗╥п╥п ╤Б╥п╤А╙й╤В╤З╥п ╨║╨╕╨╝?","answer":"╨Ц╨╛╨╛╨┐: ╨Ы╨╡╨╛╨╜╨░╤А╨┤╨╛ ╨┤╨░ ╨Т╨╕╨╜╤З╨╕ - \\"╨Ь╨╛╨╜╨░ ╨Ы╨╕╨╖╨░\\" ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ \\"╨Р╨║╤Л╤А╨║╤Л ╨║╨╡╤З╨║╨╕ ╤В╨░╨╝╨░╨║\\" ╤Б╥п╤А╙й╤В╤В╙й╤А╥п ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨╡╨╗╨│╨╕╨╗╥п╥п ╨╕╤В╨░╨╗╨╕╤П╨╗╤Л╨║ ╨░╤В╨░╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╤Б╥п╤А╙й╤В╤З╥п."},{"question":"┘╛┘И┌Ъ╪к┘Ж┘З: ┌й┘З █М┘И ┌Й╪з┌й┘╝╪▒ ╪к╪з╪│┘И ╪к┘З ╪п╪▒█Р ┌л┘И┘Д█Н ╪п╪▒┌й┌У┘К ╪з┘И ╪к╪з╪│┘И ╪к┘З ┘И┘И╪з█М┘К ┌Ж█Р ┘╛┘З ┘З╪▒ ┘Ж█М┘Е ╪│╪з╪╣╪к ┌й█Р █М┘И┘З ┌л┘И┘Д█Н ┘И╪о┘И╪▒╪ж╪М ┌л┘И┘Д█Н ╪и┘З ┌Е┘И┘Е╪▒┘З ┘И╪о╪к ┘И┘Ж█М╪│┘К╪Я","answer":"┌Б┘И╪з╪и: █М┘И ╪│╪з╪╣╪к. ┌й┘З ╪к╪з╪│┘И ┘Д┘И┘Е┌У█М ┌л┘И┘Д█Н ╪│┘Е╪п┘Д╪з╪│┘З ┘И╪о┘И╪▒╪ж╪М ╪п┘И█М┘Е┘З ┌л┘И┘Д█Н 30 ╪п┘В█М┘В█Р ┘И╪▒┘И╪│╪к┘З╪М ╪з┘И ╪п╪▒█М┘Е ┌л┘И┘Д█Н ╪и┘Д 30 ╪п┘В█М┘В█Р ┘И╪▒┘И╪│╪к┘З╪М ╪к╪з╪│┘И ┘╝┘И┘Д ╪п╪▒█Р ┌л┘И┘Д█Н ┘╛┘З █М┘И ╪│╪з╪╣╪к ┌й█Р ┘И╪о┘И╪▒╪ж."},{"question":"тАШBoth Belgium and Sri Lanka are democracies, but they follow different systems of power sharingтАЩ. Support the statement by giving three points of difference.","answer":"In Belgium, communities have an equal share in the government, while in Sri Lanka, leaders of the Sinhala community sought to secure dominance over the government by virtue of their majority.тАв In Belgium, there is provision of special government called тАШCommunity governmentтАЩ to look after cultural, educational and language-related issues, while In Sri Lanka, none of the major political parties led by the Buddhist Sinhala leaders were sensitive to language and culture of Tamils"},{"question":"\\"╨Р╨┤╨░╨╝ ╙й╨╗╨▒╙й╤Б╙й ╨░╨╣╤Л╨╗ ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л...\\"  ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨╝╨░╨║╨░╨╗-╨╗╨░╨║╨░╨┐╤В╤Л ╤Г╨╗╨░╨╜╤В╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤З╨╕?","answer":"╨б╨╕╨╖ ╤Б╤Г╤А╨░╨╜╨│╨░╨╜ ╨╝╨░╨║╨░╨╗-╨╗╨░╨║╨░╨┐ ╨╝╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╤И╤Г ╨╝╥п╨╝╨║╥п╨╜: \\"╨Р╨┤╨░╨╝ ╙й╨╗╨▒╙й╤Б╙й ╨░╨╣╤Л╨╗ ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л, ╤Б╨╛╨╛╨┤╨░╨│╨╡╤А ╙й╨╗╨▒╙й╤Б╙й ╨║╨╡╤А╨▒╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л.\\""},{"question":"риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риХри░риХрйЗ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐ри╕риери╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ ри╣рйЗриари╛риВ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗ рижри╛ риХрйА риЕри░рие ри╣рйИред\\"риори╛риЭ риори╣ри▓ри╛ рйл реерикрйНри░рин риХри┐ри░рикри╛ ридрйЗ ри╣ри░ри┐ ри╣ри░ри┐ ризри┐риЖри╡риЙ реерикрйНри░ринрйВ рижриЗриЖ ридрйЗ риорй░риЧри▓рйБ риЧри╛ри╡риЙ реериКриарид римрйИриарид ри╕рйЛри╡рид риЬри╛риЧрид ри╣ри░ри┐ ризри┐риЖриИриР ри╕риЧри▓ риЕри╡ри░рижри╛ риЬрйАриЙ реерйзреериири╛риорйБ риЕриЙриЦризрйБ риорйЛ риХриЙ ри╕ри╛ризрйВ рижрйАриЖ реериХри┐ри▓римри┐риЦ риХри╛риЯрйЗ риири┐ри░риори▓рйБ риерйАриЖ реериЕриирижрйБ ринриЗриЖ риири┐риХри╕рйА ри╕рин рикрйАри░ри╛ ри╕риЧри▓ римри┐риири╛ри╕рйЗ рижри░рижри╛ риЬрйАриЙ реерйиреериЬри┐ри╕ риХри╛ риЕрй░риЧрйБ риХри░рйЗ риорйЗри░ри╛ рикри┐риЖри░ри╛ рее ри╕рйЛ риорйБриХридри╛ ри╕ри╛риЧри░ ри╕рй░ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ реери╕ридри┐ риХри░рйЗ риЬри┐риири┐ риЧрйБри░рйВ рикриЫри╛ридри╛ ри╕рйЛ риХри╛ри╣рйЗ риХриЙ рибри░рижри╛ риЬрйАриЙ реерййреериЬрим ридрйЗ ри╕ри╛ризрйВ ри╕рй░риЧридри┐ рикри╛риП рее риЧрйБри░ ринрйЗриЯрид ри╣риЙ риЧриИ римри▓ри╛риП реери╕ри╛ри╕ри┐ ри╕ри╛ри╕ри┐ ри╣ри░ри┐ риЧри╛ри╡рйИ риири╛риириХрйБ ри╕ридри┐риЧрйБри░ риври╛риХри┐ ри▓рйАриЖ риорйЗри░ри╛ рикрйЬрижри╛ риЬрйАриЙ реерйкреерйзрйнреерйирйкрее\\"","answer":"риЗри╣ ри╕рйНри░рйА риЧрйБри░рйВ риЧрйНри░рй░рие ри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐рим риЬрйА рижрйЗ рикрй░риири╛ 101 ридрйЛриВ ри▓ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риЧрйБри░рйВ риЕри░риЬрии рижрйЗри╡ риЬрйА риЗри╣риири╛риВ римри╛ригрйАриЖриВ рижрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЦри╛ри░рйА ри╣рииредриЗри╕ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйЗриа ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ риЕриирйБри╕ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЦри┐риЖрии риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ,\\"рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйА риори┐ри╣ри░ риири╛ри▓ риорйИриВ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижри╛ риири╛рио ри╕ри┐риори░рижри╛ ри╣ри╛риВ, рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйА ри╣рйА риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риири╛ри▓ риорйИриВ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйА ри╕ри┐рйЮридри┐-ри╕ри╛ри▓ри╛ри╣ рижри╛ риЧрйАрид риЧри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣ри╛риВ ред (ри╣рйЗ ринри╛риИ !) риЙриарижри┐риЖриВ римрйИриарижри┐риЖриВ ри╕рйБрй▒ридри┐риЖриВ риЬри╛риЧрижри┐риЖриВ ри╕ри╛ри░рйА (ри╣рйА) риЙриори░ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижри╛ риири╛рио ри╕ри┐риори░риири╛ риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйзред рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижри╛ риири╛рио рижри╛ри░рйВ (риорйИриирйВрй░ риЧрйБри░рйВ риирйЗ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ ри╣рйИ)(риЗри╕ рижрйА римри░риХридри┐ риири╛ри▓ риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ) рикри╛рик риХрй▒риЯрйЗ риЧриП ридрйЗ риорйИриВ рикри╡ри┐ридрйНри░ ри╣рйЛ риЧри┐риЖ ред (риорйЗри░рйЗ риЕрй░рижри░ риЖридриориХ) ри╕рйБриЦ рикрйИрижри╛ ри╣рйЛ риЧри┐риЖ (риорйЗри░рйЗ риЕрй░рижри░рйЛриВ ри╣риЙриорйИ рижрйА) ри╕ри╛ри░рйА рикрйАрйЬри╛ риири┐риХри▓ риЧриИ, риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ рижрйБриЦ-рижри░риж рижрйВри░ ри╣рйЛ риЧриП редрйиред (ри╣рйЗ ринри╛риИ !) риорйЗри░ри╛ рикри┐риЖри░ри╛ (риЧрйБри░рйВ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛) риЬри┐ри╕ риориирйБрй▒риЦ рижрйА ри╕ри╣рйИридри╛ риХри░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ, риЙри╣ риЗри╕ ри╕рй░ри╕ри╛ри░-ри╕риорйБрй░рижри░ (рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риХри╛ри░ри╛риВ) ридрйЛриВ риорйБриХрид ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред риЬри┐ри╕ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риирйЗ ри╕ри░ризри╛ ризри╛ри░ риХрйЗ риЧрйБри░рйВ риири╛ри▓ ри╕ри╛риВриЭ рикри╛ ри▓риИ, риЙри╕ риирйВрй░ (риЗри╕ ри╕рй░ри╕ри╛ри░-ри╕риорйБрй░рижри░ ридрйЛриВ) рибри░рии рижрйА ри▓рйЛрйЬ ри╣рйА риири╣рйАриВ ри░ри╣ри┐ риЬри╛риВрижрйА редрййред (ри╣рйЗ ринри╛риИ┬а!) риЬрижрйЛриВ ридрйЛриВ риорйИриирйВрй░ риЧрйБри░рйВ рижрйА ри╕рй░риЧридри┐ риори┐ри▓рйА ри╣рйИ, риЧрйБри░рйВ риирйВрй░ риори┐ри▓ри┐риЖриВ (риорйЗри░рйЗ риЕрй░рижри░рйЛриВ) ри╣риЙриорйИ рижрйА римри▓ри╛ рижрйВри░ ри╣рйЛ риЧриИ ред ри╡ри┐риХри╛ри░ри╛риВ ридрйЛриВ римриЪри╛ риХрйЗ) риорйЗри░рйА риЗрй▒рйЫрид ри░рй▒риЦ ри▓риИ ри╣рйИ ред ри╣рйБриг риири╛риириХ ри╣ри░рйЗриХ ри╕рйБриЖри╕ рижрйЗ риири╛ри▓ рикри░риори╛ридриори╛ рижрйЗ риЧрйБриг риЧри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйкредрйзрйнредрйирйкред\\""},{"question":"Thс╗г may cс║зn d├╣ng ─Сс║┐n vс║нt dс╗еng n├аo?A тАУ M├бy kh├вuB тАУ Kim ti├кmC тАУ Nhiс╗Зt kс║┐D тАУ S├║ng","answer":"─Р├бp ├бn: A"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: родрооро┐ро┤роХ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНродрпБ роТро░рпБ роХроЯрпНроЯрпБро░рпИ ро╡ро░рпИроХ. ","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: роХро▓рпИроХро│рпИрокрпН рокро▓рпНро╡рпЗро▒рпБ ро╡роХрпИроХро│ро╛роХрокрпН рокроХрпБродрпНродро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ройро░рпН роироорпН роорпБройрпНройрпЛро░рпН. роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпБро│рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпН роХро▓рпИ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпЛроЯрпБ рокро┐рогрпИроирпНрод роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХрпБроорпН. тАЬроЕроирпНродроирпНрод роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИ роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБ, роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБрокрпНрокрпБро▒роЪрпН роЪрпВро┤ро▓рпН, роороХрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЪро┐роирпНродройрпИроХро│рпН, рокро┤роХрпНроХ ро╡ро┤роХрпНроХроЩрпНроХро│рпН, роЪрооропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роорпБродро▓ро┐ропро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпН родройрпНроорпИроХрпНроХрпЗро▒рпНрок роХро▓рпИроХро│рпН ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ рокрпЖро▒рпБроорпНтАЭ роОройрпНро▒рпБ рооропро┐ро▓рпИ. роЪрпАройро┐. ро╡рпЗроЩрпНроХроЯроЪро╛рооро┐ (родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпН ро╡ро│ро░рпНродрпНрод роЕро┤роХрпБ роХро▓рпИроХро│рпН) роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН. роЕро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпЗ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБроорпН роороХрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ропро▓рпН роЪрпВро┤ро▓рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роПро▒рпНрок родройро┐родрпНродройрпНроорпИроХро│рпБроЯройрпН родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЕро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпН роХро▓рпИропро╛ройродрпБ родрооро┐ро┤роХ роиро┐ро▓рокрпНрокро░рокрпНрокро┐ройрпБро│рпН родрпКроЯроХрпНроХроХрпН роХро╛ро▓роорпН роорпБродро▓рпН роЗройрпНро▒рпБ ро╡ро░рпИ роОро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпЖро▓рпНро▓ро╛роорпН ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой роОройрпНрокродрпИроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНродродро╛роХ роЗроХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯрпБро░рпИ роЕроорпИроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рооройро┐родройрпН роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИропрпЛроЯрпБ роЗропрпИроирпНродрпБ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроирпНродрокрпЛродрпБ рокро▓ роЪро╡ро╛ро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЕро╡ройрпН роорпБройрпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрой. роЕро╡рпИ роЕро╡ройрпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЖро▒рпНро▒ро▓рпИрокрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐роХрпН роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН, роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИропрпИ роОродро┐ро░рпН роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН роЕро╡ройрпБроХрпНроХрпБроХрпН роХро▒рпНро▒рпБродрпНродроирпНродродрпБ. родрпКроЯроХрпНроХродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родро▒рпНрокро╛родрпБроХро╛рокрпНрокрпБроХрпНроХро╛роХ роУроЯро╡рпБроорпН, роЪро╛роЯро╡рпБроорпН, родро╛рогрпНроЯро╡рпБроорпН, роирпАроирпНродро╡рпБроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родройрпН роЪроорпВроХро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роиро┐ро▓рпИропро╛рой ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИроХрпНроХрпБ ро╡роирпНрод рокрпЛродрпБ роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпИродрпН родройрпН роЖро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро┐ройрпН роЕроЯрпИропро╛ро│рооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро┐ройрпН родрпЛро▒рпНро▒роорпН роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНродрпБ, тАЬро╡рпАро░родрпНродрпИ ро╡ро│ро░рпНроХрпНроХ, рокропродрпНродрпИро╡ро┐ро░роЯрпНроЯ, роироорпНрокро┐роХрпНроХрпИропрпИ роКроЯрпНроЯ, роирогрпНрокро░рпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроХрпНроХ, рокрпКро┤рпБродрпБ рокрпЛроХрпНроХрпИ ро╡ро░ро╡рпЗро▒рпНроХ, роорпБро░рогрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИ роЙрогро░рпНроирпНрод, ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИропро┐ройрпИропрпБроорпН, родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро┐ройрпИропрпБроорпН роОродро┐ро░рпКро▓ро┐роХрпНроХ, рокрпЛро▓роЪрпН роЪрпЖропрпНроп роОройрокрпН рокро▓ роиро┐ро▓рпИроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН родрпЛройрпНро▒ро▓ро╛ропро┐ройтАЭ роОройрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН. роЪрпБ. роЪро┐ро╡роЪро╛рооро┐роЪрпБроирпНродро░ро┐ (роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпН роХро│роЮрпНроЪро┐ропроорпН)рооройро┐род роЪроорпВроХроорпН роЪро┐роирпНродро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЖро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роЙро┤рпИрокрпНрокро╛ро▓рпБроорпН родройрпНройрпИ родроХро╡роорпИродрпНродрпБроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ  роЙропро░рпНродрпНродро┐роХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпБроЯрпИропродрпБ. родрпКроЯроХрпНроХроХрпН роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родроородрпБ роЙро┤рпИрокрпНрокрпБ тАУ родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпН роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНродродро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро┐ройрпНройро░рпН роЪроорпБродро╛роп ро╡ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐рокрпН рокроЯро┐роиро┐ро▓рпИропро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН родройро┐родрпНродройрпНроорпИ рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роЕро▒ро┐роЮро░рпНроХро│рпН роХро░рпБродрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН.рооро┐роХродрпН родрпКройрпНроорпИропро╛рой рокродро┐ро╡рпБроХро│ро╛роХ роироороХрпНроХрпБроХрпН роХро┐роЯрпИроХрпНроХроХрпН роХрпВроЯро┐роп роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНрод роЪрпЖропрпНродро┐роХро│рпН роЗроЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│рой. роЗродройрпИ, тАЬрокрогрпНроЯрпИроп родрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН  роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН тАУ роЖроЯро╡ро░рпБроорпН рокрпЖрогрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН рооро┐роХрпБродро┐ропро╛роХ роИроЯрпБрокроЯрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроирпНродройро░рпН роОройрпНрокродрпИроЪрпН роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБро░рпИроХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. тАШро╡ро┐ро│рпИтАЩ роОройрпНро▒ роЪрпКро▓рпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН рокрпКродро┐роирпНродродрпБ. тАШро╡ро┐ро│рпИроХтАЩ, тАШрокрпКро▓ро┐роХтАЩ роОрой рокро░ро┐рокро╛роЯро▓рпН (10-86) роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. тАШро╡ро┐ро│рпИроХтАЩ, роОройрпНрокродрпБ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНродрпНродрпБро╡родро╛роХрпБроорпН. роироЪрпНроЪро┐ройро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХро┐ройро┐ропро░рпН роЪрпАро╡роХроЪро┐роирпНродро╛роорогро┐ 260 роЖроорпН рокро╛роЯро▓рпБроХрпНроХрпБ ро╡ро░рпИроирпНрод роЙро░рпИропро┐ро▓рпН  тАЬро╡ро┐ро│рпИроХ, рокрпКро▓ро┐роХ роТро░рпБ ро╡ро┤роХрпНроХрпБ роОройрпНрокро╛ро░рпБроорпН роЙро│ро░рпНтАЭ роОройроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБро╡родро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роиро▓рпНро▓родрпЗ роЖроХрпБроХ роОрой ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНродрпНродрпБро╡родрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИродро▓ро╛роХрпБроорпН роОройрпНро▒рпБ  родрпЖро░ро┐ропро▓ро╛роорпН. роОройро╡рпЗ тАШро╡ро┐ро│рпИтАЩ роОройрпНро▒ ро╡рпЗро░рпНроЪрпНроЪрпКро▓рпН роиро▓рпНро▓родро╛рой роЗройрпНрокроорпН рокропрокрпНрокродрпБ роОройрпНро▒рпБ рокрпКро░рпБро│рпНрокроЯрпБроорпН. тАШро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛роп роорпКроЯрпБ роУро░рпИропро╛роЯро╛родрпБтАЩ (роиро▒рпНро▒ро┐рогрпИ тАУ 68), тАШро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЖропроорпКроЯрпБтАЩ ро╡рпЖрогрпНроорогро▓рпН роЕро┤рпБродрпНродро┐ (роиро▒рпНро▒ро┐рогрпИ тАУ 172) роОройрпНройрпБроорпН ро╡ро░ро┐роХро│ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роХрпВроЯрпНроЯрпБродрпНродройрпНроорпИ роЕроГродро╛ро╡родрпБ рокро▓ро░рпН роХрпВроЯро┐рокрпН рокроЩрпНроХрпБ рокрпЖро▒рпБроорпН родройрпНроорпИ рокрпБро▓ройро╛роХро┐ро▒родрпБ. рокрогрпНроЯрпИродрпН родрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпЖройрпНро▒рпБроорпН, роЖроЯро╡ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпЖройрпНро▒рпБроорпН, рокрпЖрогрпНроЯро┐ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпЖройрпНро▒рпБроорпН, роЗро░рпБрокро╛ро╡ро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпЖройрпНро▒рпБроорпН, роЗро░рпБрокро╛ро╡ро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпЖройрпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро▓ро╡роХрпИ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрой. роЕро╡рпИ роиро╛роиро┐ро▓рокрпН рокро╛роХрпБрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИ роТроЯрпНроЯро┐ роЕроорпИроирпНродродройрпИропрпБроорпН роХро╛рогро▓ро╛роорпН. роХрпБро▒ро┐роЮрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роХро┐ро│ро┐ роУроЯрпНроЯрпБродро▓рпБроорпН роорпБро▓рпНро▓рпИ, рооро░рпБродродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роПро▒рпБ родро┤рпБро╡рпБродро▓рпБроорпН роирпЖропрпНродро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роЕро▓ро╡ройрпН роЖроЯрпНроЯро▓рпБроорпН роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН.тАЭ роОройрпНрокродройрпН (рокродро┐рокрпНрокрпБро░рпИ, роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпН роХро│роЮрпНроЪро┐ропроорпН) роорпВро▓роорпН роЕро▒ро┐ропро▓ро╛роорпН.роЪрпБ.роЪро┐ро╡роХро╛рооро┐роЪрпБроирпНродро░ро┐ роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпН роХро│роЮрпНроЪро┐ропроорпН роОройрпНройрпБроорпН родроородрпБ роЖропрпНро╡рпБ роирпВро▓ро┐ро▓рпН тАШ37тАЩ ро╡роХрпИропро╛рой ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐роп роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЗроЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│родро╛роХроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН. роЕро╡рпИ,роЕроЪродро┐ропро╛роЯро▓рпН тАУроЕроорпНрокрпБро▓ро┐ роЕро┤рпИродрпНродро▓рпН тАУ роЕро▓ро╡ройрпН роЖроЯрпНроЯро▓рпН роЙро▓ро╛ро╡ро▓рпНроКроЪро▓рпН роОрогрпНрогро┐ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯро▓рпН роОродро┐ро░рпКро▓ро┐ роХрпЗроЯрпНроЯро▓рпН роПро▒рпБ роХрпЛро│рпНроХрогрпН рокродрпИродрпНродрпБ роТро│ро┐родрпНродро╛роЯро▓рпН роХро╡рогрпН роХро┤роЩрпНроХрпБроХрпБродро┐ро░рпИ роПро▒рпНро▒роорпБроорпН ропро╛ройрпИ роПро▒рпНро▒роорпБроорпН роХрпБро░ро╡рпИ (роХрпВродрпНродрпБ) роХрпБро▒рпБроорпНрокрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЪро╛роо ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роЪрпЛро▒рпБ роЖроХрпНроХро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▒рпБродрпЗро░рпН роЪро┐ро▒рпБ рокро▒рпИроЪро┐ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНродро▓рпНроЪрпБрогрпНрог ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЪрпЖроЯро┐ роХрпКроЯро┐ ро╡ро│ро░рпНрокрпНрокрпБроирпАро░рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБрокроирпНродрпБрокро▒ро╡рпИроХро│рпИроХрпН роХро╛рогро▓рпБроорпН роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпН роЪрпЖропро▓рпНроХро│рпН рокрпЛро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНродро▓рпБроорпН рокро▒ро╡рпИ ро╡ро│ро░рпНрокрпНрокрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХрпБ ро╡ро│ро░рпНрокрпНрокрпБроорпН  рокро▒ро╡рпИ ро╡ро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХрпБроХро│рпБроЯройрпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯро▓рпН рокро╛ро╡рпИ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБрокро┐роЪро┐ тАУ роирпКроЯро┐ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБрокрпБро│рпН роУроЯрпНроЯро▓рпН роорогро▒рпН роХрпБро╡ро┐ропро▓ро┐ро▓рпН рооро▒рпИродрпНродро╛роЯро▓рпН рооро▓ро░рпН роХрпКропрпНродро▓рпБроорпН рооро╛ро▓рпИ родрпКроЯрпБродрпНродро▓рпБроорпН  ро╡роЯрпНроЯрпБро╡ро│рпНро│рпИ ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡рпЗроЯрпНроЯрпИродрпК. роЗро░ро╛. роироЮрпНроЪрпБрогрпНроЯройрпН роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роХро╛рокрпНрокро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роОройрпНройрпБроорпН роирпВро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роЗродрпЗ рокрпЛройрпНро▒рпБ 34 ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИ роЕроЯрпНроЯро╡рогрпИрокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│ро╛ро░рпН. роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роорпЗро▓рпНроХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│ро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро▓рпНро▓ро╛род рокродрпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЗроЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│рой. роЕро╡рпИроЕроорпНрооро╛ройрпИроЗроЯрпБродрпЗро│ро┐роЯро▓рпНроЙроХро┐ро░ро╛ро▓рпН рокро▒рпНрокро▓ роЙро░рпБро╡роорпН роХро┐ро│рпНро│ро▓рпНроХро░рпБро╡рпБро▒рпНро▒ рокрпЖрогрпНрокрпЛро▓рпН роироЯро┐родрпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯро▓рпНроХро│рпНро╡ро░рпН тАУ роХро╛рокрпНрокро╡ро░рпН тАУ рооро▒ро┐роХро│рпН роОрой роироЯро┐родрпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯро▓рпНроЪроорпНроороЩрпНроХрпЛро░рпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯро▓рпНтАЩроЪро┐ро╡роорпНрокроорпНроЪрпЖрогрпНроЯро╛роЯро▓рпНрокроЯрпНроЯроорпН рокроЯроХрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБро│рпН роЕроЪродро┐ропро╛роЯро▓рпН, роЕроорпНрокрпБро▓ро┐ роЕро┤рпИродрпНродро▓рпН, роЕро▓ро╡ройрпН роЖроЯрпНроЯро▓рпН, роЙро▓ро╛ро╡ро▓рпН, роКроЪро▓рпН, роОрогрпНрогро┐ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯро▓рпН, роЪрпБрогрпНрог ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ, роЪрпВродрпБ, роирпАро░рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ, рокроирпНродрпБ, рокро▒ро╡рпИроХро│рпИроХрпН роХро╛рогро▓рпБроорпН роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпН роЪрпЖропро▓рпНроХро│рпН рокрпЛро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНродро▓рпБроорпН, рокро▒ро╡рпИ, ро╡ро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХрпБроХро│рпБроЯройрпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯро▓рпН роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН рокройрпНройро┐ро░рпЖрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБроорпН роЗро░рпБрокро╛ро▓ро╛ро░рпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро╛роорпН. роЕродрпЗ рокрпЛройрпНро▒рпБ, роПро▒рпБроХрпЛро│рпН, роХрпБродро┐ро░рпИ роПро▒рпНро▒роорпБроорпН ропро╛ройрпИ роПро▒рпНро▒роорпБроорпН, роХрпБро▒рпБроорпНрокрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН, роЪро╛рооро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ, роЪро┐ро▒рпБродрпЗро░рпН, роЪро┐ро▒рпБрокро▒рпИ, рооро▓рпН, ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ, ро╡роЯрпНроЯрпБ, ро╡рпЗроЯрпНроЯрпИ роорпБродро▓ро╛ройро╡рпИ роЖрогрпНрокро╛ро▓ро╛ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН, роОродро┐ро░рпКро▓ро┐ роХрпЗроЯрпНроЯро▓рпН, роХрогрпНрокродрпИродрпНродрпБ роТро│ро┐роирпНродро╛роЯро▓рпН, роХро╡рогрпН, роХро┤роЩрпНроХрпБ, роХрпБро░ро╡рпИ, роЪро┐ро▒рпБроЪрпЛро▒рпБ, роЪро┐ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНродро▓рпН, роЪрпЖроЯро┐ тАУ роХрпКроЯро┐ ро╡ро│ро░рпНрокрпНрокрпБ, рокро▒ро╡рпИ ро╡ро│ро░рпНрокрпНрокрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХрпБ ро╡ро│ро░рпНрокрпНрокрпБроорпН, рокро╛ро╡рпИ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ, рокро┐роЪро┐ тАУ роирпКроЯро┐ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ, рокрпБро│рпН роУроЯрпНроЯро▓рпН, роорогро▒рпН роХрпБро╡ро┐ропро▓ро┐ро▓рпН рооро▒рпИродрпНродро╛роЯро▓рпН, рооро▓ро░рпН роХрпКропрпНродро▓рпБроорпН рооро╛ро▓рпИ родрпКроЯрпБродрпНродро▓рпБроорпН, ро╡ро│рпНро│рпИ роорпБродро▓ро╛ройро╡рпИ рокрпЖрогрпНрокро╛ро▓ро╛ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЙро░ро┐ропройро╡ро╛роХроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роЗродрпЗ рокрпЛройрпНро▒рпБ роЗройрпНро▒ро│ро╡ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роироорпНрооро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИ роЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЙро░ро┐ропрой, рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЙро░ро┐ропрой, роЗро░рпБрокро╛ро▓ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЙро░ро┐ропрой роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роХрпБро┤роирпНродрпИроХро│рпБроХрпНроХро╛рой ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ, рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХро╛рой ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН рокроХрпБродрпНродро▒ро┐ропро▓ро╛роорпН.родрооро┐ро┤рпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБро│рпН роЗройрпНро▒рпБ роЪро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН рооро┐роХрпБродро┐ропро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро╛рой роХрпЛро▓ро┐, роХро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро┐ (роХро┐роЯрпНроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпБро│рпН) роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЪро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро╛роЩрпНроХрпБроЪрпНроЪрпБ, роОро▒ро┐рокроирпНродрпБ, роХро╛ропро╛ рокро┤рооро╛, рокроорпНрокро░роорпН, роХро┐ро│ро┐родрпНродроЯрпНроЯрпБ, роЪроЯрпБроХрпБроЯрпБ(роХрокроЯро┐), рокрпВроХрпНроХрпБродро┐ро░рпИ, рокро╛ропрпНроЪрпНроЪро▓рпН роХрпБродро┐ро░рпИ роЖроХро┐ропрой роЙро│рпНро│рой.роХрпЛро▓ро┐роХрогрпНрогро╛роЯро┐ропро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роХро▓рпНро▓ро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роЖрой роЪро┐ро▒рпНро▒рпБро░рпБрогрпНроЯрпИроХро│рпИ ро╡ро┐ро░ро▓рпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роЪрпБрогрпНроЯро┐ропрпБроорпН, роЙро░рпБроЯрпНроЯро┐ропрпБроорпН, роОро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН роХрпЛро▓ро┐ роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН роОройрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН.роХро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро┐роХро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро┐ роЖроЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБроХрпН роХро┐роЯрпНроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпБро│рпН, роЪро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро╛роЩрпНроХрпБроЪрпНроЪрпБ роЖроХро┐роп рокрпЖропро░рпНроХро│рпБроорпН роЙро│рпНро│рой. роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роХрпБроЪрпНроЪрпБ роТройрпНро▒рпИ роТро░рпБ роХрпЛро▓ро╛ро▓рпН родроЯрпНроЯро┐ роЖроЯрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯрооро╛роХ роЗродрпБ роЕроорпИроХро┐ро▒родрпБроОро▒ро┐рокроирпНродрпБрокроирпНродро┐ройрпИ роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роорпЗро▓рпН роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роОро▒ро┐роирпНродро╛роЯрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯрооро╛роХрпБроорпН.роХро╛ропро╛ рокро┤рооро╛?роирпАро░рпН роиро┐ро▓рпИроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роиро┐ройрпНро▒рпБ роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ роХро╛ропро╛ рокро┤рооро╛? роОройрпНро▒рпБ роХрпЗроЯрпНроЯрпБ родрогрпНрогрпАро░ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро░ро▓ро╛ро▓рпН роЪрпБрогрпНроЯро┐ роУроЪрпИ роОро┤рпБрокрпНрокро┐ роЖроЯрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯрооро╛роХрпБроорпН.рокроорпНрокро░роЩрпНроХро│рпИ роЖроЯро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЖроЯрпБроорпН рокроорпНрокро░ роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН роУропро╛роХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯрпИ, роЙроЯрпИроирпНрод роХроЯрпНроЯрпИ, рокроорпНрокро░ роХрпБродрпНродрпБ, роЗро░рпБро╡роЯрпНроЯроХрпН роХрпБродрпНродрпБ, родро▓рпИропро╛ро░ро┐ роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роорпБро▒рпИроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокро┐роп ро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЖроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роХро┐ро│ро┐родрпНродроЯрпНроЯрпБроирпАро│рпН роиро╛ро▒рпНроХрпЛрог ро╡ро░рокрпНрокрпБроХрпН роХрпЛроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЕроорпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБ роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпН роХрпБро▒рпБроХрпНроХрпЗ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпБрокро╡ро░ро┐ройрпН роОрогрпНрогро┐роХрпНроХрпИропрпИрокрпН рокрпКро▒рпБродрпНродрпБ роХрпБро▒рпБроХрпНроХро╛роХродрпН родроЯрпНроЯрпБроХрпН роХрпЛроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЕроорпИродрпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпБро╡ро░рпН. роЗро░рпБ роЕрогро┐ропро╛роХрокрпН рокро┐ро░ро┐роирпНродрпБ роТро░рпБ роЕрогро┐ропро┐ройрпН родроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпН. роЗро▒роЩрпНроХрпБро╡ро░рпН рооро▒рпБ роЕрогро┐ропро┐ройро░рпН рооро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро░рпН. рокро┐роЯро┐ роХрпКроЯро╛рооро▓рпН родрокрпНрокро┐рокрпНрокродро▒рпНроХрпБрокрпН рокропро┐ро▒рпНроЪро┐ропро╛роХ роЕроорпИропрпБроорпН роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ.роЪроЯрпБроХрпБроЯрпБ (роХрокроЯро┐)родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБро│рпН роорпБродройрпНроорпИропро╛рой роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХ роЪроЯрпБроХрпБроЯрпБ родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роПро▒рпБ родро┤рпБро╡рпБродро▓рпБроХрпНроХрпБ (роЬро▓рпНро▓ро┐роХроЯрпНроЯрпБ) родропро╛ро░ро╛ро╡родро▒рпНроХрпБ роорпБройрпН роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпКро│рпНро│рпБроорпН рокропро┐ро▒рпНроЪро┐ропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЗродройрпИ роЪро┐ро▓ро░рпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН. роХрпИ + рокро┐роЯро┐ = роХрокроЯро┐ роОройрпНро▒рпБ роЗродро▒рпНроХрпБ рокрпЖропро░рпН ро╡роирпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН роОройрпНрокро╛ро░рпБроорпН роЙро│ро░рпН. роЗро░рпБ роЕрогро┐роХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЗроЯрпИропрпЗ роиро┐роХро┤рпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокро┐роЯро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро╛роХ роЗродрпБ родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рокрпВроХрпНроХрпБродро┐ро░рпИроТро░рпБ рокрпВро╡ро┐ройрпН рокрпЖропро░рпИроЪрпН роЪрпКро▓рпНро▓ро┐ роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роорпЗро▓рпН роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роХрпБродро┐ро░рпИропрпЗро▒ро┐ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпБро╡родрпБ рокрпВроХрпНроХрпБродро┐ро░рпИ.рокро╛ропрпНроЪрпНроЪро▓рпН роХрпБродро┐ро░рпИроТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роХрпАро┤рпЗ роЕрооро░рпНроирпНродрпБроорпН, рокро┐ройрпН роХрпБройро┐роирпНродрпБроорпН родройрпН роЙропро░родрпНродрпИрокрпН рокроЯро┐рокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛роХ роЙропро░рпНродрпНродро┐роХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпЗ роЗро░рпБрокрпНрокро╛ро░рпН. ро╡ро░ро┐роЪрпИропро╛роХ родро╛рогрпНроЯрпБрокро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роОроирпНроиро┐ро▓рпИропро┐ро▓рпЗройрпБроорпН родро╛рогрпНроЯ роорпБроЯро┐ропро╛родрпБ роиро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН роЕро╡ро░рпН роХрпБройро┐роирпНродрпБ роиро┐ро▒рпНроХ, рокро┐ро▒ро░рпН роЕро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпЗ родро╛рогрпНроЯро┐ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпБро╡родрпБ рокро╛ропрпНроЪрпНроЪро▓рпН роХрпБродро┐ро░рпИ.роЕродрпЗ рокрпЛройрпНро▒рпБ рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роЖроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡ройро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпН роХро┤роЩрпНроХрпБ, рокро╛роЯро▓рпН роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН, рокро╛рогрпНроЯро┐, роХрогрпНрогро╛роорпНрокрпКродрпНродро┐ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡рпИ роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокро┐роЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпБро╡ройро╡ро╛роХрпБроорпН.роХро┤роЩрпНроХрпБрокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБро│рпН роХро┤роЩрпНроХрпБ роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокро┐роЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.  рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпН роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роХро▒рпНроХро│рпИроХрпН роХрпИроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН  родроЯрпНроЯро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛роХ роЗродрпБ роЕроорпИроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.  роХро┤роЩрпНроХрпБ ро╡рпАроЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпБро│рпНро│рпБроорпН ро╡рпАроЯрпНроЯрпБ роорпБро▒рпНро▒родрпНродро┐ро▓рпБроорпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН.  роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛ройродрпБ рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роХро▒рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роОрогрпНрогро┐роХрпНроХрпИропрпИрокрпН рокрпКро▒рпБродрпНродрпБ рокро▓ рокрпЖропро░рпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роЕро┤рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.  роЕро╡рпИ роорпВройрпНро▒ро╛роЩрпНроХро▓рпН, роРроирпНродро╛роЩрпНроХро▓рпН, роПро┤ро╛роЩрпНроХро▓рпН, рокро▓ роиро╛ро▓рпКро░рпБроХро▓рпН, рокройрпНройро┐ро░рпБроХро▓рпН, рокро▓роХро▓рпН, рокродро┐ройро╛ро▒ро╛роЩрпНроХро▓рпН роОройрпНрокройро╡ро╛роХрпБроорпН. родроЯрпНроЯро╛роЩрпНроХро▓рпН роОрой рокрпКродрпБро╡ро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЕро┤рпИрокрпНрокродрпБрогрпНроЯрпБ.рокро╛роЯро▓рпН роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпНроЪро┐ро▒рпБрооро┐ропро░рпН роЗро░рпБро╡ро░ро╛роХро╡рпЛ, роЗро░рпБ роЕрогро┐ропро┐ройро░ро╛роХро╡рпЛ роиро┐ройрпНро▒рпБ роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ рокрпБродро┐ро░рпНрокро╛роЯро▓рпНроХро│рпН рокро╛роЯро┐ роЖроЯрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН рокро╛роЯро▓рпН роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН роОройрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН.роЙродро╛ро░рогрооро╛роХ роЖроЯрпБроорпН тАУ роУроиро╛ропрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН.роЗродро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро░ро┐роЪрпИропро╛роХ роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роЗроЯрпБрокрпНрокрпИ рооро▒рпНро▒ро╡ро░рпН рокро┐роЯро┐родрпНродрокроЯро┐ роиро┐ро▒рпНрокро╛ро░рпНроХро│рпН.   роЗро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЖроЯрпБроХро│рпН, роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роороЯрпНроЯрпБроорпН роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро╡роирпНродрпБ ро╡ро░ро┐роЪрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродродрпБ рокро┐ро░ро┐рокро╡ро░рпИрокрпН рокро┐роЯро┐роХрпНроХ роорпБропро▓рпНро╡ро╛ро░рпН.  роЕро╡ро░рпН роУроиро╛ропрпН. роХрпАро┤рпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ рокрпЛро▓рпН, родроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЙро│рпНро│роорпН рокрпЛро▓рпН рокро╛роЯро┐роХрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯрпЗ роЖроЯрпБро╡ро░рпН.роУроиро╛ропрпН:роОройрпНройро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИроХрпН роХро╛рогрпЛроорпЗроЖроЯрпБ: родрпЗроЯро┐рокрпН рокро┐роЯро┐роЪрпНроЪрпБроХрпНроХрпЛроУроиро╛ропрпН: роЕроЯрпБрокрпНрокрпБ роорпЗро▓ роПро▒рпБро╡рпЗройрпНроЖроЯрпБ: родрпБроЯрпБрокрпНрокрпИроХрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ роЪро╛родрпНродрпБро╡рпЗройрпНроУроиро╛ропрпН: роирпЖро▓рпНро▓рпИроХрпН роХрпКро▒ро┐рокрпНрокрпЗройрпНроЖроЯрпБ: рокро▓рпНро▓рпИ роЙроЯрпИрокрпНрокрпЗройрпНроУроиро╛роЯрпБ: ро╡роЯро┐ родрогрпНрогро┐ропрпИроХрпН роХрпКроЯрпНроЯрпБро╡рпЗройрпНроЖроЯрпБ:ро╡ро┤ро┐роЪрпНроЪрпБ ро╡ро┤ро┐роЪрпНроЪрпБ роироХрпНроХро┐роХрпНроХрпЛроУроиро╛ропрпН:роХрпЛроЯрпНроЯрпИ роорпЗро▓рпЗ роПро▒рпБро╡рпЗройрпНроЖроЯрпБ: роХрпКро│рпНро│ро┐роХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ роЪро╛родрпНродрпБро╡рпЗройрпНроУроиро╛ропрпН:роОройрпНройро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИроХрпН роХро╛рогрпЛроорпЗ?роЖроЯрпБ: родрпЗроЯро┐рокрпН рокро┐роЯро┐роЪрпНроЪрпБроХрпНроХрпЛ.роЗро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпБ роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐-рокродро┐ро▓рпН ро╡роЯро┐ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН родрпКроЯро░рпБроорпН. роХрпБро┤роирпНродрпИроХро│рпН роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐роХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБроЪрпН роЪроЯрпНроЯрпЖройрпНро▒рпБ(роЙроЯройроЯро┐ропро╛роХ) рокродро┐ро▓ро│ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН рокро┤роХрпНроХродрпНродрпИ роЗро╡рпИ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрпБроорпН.  роЪро┐ро▒рпБро╡ро░рпН, роЪро┐ро▒рпБрооро┐ропро░рпН роЗро░рпБрокро╛ро▓ро░рпБроорпН роЗродрпНродроХрпИроп рокро╛роЯро▓рпН роЖроЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпИ роЖроЯрпБро╡ро░рпН.роХрогрпНрогро╛роорпНрокрпКродрпНродро┐роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН роХрогрпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокрпКродрпНродро┐ роХрпКрогрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпНрокрпЛродрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒ роЪро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпНроХро│рпН роУроЯро┐ роТро│ро┐ро╡ро░рпН.  рокро┐ройрпНройро░рпН роХрогрпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокрпКродрпНродро┐роХрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯ роЪро┐ро▒рпБро╡ро░рпН роУроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпЛропрпН роЕроЩрпНроХрпБроорпН роЗроЩрпНроХрпБроорпН рокро╛ро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роТро│ро┐роирпНродрпБ роХрпКрогрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▒рпБро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпБро│рпН роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпИродрпН родрпКроЯроорпБропро▓рпНро╡ро╛ро░рпН.  роорпБродро▓ро╛ро╡родрпБ родрпКроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роЪро┐ро▒рпБро╡ро░рпН роЕроЯрпБродрпНрод роорпБро▒рпИ роХрогрпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокрпКродрпНрод роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН родрпКроЯро░рпБроорпН.роХрпБро▓рпИроХрпБро▓рпИропро╛ропрпН роорпБроирпНродро┐ро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛ропрпНроЪро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН рокро▓ро░рпБроорпН ро╡роЯрпНроЯрооро╛ропрпН роЙро│рпНроирпЛроХрпНроХро┐ роЙроЯрпНроХро╛ро░рпНроирпНродро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокро░рпН.  роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН родро┐ро░ро┐рокрпЛро▓ роорпБро▒рпБроХрпНроХро┐роп родрпБрогро┐ропрпКройрпНро▒рпИроХрпН роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ тАШроХрпБро▓рпИроХрпБро▓рпИропро╛ропрпН роорпБроирпНродро┐ро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛ропрпНтАЩ  роОройрпНро▒рпБ роХрпВро▒ро┐ропрокроЯро┐ роЪро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпИроЪрпН роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒ро┐ ро╡ро▓рооро╛роХ роУроЯро┐ро╡ро░рпБроорпНрокрпЛродрпБ ропро╛ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН родрпЖро░ро┐ропро╛рооро▓рпН роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ родро┐ро░ро┐ропрпИ роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпН рокро┐ройрпНройрпЗ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐роЯрпБро╡ро╛ро░рпН.  ро╡рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ родро┐ро░ро┐ропро┐ройрпН роирпЗро░рпЗ роЙро│рпНро│ро╡ро░рпН роЙроЯройрпЗ роХрогрпНроЯрпБ роОроЯрпБроХрпНроХро╛ро╡ро┐роЯро┐ройрпН роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒ро┐ ро╡ро░рпБрокро╡ро░рпН  роЕро░рпБроХро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро░рпБроорпНрокрпЛродрпБ роЕро╡ро░рпН роорпБродрпБроХро┐ро▓рпН родро┐ро░ро┐ропро╛ро▓рпН роорпЖродрпБро╡ро╛роХродрпН родроЯрпНроЯро┐ роОро┤рпБрокрпНрокро┐ро╡ро┐роЯрпБро╡ро╛ро░рпН.  роУроЯро┐ро╡роирпНродро╡ро░рпН роЕроЩрпНроХрпБ роЕрооро░рпНроирпНродрпБро╡ро┐роЯрпБро╡ро╛ро░рпН. роОро┤рпБроорпНрокро┐ропро╡ро░рпН родро┐ро░ро┐ропрпБроЯройрпН роУроЯро┐ро╡ро░ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН.  роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБродрпН родро┐ро░ро┐родрпНродро┐ро░ро┐ рокроирпНродроорпН роОройрпНро▒ рокрпЖропро░рпБроорпН роЙрогрпНроЯрпБ.роирпКрогрпНроЯро┐роХроЯрпНроЯрооро╛роХро╡рпЛ, роЪродрпБро░рооро╛роХро╡рпЛ роХрпАро▒рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роХрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпБро│рпН роЕрогро┐ропро╛роХ роиро┐ро▒рпНрокро░рпН.  роТро░рпБроХро╛ро▓рпИ роороЯроХрпНроХро┐ роирпКрогрпНроЯро┐ роЪрпЖро▓рпНрокро╡ро░рпН роТро░рпБро╡ро░рпИропрпЛ, рокро▓ро░рпИропрпЛ родрпКроЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропрпЗро▒рпНро▒ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН.роХрпБроорпНрооро┐роЪро┐ро▒рпБрооро┐ропро░рпН роХрпИроХро│рпИроХрпН роХрпБро╡ро┐родрпНродрпБ родроЯрпНроЯро┐ роУроЪрпИропрпЖро┤рпБрокрпНрокро┐ рокро╛роЯро▓рпЛроЯрпБ роЖроЯрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯроорпН роХрпБроорпНрооро┐ропро╛роХрпБроорпН.  роЗродро▒рпНроХрпЖрой родройро┐ропро╛роХрокрпН рокро╛роЯро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЙро│рпНро│рой.родро╛ропроорпНродро╛ропроорпН рооро┐роХродрпНродрпКройрпНроорпИропро╛рой ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБро│рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХрокрпН рокро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.  родрооро┐ро┤ро┐ро▓рпН роХро┐роЯрпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│ роорпБродро▓рпН роирпВро▓ро╛рой родрпКро▓рпНроХро╛рокрпНрокро┐ропродрпНродро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЗродрпБ роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНродроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпН роЗроЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│рой.  роЗродрпБ рокро▓ро╡роХрпИрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН.  роиро╛ропрпБроорпН, рокрпБро▓ро┐ропрпБроорпН, рокро░роорокродроороорпН, роХрпБро▒рпБроХрпНроХрпБроХрпН роХроЯрпНроЯродрпНродро╛ропроорпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡рпИропрпБроорпН роЗродройрпН ро╡ро┤ро┐ро╡роирпНродро╡рпИропрпЗ роОройрпНрокро░рпН.роЗродрпЗ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роороЯрпНроЯрпБрооро▓рпНро▓ро╛рооро▓рпН роПро▒рпБродро┤рпБро╡рпБродро▓рпН, роЪро┐ро▓роорпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯроорпН, роХро│ро░ро┐ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ ро╡рпАро░ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБроорпН родрпКройрпНроорпИропро╛рой роХро╛ро▓роирпНродрпКроЯрпНроЯрпЗ родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.роПро▒рпБродро┤рпБро╡рпБродро▓рпНроХро╛ро│рпИроХро│рпИ роЕроЯроХрпНроХрпБроорпН ро╡рпАро░ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛роХ роЗродрпБ родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.  родрпКройрпНроорпИропро╛рой роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН рокро▓ро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЗродрпБ родрпКроЯро░рпНрокро╛рой роЪрпЖропрпНродро┐роХро│рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЗройрпНро▒рпИроп роЬро▓рпНро▓ро┐роХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯрпБ роЗродройрпЛроЯрпБ родрпКроЯро░рпНрокрпБрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐рокрпН рокро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХроХрпН роХрпВроЯро┐ропродро╛роХ роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЖроиро┐ро░рпИроХро│рпИ роЕроЯроХрпНроХрпБродро▓рпН, роХро╛ро│рпИроХро│рпИ роЕроЯроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роорпБройрпН роХрпБро░ро╡рпИроХрпНроХрпВродрпНродрпБ роиро┐роХро┤рпНродрпНродрпБродро▓рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ родроХро╡ро▓рпНроХро│рпН рокро┤роирпНродрооро┐ро┤рпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНрод ро╡ро┐ро░ро┐ро╡ро╛рой родроХро╡ро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпН роЗроЯроорпНрокрпЖро▒ро╡ро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпИ.  роЗро░рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройрпБроорпН родрпКройрпНро▒рпБродрпКроЯрпНроЯрпБ роиро┐роХро┤рпНроирпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХ роЗродройрпИроХрпН роХро░рпБродрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН.роЪро┐ро▓роорпНрокроорпНроЗродрпБ родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН родро▒рпНрокро╛родрпБроХро╛рокрпНрокрпБроХрпНроХро▓рпИ.  ро╡рпАро░ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.  роХроорпНрокрпБ роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБродро▓рпН роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роХрпВро▒рпБро╡родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБ. роЗродро┐ро▓рпН роХроорпНрокрпБ роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роорпБро▒рпИ, роХро╛ро▓рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЙроЯро▓рпН роЕроЪрпИро╡рпБроХро│рпН роорпБродройрпНроорпИ роЗроЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.  роХро▓ро┐роЩрпНроХродрпНродрпБрокрпН рокро░рогро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН тАЬро╡рпАроЪрпБ родрогрпНроЯро┐роЯрпИ роХрпВро░рпНрооро┤рпБ роТроХрпНроХрпБроорпЗтАЭ роОройрпНро▒рпБ ро╡ро░рпБроорпН роЗроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родрогрпНроЯрпБ роОройроХрпНроХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБро╡родрпБ роЪро┐ро▓роорпНрокроХрпНроХроорпНрокро┐ройрпИропрпЗ роОройрпНрокро░рпН. роХроорпНрокрпБроЪрпВродрпНродро┐ро░роорпН, роХрпБро▒рпБроирпНродроЯро┐ роЪро┐ро▓роорпНрокроорпН роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роЪрпБро╡роЯро┐роХро│рпН роЪро┐ро▓роорпНрокрокрпНрокропро┐ро▒рпНроЪро┐ родрпКроЯро░рпНрокро╛ройро╡рпИ роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роХрпВро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН.роХро│ро░ро┐роХро│ро░ро┐роХрпН роХро▓рпИропрпБроорпН рокро┤роирпНродрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родрпЛройрпНро▒ро┐роп ро╡рпАро░ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБро│рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗродрпБ ро╡роЯроХрпНроХройрпНроХро│ро░ро┐,  родрпЖроХрпНроХройрпН роХро│ро░ро┐ роОрой роЗро░рпБ ро╡роХрпИрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН.  родрооро┐ро┤роХродрпНродро┐ройрпН родрпЖройрпНрокроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЗройрпНро▒рпИроп роХрпЗро░ро│ро╛ро╡ро╛рой роЪрпЗро░роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЗроХрпНроХро▓рпИ ро╡роЯро┐ро╡роорпН роЗройрпНро▒рпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБроЯройрпН родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ.  ро╡ро╛ро│рпН, роХродрпНродро┐, рооро╛ройрпНроХрпКроорпНрокрпБ, роЪрпБро░рпБро│рпНро╡ро╛ро┤рпН, рооро┤рпБ, роХрпЛроЯро╛ро▓ро┐ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роЖропрпБродроЩрпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ роЖроЯрпБроорпН роЖроЯрпНроЯрооро╛роХрпБроорпН.роЗродрпЗ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роОрогрпНрогро┐роЯро▓роЩрпНроХро╛род ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЙро░ро┐роорпИропрпБроЯрпИропро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро╛роХ роироорпНрооро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН.  роироородрпБ роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИроЪрпН роЪрпВро┤ро▓рпН, рокрогрпНрокро╛роЯрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ роПро▒рпНрок роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЗроЯроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.роЗро╡рпНро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНродрпБ роирпБрогрпБроХро┐ роЖропрпНро╡рпБроХро│рпН роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпН родрооро┐ро┤роХ роороХрпНроХро│рпН роОродрпНродроХрпИроп ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИ роОро▓рпНро▓ро╛роорпН родрпКроЯро░рпНроирпНродрпБ роЖроЯро┐ро╡роирпНродройро░рпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ ро╡рпЖро│ро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН.  роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН родрпКройрпНроорпИропро╛рой ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН рокро▓ро╡рпБроорпН роОро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпЖро▓рпНро▓ро╛роорпН рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒роорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБ роЖроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой роОройрпНрокродрпИропрпБроорпН роЕро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБроХрпКро│рпНро│ роорпБроЯро┐ропрпБроорпН."},{"question":"рк▓ркЧрки ркЧрлАркд \\"ркоркВркЧрк│ рклрлЗрк░рк╛тАж\\"  рк▓ркЦрлЛ.","answer":"рккрк╣рлЗрк▓рлБркВ рккрк╣рлЗрк▓рлБркВ ркоркВркЧрк│рлАркпрлБркВ рк╡рк░ркдрк╛ркп рк░рлЗрккрк╣рлЗрк▓рлЗ ркоркВркЧрк│ ркЧрк╛ркпрлЛркирк╛ркВ ркжрк╛рки ркжрлЗрк╡рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркЕркЧрлНркирк┐ркжрлЗрк╡ркирлА рк╕рк╛ркХрлНрк╖рлАркП рклрлЗрк░рк╛ рклрк░рк╛ркп рк░рлЗрк╕рлМркирлЗ рк╣рлИркпрлЗ ркЖркиркВркж ркЕркдрк┐ ркЙркнрк░рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркмрлАркЬрлБркВ ркмрлАркЬрлБркВ ркоркВркЧрк│рлАркпрлБркВ рк╡рк░ркдрк╛ркп рк░рлЗркмрлАркЬрлЗ ркоркВркЧрк│ рк░рлВрккрк╛ркирк╛ркВ ркжрк╛рки ркжрлЗрк╡рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркорк╛ркВркбрк╡ркбрк╛ркирк╛ркВ ркоркВркЧрк│ ркЧрлАркдрлЛ ркЧрк╡рк╛ркп рк░рлЗрк╢рлБркнркжрк┐рки ркЖркЬрлЗ рк╢рлБркХркиркирлЛ ркХрк╣рлЗрк╡рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркдрлНрк░рлАркЬрлБркВ ркдрлНрк░рлАркЬрлБркВ ркоркВркЧрк│рлАркпрлБркВ рк╡рк░ркдрк╛ркп рк░рлЗркдрлНрк░рлАркЬрлЗ ркоркВркЧрк│ рк╕рлЛркирк╛ркирк╛ркВ ркжрк╛рки ркжрлЗрк╡рк╛ркп рк░рлЗрклрлБрк▓ркбрк╛ркВ ркХрлЗрк░рлА рклрлЛрк░рко ркмркзрлЗ рккрлНрк░рк╕рк░рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркмркирлНркирлЗ рккркХрлНрк╖рлЗ ркЖркиркВркж ркЕркдрк┐ ркЙркнрк░рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркЪрлЛркерлБркВ ркЪрлЛркерлБркВ ркоркВркЧрк│рлАркпрлБркВ рк╡рк░ркдрк╛ркп рк░рлЗркЪрлЛркерлЗ ркоркВркЧрк│ ркХркирлНркпрк╛ркирк╛ркВ ркжрк╛рки ркжрлЗрк╡рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркЕркЧрлНркирк┐ркжрлЗрк╡ркирлА рк╕рк╛ркХрлНрк╖рлАркП рклрлЗрк░рк╛ рклрк░рк╛ркп рк░рлЗркорк╛ркВркбрк╡ркбрк╛ркирк╛ркВ ркоркВркЧрк│ ркЧрлАркдрлЛ ркЧрк╡рк╛ркп рк░рлЗ"},{"question":"The Umbilical Cord","answer":"The Umbilical Cord is a tube that connects you to your baby during pregnancy. It has three blood vessels: one vein that carries food and oxygen from the placenta to your baby, and two arterials that carry waste from your baby back to the placenta. For short \\"AVA\\"."},{"question":"ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии риХрйА ри╣рйБрй░рижрйЗ ри╣рии ? риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛рибрйЗ ри╕ри░рйАри░ ри▓риИ риХри┐риЙриВ риЬри╝ри░рйВри░рйА ри╣рйБрй░рижрйЗ ри╣рии ?","answer":"ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии -ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии риЕриЬри┐ри╣рйЗ ри░ри╕ри╛риЗригри┐риХ рикрижри╛ри░рие ри╣рии риЬри┐риирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйА ри╕ри╛рибрйЗ ри╕ри░рйАри░ рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риХри╛ри╕ ри▓риИ ри▓рйЛрйЬ ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА ри╣рйИ ред ри╣рйБриг ридриХ риХриИ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐риири╛риВ рижрйА риЦрйЛриЬ риХрйАридрйА риЬри╛ риЪрйБрй▒риХрйА ри╣рйИ рикри░ риорйБрй▒риЦ ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии риЫрйЗ ри╣рйА риорй░риирйЗ риЬри╛риВрижрйЗ ри╣рии риЬрйЛ риЗри╕ рикрйНри░риХри╛ри░ ри╣рии : тАШриПтАЩ, тАШримрйАтАЩ, тАШри╕рйАтАЩ, тАШрибрйАтАЩ, тАШримрйАтАЩ риЕридрйЗ тАШриХрйЗтАЩ ред риЗри╣риири╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪрйЛриВ ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии тАШримрйАтАЩ ридрйЗ тАШри╕рйА рикри╛ригрйА ри╡ри┐риЪ риШрйБри▓ригри╕ри╝рйАри▓ ри╣рии ридрйЗ римри╛риХрйА ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии тАШриПтАЩ тАШрибрйАтАЩ ридрйЗ тАШриХрйЗ риЪри░римрйА ри╡ри┐риЪ риШрйБри▓ригри╕ри╝рйАри▓ ри╣рйБрй░рижрйЗ ри╣рии ред ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии риХриИ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйЗ риЦри╝рйБри░ри╛риХ рикрижри╛ри░риери╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ рикри╛риП риЬри╛риВрижрйЗ ри╣рии ред ринрйЛриЬрии ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐риири╛риВ рижрйА риЙрй▒риЪри┐рид риори╛ридри░ри╛ рижри╛ ри╣рйЛригри╛ риЬри╝ри░рйВри░рйА ри╣рйИ ред ринрйЛриЬрии рижрйА риЬрйАри╡рии ри▓риИ римри╣рйБрид риЬри╝ри┐риЖрижри╛ риори╣рй▒ридридри╛ риирйВрй░ риЕриирйБринри╡ риХри░рижрйЗ ри╣рйЛриП риЗри╣риири╛риВ риирйВрй░ риЬрйАри╡рии-рижри╛ридри╛ ри╡рйА риЖриЦри┐риЖ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии рибрйА ризрйБрй▒рик ридрйЛриВ риори┐ри▓рижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии рижрйА ри╕ри░рйАри░ ри▓риИ риЬри╝ри░рйВри░рид  тАУри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии рижрйА ри╕ри╛рибрйЗ ри╕ри░рйАри░ ри▓риИ риЬри╝ри░рйВри░рид риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ ридрй▒ридри╛риВ ридрйЛриВ римри┐ри▓риХрйБри▓ ри╕рикрй▒ри╕ри╝риЯ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижрйА ри╣рйИ тАУ    * ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии ри╕ри╛рибрйА ри╕ри┐ри╣рид риирйВрй░ риарйАриХ ри░рй▒риЦрижрйЗ ри╣рии ред    * риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛рибрйЗ ри╕ри░рйАри░риХ ри╡ри╛ризрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╕ри╣ри╛риЗридри╛ риХри░рижрйЗ ри╣рии ред    * риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛рибрйА рикри╛риЪрии ри╕ри╝риХридрйА ри╡ризри╛риЙриВрижрйЗ ри╣рии ред    * риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛рибри╛ риЦрйВрии ри╕ри╛рил риХри░рижрйЗ ри╣рии риЕридрйЗ риЦрйВрии рижрйА риори╛ридри░ри╛ ри╡ри┐риЪ  ри╡ри╛ризри╛ риХри░рижрйЗ       ри╣рии ред    * риЗри╣ ри╣рй▒рибрйАриЖриВ риЕридрйЗ рижрй░рижри╛риВ риирйВрй░ риориЬри╝римрйВрид римригри╛риЙриВрижрйЗ ри╣рии ред    * риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛риирйВрй░ римри┐риори╛ри░рйАриЖриВ рижри╛ риорйБриХри╛римри▓ри╛ риХри░рии рижрйЗ рипрйЛриЧ римригри╛риЙриВрижрйЗ ри╣рии ред    * ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии ри░ри╛ри╣рйАриВ риЪриорйЬрйА рижрйЗ ри░рйЛриЧ рижрйВри░ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижрйЗ ри╣рии ред    * ри╡ри┐риЯри╛риори┐рии ри╕ри░рйАри░ рижрйА ри╕ри╝риХридрйА ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╡ри╛ризри╛ риХри░рижрйЗ ри╣рии ред"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'daripada bersahabat dengan orang yang bodoh, baik berseteru dengan orang berakal'?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini ialah lebih berbaloi untuk bermusuh dengan orang berakal daripada berkawan dengan orang yang bodoh, kerana kita boleh bermanfaat daripada tindak balas dengan orang yang cerdik."},{"question":"Qual das seguintes frases est├б no modo imperativo: A - Jo├гo, pintaste as figuras para o espet├бculo rapidamente.B - O Jo├гo pintava as figuras para o espet├бculo rapidamente.C - Jo├гo, pinta as figuras para o espet├бculo rapidamente.D - O Jo├гo pinta as figuras para o espet├бculo rapidamente.","answer":"A resposta ├й C."},{"question":"Limal ma diwaan yi ame ci senegaal ","answer":"Diwaan yi ame ci senegaal ├▒o ngii:Dakar, Thies, Diourbel, Kaolack, Kaffrine, Louga, Ndarr, Tambacounda, Siguithior, Matam, Kolda, Sedhiou, Kedougou ak Fatick"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ┘Ж╪╕╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д┘Г┘Е╪и┘К┘И╪к╪▒╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ┘Ж╪╕╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д┘Г┘Е╪и┘К┘И╪к╪▒ ┘З┘И ┘Е╪▓┘К╪м ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪░╪з┘Г╪▒╪й ┘И┘И╪н╪п╪й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╣╪з┘Д╪м╪й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪▒┘Г╪▓┘К╪й ┘И╪з┘Д╪г╪м┘З╪▓╪й ╪з┘Д╪╖╪▒┘Б┘К╪й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к╪╡┘Д╪й ╪и┘З ┘И┘Ж╪╕╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д╪к╪┤╪║┘К┘Д (┘Ж╪╕╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д╪к╪┤╪║┘К┘Д)."},{"question":"р╢╕р╖Фр╢╜р╖Кр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢п?","answer":"р╢Ър╢нр╖Эр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢пр╖Пр╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖А р╢Ър╢нр╖Эр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢┤р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Гр╖Рр╢╜р╢Ър╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢║. р╢Ър╢нр╖Эр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╢║р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢з р╢╕ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢░ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ър╖Ар╢╗р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢░р╖Цр╢╗р╢║ р╖Др╖Щр╢╢р╖Ар╖Ц р╖Гр╖Ър╢Ъ. р╢Ър╢нр╖Эр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖А р╖Гр╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Ер╢╕р╖Ф р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╖Кр╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢вр╖Ър╖Гр╖Фр╖Гр╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ър╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ер╢┤р╖Эр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Фр╖Ер╖Фр╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖Ф р╖Ар╖Ц р╖Бр╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢н р╢┤р╖Ур╢нр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Пр╢┤р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢║. р╖Бр╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╖Ар╖Ц р╢╢р╢║р╖Тр╢╢р╢╜р╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖А р╢вр╖Ър╖Гр╖Фр╖Гр╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Фр╖Др╖Фр╢з р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╢║р╖Ъ р╢║р╢нр╖Фр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢▒р╢╕р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Ц р╖Гр╖Ър╢Ъ. "},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: роПро┤рпИроХро│ро┐ройрпН роКроЯрпНроЯро┐ роОройрпНро▒рпБ роЕро┤рпИроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роЗроЯроорпН роОродрпБ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: роПро▒рпНроХро╛роЯрпБ"},{"question":"Ajс╗Н WAEC gbс║╣sс║╣ le esi idanwo awс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н to jiwee wo lasiko idanwo","answer":"Awс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н bii igba o le diс║╣ (215,149), ni ajс╗Н to n с╣гeto idanwo WAEC ti sс╗Н pe oun ko ni i ti i fun ni esi idanwo wс╗Нn bayii.с╗Мga agba fun ajс╗Н naa, Patrick Areghan, lo sс╗Нrс╗Н yii nipinlс║╣ Eko nigba to n ba awс╗Нn oniroyin sс╗Нrс╗Н pe ajс╗Н naa ti с╣гetan lati gbe esi idanwo с╗Нhun jade.с║╕sun ti wс╗Нn fi kan awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn ko gbe esi idanwo wс╗Нn jade ni pe wс╗Нn ji iwe wo lasiko ti idanwo с╗Нhun waye.O ni bii ida mс║╣tala-o-le (13.98%) ninu awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn jokoo с╣гe idanwo с╗Нhun ni wс╗Нn ko ni i ti i ri esi idanwo с╗Нhun gba latari oriс╣гiiriс╣гii с║╣sun ti wс╗Нn fi kan wс╗Нn.Bakan naa lo sс╗Н pe iwadii ti waye lori с║╣sun ti wс╗Нn fi kan wс╗Нn pe wс╗Нn ji iwe wo atawс╗Нn ohun mi-in to с╣гс║╣lс║╣ lasiko idanwo. O ni awс╗Нn yoo fi abajade awс╗Нn с╣гс╗Нwс╗Н si igbimс╗Н to yс║╣, nibi ti aс╣гaro yoo ti waye lori с╗Нrс╗Н с╗Нhun. Bс║╣с║╣ gс║╣gс║╣ lo sс╗Н pe gbogbo awс╗Нn ileewe ti с╗Нrс╗Н ba kan pata lawс╗Нn yoo kan si.Akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н tiye wс╗Нn le ni miliс╗Нnu kan aabс╗Н ni wс╗Нn с╣гedanwo с╗Нhun, nigba ti awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn le diс║╣ ni miliс╗Нnu kan с╣гe daadaa ninu iс╣гс║╣ bii marun-un, ninu eyi ti с║╣kс╗Н ede oyinbo ati imс╗Н iс╣гiro ti wa.O ni apapс╗Н akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н bii miliс╗Нnu kan ati с║╣gbс║╣run lс╗Нna с╗Нс╗Нdunrun-o-le diс║╣ ni wс╗Нn с╣гe daadaa ninu iс╣гс║╣ marun-un, yala wс╗Нn jokoo tabi wс╗Нn ko jokoo с╣гedanwo fun с║╣kс╗Н iс╣гiro ati с║╣kс╗Н ede gс║╣с║╣si ninu idanwс╗Н с╗Нhun.с╗Мjс╗Н kс║╣tadinlogun, oс╣гu kс║╣jс╗Н с╗Нdun yii ni idanwo с╗Нhun bс║╣rс║╣, ti wс╗Нn si kadii с║╣ nilс║╣ lс╗Нjс╗Н kejila, oс╣гu kс║╣san-an, с╗Нdun yii"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:рокро┐ройрпНро╡ро░рпБроорпН рокро╛роЯро▓рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп роиропроорпН рокро╛ро░ро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роО ро┤рпБродрпБроХ:тАЭроОродрпНродрпБрогрпИропрпБроорпН рокрпЗродроорпБро▒ро╛родрпБ роОро╡рпНро╡рпБропро┐ро░рпБроорпНродроорпНроорпБропро┐ро░рпНрокрпЛро▓рпН роОрогрпНрогро┐ роЙро│рпНро│рпЗроТродрпНродрпБро░ро┐роорпИ роЙроЯрпИропро╡ро░ро╛ропрпН роЙро╡роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпНропро╛ро╡ро░рпН роЕро╡ро░рпН роЙро│рпНро│роорпНродро╛ройрпН роЪрпБродрпНродроЪро┐родрпНродрпБро░рпБро╡ро╛ропрпН роОроорпНрокрпЖро░рпБрооро╛ройрпН роироЯроорпНрокрпБро░ро┐ропрпБроорпНроЗроЯроорпН роОрой роиро╛ройрпН родрпЖро░ро┐роирпНродрпЗройрпН роЕроирпНродро╡ро┐родрпНродроХро░рпНродроорпН роЕроЯро┐роХрпНроХрпЗро╡ро▓рпН рокрпБро░ро┐роирпНродро┐роЯ роОройрпНроЪро┐роирпНродрпИ рооро┐роХ ро╡ро┐ро┤рпИроирпНрод родро╛ро▓рпЗтАЭ тАУ ро╡ро│рпНро│ро▓ро╛ро░рпН","answer":" ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп роиропроорпН рокро╛ро░ро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБродро▓рпН: роорпБройрпНройрпБро░рпИ:ро╡ро│рпНро│ро▓ро╛ро░рпН роОройрокрпН рокрпЛро▒рпНро▒рокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роЗро░ро╛рооро▓ро┐роЩрпНроХ роЕроЯро┐роХро│рпН роЪроородрпНродрпБро╡роорпБроорпН, роЪроородро░рпНроороорпБроорпН ро╡ро│ро░ро╡рпБроорпН, роЪрооропроорпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ рокро┐ро▒ро░рпНроиро▓ройрпН рокрпЛро▒рпНро▒рпБро╡родро╛роХ роЕроорпИропро╡рпБроорпН роХрпБро░ро▓рпН роХрпКроЯрпБродрпНродро╡ро░рпН роЖро╡ро╛ро░рпН. роЗро▒рпИро╡ройрпИ роОрогрпНрогро┐ роЗро╡ро░рпН рокро╛роЯро┐роп рокро╛роЯро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБроЯройрпН ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЕроирпНрод ро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЗро╡ро░родрпБ рокро╛роЯро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп роиропроЩрпНроХро│рпИроХрпН роХро╛рогрпНрокрпЛроорпН.родро┐ро░рогрпНроЯ роХро░рпБродрпНродрпБ:роОроирпНрод роТро░рпБ ро╡рпЗро▒рпБрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИропрпБроорпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро╛родрпБ роОро▓рпНро▓ро╛ роЙропро┐ро░рпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН родроорпН роЙропро┐ро░рпН рокрпЛро▓ роОрогрпНрогро┐, родройрпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпНродрпБро│рпНро│рпЗ роТродрпНрод роЕройрпНрокрпБроЯрпИропро╡ро░ро╛ропрпН роЗро░рпБрокрпНрокро╡ро░рпИ роЗро▒рпИро╡ройрпН роЙро╡роирпНродрпБ роПро▒рпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН роЕродрпНродроХрпИроп роЙро│рпНро│роорпН роЙроЯрпИропро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпЗ роЪро┐родрпНродрпБро░рпБро╡ро╛ропрпНродрпН родро┐роХро┤рпБроорпН роОроорпНрокрпЖро░рпБрооро╛ройрпН роироЯроорпНрокрпБро░ро┐ропрпБроорпН роЗроЯроорпН роЖроХрпБроорпН. роОро▓рпНро▓ро╛ ро╡ро▓рпНро▓ роЗро▒рпИро╡ройрпН роЕроЯро┐роХрпНроХрпБ роПро╡ро▓рпН рокрпБро░ро┐ропрпБроорпН роЪро┐роирпНродрпИрооро┐роХ роЗро░рпБроирпНродродро╛ро▓рпН роОро╡рпНро╡рпБропро┐ро░ро┐роЯродрпНродрпБроорпН роЕройрпНрокрпБроЯройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤ ро╡ро┐ро┤рпИроирпНродрпЗройрпН.роорпИропроХрпНроХро░рпБродрпНродрпБ:роЕройрпИродрпНродрпБ роЙропро┐ро░рпНроХро│ро┐роЯродрпНродрпБроорпН роЕройрпНрокрпБ рокро╛ро░ро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ роЙропро┐ро░рпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роПро╡ро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпЗ роЗро▒рпИро╡ройрпБроХрпНроХрпБроЪрпН роЪрпЖропрпНропрпБроорпН родрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ. роЕро╡ро░рпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпНродрпБро│рпНро│рпЗ роЗро▒рпИро╡ройрпН роЙро│рпНро│ро╛ройрпН роОройрпНро▒ роХро░рпБродрпНродрпИ роорпИропрооро╛роХ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ ро╡ро│рпНро│ро▓ро╛ро░рпН роЗрокрпНрокро╛роЯро▓рпИрокрпН рокрпБройрпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ро╛ро░рпН.роорпЛройрпИ роиропроорпН:роЪрпЖропрпНропрпБро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЕроЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпЛ роЪрпАро░ро┐ро▓рпЛ роорпБродро▓рпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродрпБ роТройрпНро▒ро┐ ро╡ро░родрпН родрпКроЯрпБрокрпНрокродрпБ роорпЛройрпИ роЖроХрпБроорпН.роЪро╛ройрпНро▒рпБ: роОродрпНродрпБрогрпИропрпБроорпН роОро╡рпНро╡рпБропро┐ро░рпБроорпН роЙроЯрпИропро╡ро░ро╛ропрпН роЙро╡роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН роОрой роорпЛройрпИ роиропроорпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.роОродрпБроХрпИ роиропроорпН:роЪрпЖропрпНропрпБро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЕроЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпЛ роЪрпАро░ро┐ро▓рпЛ роЗро░рогрпНроЯро╛ро╡родрпБ роОро┤рпБродрпНродрпБ роТройрпНро▒ро┐ ро╡ро░родрпН родрпКроЯрпБрокрпНрокродрпБ роОродрпБроХрпИ роЖроХрпБроорпН.роЪро╛ройрпНро▒рпБ:роОродрпНродрпБрогрпИропрпБроорпН, роТродрпНродрпБро░ро┐роорпИ, роЪро┐родрпНродрпБро░рпБ, ро╡ро┐родрпНродроХро░рпН роОрой роОродрпБроХрпИ роиропроорпН рооро┐роХрпНроХрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.роЪроирпНрод роиропроорпН:тАЬроЪроирпНродроорпН родрооро┐ро┤рпБроХрпНроХрпБроЪрпН роЪрпКроирпНродроорпНтАЭ роОройрпНрокродрпИ роЙрогро░рпНродрпНродрпБроорпН ро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЕро▒рпБроЪрпАро░рпНроХрпНроХро┤ро┐роирпЖроЯро┐ро▓роЯро┐ роЖроЪро┐ро░ро┐роп ро╡ро┐ро░рпБродрпНродроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБ роЕроХро╡ро▓рпН роУроЪрпИропрпБроЯройрпН роорпИропроорпН рокрпКро░рпБроирпНрод роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.роЕрогро┐ роиропроорпН:тАЬроОро╡рпНро╡рпБропро┐ро░рпБроорпН родроорпНроорпБропро┐ро░рпН рокрпЛро▓тАЭ роОройрпНрокродро┐ро▓рпН роЙро╡роорпИропрогро┐ роЗроЯроорпНрокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│родрпБроорпБроЯро┐ро╡рпБро░рпИ:рокроХрпНродро┐ роЙрогро░рпНро╡рпБ роЪрпКроЯрпНроЯ рокро╛роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│ роЗрокрпНрокро╛роЯро▓рпН рокроХрпНродро┐роЪрпНроЪрпБро╡рпИропрпБроорпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЪрпН роЪрпБро╡рпИропрпИропрпБроорпН роТро░рпБроЩрпНроХрпЗ рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБро│рпНро│родрпБ."},{"question":"сЙвсИН сКнсИКсКХсЙ░сКХ сЛИсЛ░сЛЪсИЕ сИЭсЛ╡сИн сКисИШсИЭсМгсЙ│сЙ╕сЛН сКисИ╡сКХсЙ╡ сМКсЛЬ сЙасНКсЙ╡ сКРсЛН сКасЙгсЙ│сЙ╕сЛН сЛисИЮсЙ▒сЙ╡?","answer":"сИ╢сИ╡сЙ╡ сЛИсИн"},{"question":"O que ├й o super bowl?","answer":"Super bowl ├й o jogo final da temporada da NFL que ocorre, desde 2002, no segundo domingo do m├кs de fevereiro. Neste jogo se enfrentam os times campe├╡es da Confer├кncia Nacional (NFC) e da Confer├кncia Americana (AFC). O time vencedor do super bowl ├й consagrado campe├гo da temporada e recebe o trof├йu Vince Lombardi. "},{"question":"ржирж┐ржЪрзЗрж░ ржмрж╛ржХрзНржпржЯрж┐рж░ ржЙржкрж░ ржнрж┐рждрзНрждрж┐ ржХрж░рзЗ ржПржХржЯрж┐ рж╕ржорзНржкрзВрж░рзНржг ржкрж╛ржарзНржп рж▓рж┐ржЦрзБржиредрзирзжрзжрзи ржЦрзНрж░рж┐рж╖рзНржЯрж╛ржмрзНржжрзЗрж░ ржЧрзБржЬрж░рж╛ржд ржжрж╛ржЩрзНржЧрж╛рж░ ржШржЯржирж╛ржпрж╝","answer":"рзирзжрзжрзи ржЦрзНрж░рж┐рж╖рзНржЯрж╛ржмрзНржжрзЗрж░ ржЧрзБржЬрж░рж╛ржд ржжрж╛ржЩрзНржЧрж╛рж░ ржШржЯржирж╛ржпрж╝ рждрж╛рж░ ржкрзНрж░рж╢рж╛рж╕ржи рж╕ржорж╛рж▓рзЛржЪрж┐ржд рж╣ржУржпрж╝рж╛ржпрж╝ ржнрж╛рж░ржд ржУ ржмрж┐ржжрзЗрж╢рзЗ рждрж╛рж░ рж╕ржорж╛рж▓рзЛржЪржирж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ред ржХрж┐ржирзНрждрзБ ржЧрзБржЬрж░рж╛ржЯрзЗрж░ ржЕрж░рзНржержирзИрждрж┐ржХ ржЙржирзНржирждрж┐рж░ ржмрзГржжрзНржзрж┐рждрзЗ рж╕рж╣рж╛ржпрж╝ржХ ржкрж░рж┐ржмрзЗрж╢ ржЧржаржирзЗрж░ ржЬржирзНржп рждрж┐ржирж┐ рждрж╛рж░ ржЖрж░рзНржерж┐ржХ ржирзАрждрж┐рж░ ржЬржирзНржп ржкрзНрж░рж╢ржВрж╕рж┐ржд рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗржЫрзЗржиред ржЕржирзНржпржжрж┐ржХрзЗ рждрж╛рж░ рж░рж╛ржЬрзНржпрзЗрж░ ржорж╛ржиржмрзЛржирзНржиржпрж╝ржирзЗрж░ ржУржкрж░ ржЧржаржиржорзВрж▓ржХ ржкрзНрж░ржнрж╛ржм ржмрж┐рж╕рзНрждрж╛рж░рзЗ рждрж╛рж░ ржкрзНрж░рж╢рж╛рж╕ржирзЗрж░ ржЕржХрзНрж╖ржорждрж╛рж░ ржЬржирзНржп рждрж┐ржирж┐ рж╕ржорж╛рж▓рзЛржЪрж┐рждржУ рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗржЫрзЗржиред"},{"question":"Ekwughi ekwu m├иr├и с╗Нnс╗е .","answer":"Egeghi ege mere ntс╗Л"},{"question":" ┌Ж╪▒╪з ┘З┘Ж┌п╪з┘Е ╪з╪│╪к┘Б╪з╪п┘З ╪з╪▓ ╪о╪з┌йтАМ╪и╪▒┌п ╪и╪▒╪з█М ╪к╪╣┘И█М╪╢ ┌п┘Д╪п╪з┘Ж ┘Ж╪и╪з█М╪п ╪в┘Ж ╪▒╪з ┘Б╪┤╪з╪▒ ╪п╪з╪п╪Я","answer":"╪и┘ЗтАМ╪з█М┘ЖтАМ╪╣┘Д╪к ┌й┘З ┘Б╪┤╪▒╪п┌п█М ╪▓█М╪з╪п ╪о╪з┌йтАМ╪и╪▒┌п ╪│╪и╪и ┘Е█МтАМ╪┤┘И╪п ┌й┘З ╪о╪з┌йтАМ╪и╪▒┌птАМ┘З╪з ╪и┘З ┘З┘Е ╪и┌Ж╪│╪и┘Ж╪п ┘И ╪з╪▓ ┘И╪▒┘И╪п ┘З┘И╪з ┘И ╪к┘Ж┘Б╪│ ╪▒█М╪┤┘З ┌й┘З ╪и╪▒╪з█М ╪▒╪┤╪п ┌п█М╪з┘З ╪и╪│█М╪з╪▒ ┘Е┘З┘Е ┘И ╪╢╪▒┘И╪▒█М ╪з╪│╪к ╪м┘Д┘И┌п█М╪▒█М ┘Ж┘Е╪з█М╪п."},{"question":"┘Б┘К┘Ж ┘Г╪з┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪м╪и┘Д ╪з┘Д╪з╪о╪╢╪▒╪Я","answer":"╪│┘Д╪╖┘Ж╪й ╪╣┘Е╪з┘Ж."},{"question":"ржПржЗ ржЕржирзБржЪрзНржЫрзЗржжрзЗрж░ ржЬржирзНржп ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржзрж╛рж░рж╛ржмрж╛рж╣рж┐ржХрждрж╛ рж▓рж┐ржЦрзБржи :ржкрж╛рж░рж╕рзНржпрзЗрж░ ржорзБрж╕рж▓рж┐ржо ржмрж┐ржЬржпрж╝рзЗрж░ рж╕ржоржпрж╝ ржЖржлржЧрж╛ржирж┐рж╕рзНрждрж╛ржирзЗрж░ ржорзБрж╕рж▓рж┐ржо ржмрж┐ржЬржпрж╝ рж╢рзБрж░рзБ рж╣ржпрж╝ ржпржЦржи ржЖрж░ржм ржорзБрж╕рж▓ржорж╛ржирж░рж╛ ржкрзВрж░рзНржм ржжрж┐ржХрзЗ ржЦрзЛрж░рж╛рж╕рж╛ржи, рж╕рж┐рж╕рзНрждрж╛ржи ржПржмржВ ржЯрзНрж░рж╛ржирзНрж╕ржХрзНрж╕рж┐ржпрж╝рж╛ржирж╛ржпрж╝ ржЕржнрж┐ржмрж╛рж╕рзА рж╣ржпрж╝ред ржирж╛рж╣рж╛ржнрж╛ржирзНржж ржпрзБржжрзНржзрзЗрж░","answer":"рззрзл ржмржЫрж░ ржкрж░ рждрж╛рж░рж╛ ржжржХрзНрж╖рж┐ржг ржУ ржкрзВрж░рзНржм ржЖржлржЧрж╛ржирж┐рж╕рзНрждрж╛ржи ржЫрж╛ржбрж╝рж╛ рж╕ржХрж▓ рж╕рж╛рж╕рж╛ржирзАржпрж╝ ржбрзЛржорзЗржЗржи ржирж┐ржпрж╝ржирзНрждрзНрж░ржг ржХрж░рзЗред ржорзБрж╕рж▓рж┐ржо ржзрж░рзНржорзАржпрж╝ ржкрзНрж░рждрж┐рж╖рзНржарж╛ржиржЧрзБрж▓рзЛржХрзЗ ржкрзГрж╖рзНржаржкрзЛрж╖ржХрждрж╛ ржХрж╛рж░рзА ржЧржЬржирж╛ржнрж┐ржж ржУ ржШрзБрж░рж┐ржж рж░рж╛ржЬржмржВрж╢рзЗрж░ рж╢рж╛рж╕ржирж╛ржорж▓рзЗ ржжрж╢ржо ржерзЗржХрзЗ ржжрзНржмрж╛ржжрж╢ рж╢рждрж╛ржмрзНржжрзАрж░ ржоржзрзНржпржмрж░рзНрждрзА рж╕ржоржпрж╝ржХрж╛рж▓ ржкрж░рзНржпржирзНржд ржкрзВрж░рзНржг ржЗрж╕рж▓рж╛ржорзАржХрж░ржг рж╣ржпрж╝ржирж┐ред"},{"question":"Como ├й que Saramago retratou a morte e a mortalidade nas suas narrativas?","answer":"Na obra \\"As Intermit├кncias da Morte\\", Saramago imagina um mundo onde a morte deixa de existir. Ele explora as implica├з├╡es sociais e pessoais desse cen├бrio incomum, iluminando as complexidades do ciclo da vida e da transitoriedade."},{"question":"╬Я╬╗╬┐╬║╬╗╬о╧Б╧Й╧Г╬╡ ╧Д╬┐ ╬║╬╡╬п╬╝╬╡╬╜╬┐:  ╬Х╬п╧З╬╡ ╧Г╧Е╬╝╬╝╬╡╧Д╬м╧Г╧З╬╡╬╣ ╧Г╬╡ ╬╝╬п╬▒ ╧Г╬╡╬╣╧Б╬м ╬▒╧А╧М ╧А╧Б╬┐╬║╧Б╬╣╬╝╬▒╧Д╬╣╬║╬┐╧Н╧В ╬│╧Н╧Б╬┐╧Е╧В ╧Д╬╖╧В ╧З╧О╧Б╬▒╧В ╧Д╬┐╧Е ╬│╬╣╬▒ ╧Д╬╖╬╜ ╬╡╬║╧А╧Б╬┐╧Г╧О╧А╬╖╧Г╬╖ ╧Г╧Д╬╖╬╜ Eurovision. ╬д╬┐ 2009 ╬╝╬╡ ╧Д╬┐ ╧Д╧Б╬▒╬│╬┐╧Н╬┤╬╣ \\"I Still Carry On\\", ╧Д╬┐","answer":"2011 ╬╝╬╡ ╧Д╬┐ ╧Д╧Б╬▒╬│╬┐╧Н╬┤╬╣ \\"Bistvo skrito je o─Нem\\", ╧Д╬┐ 2014 ╬╝╬╡ ╧Д╬┐ ╧Д╧Б╬▒╬│╬┐╧Н╬┤╬╣ \\"I Won't Give Up\\" ╬║╬▒╬╕╧О╧В ╬║╬▒╬╣ ╬╡╧А╬п╧Г╬╖╧В ╧Г╬╡ ╬╡╬╗╬▓╬╡╧Д╬╣╬║╧М ╧А╧Б╬┐╬║╧Б╬╣╬╝╬▒╧Д╬╣╬║╧М ╬│╧Н╧Б╬┐ ╧Д╬┐ 2016 ╬╝╬╡ ╧Д╬┐ ╧Д╧Б╬▒╬│╬┐╧Н╬┤╬╣ \\"Take Me Far\\"."},{"question":"waan ku salaamay","answer":"waan kaa qaaday"},{"question":"Umbuzo othi: \\"Iavocado noma ialligator pear nayo ibhekisela esithelweni (ngokwezitshalo iberry enkulu equkethe imbewu eyodwa) somuthi.\\"? Isihloko sithi iAvocado.","answer":"\\"Yisiphi ingxenye yesitshalo okuyiavocado?\\""},{"question":"╨Ь╨╡╨╢╨┤╤Г ╨║╨░╨║╨╕╨╝╨╕ ╨┤╨▓╤Г╨╝╤П ╨╛╤А╨│╨░╨╜╨╕╨╖╨╝╨░╨╝╨╕ ╨╜╨░╨╕╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╡╨╡ ╨▓╨╡╤А╨╛╤П╤В╨╜╨╛ ╨▓╨╛╨╖╨╜╨╕╨║╨╜╨╛╨▓╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╡ ╨║╨╛╨╜╨║╤Г╤А╨╡╨╜╤Ж╨╕╨╕? ╨Ф╨╛╤Б╤В╤Г╨┐╨╜╤Л╨╡ ╨▓╨░╤А╨╕╨░╨╜╤В╤Л: - ╨╛╨╗╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╨╕ ╨▒╨░╨▒╨╛╤З╨║╨╕; - ╤Б╨╛╨▓╤Л ╨╕ ╨▒╨░╨║╤В╨╡╤А╨╕╨╕; - ╨╖╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В╤Л╨╡ ╤А╤Л╨▒╨║╨╕ ╨╕ ╨║╤А╨╛╨╗╨╕╨║╨╕; - ╤В╤А╨░╨▓╨░ ╨╕ ╨║╨╗╤Г╨▒╨╜╨╕╨║╨░.","answer":"╨Ш╨╖ ╨┐╤А╨╕╨▓╨╡╨┤╨╡╨╜╨╜╤Л╤Е ╨▓╨░╤А╨╕╨░╨╜╤В╨╛╨▓, ╨╜╨░╨╕╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╡╨╡ ╨▓╨╡╤А╨╛╤П╤В╨╜╨╛ ╨▓╨╛╨╖╨╜╨╕╨║╨╜╨╛╨▓╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╡ ╨║╨╛╨╜╨║╤Г╤А╨╡╨╜╤Ж╨╕╨╕ ╨╝╨╡╨╢╨┤╤Г ╤В╤А╨░╨▓╨╛╨╣ ╨╕ ╨║╨╗╤Г╨▒╨╜╨╕╨║╨╛╨╣. ╨Ю╨╜╨╕ ╨╛╨▒╨╕╤В╨░╤О╤В ╨▓ ╨╛╨┤╨╜╨╛╨╣ ╨╕ ╤В╨╛╨╣ ╨╢╨╡ ╤Б╤А╨╡╨┤╨╡ ╨╛╨▒╨╕╤В╨░╨╜╨╕╤П ╨╕ ╨╕╤Б╨┐╨╛╨╗╤М╨╖╤Г╤О╤В ╨╛╨┤╨╜╨╕ ╨╕ ╤В╨╡ ╨╢╨╡ ╤А╨╡╤Б╤Г╤А╤Б╤Л, ╨▓ ╨╛╤В╨╗╨╕╤З╨╕╨╡ ╨╛╤В ╨┤╤А╤Г╨│╨╕╤Е ╨▓╨░╤А╨╕╨░╨╜╤В╨╛╨▓. ╨Э╨░╨┐╤А╨╕╨╝╨╡╤А, ╤А╤Л╨▒╤Л ╨╛╨▒╨╕╤В╨░╤О╤В ╨▓ ╨▓╨╛╨┤╨╡, ╨░ ╨║╤А╨╛╨╗╨╕╨║╨╡ ╨╜╨░ ╨╖╨╡╨╝╨╗╨╡ - ╨┐╨╛╤Н╤В╨╛╨╝╤Г ╨╝╨░╨╗╨╛╨▓╨╡╤А╨╛╤П╤В╨╜╨╛, ╤З╤В╨╛ ╨╛╨╜╨╕ ╤Б╤В╨╛╨╗╨║╨╜╤Г╤В╤Б╤П."},{"question":"Sс╗▒ kiс╗Зn quan trс╗Нng n├аo ─С╞░с╗гc n├│i tс╗Ыi trong v─Гn bс║гn n├аy? - ─Рс╗Ыi bс║пt ─Сс║зu viс║┐t cho tс╗Э Trung ngoс║бi nhс║нt b├бo (ф╕нхдЦцЧеха▒) cс╗зa Th╞░с╗гng Hс║гi v├а tс╗Э Thi├кn ─Рс║бc b├бo (хдйщР╕ха▒) с╗Я tuс╗Хi 19. ├Фng lс║еy t├кn hiс╗Зu ─Рс╗Ыi Thi├кn Cс╗лu (хдйф╗З) ─Сс╗Г thс╗Г hiс╗Зn sс╗▒ c─Гm hс║нn vс╗Ыi nh├а Thanh. Ch├нnh quyс╗Бn M├гn Thanh ─Сe dс╗Нa tс╗Сng giam ├┤ng, n├кn n─Гm 1911, ├┤ng trс╗Сn sang Nhс║нt Bс║гn rс╗Уi Penang, tс║бi ─С├│ ├┤ng gia nhс║нp ─Рс╗Уng minh hс╗Щi (хРМчЫЯцЬГ) v├а viс║┐t b├аi cho tс╗Э Quang Hoa b├бo (хЕЙшПпха▒) cс╗зa hс╗Щi. C├╣ng n─Гm, ├┤ng trс╗Я vс╗Б Th╞░с╗гng Hс║гi sau Khс╗Яi ngh─йa V┼й X╞░╞бng v├а lс║нp ra D├вn quyс╗Бn b├бo (ц░СцмКха▒).","answer":"Sс╗▒ kiс╗Зn quan trс╗Нng ─С╞░с╗гc n├│i tс╗Ыi trong v─Гn bс║гn n├аy l├а cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Эi v├а hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng cс╗зa ng╞░с╗Эi c├│ t├кn hiс╗Зu ─Рс╗Ыi Thi├кn Cс╗лu (хдйф╗З), ng╞░с╗Эi ─С├г ─С├│ng g├│p t├нch cс╗▒c v├аo c├бc hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng b├бo ch├н v├а phong tr├аo c├бch mс║бng tс║бi Trung Quс╗Сc v├аo thс╗Эi kс╗│ kh├бng M├гn Thanh. ├Фng bс║пt ─Сс║зu viс║┐t cho c├бc tс╗Э b├бo nh╞░ Trung ngoс║бi nhс║нt b├бo v├а Thi├кn ─Рс║бc b├бo, v├а sс╗н dс╗еng t├кn hiс╗Зu ─Сс╗Г thс╗Г hiс╗Зn sс╗▒ c─Гm hс║нn vс╗Ыi nh├а Thanh."},{"question":"Inona no maha samy hafa ny vola sy ny harena?","answer":"Ny vola dia manondro manokana ny vola na loharanon-karena ara-bola azo ampiasaina hividianana entana sy serivisy. Izy io dia fitaovam-panakalozana eken'ny maro amin'ny toe-karena. Ny harena kosa dia fepetra mivondrona kokoa izay tsy ny vola ihany fa ahitana ny fananana materialy. Ny fananana vola dia afaka manampy amin'ny harena, fa ny harena dia ahitana ny fananana, fampiasam-bola ary fananana hafa azo tsapain-tanana sy tsy azo tsapain-tanana."},{"question":"#р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢Ьр╢╕р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢п?","answer":"\\"р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢В р╢пр╖Ър╢║р╢В...\\"\\"р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Ср╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖Пр╢з р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╢лр╖Тр╖Г р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Т р╢Ср╢Ъ р╖Др╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╢Ъ р╖Ар╢┤р╖Гр╢╗р╖Тр╢║ р╢пр╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢║\\" (р╢вр╖Ър╢нр╖Ар╢▒р╖Пр╢╗р╖Пр╢╕ (р╢Ер╢╖р╢║р╢Ьр╖Тр╢╗р╖Т) р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢н р╖Гр╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢║)р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢В - р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖К. р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢║ р╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢лр╖Тр╖Г р╢пр╖Щр╢▒ р╢пр╖Щр╢║ - р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖К.р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖К - р╢║р╢╕р╖К р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢пр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ьр╢╕р╖К р╢╢р╖Тр╢╕р╖К р╢Жр╢пр╖Тр╢║.р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢Ьр╢╕- р╢╗р╖Пр╢в р╖Гр╖Ър╖Ар╢║ р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢╢р╖П р╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢╕."},{"question":"Geef me een voorbeeld van trivia in deze categorie: geschiedenis","answer":"Hier is een voorbeeld: Wanneer is de eerste wereldoorlog begonnen? Antwoord: 1914"},{"question":"A cikin wanne nau'in ra'ayi za ku rarraba tweet mai zuwa? Mai kyau, Marar kyau, ko tsaka tsaki?wannan ba har zuciyar sa ba siyasa ce kawai a hakan ma","answer":"Zan rarraba tweet ╔Чin da aka bayar a matsayin: Marar kyau"},{"question":"╪г╪м╪и ╪╣┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К: \\"┘Г┘Е ╪╣╪╕┘Е╪й ╪к┘И╪м╪п ┘Б┘К ╪м╪│┘Е ╪з┘Д╪е┘Ж╪│╪з┘Ж  ╪Я\\"","answer":"╪н╪│┘Ж╪з ╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ┘З┘К: \\"206 ╪╣╪╕┘Е╪й\\"."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _ :\\" Ny tsiny izany dia fanamelohana ataonтАЩny mpiara-belona aminтАЩny olona iray noho ny fahadisoana nataony na tandrina na tsy tandrina izany. Mety tsy fahafaham-po na tsy fahafenoana na kilema ihany koa ny tsiny, araka ny fitenenana hoe: тАЬIndrokelinтАЩny mpandrafitraтАЭ sy ny hoe тАЬtovovavy tsara tarehy _ ka voatandro iray no tsininy.тАЭ\\"","answer":" Ny tsiny izany dia fanamelohana ataonтАЩny mpiara-belona aminтАЩny olona iray noho ny fahadisoana nataony na tandrina na tsy tandrina izany. Mety tsy fahafaham-po na tsy fahafenoana na kilema ihany koa ny tsiny, araka ny fitenenana hoe: тАЬIndrokelinтАЩny mpandrafitraтАЭ sy ny hoe тАЬtovovavy tsara tarehy petakтАЩorona ka voatandro iray no tsininy.тАЭ"},{"question":"What does FAS, MTO and ATO stand for? Final Assembly Schedule, often abbreviated as FAS and sometimes referred to as finishing schedule, is a schedule of end items to finish the product for specific customer orders in a make to order (MTO) or assemble-to-order (ATO) environment.","answer":"\\"FAS = Final Assembly ScheduleMTO = make to orderATO = assemble-to-order\\""},{"question":"рдкреНрд░рд╢реНрди :  рднреВрдд рдХрд╛рд▓рдХрд╛ рдЕрднреНрдпрд╕реНрдд рдкрдХреНрд╖рдХрд╛ рдХреНрд░рд┐рдпрд╛рдкрджрдХреЛ рдкреНрд░рдпреЛрдЧ рдЧрд░реА рдЖрдлреНрдиреЛ рдмрд╛рд▓реНрдпрдХрд╛рд▓рдХрд╛ рдмрд╛рд░реЗрдорд╛ рд╡рд░реНрдгрди рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реНтАМ ред","answer":"рдЙрддреНрддрд░ :  рдо рдмрд╛рд▓реНрдпрдХрд╛рд▓рдорд╛ рд╕рд╛рдереАрд╣рд░реВрд╕рдБрдЧ рдЦреБрдм рдЦреЗрд▓реНрдереЗрдБ ред рдо рдкреНрд░рд╛рдпрдГ рдШреБрдореНрди рдЬрд╛рдиреНрдереЗрдБ ред рдо рдЬрдЩреНрдЧрд▓рдорд╛ рдХрдЯреБрд╕ рдЯрд┐рдкреНрдердБ, рджрдореМрд░рд╛ рдЯрд┐рдкреНрдпреИ, рд▓рд┐рдЪреА рдЯрд┐рдкреНрдердБред рдЖрдБрдк рдЯрд┐рдкреНрдпрдБ, рдХрд╛рдлрд▓ рдЯрд┐рдкреНрдердБ, рддрд┐рдЬреБ рдЯрд┐рдкреНрдереЗрдБ рдЕрдирд┐ рд╕рд╛рдереАрд╣рд░реВрд╕рдБрдЧреИ рд░рдорд╛рдЙрдБрджреИ рдЦрд╛рдиреНрдереЗрдБ ред рдорд▓рд╛рдИ рдкреМрдбреА рдЦреЗрд▓реНрди рдЕрд╕рд╛рдзреНрдпреИ рдорди рдкрд░реНрдереНрдпреЛ ред рдо рд╣рд░реНрдкрди рдЦреЛрд▓рд╛рдорд╛ рдЦреБрдм рдкреМрдбреА рдЦреЗрд▓реНрдереЗрдБ ред рдорд▓рд╛рдИ рдкреБрд▓рдмрд╛рдЯ рддрд▓ рдЦреЛрд▓рд╛рдорд╛ рд╣рд╛рдо рдлрд╛рд▓реНрди рдЦреБрдм рдордЬреНрдЬрд╛ рдЖрдЙрдБрдереНрдпреЛ ред рдХреЛрд╣реА рд╕рд╛рдереАрд╣рд░реВ рдбреБрдмреЗрдХреЛ рдЦрдгреНрдбрдорд╛ рдореИрд▓реЗ рдиреИ рдирд┐рдХрд╛рд▓реНрдереЗрдБ ред рдо рдХрд╛рд▓рд┐рдХрд╛ рдорд╛. рд╡рд┐. рдорд╛ рдкрдвреНрдереЗрдБ ред рдо рдХрд╣рд┐рд▓реЗрдХрд╛рд╣реАрдБ рдХрд╢реНрдпрдк рддрд╛рд▓рдорд╛ рдкрдирд┐ рдкреМрдбреА рдЦреЗрд▓реНрди рдЬрд╛рдиреНрдереЗрдБ ред рдо рдХрд╢реНрдпрдк рддрд╛рд▓ рдкреВрд░реИ рдПрдХ рдлрдиреНрдХрд╛ рд╣рд╛рдиреНрдереЗрдБ ред рдо рддрд┐рдмреНрд░ рдЧрддрд┐рдорд╛ рдкреМрдбреА рдЦреЗрд▓реНрди рд╕рдХреНрдереЗрдБ ред рдорд▓рд╛рдИ рдкреМрдбреА рдЦреЗрд▓рдорд╛ рдХрд╕реИрд▓реЗ рдЬрд┐рддреНрди рд╕рдХреНрджреИрдирдереНрдпреЛ ред рдо рдЕрдиреБрд╢рд╛рд╕рд┐рдд, рдорд┐рд╣рд┐рдиреЗрддреА рд╡рд┐рджреНрдпрд╛рд░реНрдереА рднрдиреЗрд░ рдЪрд┐рдирд┐рдиреНрдереЗрдБ ред рдо рдкрд░реАрдХреНрд╖рд╛рдорд╛ рдкреНрд░рд╛рдпрдГ рдкреНрд░рдердо рдиреИ рд╣реБрдиреНрдереЗрдБ ред"},{"question":"K├н ni с║╣с╣гin с╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А?","answer":"├Тwe ni."},{"question":"Kaynak├з─▒ Sertifikas─▒ ka├з TL?","answer":"Aday, s─▒navdan ├╢nce T.C. kimlik numaras─▒ bulunan kimlik belgesini ibraz etmeli ve s─▒nav ba┼Яvuru formunu doldurmal─▒d─▒r. S─▒nav─▒ takiben ilgili standarda g├╢re yap─▒lan de─Яerlendirme sonucunda ba┼Яar─▒l─▒ bulunan adaylar sertifika almaya hak kazan─▒rlar. (Kaynak├з─▒ Sertifikas─▒ ├╝creti, her bir sertifika i├зin 500TL+KDV(%20)'dir)."},{"question":"R├йwum Soudan mu ngi n├йkk ci kembaar bi ├▒uy wakh Afrique","answer":"Ci ban kembaar la r├йwum Soudan du Sud n├йkk"},{"question":"Inona ny fanalavana ny HJRA?","answer":"Ny fanalavana ny HJRA dia: Hopitaly Joseph Ravoahangy Andrianavalona"},{"question":"Baboy sa lasang, ang tunok puro lansang.","answer":"nangka"},{"question":"fenoy ny banga:\\"\\tAza dia atao fatra-pandefitra toy ny mpivaro-tantely :_\\"","answer":"\\" ny tompony indray no milela-tanana.\\""},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Andriy Yarmolenko. ","answer":"Is imreoir sacair R├║iseach ├й Andriy Yarmolenko a rugadh ar an 23 Deireadh F├│mhair 1989 i Saint Petersburg. Imr├нonn s├й faoi l├бthair le West Ham."},{"question":"Amelia Earhart р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п, р╖Гр╖Д р╢Зр╢║р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Рр╢┤р╖У р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢вр╢║р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Др╢л р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢п?","answer":"Amelia Earhart р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Эр╢Ьр╖Пр╢╕р╖У р╢Ър╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖П р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢╕р╖Фр╖Ар╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Йр╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Ар╢йр╖Пр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╢ар╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢║. р╢Зр╢║ р╢Ер╢нр╖Кр╢╜р╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Пр╢Ьр╢╗р╢║ р╖Др╢╗р╖Др╖П р╢нр╢▒р╖Тр╖А р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Гр╢╗ р╢Ър╖Е р╢┤р╖Ер╢╕р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Пр╖А р╢╢р╖Ар╢з р╢┤р╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢нр╢╗, р╢Зр╢║ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢вр╢▒р╢┤р╢пр╢║ р╖Др╢╗р╖Др╖П р╢┤р╖Ер╢╕р╖Ф р╢Тр╢Ър╢╜, р╢▒р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒ р╢п р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╖Цр╢╗р╖Кр╢л р╢Ър╖Ер╖Пр╢║. "},{"question":"╙и╤А╥п╨║╨╖╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╡╨╗╨╕ - ╨╛╨▒╨╛╨╜╨┤╤Г╤Г ╤Л╤А╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п ╨║╨░╨╣╤Б╤Л?","answer":"╙и╨а╥о╨Ъ╨Ч╨Р╨а╨У╨Р ╨Ъ╨Х╨в╨Х╨Ы╨Ш╨б╙й╨╖╥п ╨Ь.╨в╤Г╤А╨░╨╡╨▓╨░╨╜╤Л╨║╤Л,╨╛╨▒╨╛╨╜╤Г ╨Р.╨Ц╨░╨╣╨╜╨░╨║╨╛╨▓╨┤╤Г╨║╤Г╨Ц╥п╤А ╤Н╤Н╤А╤З╨╕╤И╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╡╨╗╨╕ ╙й╤А╥п╨║╨╖╨░╤А╨│╨░,╨б╤Г╨╜╤Г╤И╤Г╨╝╨┤╤Г ╤Б╤Г╤А╨░╨╜╨░╨╝ ╤З╨╡╤В╨║╨╡ ╨║╨░╨║╨┐╨░.╨б╥п╨╣╥п╥п╨▒╥п╨╖╨│╙й ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г╨│╤Г╨┐ ╨░╨╣╨╗╤Г╤Г ╤В╥п╨╜╨┤╙й,╨б╤Л╨╣╤Л╨╜╨░╨╗╤Л ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╨╡╨╗╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨░╨║╤В╤Л╨▒╤Л╨╖╨│╨░.╨Ь╙й╨╗ ╨▒╤Г╨╗╨░╨║╨║╨░ ╨▒╨░╤А╨░╨▒╤Л╨╖ ╨Р╨╣ ╤В╨╛╤Б╨║╨╛╨╜╤Г╨Р╤В ╨╢╨░╨╗╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╤И╨░╨╝╨░╨╗╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨╛╨╣╨╜╨╛╤И╨║╨╛╨╜╤Г.╨Ъ╨╡╤З╨╕╨║╨┐╨╡╨╣╨╗╨╕ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╨╡╨╗╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨░╨║╤В╤Л╨▒╤Л╨╖╨┤╨░╨╜,╙и╤А╥п╨║╨╖╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╡╨╗╨╕ ╨╝╨░╨║╤Г╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤З╤Г.╨Ъ╨░╤А╨╡╨║╤В╨╡╤А╨│╨╡ ╨╢╨░╤И╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐ ╤Б╥п╨╣╥п╥п╨▒╥п╨╖╨┤╥п,╨Ь╙й╨╗ ╨▒╤Г╨╗╨░╨║╨║╨░ ╤Б╥п╤А╤В╙й╨╗╥п ╨╢╥п╨╖╥п╨▒╥п╨╖╨┤╥п.╨Ц╤Л╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╖╨┤╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╤З╨░╨║╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╛╨╣╨╜╤Г╨▒╤Г╨╖╨│╨░╙и╤В╨║╙й╤А╙й╨╗╥п ╤Н╨║╙й╙й╨╗╙й╨┐ ╤В╥п╨╜╥п╨▒╥п╨╖╨┤╥п.╨Р╨╣╨╗╤Г╤Г ╤В╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╨╢╨╡╤В╨╡╨╗╨╡╨┐ ╤Б╥п╨╣╥п╥п╨▒╥п╨╖╨┤╥п,╙и╤А╥п╨║╨╖╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╤З╨░╤З╨░╨╗╤Л ╨║╥п╨╗╨║╥п╨▒╥п╨╖╨┤╥п.╨Ц╤Л╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╖╨┤╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤В╨╡╤А╨╡╨╗╨╕ ╤З╨░╤З╤Л╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╨╜,╨С╤Г╨╗╨░╨║╤В╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╤Б╥п╨╣╨┤╥п╤А╥п╨┐ ╨╢╥п╨╖╥п╨▒╥п╨╖╨┤╥п."},{"question":"Apakah tsunami?","answer":"Tsunami merupakan satu siri ombak yang berlaku selepas gempa bumi , tanah runtuh(di dasar laut), aktiviti gunung berapi, letupan, atau hentaman meteor yang berlaku di dalam atau berhampiran laut."},{"question":"р╢╢р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ър╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Ср╢йр╖К р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢Ер╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢Ър╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖П р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п?","answer":"р╢╢р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ър╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Ср╢йр╖К р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢Ер╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢Ър╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖П, р╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢Ьр╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ьр╢▒р╖К р╢╕р╖Др╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╢║."},{"question":"Desmond Elliot","answer":"Desmond Elliot ni wс╗Н╠Бn b├н n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б Kс║╣rin oс╣г├╣ Kej├м с╗Нd├║n 1974. Jс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├й or├н-├мt├аg├й, adar├н er├й ├аti ol├│с╣г├иl├║ с╗Нmс╗Н or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а. ├У ti k├│pa n├нn├║ er├й ├аti ├аwс╗Нn er├й ├аt├мgb├а-d├йgb├а on├нpele or├н с║╣╠Аtс╗Н am├│h├╣n-m├бw├▓r├бn t├н ├│ ti j├║ igba lс╗Н n├н or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и baba rс║╣╠А ati n├н ├▓k├и ├▓kun. ├У ti gba am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ f├║n am├║gb├бlс║╣╠Бgbс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б с║╣╠Аd├б ├мt├аn t├н ├│ pereged├й j├╣lс╗Н n├нbi ayс║╣yс║╣ ti Africa Magic Viewers Choice Awards с║╣lс║╣╠Бkej├м ir├║ rс║╣╠А, ├│ s├м t├║n ti gba am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ f├║n am├║gb├бlс║╣╠Бgbс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б с║╣╠Аd├б ├мt├аn t├н ├│ pereged├й j├╣lс╗Н n├нbi ayс║╣yс║╣ ti Africa Movie Academy Awards с║╣lс║╣╠Бkс║╣w├а├б ir├║ rс║╣╠А. Wс╗Н╠Бn t├║n y├аn ├бn k├н ├│ lс╗Н с╣гoj├║ ├аwс╗Нn ├иn├мy├аn agb├иgb├и ├мjс╗Нba ├мb├нlс║╣╠А S├║r├╣l├йr├и n├н Il├й ├мgb├мmс╗Н╠А Aс╣г├▓fin ti ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├│ n├нn├║ ├мd├мb├▓ t├н ├│ w├бy├й n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kс╗Нk├аnl├б oс╣г├╣ Kс║╣rin с╗Нd├║n 2015.Wс╗Н╠Бn b├н Desmond n├н agb├иgb├и Ol├│w├│gbow├│ n├н ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├│, b├аb├б rс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б с╗Нmс╗Н Yor├╣b├б t├н wс╗Н╠Бn b├н n├н agb├иgb├и Lagos Island, n├н ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├│ t├н ├мy├б rс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б с╗Нmс╗Н ├мl├║ Illah n├н ├мjс╗Нba ├мb├нlс║╣╠А Oshimili North, n├н ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А Delta; ├У kс║╣╠Бkс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Б j├бde n├н il├й-с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б al├бkс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Бbс║╣╠Аrс║╣╠А ol├│gun oj├║ ├▓furuf├║ t├н ├│ s├м pada lс╗Н s├н il├й-с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б St John's College, n├н ├мl├║ Jos. ├У kс║╣╠Бkс╗Н╠А├│ gboy├и n├нn├║ ├мmс╗Н╠А ok├▓w├▓ n├н il├йс║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б g├нga ti Yunif├бsit├м ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├│ t├н ├│ s├м j├бde n├н с╗Нd├║n 2003.K├нk├│pa n├нn├║ er├й on├нс╣гс║╣╠Б or├н-├мt├аg├й Demond ni ├│ jс║╣╠Б w├нp├й с╗Н╠Аrс║╣╠Б rс║╣╠А.kan ni ├│ с╣гok├╣nf├а rс║╣╠А. ├У bс║╣╠Аrс║╣╠А s├н ┼Д k├│pa n├нn├║ awс╗Нn er├й on├нpele ├аt├мgb├а-d├йgb├а ti Everyday People, One Too Much ati Saints and Sinners. ├У jс║╣╠Б с╗Н╠Аkan l├бra awс╗Нn l├а├аm├м-laaka ├▓с╣г├иr├й n├н il├й-iс╣гс║╣╠Б Nollywood, n├нgb├а t├н ├│ ti k├│pa n├нn├║ awс╗Нn er├й t├н ├│ ti t├│ с╗Нgс╗Н╠Бr├╣n ├║n t├н a ti r├н Men Who Cheat, Yahoo Millionaire ├аti Atlanta. N├н с╗Нd├║n 2006, wс╗Н╠Бn y├аn ├бn f├║n ├Тс╣г├иr├йk├╣nrin am├║gb├бlс║╣╠Бgbс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б t├│ pereged├й j├╣lс╗Н n├нn├║ am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ African Movie Academy Award n├нn├║ er├й \\"Behind closed doors\\". N├н с╗Нd├║n 2018, Desmond pawс╗Н╠Бpс╗Н╠А gb├й er├й t├н akс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А ┼Д jс║╣╠Б Reloaded. Er├й t├н wс╗Н╠Бn y├аn f├║n am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ mс║╣╠Бta с╗Н╠Аtс╗Н╠Аtс╗Н╠А b├нi: African Movie Academy Awards n├н с╗Нd├║n 2009. Wс╗Н╠Бn y├аn ├бn f├║n am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ ├Тс╣г├иr├йk├╣nrin t├н ├│ pereged├й j├╣lс╗Н n├н с╗Нd├║n 2009 ├аti с╗Нd├║n 2010. N├н с╗Нd├║n 2014, wс╗Н╠Бn yan Elliot f├║n ├аm├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ \\"African Movie Academy Award\\" f├║n am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ ├Тс╣г├иr├йk├╣nrin am├║gb├бlс║╣╠Бgbс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б t├│ pereged├й j├╣lс╗Н n├нn├║ er├й \\"Finding Mercy\\"Elliot k├йde ├мfс║╣╠Б rс║╣╠А l├бti gb├йgb├б ├мb├▓ s├н Il├й ├мgb├мmс╗Н╠А aс╣г├▓fin ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├│ n├н ├аs├мk├▓ с╗Нd├║n 2014 l├бbс║╣╠Б с║╣gbс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иl├║ All Progressives Congress. ├У d├нje s├н ip├▓ y├н, ├│ s├м wс╗Нl├й l├бti с╣гoj├║ agb├иgb├и ├мjс╗Нba ├мb├нlс║╣╠А S├╣├║r├╣l├йr├и n├нn├║ ├мd├мb├▓ t├н ├│ w├бy├й n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kс╗Нkanl├б oс╣г├╣ Kerin с╗Нd├║n 2015. N├н in├║ oс╣г├╣ Kс║╣w├а├б с╗Нd├║n 2020 l├бs├мk├▓ r├▓gb├▓d├мy├аn End SARS, Wс╗Н╠Бn sс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А s├н Demond l├бt├аr├н w├нp├й ├│ fс╗Нwс╗Н╠Б s├н k├н wс╗Н╠Бn fagi l├й ├аwс╗Нn ├мr├▓y├мn or├н ├мkan├м ├мb├бnidс╗Н╠Бrс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Б gbogbo tab├н k├н wс╗Н╠Бna с╣гe ├аgb├йyс║╣╠Аwс╗Н╠А gbogbo ├мr├▓y├мn t├н y├│├▓ gba ibс║╣╠А kс╗Нj├б. N├нn├║ ├аwс╗Нn fс╗Н╠Бnr├бn f├нd├н├▓ t├н ├│ ┼Д kс╗Нj├б n├нgboro l├│r├н ├мkan├м ay├йluj├бra, wс╗Н╠Бn r├н Desmond n├нn├║ fс╗Н╠Бr├бn y├н w├нp├й ├│ ┼Д sс╗Нrс╗Н╠А k├нkan k├нkan tako ├мr├▓y├мn or├н ├мkan├м ay├йluj├бra gbogbo. B├н k├▓ b├б r├н bс║╣╠Бс║╣╠А, or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а y├│├▓ b├аjс║╣╠Б.Desmond Elliot ├аti ├мy├аw├│ rс║╣╠А ti b├нmс╗Н mс║╣╠Бrin. si tun je agbс║╣nu sс╗Н f├║n il├й-iс╣гс║╣╠Б ├м╠Аb├бnisс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А Globacom. Desmond ├аti ├мyaw├│ rс║╣╠А с╣гe ayс║╣yс║╣ с╗Нd├║n kс║╣с║╣╠Аd├│g├║n l├│r├н ├мgb├йy├аw├│ wс╗Нn n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б Kс║╣r├мnd├нnlс╗Н╠Бgbс╗Н╠Аn oс╣г├╣ Kej├мl├б с╗Нd├║n 2018.Falling (2015)Black Val (2015)The Department (2015)[25]When Love Happens (2014)30 Days in Atlanta (2014)Okon Goes to SchoolKamara's Tree (2013)Kiss and Tell (2011)I'll Take My Chances (2011)Bursting Out (2010)Holding Hope (2010)Nollywood Hustlers (2010)Before the Light (2009)EdikanUyai (2008)Final Tussle (2008) (V)Guilty Pleasures (2008)Black Night in South America (2007)A Better Place (2007)Caught-Up (2007)Double Game (2007)Fine Things (2007)Ghetto Queen (2007)Secret Pain (2007)Men Who Cheat (2006)A Time to Love (2007) .... HankYahoo Millionaire (2007) .... JerryPut It on Me (2006)Asunder (2006)Behind the Plot (2006)Divided Attention (2006)Efficacy (2006)EkaetteExtreme Measure (2006) ... FestusFinal Point (2006)The Greatest Sacrifice (2006)King of the Town (2006)Love Wins (2006) .... AustinMarried to the Enemy (2006)My Little Secret (2006)My Sister My Love (2006) .... JarNaked Sin (2006)Romeo (2006)Strange Love (2006)Supremacy (2006)Too Late to Claim (2006)Traumatised (2006)Unbreakable Affair (2006)Up to Me (2006)Without Apology (2006)The Wolves (2006)Zoza (2006)A Night in the Philippines (2005)2 Face (2005)Behind Closed Doors (2005)The Bet (2005)Broadway (2005)Destiny's Challenge (2005)Flying Without Wings (2005)Fools in Love (2005)Games Women Play (2005)Girls in the Hood (2005)Hold Me Down (2005)It's Juliet or No One (2005)Just Me (2005)The King's Son (2005)Knowing You (2005)Men Do Cry (2005)My Precious Son (2005)My Sister My Child (2005)My Sister's Act (2005)Now & Forever (2005)Orange Groove (2005)The Price of Love: Life Is Beautiful (2005)Shackles of Death (2005)Wedding Gift (2005)Wheel of Change (2005)Images in the Mirror (2004) .... DejiAbove Love (2004)Atlanta (2004)Big Pretenders (2004)Cinderella (2004)Danger Signal (2004)Deep Loss (2004)Died to Save (2004)Discord (2004)For Real (2004)A Kiss from Rose (2004)Lake of Fire (2004) .... Brother EmmanuelLife in New York (2004)Magic Moment (2004)Melody of Life (2004)Missing Angel(2004)Passion of Mind (2004)Power of Trust (2004)Promise & Fail (2004)True Romance (2004)Great Change (2003)Magic Love (2003)My Faithful Friend (2003)Passion & Pain (2003)Tunnel of Love (2003)Fire Love (2002)Jesu Mushin (2002)FISHERS OF MEN"},{"question":"Tr├мnh b├аy thс║┐ mс║бnh vс╗Б tс╗▒ nhi├кn v├а hiс╗Зn trс║бng ph├бt triс╗Гn thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn cс╗зa v├╣ng Trung du v├а miс╗Бn n├║i Bс║пc Bс╗Щ.","answer":"V├╣ng Trung du v├а miс╗Бn n├║i Bс║пc Bс╗Щ c├│ nhiс╗Бu tiс╗Бm n─Гng ph├бt triс╗Гn thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn do c├│ ─Сс╗Лa h├мnh ─Сс╗Уi n├║i phong ph├║ v├а hс╗З thс╗Сng s├┤ng ng├▓i dс╗Уi d├аo. C├бc thс║┐ mс║бnh cс╗зa v├╣ng n├аy bao gс╗Уm:─Рс╗Лa h├мnh ─Сс╗Уi n├║i: V├╣ng Trung du v├а miс╗Бn n├║i Bс║пc Bс╗Щ c├│ ─Сс╗Лa h├мnh ─Сс╗Уi n├║i cao, ─Сс╗Уi n├║i trung b├мnh v├а ─Сс╗Уi n├║i thс║еp, tс║бo ─Сiс╗Бu kiс╗Зn thuс║нn lс╗гi cho viс╗Зc x├вy dс╗▒ng c├бc c├┤ng tr├мnh thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn.Hс╗З thс╗Сng s├┤ng ng├▓i phong ph├║: V├╣ng n├аy c├│ nhiс╗Бu con s├┤ng lс╗Ыn nh╞░ S├┤ng Hс╗Уng, S├┤ng ─Р├а, S├┤ng L├┤, S├┤ng Th╞░╞бng, S├┤ng Lс╗еc Nam, tс║бo ─Сiс╗Бu kiс╗Зn thuс║нn lс╗гi cho viс╗Зc khai th├бc n─Гng l╞░с╗гng thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn.Tiс╗Бm n─Гng ph├бt triс╗Гn lс╗Ыn: Vс╗Ыi hс╗З thс╗Сng s├┤ng ng├▓i dс╗Уi d├аo, v├╣ng Trung du v├а miс╗Бn n├║i Bс║пc Bс╗Щ c├│ tiс╗Бm n─Гng ph├бt triс╗Гn thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn lс╗Ыn, ─С├бp с╗йng nhu cс║зu n─Гng l╞░с╗гng cс╗зa khu vс╗▒c v├а cс║г n╞░с╗Ыc.Tuy nhi├кn, hiс╗Зn trс║бng ph├бt triс╗Гn thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn с╗Я v├╣ng n├аy c├▓n hс║бn chс║┐ do mс╗Щt sс╗С nguy├кn nh├вn:Ch╞░a khai th├бc hс║┐t tiс╗Бm n─Гng: Mс║╖c d├╣ c├│ nhiс╗Бu tiс╗Бm n─Гng, nh╞░ng hiс╗Зn tс║бi vс║лn ch╞░a khai th├бc hс║┐t ─С╞░с╗гc t├аi nguy├кn n─Гng l╞░с╗гng thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn cс╗зa v├╣ng Trung du v├а miс╗Бn n├║i Bс║пc Bс╗Щ.C├бc c├┤ng tr├мnh thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn c┼й: Mс╗Щt sс╗С c├┤ng tr├мnh thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn ─С├г ─С╞░с╗гc x├вy dс╗▒ng tс╗л l├вu v├а ─С├г qua thс╗Эi kс╗│ khai th├бc hiс╗Зu quс║г, cс║зn ─Сс║зu t╞░ ─Сс╗Г n├вng cс║еp v├а cс║гi thiс╗Зn hiс╗Зu suс║еt.T├бc ─Сс╗Щng m├┤i tr╞░с╗Эng: X├вy dс╗▒ng c├бc c├┤ng tr├мnh thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn c├│ thс╗Г g├вy t├бc ─Сс╗Щng ti├кu cс╗▒c ─Сс║┐n m├┤i tr╞░с╗Эng, nh╞░ thay ─Сс╗Хi d├▓ng chс║гy s├┤ng, с║гnh h╞░с╗Яng ─Сс║┐n sinh th├бi v├а ─Сс╗Эi sс╗Сng cс╗зa ng╞░с╗Эi d├вn ─Сс╗Лa ph╞░╞бng.Tс╗Хng quan, v├╣ng Trung du v├а miс╗Бn n├║i Bс║пc Bс╗Щ c├│ tiс╗Бm n─Гng ph├бt triс╗Гn thuс╗╖ ─Сiс╗Зn lс╗Ыn nh╞░ng cс║зn ─Сс║зu t╞░ v├а quс║гn l├╜ hс╗гp l├╜ ─Сс╗Г khai th├бc hiс╗Зu quс║г v├а bс║гo vс╗З m├┤i tr╞░с╗Эng."},{"question":"Inona avy no teny nahazoana ny hoe fari-bolana?","answer":"ny teny nahazoana ny teny hoe fari-bolana dia faritra sy volana"},{"question":"Escreva uma continua├з├гo para este par├бgrafo - Em 2016, ap├│s a demiss├гo de Rafa Ben├нtez, o Real Madrid anunciou Zidane como novo treinador. Assim come├зaria uma das eras mais vitoriosas do Real Madrid, com grandes t├нtulos sendo conquistados. Com um belo trabalho dentro de campo, conseguiu conduzir a equipe at├й a final da Liga dos Campe├╡es de 2015-16 onde enfrentou o arquirrival Atl├йtico de Madrid, na qual o Real Madrid empatou no tempo regulamentar e venceu nos p├кnaltis, assim conquistando a Und├йcima no San Siro em Mil├гo na It├бlia. Logo ap├│s conquistou a","answer":"Supercopa da Uefa de 2016, na qual derrotou o Sevilla e se sagrou campe├гo. Conquistou a Copa do Mundo de Clubes da FIFA de 2016 no qual enfrentou o Kashima Anlters na final e sagrou-se campe├гo ao vencer por 4x2. Com a gloriosa campanha na La Liga de 2016-17 foi campe├гo e conquistou assim o 33┬░ t├нtulo do Campeonato Espanhol. Tamb├йm na mesma temporada , conquistou a Liga dos Campe├╡es de 2016-17 com uma bela campanha eliminando Bayern Munchen e Atl├йtico de Madrid nas fases eliminat├│rias e derrotando a Juventus na final por 4x1 e assim conquistando a Duod├йcima no Millenium Stadium em Cardiff no Pa├нs de Gales. Iniciando a temporada de 2017/18, conquistou a Supercopa da UEFA de 2017 derrotando o Manchester United por 2x1 e logo em seguida conquistou a Supercopa da Espanha de 2017 , derrotando o rival Barcelona por 5x1 na soma do placar agregado. Sagrou-se campe├гo da Copa do Mundo de Clubes da FIFA de 2017 ap├│s derrotar o Gr├кmio por 1x0. Conquistou tamb├йm a Liga dos Campe├╡es de 2017-18, chegando assim ao seu d├йcimo terceiro t├нtulo, ap├│s bater o Liverpool por 3x1 no est├бdio Ol├нmpico em Kiev na Ucr├вnia. Ap├│s a conquista, Zidane encerra seu ciclo como treinador do Real com uma passagem bastante vitoriosa, ganhando 11 t├нtulos como treinador da equipe."},{"question":"р╢пр╖Гр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢▒ р╢Йр╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖Рр╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ър╢п?","answer":" р╢пр╖Гр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щр╢▒р╖К  10 р╢Йр╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢╕ р╖Др╖Рр╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ъ"},{"question":"Completa la seguente frase:\\"Il Commonwealth delle nazioni o Commonwealth (acronimo CN) ├и ...\\"","answer":"\\"... un'organizzazione intergovernativa di 56 Stati indipendenti, quasi tutti (eccetto Mozambico, Ruanda, Gabon e Togo) accomunati dalla passata appartenenza all'Impero britannico, del quale esso rappresenta una sorta di sviluppo su base volontaria. La popolazione complessiva degli Stati che vi aderiscono ├и di oltre due miliardi di persone. La parola Commonwealth deriva dall'unione di common (comune) e wealth (benessere), cio├и benessere comune.\\""},{"question":"THUNDERSTORMChapter 1","answer":"THUNDERSTORMChapter 1My back aches. I don't know what's wrong with me, auntie. Chika complained to her madam.Since when did it start? When did you start feeling it? Mrs. Ikemike askedSince yesterday, Auntie, it really hurts. She cried.Chika,your nose is getting bigger, and you're gaining weight recently despite all the stress you go through. Are you pregnant? She asked again, dropping the booklet on the table.Errrm, no, ma, I'm not pregnant; the pain has ceased, auntie; I'll be fine. Chika replied, turning to leave.Chika!!! You're pregnant, Chika... Mrs. Ikemike shouted, dragging her closer.No, auntie, I'm not pregnant. It's just a backache, she said, trying to free herself.Mrs. Ikemike stared into her eyes, smiled to herself, released her from the grip, and sat on the bed.Can you tell me who's responsible for this pregnancy? The symptoms are all over you, Chika. Can't you see your breasts? Now tell me who the hell is responsible... Mrs. Ikemike asked calmly.Auntie, nobody is responsible. I'm not pregnant; I'm still a virgin auntie. You can check if you want to. Chika defendedYou're just confused. Now take this money,rush to the chemist across the road, and get me a test strip immediately. Said Mrs. Ikemike, throwing money at her.Chika zoomed off. She cried her eyes out and regretted telling her madam about her backache.Hello dear.. Mr. Ikemike said as he picked up his wife's call.Chika, Diamond, is expecting a child. Mrs. Ikemike shouted from the phone.Babe, calm down. I'll call you later. Mr. Ikemike replied and dropped the call.Chika came back, and her madam ran a test for her, and the result came out positive.For the last time, who's responsible? How come, Chika? Start talking right now. She shouted, hitting her hard on the face.Auntie, please, I'll talk. Chika replied, crying.Who's responsible? She questioned me again.Your husband, auntie..."},{"question":"Allah Ya ambaci garin Madina da sunanta na farko kafin a canza ta koma Madina, Yaya sunan nata na farkon","answer":"(a) Magriba (b) Da'ifa (c) Yasriba"},{"question":"р╖Жр╖Кр╢╜р╖Эр╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢▒р╢║р╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢Вр╢Ьр╖Ър╢╜р╖К р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п?","answer":"р╖Жр╖Кр╢╜р╖Ьр╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢▒р╢║р╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢Вр╢Ьр╖Ър╢╜р╖К р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢в р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖Тр╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╢╗р╢лр╖Ар╖Пр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ыр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢╜р╖Ър╢Ыр╢▒р╢ер╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢▒р╖Цр╢нр╢▒ р╖Др╖Щр╢п р╖Гр╖Ър╖Ар╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Тр╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Пр╢нр╖Шр╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖П р╢п р╖Ар╖Тр╢║. р╢Зр╢║ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Кр╢░р╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢┤р╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Цр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢╕р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢║р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░р╢║р╖Ър╢пр╖У р╢Зр╢║ р╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Пр╢╜ р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Ц р╖Гр╖Ьр╢╜р╖Кр╢пр╖Пр╢пр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╖Гр╢нр╖Кр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Ар╖Тр╢░р╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╢Ър╖Е р╖Др╖Щр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ер╢╕р╢▒р╖Пр╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢Ър╖Ф р╖Гр╖Д р╢┤р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢лр╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢Ър╖Ф р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Гр╖Ър╖Ар╢║ р╢Ър╢╗р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢пр╖Ур╢║."},{"question":"Ndoa ni nini?","answer":"Ndoa ni muunganiko wa watu wawili wenye jinsia mbili tofauti, yaani mwanamke na mwanamme waliopendana na kukubali kwa hiari yao kuishi pamoja kama mke na mume. Ndoa hufungwa kanisani na msikitini kama watu ni wa dini au mahakamani kama watu hao hawana dini. Ndoa pia japo ilianzishwa na Mungu, inalindwa na kanuni za kidini na sheria za nchi."},{"question":"Napol├йon est-il en ad├йquation avec la libert├й individuelle ?","answer":"Non, Napol├йon s'appuie sur une police toute-puissante qui proc├иde ├а des arrestations arbitraires et ne respecte pas la libert├й individuelle."},{"question":"хПехнР1: хЬиWerderaner WachtelbergцЬЙф╕Аф╕кхдзщЩЖц░ФхАЩ, ф╗ОхМЧцЦ╣хТМше┐щГихПЧхИ░хдзше┐ц┤Лц░ФхАЩчЪДх╜▒хУН, ф╕ЬцЦ╣ц░ФхАЩц╕йхТМ. хПехнР2: щЯжх╛╖цЛЙч║│чУжш╡лчЙ╣х░Фф╝пца╝чЪДц░ФхАЩц╕йхТМ, ц░ФхАЩф╗ехдзше┐ц┤Лц░ФхАЩф╕║чЙ╣х╛Б, ф╗ОхМЧщГихТМше┐щГи, щЧощвШ:чммф╕АхПехТМчммф║МхПешбиш╛╛чЫ╕хРМчЪДцДПф╣ЙхРЧ? чЫ╕хРМш┐ШцШпф╕НхРМ?","answer":"ф╕НхРМ"},{"question":"A┼Яa─Я─▒daki ifadeyi tamamlay─▒n: Timur,","answer":"1402 Ankara Muharebesi'nden d├╢nerken bu b├╢lgeye de u─Яram─▒┼Я. Timur'un askerlerinin buralar─▒ da talan ettikleri, askerlerin bask─▒lar─▒ndan ka├зanlar─▒n \\"G├╝m├╝┼Я oluk\\" mevkine sakland─▒klar─▒ ve ilk defa burada yerle┼Яtikleri rivayet edilmektedir. ├Зevre k├╢ylerin or┬нtas─▒nda merkezi bir yerde yollar─▒n birle┼Яti─Яi toplanma yeri olarak kuytu yer anlam─▒nda \\"Peyke\\" ad─▒n─▒ vermi┼Яler. Bu isim zamanla \\"Peyik\\" olarak s├╢ylene gelmi┼Я."},{"question":"Inona no voalohan-karena amin'ny Malagasy ?","answer":"Amin'ny Malagasy dia ny zanaka no voalohan-karena. "},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: роХрпАро┤рпНроХрогрпНроЯ роиро╛роЯрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЪроирпНродрпИ рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░роорпН роироЯрпИ рокрпЖро▒рпБроорпН роиро╛роЯрпБ роОродрпБ? \\t1. роЪрпАройро╛2. роЪро┐роЩрпНроХрокрпНрокрпВро░рпН3. роЪрпБро╡рпАроЯройрпН4. рокро┐ро░ро╛ройрпНро╕рпН","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: 2. роЪро┐роЩрпНроХрокрпНрокрпВро░рпН.ро╡ро┐ро│роХрпНроХроорпН : роЪроирпНродрпИрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░роорпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роХроЯрпНроЯро▒рпНро▒ роЪроирпНродрпИрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░роорпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ роТро░рпБ рокрпКро░рпБро│ро┐ропро▓рпН роорпБро▒рпИ роЖроХрпБроорпН. роЗродро┐ро▓рпН рокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроХро│ро┐ройродрпБроорпН, роЪрпЗро╡рпИроХро│ро┐ройродрпБроорпН роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐ропрпБроорпН, ро╡ро┐роиро┐ропрпЛроХроорпБроорпН роХроЯрпНроЯро▒рпНро▒ ро╡ро┐ро▓рпИ роорпБро▒рпИроорпИропро┐ройро╛ро▓рпН роирпЖро▒ро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роХроЯрпНроЯро▒рпНро▒ роЪроирпНродрпИрокрпН рокрпКро▒ро┐роорпБро▒рпИропро┐ройро╛ро▓рпН роироЯрпИрокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роТро░рпБ роЪроирпНродрпИрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░ роЕроорпИрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рогро┐роХродрпНродрпБро▒рпИропрпБроорпН, роирпБроХро░рпНро╡рпЛро░рпБроорпН роОродрпИ ро╡ро╛роЩрпНроХрпБро╡родрпБ роОродрпИ роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роорпБроЯро┐ро╡рпБроХро│рпИродрпН родро╛роЩрпНроХро│ро╛роХро╡рпЗ роОроЯрпБроХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒ройро░рпН. роЗроорпНроорпБро▒рпИропро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро│роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роТродрпБроХрпНроХроорпН роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИропрпАроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЗройрпНро▒ро┐ роироЯрпИрокрпЖро▒рпБроорпН. роХрпЛроЯрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЕроЯро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЗроорпН роорпБро▒рпИропро┐ройрпН роХрпАро┤рпН, роОродройрпИ роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ, роОро╡рпНро╡ро│ро╡рпБ роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ, роОройрпНрой ро╡ро┐ро▓рпИ ро╡ро┐ро▒рпНрокродрпБ, родрпКро│ро┐ро▓ро╛ро│ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роОро╡рпНро╡ро│ро╡рпБ роКродро┐ропроорпН ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХрпБро╡родрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роорпБроЯро┐ро╡рпБроХро│рпИ роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐ропро╛ро│ро░рпЗ роОроЯрпБрокрпНрокро╛ро░рпН, роЕро░роЪрпБ роЕро▓рпНро▓. роЪроирпНродрпИрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗроорпН роорпБроЯро┐ро╡рпБроХро│рпН, рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐, родрпЗро╡рпИропрпБроорпН ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХро▓рпБроорпН, рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН роЙрогрпНроЯро╛роХрпБроорпН роЕро┤рпБродрпНродроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро╡ро╛роХрпНроХро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ роЙроЯрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЗродрпБ роОройрпНрой рокрпКро░рпБро│рпИ роОро╡рпНро╡ро│ро╡рпБ роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпИ роЕро░роЪрпЗ родрпАро░рпНрооро╛ройро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯрооро┐роЯрпНроЯ рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░ роорпБро▒рпИроХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокрпБро▒роорпНрокро╛ройродрпБ. родро┐роЯрпНроЯрооро┐роЯрпНроЯ рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░роорпНрокрпЛро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро░ро┐ро╡ро╛роХ роЗро▓рпНро▓ро╛ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпБроорпН, роорпБро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роХроЯрпНроЯро▒рпНро▒ роорпБро▒рпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЗро▓рпНро▓ро╛рооро▓рпН роУро░ро│ро╡рпБ роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН роХроЯрпНроЯрпБрокрпНрокро╛роЯрпБроХро│рпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родро╛ро▓рпН роХро▓рокрпНрокрпБрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░ роорпБро▒рпИропрпБроорпН, роЪроирпНродрпИрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБ ро╡рпЗро▒рпБрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роироЯрпИроорпБро▒рпИропро┐ро▓рпН роОроирпНрод роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЙрогрпНроорпИропро╛рой роЪроирпНродрпИрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│ро╛родро╛ро░роорпН роЗро░рпБрокрпНрокродро╛роХроХрпН роХрпВро▒роорпБроЯро┐ропро╛родрпБ."},{"question":"р░Ер░ор▒Ар░мр░╛ р░╕р░Вр░Хр▒Лр░Ъ р░░р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░др░┐р░Хр░▓ р░жр▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р░╛ р░жр▒Нр░░р░╡р░╛р░нр░┐р░╕р░░р░г р░Хр▒Нр░░р░ор░др░ир▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░кр▒Бр░др░╛р░пр░┐. р░ор░░р▒Л р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░г р░Зр░╡р▒Нр░╡р░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░кр░╛р░░р░╛р░ор▒Ар░╖р░┐р░пр░В"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:родрогрпНрогрпАро░рпН роОро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпБ роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХро┐ро▒родрпБ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ :родрогрпНрогрпАро░рпН ро╣рпИроЯрпНро░роЬройрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЖроХрпНроЪро┐роЬройрпН роОройрпНро▒ роЗро░рогрпНроЯрпБ роЕроЯро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпИ роорпВро▓роХрпНроХрпВро▒рпБроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХро┐ро▒родрпБ. родрогрпНрогрпАро░рпН роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН рокро▓рпНро╡рпЗро▒рпБ ро╡роЯро┐ро╡роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роХроЯро▓рпН, роЖро▒рпБроХро│рпН, роПро░ро┐роХро│рпН, рокройро┐роХрпНроХроЯрпНроЯро┐роХро│рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡рпИ родрогрпНрогрпАро░ро┐ройрпН рокро▓рпНро╡рпЗро▒рпБ ро╡роЯро┐ро╡роЩрпНроХро│рпН."},{"question":"роЪрпБ. родро┐ропрпЛроЯро░рпН рокро╛ро╕рпНроХро░ройрпН роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒ро┐ройрпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"родрпЗро╡рпИроХрпНроХрпБ роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИропрпИрокрпН рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро╛рооро▓рпН рокрпЗро░ро╛роЪрпИроХрпНроХрпБ роЗропро▒рпНроХрпИропрпИроЪрпН роЪрпБро░рогрпНроЯ роЖро░роорпНрокро┐родрпНрод рокро┐ро▒роХрпБродро╛ройрпН, рооройро┐родройрпН роЙрогро╡рпИроХрпН роХрпКроЮрпНроЪрооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, рооро╛родрпНродро┐ро░рпИроХро│рпИ роЕродро┐роХрооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХрпКро│рпНро│ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯро┐ропродро╛роХро┐ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпБ."},{"question":"┌й┘И╪▒╪п█Х┌й╪з┘Ж ┘Д█Х ╪м█Х┌Ш┘Ж█М ┘Ж█Х┘И╪▒█Ж╪▓╪п╪з ┌Ж█М ╪п█Х┌й█Х┘Ж ┘Д█Х ┌Ж█М╪з┌й╪з┘Ж╪Я ","answer":"┘Д█Х ╪│█Х╪▒ ┌Ж█М╪з┌й╪з┘Ж╪п╪з ╪ж╪з┌п╪з╪▒ ╪п█Х┌й█Х┘Ж█Х┘И█Х "},{"question":"цЬмуБоцЬАхИЭуБлцЫ╕уБПцЦЗчлауВТх║ПцЦЗуБиуБДуБЖуБоуБлхп╛уБЧуАБцЬАх╛МуБлцЫ╕уБПцЦЗчлауВТф╜ХцЦЗуБиуБДуБЖуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"ш╖ЛцЦЗя╝ИуБ░уБдуБ╢уВУя╝Й тА╗ш╖Ля╝ИуБ░уБдя╝ЙуБоуБ┐уБзя╝пя╝луБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"Dс╗▒a tr├кn ti├кu ─Сс╗Б sau, h├гy viс║┐t mс╗Щt b├аi b├бo n├│i vс╗Б chс╗з ─Сс╗Б n├аy: Nhan sс║пc Hoa hс║нu Ho├аn v┼й Th├бi Lan 2022","answer":"Anna Sueangam-iam v╞░с╗гt 29 th├н sinh ─С─Гng quang trong chung kс║┐t tс║бi True Icon Hall с╗Я Bangkok tс╗Сi 30/7. C├┤ nhс║нn v╞░╞бng miс╗Зn ─С╞░с╗гc thiс║┐t kс║┐ theo chс╗з ─Сс╗Б \\"Sс╗йc mс║бnh phс╗еc hс╗Уi\\" cс╗зa th╞░╞бng hiс╗Зu trang sс╗йc Mouawad, mс╗Щt triс╗Зu baht (642 triс╗Зu ─Сс╗Уng), c─Гn hс╗Щ v├а xe h╞бi. ├Б hс║нu 1 thuс╗Щc vс╗Б Nicolene Limsnukan, ├б hс║нu 2 l├а Kanyalak Nookaew. Anna Sueangam-iam v╞░с╗гt 29 th├н sinh ─С─Гng quang trong chung kс║┐t tс║бi True Icon Hall с╗Я Bangkok tс╗Сi 30/7. C├┤ nhс║нn v╞░╞бng miс╗Зn ─С╞░с╗гc thiс║┐t kс║┐ theo chс╗з ─Сс╗Б \\"Sс╗йc mс║бnh phс╗еc hс╗Уi\\" cс╗зa th╞░╞бng hiс╗Зu trang sс╗йc Mouawad, mс╗Щt triс╗Зu baht (642 triс╗Зu ─Сс╗Уng), c─Гn hс╗Щ v├а xe h╞бi. ├Б hс║нu 1 thuс╗Щc vс╗Б Nicolene Limsnukan, ├б hс║нu 2 l├а Kanyalak Nookaew. T├вn hoa hс║нu sinh n─Гm 1998 с╗Я Bangkok, tс╗Сt nghiс╗Зp ng├аnh Nghс╗З thuс║нt v├а Khoa hс╗Нc, ─Рс║бi hс╗Нc Kasetsart. Trong khu├┤n khс╗Х cuс╗Щc thi, c├┤ cho biс║┐t trс║гi qua cuс╗Щc sс╗Сng kh├│ kh─Гn, tuс╗Хi th╞б gс║пn liс╗Бn b├гi r├бc v├м cс║г bс╗С v├а mс║╣ ─Сс╗Бu l├аm c├┤ng viс╗Зc thu gom r├бc thс║гi с╗Я Bangkok. ─Рс╗У ch╞бi cс╗зa c├┤ ─Сс╗Бu ─С╞░с╗гc bс╗С mс║╣ nhс║╖t vс╗Б v├а sс╗нa lс║бi. \\"T├┤i kh├┤ng thс╗Г thay ─Сс╗Хi sс╗С phс║нn khi sinh ra nh╞░ng t├┤i nс╗Ч lс╗▒c ─Сс╗Г thay ─Сс╗Хi cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Эi m├мnh sau n├аy\\", c├┤ n├│i. T├вn hoa hс║нu sinh n─Гm 1998 с╗Я Bangkok, tс╗Сt nghiс╗Зp ng├аnh Nghс╗З thuс║нt v├а Khoa hс╗Нc, ─Рс║бi hс╗Нc Kasetsart. Trong khu├┤n khс╗Х cuс╗Щc thi, c├┤ cho biс║┐t trс║гi qua cuс╗Щc sс╗Сng kh├│ kh─Гn, tuс╗Хi th╞б gс║пn liс╗Бn b├гi r├бc v├м cс║г bс╗С v├а mс║╣ ─Сс╗Бu l├аm c├┤ng viс╗Зc thu gom r├бc thс║гi с╗Я Bangkok. ─Рс╗У ch╞бi cс╗зa c├┤ ─Сс╗Бu ─С╞░с╗гc bс╗С mс║╣ nhс║╖t vс╗Б v├а sс╗нa lс║бi. \\"T├┤i kh├┤ng thс╗Г thay ─Сс╗Хi sс╗С phс║нn khi sinh ra nh╞░ng t├┤i nс╗Ч lс╗▒c ─Сс╗Г thay ─Сс╗Хi cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Эi m├мnh sau n├аy\\", c├┤ n├│i. Ng╞░с╗Эi ─Сс║╣p ─С╞░с╗гc ─С├бnh gi├б cao с╗Я khс║г n─Гng h├╣ng biс╗Зn, thuyс║┐t tr├мnh. Trong phс║зn thi с╗йng xс╗н, khi ─С╞░с╗гc hс╗Пi: \\"Tr╞░с╗Ыc t├мnh h├мnh thс║┐ giс╗Ыi hiс╗Зn nay bс╗Л t├бc ─Сс╗Щng bс╗Яi chiс║┐n tranh, dс╗Лch bс╗Зnh, suy tho├бi kinh tс║┐ to├аn cс║зu, nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi ─Сang r╞бi v├аo trс║бng th├бi tuyс╗Зt vс╗Нng. Nс║┐u ─С╞░с╗гc trao danh hiс╗Зu hoa hс║нu, bс║бn sс║╜ gс╗нi th├┤ng ─Сiс╗Зp g├м ─Сс║┐n mс╗Нi ng╞░с╗Эi?\\", c├┤ trс║г lс╗Эi: \\"T├┤i muс╗Сn n├│i rс║▒ng bс║бn kh├┤ng phс║гi ng╞░с╗Эi duy nhс║еt tс╗лng tuyс╗Зt vс╗Нng. T├┤i c┼йng l├а mс╗Щt trong sс╗С ─С├│. Nh╞░ng ch├║ng ta phс║гi hс╗Нc c├бch th├нch nghi, c├│ thс╗Г vс║еp ng├г nh╞░ng rс╗Уi sс║╜ ─Сс╗йng dс║нy. Bс║еt kс╗Г trong t├мnh huс╗Сng n├аo, h├гy tin v├аo bс║гn th├вn. T├┤i ─С├г l├аm ─С╞░с╗гc v├а c├бc bс║бn c┼йng vс║нy\\". Ng╞░с╗Эi ─Сс║╣p ─С╞░с╗гc ─С├бnh gi├б cao с╗Я khс║г n─Гng h├╣ng biс╗Зn, thuyс║┐t tr├мnh. Trong phс║зn thi с╗йng xс╗н, khi ─С╞░с╗гc hс╗Пi: \\"Tr╞░с╗Ыc t├мnh h├мnh thс║┐ giс╗Ыi hiс╗Зn nay bс╗Л t├бc ─Сс╗Щng bс╗Яi chiс║┐n tranh, dс╗Лch bс╗Зnh, suy tho├бi kinh tс║┐ to├аn cс║зu, nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi ─Сang r╞бi v├аo trс║бng th├бi tuyс╗Зt vс╗Нng. Nс║┐u ─С╞░с╗гc trao danh hiс╗Зu hoa hс║нu, bс║бn sс║╜ gс╗нi th├┤ng ─Сiс╗Зp g├м ─Сс║┐n mс╗Нi ng╞░с╗Эi?\\", c├┤ trс║г lс╗Эi: \\"T├┤i muс╗Сn n├│i rс║▒ng bс║бn kh├┤ng phс║гi ng╞░с╗Эi duy nhс║еt tс╗лng tuyс╗Зt vс╗Нng. T├┤i c┼йng l├а mс╗Щt trong sс╗С ─С├│. Nh╞░ng ch├║ng ta phс║гi hс╗Нc c├бch th├нch nghi, c├│ thс╗Г vс║еp ng├г nh╞░ng rс╗Уi sс║╜ ─Сс╗йng dс║нy. Bс║еt kс╗Г trong t├мnh huс╗Сng n├аo, h├гy tin v├аo bс║гn th├вn. T├┤i ─С├г l├аm ─С╞░с╗гc v├а c├бc bс║бn c┼йng vс║нy\\". C├┤ cao 1,75 m, c├│ nhiс╗Бu n─Гm hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng trong l─йnh vс╗▒c ng╞░с╗Эi mс║лu. Ngo├аi ra, c├┤ l├а diс╗Еn vi├кn cс╗зa k├кnh Channel 8. C├┤ cao 1,75 m, c├│ nhiс╗Бu n─Гm hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng trong l─йnh vс╗▒c ng╞░с╗Эi mс║лu. Ngo├аi ra, c├┤ l├а diс╗Еn vi├кn cс╗зa k├кnh Channel 8. Anna Sueangam-iam c├│ nhiс╗Бu kinh nghiс╗Зm thi sс║пc ─Сс║╣p. C├┤ tс╗лng ─С─Гng quang Miss Mobile Thailand 2018, ├Б kh├┤i 2 Miss Thin Thai Ngarm 2020. Ng╞░с╗Эi ─Сс║╣p tс╗лng thi Hoa hс║нu Th├бi Lan 2020 nh╞░ng kh├┤ng ─Сoс║бt giс║гi cao. Anna Sueangam-iam c├│ nhiс╗Бu kinh nghiс╗Зm thi sс║пc ─Сс║╣p. C├┤ tс╗лng ─С─Гng quang Miss Mobile Thailand 2018, ├Б kh├┤i 2 Miss Thin Thai Ngarm 2020. Ng╞░с╗Эi ─Сс║╣p tс╗лng thi Hoa hс║нu Th├бi Lan 2020 nh╞░ng kh├┤ng ─Сoс║бt giс║гi cao."},{"question":"├Мp├нnl├и m├йl├▓├│ ni wс╗Н╠Бn ti ┼Д lo ├▓fin Sharia n├н or├нlс║╣╠А ├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а?","answer":"├Мp├нnl├и Me╠Бji╠Аla╠Б ni."},{"question":"рдЦрд╛рд▓реАрд▓ рд╢реНрд▓реЛрдХрд╛рдЪрд╛ рд╕реЛрдкреНрдпрд╛ рдорд░рд╛рдареАрдд рдЕрд░реНрде рд╕рд╛рдВрдЧрд╛ рд╢реНрд▓реЛрдХ:рддрдерд╛рдкрд┐ рдЕрд╡рдШрд╛ рджрд╛рд╕рдмреЛрдз ред рджрд╢рдХ рдлреЛрдбреВрди рдХреЗрд▓рд╛ рд╡рд┐рд╢рдж редрдЬреЗ рдЬреЗ рджрд╢рдХреАрдВрдЪрд╛ рдЕрдиреБрд╡рд╛рдж ред рддреЗ рддреЗ рджрд╢рдХреАрдВ рдмреЛрд▓рд┐рд▓рд╛ рее резрекреердЕрд░реНрде:","answer":"рддрдерд╛рдкрд┐ рдПрд╡рдвреЗ рдореНрд╣рдгрддрд╛ рдпреЗрдИрд▓ рдХреА, рд╣рд╛ рдЧреНрд░рдВрде рд╡реАрд╕ рджрд╢рдХрд╛рдВрдд рд╡рд┐рднрд╛рдЧрд▓рд╛ рдЧреЗрд▓рд╛ рдЖрд╣реЗ рд╡ рдкреНрд░рддреНрдпреЗрдХ рджрд╢рдХрд╛рдд рджрд╣рд╛ рд╕рдорд╛рд╕ рдЖрд╣реЗрдд. рдЬреНрдпрд╛ рджрд╢рдХрд╛рдд рдЬреЛ рд╡рд┐рд╖рдп рд╕рд╛рдВрдЧрд┐рддрд▓рд╛ рдЧреЗрд▓рд╛ рдЖрд╣реЗ, рддреНрдпрд╛рдЪреЗ рд╡рд┐рд╡рд░рдг рддреНрдпрд╛ рддреНрдпрд╛ рджрд╢рдХрд╛рдд рдХреЗрд▓реЗ рдЖрд╣реЗ. (резрек)"},{"question":"┬┐Cu├бntos presidentes ha tendio M├йxico?","answer":"Alrededor de 60 presidentes ha tenido M├йxico."},{"question":"шЙ▓уБоф╕ЙхОЯшЙ▓уБпш╡дуГ╗щЭТуГ╗щ╗ДуАВуБзуБпхЕЙуБоф╕ЙхОЯшЙ▓уБпш╡дуГ╗щЭТуБиуВВуБЖф╕АуБдуБпф╜Хя╝Я","answer":"ч╖СуБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"Waxaad  Sheegtaa kumuu ahaa ninkii uu Rasuulka (NNKH) uu Ku dagay markuu madiina Tagay?","answer":" Wuxu ahaa abuu ayuub Al-Ansaari (RC)"},{"question":"ркЕрк╣рлАркВ ркирк░рк╕рк┐ркВрк╣ ркорк╣рлЗркдрк╛ рк░ркЪрк┐ркд ркХрлГркдрк┐ ркПркХ \\"ркорлЛрк╣рлНркпрлБркВрк░рлЗ рк▓ркЯркХрлЗ\\" ркирк╛ рк╢рк░рлВркЖркдркирлА рккркВркХркдрк┐ркУ ркЖрккрлЗрк▓ ркЫрлЗ:\\"ркорлЛрк╣рлНркпрлБркВрк░рлЗ рк▓ркЯркХрлЗ, ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорки ркорлЛрк╣рлНркпрлБркВрк░рлЗ рк▓ркЯркХрлЗ.ркЧрк╛ркдрк░ ркнркЧ ркХрлАркзрк╛ркВ ркЧрк┐рк░ркзрк╛рк░рлА, ркЬрлЗркорк░рлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЭркЯркХрлЗ; ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорки.\\"ркЖ ркХрлГркдрк┐ркирлА ркЖркЧрк│ркирлА рккркВркХркдрк┐ркУ рк▓ркЦрлЛ.","answer":"ркорлЛрк╣рлНркпрлБркВрк░рлЗ рк▓ркЯркХрлЗ, ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорки ркорлЛрк╣рлНркпрлБркВрк░рлЗ рк▓ркЯркХрлЗ.ркЧрк╛ркдрк░ ркнркЧ ркХрлАркзрк╛ркВ ркЧрк┐рк░ркзрк╛рк░рлА, ркЬрлЗркорк░рлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЭркЯркХрлЗ; ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорки.рк╡рлЗркг рк╡ркЬрк╛ркбрлА рк╡рк╣рк╛рк▓рлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлЗ рк╡ркиркорк╛ркВ, рк░ркЧркдркгрлЗ ркХркЯркХрлЗ; ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорки.ркорки ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорлЛрк│рлАркбрлЗрк░рлЗ ркЕркЯркХрлНркпрлБркВ, рккрлЗрк▓рлЗ рккрлАркдрк╛ркВркмрк░ рккркЯркХрлЗ; ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорки.ркирк░рк╕ркИркирк╛ рк╕рлНрк╡рк╛ркорлАркирлА рк╕ркВркЧрлЗ рк░ркоркдрк╛ркВ, рк░рк╕ рк╡рк╛ркзрлНркпрлЛ ркЪркЯркХрлЗ; ркорк╛рк░рлВркВ ркорки."},{"question":"\\" ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ркирлА ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА \\" рк╡рк╛рк░рлНркдрк╛ рк▓ркЦрлЛ.","answer":"ркПркХ ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ ркиркЧрк░ркорк╛ркВ ркПркХ ркпрлБрк╡рк╛рки рк╣ркаркпрлЛркЧрлА ркЖрк╡рлНркпрлЛ.ркдрлЗркирлБркВ рк╢рк░рлАрк░ ркнрк╛рк░рлЗ ркХрк╕рк╛ркпрлЗрк▓рлБркВ рк╣ркдрлБркВ. ркдрлЗ ркЬрк╛ркдркЬрк╛ркдркирк╛ рк╢рк╛рк░рлАрк░рк┐ркХ ркХрк░ркдркм ркХрк░ркдрлЛ рк╣ркдрлЛ. ркдрлЗ рккрлНрк░рлЛркдрлНрк╕рк╛рк╣рки ркорлЗрк│рк╡рк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркЕркХркмрк░ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣ркирк╛ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлНркпрлЛ. ркдрлЗркгрлЗ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣ркирлЗ рккрлЛркдрк╛ркирлА ркЖрк╡ркбркд рк╡рк┐рк╢рлЗ ркЬркгрк╛рк╡рлНркпрлБркВ. ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ ркПркХ рк▓рлБркЪрлНркЪрк╛ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░рлАркП ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ, \\"ркПрк╡рк╛ рк╢рк╛рк░рлАрк░рк┐ркХ ркжрк╛рк╡рккрлЗркЪ ркдрлЛ ркХрлЛркИрккркг ркЕркнрлНркпрк╛рк╕рлБ ркХрк░рлА рк╢ркХрлЗ. ркЬрлЛ ркдрлБркВ ркХркВркИркХ ркирк╡рлБркВ ркХрк░рк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркЧркдрлЛ рк╣рлЛ ркдрлЛ ркЖ ркХркбркХркбркдрлА ркаркВркбрлАркорк╛ркВ ркЪрлЛрк╡рлАрк╕ ркХрк▓рк╛ркХ ркиркжрлАркорк╛ркВ ркЫрк╛ркдрлА рк╕рлБркзрлА рккрк╛ркгрлАркорк╛ркВ ркКркнрлЛ рк░рк╣рлА рк╢ркХрлЗ ркдрлЛ ркдрлБркВ рк╕рк╛ркЪрлЛ рк╣ркаркпрлЛркЧрлА!\\" ркдрлЗркирк╛ ркЬрк╡рк╛ркмркорк╛ркВ ркдрлЗ ркпрлБрк╡рк╛ркирлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ, \\"ркЬрлЛ ркЬрк╣рк╛ркВрккркирк╛рк╣, ркоркирлЗ ркоркВркЬрлВрк░рлА ркЖрккрлЗ ркдрлЛ рк╣рлБркВ ркиркжрлАркорк╛ркВ ркЪрлЛрк╡рлАрк╕ ркХрк▓рк╛ркХ ркКркнрлЛ рк░рк╣рлАрк╢. ркоркирлЗ ркХрлЛркИ ркдркХрк▓рлАркл ркирк╣рлАркВ рккркбрлЗ.\\"ркЕркХркмрк░ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣рлЗ рк░ркЬрк╛ ркЖрккрлА. ркдрлЗ ркпрлБрк╡рк╛рки ркПрк╡рлА ркХркбркХркбркдрлА ркаркВркбрлАркирк╛ ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕рлЛркорк╛ркВ, ркЫрк╛ркдрлА рк╕рлБркзрлА рккрк╛ркгрлАркорк╛ркВ ркЪрлЛрк╡рлАрк╕ ркХрк▓рк╛ркХ ркКркнрлЛ рк░рк╣рлНркпрлЛ. рк▓рлЛркХрлЛркП ркдркерк╛ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣рлЗ рккркг ркдрлЗ ркЬрлЛркпрлБркВ. ркЪрлЛрк╡рлАрк╕ ркХрк▓рк╛ркХ рккрлВрк░рк╛ ркеркпрк╛ ркПркЯрк▓рлЗ ркдрлЗ ркпрлБрк╡рк╛рки ркИркирк╛рко ркорк│рк╡рк╛ркирлА ркЖрк╢рк╛ркП рклрк░рлАркерлА ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлНркпрлЛ. ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ ркЕркХркмрк░ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣рлЗ рк╕рк╣ркЬ ркнрк╛рк╡рлЗ рккрлВркЫркпрлБркВ, \\"ркпрлБрк╡рк╛рки, ркдрлЗркВ ркЦрк░рлЗркЦрк░ ркХркорк╛рк▓ ркХрк░рлА ркЫрлЗ. ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ркирк╛ ркдрлЛ ркарлАркХ рккркг ркдрлЗркВ ркЖркЦрлА рк░рк╛ркд ркХрлЗрк╡рлА рк░рлАркдрлЗ рккрк╕рк╛рк░ ркХрк░рлА?'\\"\\"ркЕркирлНркиркжрк╛ркдрк╛. рк░рк╛ркдрлНрк░рлЗ рк╣рлБркВ ркиркжрлАркорк╛ркВ ркКркнрлЛ ркКркнрлЛ ркЖрккркирк╛ ркорк╣рлЗрк▓ркорк╛ркВ рк╕рк│ркЧркдрлЛ ркжрлАрк╡рлЛ ркЬрлЛркдрлЛ рк░рк╣рлНркпрлЛ ркЕркирлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлА рк░рк╛ркд ркХркпрк╛рк░рлЗ рккрк╕рк╛рк░ ркеркИ ркЧркИ ркдрлЗ ркоркирлЗ ркЦркмрк░ ркЬ рки рккркбрлА!\\" ркпрлБрк╡рк╛ркирлЗ ркЖ ркЬрк╡рк╛ркм ркЖрккрлНркпрлЛ ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ рккрлЗрк▓рк╛ рк▓рлБркЪрлНркЪрк╛ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░рлАркП ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ, \\"рк▓рлЛ, ркЬрк╣рк╛ркВрккркирк╛рк╣, ркЖ ркпрлБрк╡рк╛ркирлЗ ркдрлЛ ркХркВркИ ркХркорк╛рк▓ ркиркерлА ркХрк░рлА. ркП ркдрлЛ ркЖрккркирк╛ ркорк╣рлЗрк▓ркирк╛ ркжрлАрк╡рк╛ркорк╛ркВркерлА ркорк│ркдрлА ркЧрк░ркорлАркирлЗ ркХрк╛рк░ркгрлЗ ркаркВркбрлАркорк╛ркВ рк░рк╛ркд рккрк╕рк╛рк░ ркХрк░рлА рк╢ркХрлНркпрлЛ ркЫрлЗ. ркП ркдрлЛ рк╕рк╛рк╡ рк╕рк╛ркорк╛ркирлНркп рк╡рк╛ркд ркЫрлЗ.\\" ркЕркХркмрк░ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣ рккркг рк▓рлБркЪрлНркЪрк╛ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░рлАркирлА рк╡рк╛ркдркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлА ркЧркпрк╛ ркПркЯрк▓рлЗ ркдрлЗркоркгрлЗ ркпрлБрк╡рк╛ркиркирлЗ ркХркВркИ рккркг ркИркирк╛рко рки ркЖрккрлНркпрлБркВ. ркпрлБрк╡рк╛рки ркирк┐рк░рк╛рк╢ ркеркИ ркЪрк╛рк▓рлНркпрлЛ ркЧркпрлЛ. ркЖ ркмркзрлБркВ ркмркирлНркпрлБркВ ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓рлЗ ркЪрлВрккркЪрк╛ркк ркЬрлЛркпрк╛ ркХрк░рлНркпрлБркВ. рккрк░ркВркдрлБ ркмрлАркЬрк╛ ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ркерлА ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓рлЗ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рк╡рк╛ркирлБркВ ркмркВркз ркХрк░рлНркпрлБркВ. ркмрлЗ-ркдрлНрк░ркг ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ ркеркИ ркЧркпрк╛ркВ ркЫркдрк╛ркВ ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ рки ркЖрк╡рлНркпрлЛ ркПркЯрк▓рлЗ ркЕркХркмрк░ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣рлЗ ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ркирлЗ ркдрлЗркбрк╛рк╡рк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркгрк╕ ркорлЛркХрк▓рлНркпрлЛ. ркерлЛркбрлАрк╡рк╛рк░ рккркЫрлА ркдрлЗ ркорк╛ркгрк╕ рккрк╛ркЫрлЛ ркЖрк╡рлНркпрлЛ ркЕркирлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ, \\"ркЬрк╣рк╛ркВрккркирк╛рк╣, ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓рлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ ркХрлЗ рк╣рлБркВ ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА ркмркирк╛рк╡рлБркВ ркЫрлБркВ. ркЬрлЗрк╡рлА ркорк╛рк░рлА ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА ркмркирлА ркЬрк╛ркп, рккркЫрлА ркдрк░ркд ркЬ ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА ркЦрк╛ркИркирлЗ рк╣рлБркВ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлАрк╢.\\"рклрк░рлА ркмрлЗ ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ ркеркИ ркЧркпрк╛ ркЫркдрк╛ркВ ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ рки ркЖрк╡рлНркпрлЛ, ркПркЯрк▓рлЗ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣рлЗ ркирлЛркХрк░ркирлЗ рклрк░рлА ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ркирлЗ ркмрлЛрк▓рк╛рк╡рк╡рк╛ ркорлЛркХрк▓рлНркпрлЛ. ркирлЛркХрк░рлЗ рккрк╛ркЫрк╛ ркЖрк╡рлА ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ, \\"ркЬрк╣рк╛ркВрккркирк╛рк╣, ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ ркХрк╣рлЗ ркЫрлЗ ркХрлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлА ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА рк╣ркЬрлА рк╕рлБркзрлА рккрк╛ркХрлА ркиркерлА. ркЬрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА рккрк╛ркХрлА ркЬрк╢рлЗ ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ рк╣рлБркВ ркдрлЗ ркЦрк╛ркИркирлЗ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлАрк╢.\\"ркЖ ркЬрк╡рк╛ркм рк╕рк╛ркВркнрк│рлА ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣ рк╡рк┐ркЪрк╛рк░ркорк╛ркВ рккркбрлА ркЧркпрк╛. ркеркпрлБркВ ркХрлЗ \\"рк▓рк╛рк╡ рк╣рлБркВ ркЬ ркЬркИркирлЗ ркЬрлЛркИ ркЖрк╡рлБркВ ркХрлЗ ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ ркХрлЗрк╡рлА ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА ркмркирк╛рк╡рлЗ ркЫрлЗ!\\"ркЕркХркмрк░ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣ ркжрк░ркмрк╛рк░рлАркУркирлЗ рк▓ркИ ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ ркЬрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркмрлЗркарлЛ рк╣ркдрлЛ ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЧркпрк╛ркВ. ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркЬркИ ркдрлЗркоркгрлЗ ркЬрлЛркпрлБркВ ркдрлЛ ркдрлНрк░ркг рк▓рк╛ркВркмрк╛ рк╡рк╛ркВрк╕ркирлА ркШрлЛркбрлА ркмркирк╛рк╡рлА ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓рлЗ рк╡рк╛ркВрк╕ркирлА ркЙрккрк░ ркЦрлАркЪркбрлАркирлА рк╣рк╛ркВркбрк▓рлА рк▓ркЯркХрк╛рк╡рлА рк╣ркдрлА ркЕркирлЗ ркирлАркЪрлЗ ркЬркорлАрки ркЙрккрк░ ркЖркЧ рк╕рк│ркЧрк╛рк╡рлА рк╣ркдрлА. ркЖ ркЬрлЛркИ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣рлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ, \\"ркЖ рк╢рлБркВ ркЦрлЗрк▓ ркХрк░рлА рк░рк╣рлНркпрлЛ ркЫрлЗ! ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓, ркЖркЧркерлА ркЖркЯрк▓рлА ркЕркжрлНркзрк░ рк░рк╛ркЦрлАркирлЗ ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА ркХрлЛркИ ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ рккрк╛ркХркдрлА рк╣рк╢рлЗ?'\\"'\\"рк╣ркЬрлВрк░, ркЬрк░рлВрк░ рккрк╛ркХрлА ркЬрк╢рлЗ.\\" ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓рлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ.\\"ркХрлЗрк╡рлА рк░рлАркдрлЗ?\\" ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣рлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ.\\"ркЬрк╣рк╛ркВрккркирк╛рк╣, ркЬрлЗрко ркдркорк╛рк░рк╛ ркорк╣рлЗрк▓ркорк╛ркВ рк╕рк│ркЧркдрк╛ ркжрлАрк╡рк╛ркирлА ркЧрк░ркорлАркерлА ркжрлВрк░ ркиркжрлАркорк╛ркВ ркКркнрлЗрк▓рлЛ рккрк╣рлЗрк▓рлЛ рк╣ркаркпрлЛркЧрлА ркаркВркбрлА ркЙркбрк╛ркбрлА рк░рк╣рлНркпрлЛ рк╣ркдрлЛ, ркдрлЗркирлА рк╕рк░ркЦрк╛ркоркгрлАркорк╛ркВ ркдрлЛ ркЖ ркШркгрлБркВ ркУркЫрлБркВ ркЕркВркдрк░ ркЫрлЗ. ркЖркЧркерлА ркЖркЯрк▓рлА ркЬ ркЕркжрлНркзрк░ рк░рк╛ркЦрлЗрк▓рлА ркЦрлАркЪркбрлА ркЬрк░рлВрк░ рккрк╛ркХрлА ркеркИ ркЬрк╢рлЗ.\\" ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓рлЗ ркорлЛркврлБркВ ркЧркВркнрлАрк░ рк░рк╛ркЦрлА ркЬрк╡рк╛ркм ркЖрккрлНркпрлЛ. ркЕркХркмрк░ ркмрк╛ркжрк╢рк╛рк╣ ркмрлАрк░ркмрк▓ркирлА ркЖ ркжрк▓рлАрк▓ рк╕рк╛ркВркнрк│рлА ркШркгрк╛ рк╢рк░ркорк╛ркпрк╛. ркмрлАркЬрлЗ ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕рлЗ ркдрлЗркоркгрлЗ рккрлЗрк▓рк╛ рк╣ркаркпрлЛркЧрлАркирлЗ ркдрлЗркбрк╛рк╡рлА ркдрлЗркирлЗ ркпрлЛркЧрлНркп ркИркирк╛рко ркЖрккрлНркпрлБркВ."},{"question":"Nitori to n ta с║╣ran to ti bajс║╣ fawс╗Нn araalu, sifu difensi mu alapata kan ni Kwara","answer":"Ajс╗Н с║╣sс╗Н alaabo с╣гifu difс║╣nsi, с║╣ka ti ipinlс║╣ Kwara, ti mu с║╣lс║╣ran maaluu kan, Nawali Bala, niluu Patigi, nijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ Patigi, nipinlс║╣ Kwara, fс║╣sun pe o n ta с║╣ran ti ko daa fun awс╗Нn eeyan.с╗Мjс╗Н Aiku, Sannde, с╗Нс╣гс║╣ yii, ni Agbс║╣nusс╗Н ajс╗Н naa ni Kwara, с╗Мgbс║╣ni Babawale Afolabi, fс╗Нrс╗Н naa lede niluu Ilс╗Нrin. O ni ni kete ti с╗Нwс╗Н tс║╣ afurasi с╗Нhun, Bashiru Bala Zuru, to n ta с║╣ran to ti bajс║╣, to si lewu fun alaafia awс╗Нn araalu lo jс║╣wс╗Н pe с╗Нkunrin kan torukс╗Н rс║╣ n jс║╣ Dantani Jayewu, to n gbe Okoloke, nipinlс║╣ Kogi, lo gbe с║╣ran naa foun ki oun maa ta a. Lс║╣yin ayс║╣wo ti wс╗Нn с╣гe si с║╣ran naa finnifinni latс╗Нwс╗Н ileeс╣гс║╣ to n ri si с╗Нrс╗Н ayika nipinlс║╣ Kwara ni wс╗Нn sс╗Н pe o le с╣гe akoba fun alaafia araalu.с╗Мga agba ajс╗Н с╗Нhun, с╗Мgbс║╣ni Makinde, ti waa sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn yoo foju afurasi naa ba ile-с║╣jс╗Н lс║╣yin с║╣kunrс║╣rс║╣ iwadii."},{"question":"р░Хр░┐р░Вр░ж р░Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐р░и р░ор▒Кр░жр░Яр░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р░╛ р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░Ър░┐р░╡р░░р░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р░╛ р░Ер░ир▒Бр░╕р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър▒Б р░ор░зр▒Нр░п р░кр▒Зр░░р░╛ р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐:р░ор▒Кр░жр░Яр░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р░╛:р░ир░┐р░Ьр░╛р░В р░ир░┐р░пр░Вр░др▒Гр░др▒Нр░╡ р░кр░╛р░▓р░ир░Хр▒Б р░╡р▒Нр░пр░др░┐р░░р▒Зр░Хр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░╡р░┐р░ор▒Бр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐р░кр▒Лр░░р░╛р░Яр░Хр░╛р░▓р░В р░ир░╛р░Яр░┐ р░кр░░р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░ер░┐р░др▒Бр░▓р░ир▒Б р░Хр░│р▒Нр░│р░Хр▒Б р░Хр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░┐р░ир░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░Хр░е р░Зр░жр░┐. р░ир░┐р░Ьр░╛р░В р░кр▒Лр░▓р▒Ар░╕р▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б, р░░р░Ьр░╛р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░╡р▒Нр░пр░др░┐р░░р▒Зр░Хр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░жр▒Нр░пр░ор░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░Тр░Х р░╕р▒Нр░Яр▒Зр░Яр▒Н р░Хр░╛р░Вр░Чр▒Нр░░р▒Жр░╕р▒Н тАШр░╡р░╛р░▓р░Вр░Яр▒Ар░░р▒Бр░ир▒Б, р░╡р░┐р░кр▒Нр░▓р░╡ р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Бр░бр░┐р░ир░┐ р░Тр░Х р░╕р░╛р░ор░╛р░ир▒Нр░п р░╡р▒Гр░жр▒Нр░зр▒Бр░░р░╛р░▓р▒Б р░░р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░Ер░кр▒Вр░░р▒Нр░╡ р░Зр░др░┐р░╡р▒Гр░др▒Нр░др░В р░Чр▒Кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░░р░╛р░ор░╡р▒Нр░╡р░Хр░е. р░др▒Жр░▓р░Вр░Чр░╛р░гр░кр▒Лр░░р░╛р░Я р░Ър░░р░┐р░др▒Нр░░р░▓р▒Л р░И р░Хр░е р░Тр░Х р░╕р▒Гр░Ьр░ир░╛р░др▒Нр░ор░Х р░бр░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр▒Бр░ор▒Жр░Вр░Яр▒Нр░Ър░┐р░╡р░░р░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р░╛:р░Чр▒Кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░░р░╛р░ор░╡р▒Нр░╡ р░др░и р░Чр▒Бр░бр░┐р░╕р▒Жр░▓р▒Л р░Ър▒Ар░Хр░Яр░┐р░▓р▒Лр░ир▒З р░Хр▒Вр░░р▒Нр░Ър▒Кр░ир░┐ р░Йр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░╡р░бр░┐р░▓р▒Л р░нр░пр░В р░нр░пр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░кр░жр░┐р░╣р▒Зр░ир▒Зр░Вр░бр▒Нр░▓ р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Х р░др░▓р░жр░╛р░Ър▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░ир░┐ р░Йр░Вр░жр░┐.","answer":"р░др▒Жр░▓р░Вр░Чр░╛р░гр░▓р▒Л р░Ер░жр▒Л р░кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Ж. р░Ж р░кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Жр░▓р▒Лр░Хр░┐ р░Йр░жр▒Нр░пр░ор░Хр░╛р░░р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р░╡р▒Зр░╢р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░░р░Ьр░╛р░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░▓р░ир▒Б, р░кр▒Лр░▓р▒Ар░╕р▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б, р░ир░╡р░╛р░мр▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░╡р▒Нр░пр░др░┐р░░р▒Зр░Хр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░кр▒Нр░░р░Ьр░▓р▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Ър▒Ир░др░ир▒Нр░пр░В р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р░ир░┐ р░ир░┐р░Ьр░╛р░В р░кр▒Нр░░р░нр▒Бр░др▒Нр░╡р░╡р░╛р░жр░и. р░Ж р░░р▒Лр░Ьр▒Б р░Зр░жр▒Нр░жр░░р▒Б р░кр▒Лр░▓р▒Ар░╕р▒Бр░▓р▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Ър░Вр░кр░┐р░ир░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░╕р░ор░╛р░Ър░╛р░░р░В. р░Ер░░р▒Нр░зр░░р░╛р░др▒Нр░░р░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░╢р░╛р░Вр░д р░╡р░╛р░др░╛р░╡р░░р░гр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Ър░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░нр░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир░В р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░мр░╛р░Вр░мр▒Бр░▓р░ор▒Лр░д."},{"question":"р╢Ер╢╖р╖Тр╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ср╢▒ р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п ?","answer":"р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║ р╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢о р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╖П р╢Ер╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢о р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢п р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢▒р╖Ър╢Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╖Ар╖Ц р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╢║, тАЬр╢ар╖Ър╢н, р╢╕р╢▒, р╖Ар╖Тр╢др╖Кр╢др╖Пр╢л, р╖Др╢пр╢║, р╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Г,тАЭ р╢║р╢▒ р╢╕р╖Ър╖Ар╖П р╢п р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║ р╢╕ р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╢▒ р╢┤р╖Пр╖Ер╖Т р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╖Э р╢║. р╢Зр╖Гр╢║, р╢Ър╢▒р╢║, р╢▒р╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╢║, р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╢║, р╢Ър╢║р╢║, р╖Др╖Шр╢пр╢║р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Ср╢║ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Фр╖Ар╢п р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╖Др╖Пр╢╗ р╢┤р╖Др╖Гр╖Фр╖А р╢┤р╖Тр╢лр╖Тр╖Г р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢Ър╢╗р╖Кр╢нр╖Ш р╖Бр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢пр╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Ъ р╢п р╢Ър╢╗р╢л р╖Бр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢пр╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Ъ р╢п р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╖Пр╖Др╢╗ р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Ъ. р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Ур╢╕р╢║, р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢║, р╢Зр╖Гр╖Ур╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Пр╢пр╖Т р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Т р╢Т р╢Жр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Лр╢┤р╢пр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╖Др╖Рр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢┤р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Т р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╖Др╖Пр╢╗ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╢Ьр╢лр╢▒р╢Ър╖Т. р╢Зр╖Гр╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢╗р╖Цр╢┤р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╢Ср╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Ср╢║ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╢Ър╖Пр╖Б р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╢пр╖У р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╖Др╖Пр╢╗ р╢▒р╖Ь р╢Ър╖Ьр╢з р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢║ р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Ур╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╖Др╖Пр╢╗ р╢Ър╢╗р╢нр╖Т. р╢Зр╖Гр╢з р╖Др╢╕р╖Фр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢║р╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╢пр╢нр╖К р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╖Др╖Э р╢пр╖Фр╢зр╖Фр╢║р╖Ър╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╖Др╖Э р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╢Ер╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Фр╖Ар╢п р╢Ср╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╢Яр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╢╕р╢║, р╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢╕ р╢║. р╢Ър╢▒р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╖Бр╢╢р╖Кр╢пр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т, р╢Т р╖Др╢м р╢пр╖Рр╢▒ р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢Ър╖К р╢Лр╢┤р╢пр╖У. р╢Ср╢║р╢з р╖Др╢м р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Фр╢╕ р╢║ р╢║р╖Т р╢▒р╖Ь р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢Зр╖Гр╖Ур╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Ъ. р╢Зр╖Гр╖Ур╢╕ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Др╢м р╢пр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╖Ар╖Ц р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢║. р╢▒р╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╢з р╢пр╖Фр╢Яр╢│р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Т р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢Ьр╢│р╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ър╢║ р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╢▒р╖Ь р╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ьр╢│р╢║р╢║р╖Т р╢╕ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╢Ср╢╢р╢│р╖Ф р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╖Ар╢╜р╢пр╖У р╢Ьр╢│р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╢Яр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢п р╢Ьр╢│ р╢пр╖Рр╢▒ р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢╕ р╢║. р╢╗р╖Гр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Фр╢Ыр╢║р╢з р╢┤р╖Рр╢╕р╖Тр╢лр╖Т р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╢п р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢╗р╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ър╢║р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢Ср╖Гр╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Ь р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢нр╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║ р╢Зр╢╣р╖Фр╢╜р╖Кр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Пр╢пр╖Ур╢▒р╖К р╢╗р╖Гр╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╢╕ р╢╕ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╢Ср╢╢р╢│р╖Ф р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╖Ар╢╜ р╢пр╖У р╢╗р╖Гр╢║р╖Ъ р╢▒р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢п р╢Т р╢╗р╖Гр╢║ р╢пр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢╕ р╢║. р╖Бр╢╗р╖Ур╢╗р╢║р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢║р╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Рр╢┤р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╖Гр╖Рр╢┤р╖Щр╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ър╢║ р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢Ср╖Гр╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Ь р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╖Гр╖Рр╢┤р╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢╡р╢╜р╢║ р╖Др╢Яр╖Ар╢▒ р╢╗р╖Тр╢пр╖Ур╢╕р╢║, р╖Бр╖Ур╢нр╢╜р╢║, р╢Лр╖Вр╖Кр╢лр╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╢Ср╢╢р╢│р╖Ф р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╖Ар╢╜ р╢пр╖У р╢Т р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Рр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢п р╖Гр╖Кр╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╖Вр╖Кр╢зр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╢пр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢║. р╢┤р╢др╖Кр╢ар╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╖Гр╖Пр╢п р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Тр╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╢║ р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╢║, р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╢▒р╖П р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╢║, р╢Хр╢▒р╖С р╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖Ър╢║, р╖Ар╖Рр╢зр╖Др╖Фр╢лр╖Ъ р╢║, р╢нр╖Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╢║, р╖Др╖Рр╢Яр╖Фр╢лр╖Ър╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Пр╢пр╖Т р╖Ар╢ар╢▒ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╢Т р╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╕ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Рр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢╕ р╢║. р╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢╕р╖Щр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Др╖Щр╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Ур╢╕р╢║, р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢║, р╢Зр╖Гр╖Ур╢╕р╢║, р╢Ьр╢│р╢║, р╖Гр╖Фр╖Ар╢│р╢║, р╢нр╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║, р╢Ър╖Гр╢зр╢║, р╖Бр╖Ур╢нр╢║, р╢Лр╖Вр╖Кр╢лр╢║, р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╢║, р╢Хр╢▒р╖Ср╢Ър╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Пр╢пр╖Т р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║ р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║ р╢║р╖Т р╢пр╢н р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢║. р╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢нр╖Фр╢╗р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Рр╢╕р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢о р╢п р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Рр╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╖Рр╢╗р╢пр╖Тр╖А р╢╕ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖П р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢о р╖Др╖Е р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢║.р╢╗р╢ор╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╢╗р╢ор╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╕ р╢Ср╢▒ р╖Ар╖Ър╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖Т. р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╢Ър╖Фр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╖Бр╢╗р╖Ур╢╗р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢Яр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Ър╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖Т. р╢Ер╢нр╢Ъ р╢Ср╖Гр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╢Ер╢нр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Ър╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖Т. р╢Ср╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢║ р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒ р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╢л р╖Ар╖Тр╢вр╖Пр╢▒р╢▒ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╢л р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╖Др╢л р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢н р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢Ь р╢Ср╢▒ р╖Ар╖Ър╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖Т. р╢┤р╖Эр╢╗ р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒ р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Рр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢з р╖Ар╖Рр╢╜р╢Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╢╜р╖Ф р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Пр╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒ р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Рр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢Т р╢Т р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢н р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╖Ер╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢Ер╖Ер╖Фр╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╢▒р╖Фр╢║р╖Ъ р╢ар╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Фр╢╗р╖Пр╢пр╖Т р╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Цр╢▒р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╢║. р╢Ср╖Др╖Щр╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢Тр╖Ар╖Пр╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢Я р╢Ср╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Рр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢▒р╖Ь р╢Ьр╢н р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢║. р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢ар╢Ър╖КтАНр╖Вр╖Фр╢╗р╖Пр╢пр╖Т р╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Цр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢Я р╢Ср╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Ф р╢Ър╖Ур╢┤р╢║р╢Ъ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Ар╢╗ р╢╗р╖Цр╢┤ р╖Бр╢╢р╖Кр╢пр╖Пр╢пр╖Т р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╢Т р╢Т р╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╢╜ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Ар╢╗ р╢╕ р╢Т р╢Т р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢║. р╢Ср╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Пр╢▒р╢║р╢Ъ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Ар╢╗ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╢▒ р╢╢р╖Рр╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Бр╢╗р╖Ур╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ьр╢нр╖Рр╢▒р╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╖Фр╖А р╢п р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Гр╖Ср╢╕ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢Ър╖К р╢╕ р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢н р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Др╖Е р╖Ар╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╢пр╢н р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢║. р╖Гр╖Тр╢н: р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢н р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢╕ р╢▒р╖Рр╢Я р╢▒р╖Рр╢Я р╢Ср╢▒ р╖Ар╖Ър╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Рр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢▒р╖Ь р╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Бр╢╗р╖Ур╢╗р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╖Щр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢Гр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╢║ р╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Цр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Ър╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Рр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢Ьр╢нр╖Др╖Ьр╢нр╖К р╢Ер╢╗р╖Цр╢┤ р╢╖р╖Цр╢╕р╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╢р╖А р╢Фр╢┤р╖Кр╢┤р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Е р╢▒р╖Ь р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢║. р╢┤р╖Фр╢▒р╢╗р╖Фр╢нр╖Кр╢┤р╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╢р╖А р╢п р╢Фр╢┤р╖Кр╢┤р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Е р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢▒р╖Ь р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢║. р╖Гр╖Тр╢н: р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢н р╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╕ р╢▒р╖Рр╢Яр╖Щр╢▒ р╢пр╖Щр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Рр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╢нр╖Рр╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖П р╖Др╢з р╢┤р╖Фр╢▒р╢╗р╖Фр╢нр╖Кр╢┤р╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╢р╖А р╢п р╢┤р╖Др╖Гр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╕ р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢║.р╢Зр╢нр╖Рр╢╕р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Тр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖А р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╢║р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢нр╖Т. р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╖Гр╖Ср╢╕ р╢нр╖Рр╢▒ р╢╕ р╢Зр╢н. р╢Ър╖Ьр╢нр╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Зр╢нр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢н р╢Ср╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Цр╢┤р╢пр╖У. р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╢лр╖Пр╢пр╖Т р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Цр╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╖Гр╖Тр╢н р╢Йр╢┤р╢п р╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢н р╢Ср╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖Т р╢┤р╢╕р╢лр╖Щр╢Ър╖Т. р╢Ср╢╢р╖Рр╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗тАНр╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖А р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╢лр╢║ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖А р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢н р╢Ср╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Пр╖А р╢╢р╖А р╢пр╢н р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢║. р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╢з р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Др╖Щр╢▒ р╢╢р╖Рр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢л р╢п р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╢╢р╢╜р╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╢р╖А р╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢║."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:  рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро╛ро░рпН роОроирпНрод рокро╛рогрпНроЯро┐роп рооройрпНройро░ро┐ройрпН роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐роХрпН роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроирпНродро╛ро░рпН?1. роЪрпБроирпНродро░рокро╛рогрпНроЯро┐ропройрпН2. ро╕рпНро░рпАрооро╛ро▒ ро╕рпНро░рпАро╡ро▓рпНро▓рокройрпН3. ро╡ро┐роХрпНро░роо рокро╛рогрпНроЯро┐ропройрпН4. ро╡рпАро░ рокро╛рогрпНроЯро┐ропройрпН","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: 2. ро╕рпНро░рпАрооро╛ро▒ ро╕рпНро░рпАро╡ро▓рпНро▓рокройрпН"},{"question":"Dс╗▒a tr├кn ti├кu ─Сс╗Б sau, h├гy viс║┐t mс╗Щt b├аi b├бo n├│i vс╗Б chс╗з ─Сс╗Б n├аy: D├вn mс║бng Trung Quс╗Сc phс║лn nс╗Щ v├м mс╗Щt nс╗п shipper bс╗Л kh├бch mс║бt s├бt. Nс╗Щi dung ch├нnh cс╗зa ─Сoс║бn v─Гn kс╗Г vс╗Б mс╗Щt nс╗п sinh vi├кn l├аm c├┤ng viс╗Зc giao h├аng tс║бi th├аnh phс╗С Uy Hс║гi, Trung Quс╗Сc. Trong qu├б tr├мnh giao h├аng, c├┤ phс║гi ─Сс╗Сi mс║╖t vс╗Ыi mс╗Щt kh├бch h├аng kh├┤ng lс╗Лch sс╗▒ v├а th├┤ lс╗Ч. Kh├бch h├аng n├аy ban ─Сс║зu y├кu cс║зu c├┤ sс╗н dс╗еng thang m├бy, sau ─С├│ lс║бi thay ─Сс╗Хi ├╜ v├а g├вy rс╗Сi. Sau khi c├┤ ─С├г giao h├аng, kh├бch h├аng n├аy thс║нm ch├н n├йm t├┤ m├м xuс╗Сng s├аn, l├аm n╞░с╗Ыc s├║p n├│ng bс║пn l├кn ng╞░с╗Эi c├┤. Nс╗п shipper ─С├г cс╗С gс║пng giс║гi quyс║┐t t├мnh huс╗Сng nh╞░ng vс║лn bс╗Л kh├бch h├аng coi th╞░с╗Эng. C├┤ ─С├г quay video vс╗Б sс╗▒ viс╗Зc n├аy v├а ─С─Гng tс║гi l├кn mс║бng x├г hс╗Щi, g├вy sс╗▒ phс║лn nс╗Щ tс╗л cс╗Щng ─Сс╗Уng mс║бng. Tuy nhi├кn, sau ─С├│, c├┤ phс║гi k├кu gс╗Нi kh├┤ng tс║еn c├┤ng kh├бch h├аng v├а nhс║еn mс║бnh rс║▒ng c├│ nhiс╗Бu kh├бch h├аng c├│ th├бi ─Сс╗Щ xс║еu t├нnh v├а kh├┤ng t├┤n trс╗Нng t├аi xс║┐ giao h├аng. ─Рiс╗Бu n├аy bс║нt m├н vс╗Б t├мnh trс║бng bс║бo h├аnh v├а th├бi ─Сс╗Щ kh├┤ng t├┤n trс╗Нng ─Сс╗Сi vс╗Ыi ng╞░с╗Эi giao h├аng trong ng├аnh giao ─Сс╗У ─Гn trс╗▒c tuyс║┐n с╗Я Trung Quс╗Сc.","answer":"Mс╗Щt nс╗п sinh vi├кn (giс║еu t├кn) l├аm th├кm c├┤ng viс╗Зc giao h├аng tс║бi th├аnh phс╗С Uy Hс║гi, tс╗Йnh S╞бn ─Р├┤ng, Trung Quс╗Сc. Ng├аy 24/7, c├┤ giao t├┤ m├м thс╗Лt b├▓ gi├б 17 nh├вn d├вn tс╗З (t╞░╞бng ─С╞░╞бng 2,5 USD) cho mс╗Щt thс╗▒c kh├бch. Shipper n├аy gс╗Нi ─Сiс╗Зn, nhс╗Э kh├бch chс╗Й dс║лn c├бch sс╗н dс╗еng thang m├бy cс╗зa t├▓a nh├а. ─Р├бp trс║г c├┤, nс╗п kh├бch h├аng cho biс║┐t thang m├бy kh├┤ng phс╗еc vс╗е t├аi xс║┐ giao h├аng. \\"C├┤ kh├┤ng xс╗йng ─С├бng ─Сi thang m├бy, leo thang bс╗Щ ─Сi!\\", ng╞░с╗Эi phс╗е nс╗п n├│i qua ─Сiс╗Зn thoс║бi. Shipper chс║еp nhс║нn di chuyс╗Гn bс║▒ng cс║зu thang bс╗Щ. C├┤ ─Сс║╖t phс║зn ─Гn tr╞░с╗Ыc cс╗нa nh├а thс╗▒c kh├бch, sau ─С├│ rс╗Эi ─Сi. Tuy nhi├кn, ngay sau ─С├│, vс╗Л kh├бch h├аng gс╗Нi ─Сiс╗Зn y├кu cс║зu c├┤ quay trс╗Я lс║бi. Ng╞░с╗Эi phс╗е nс╗п n├аy cho rс║▒ng ─С╞бn h├аng cс╗зa m├мnh bс╗Л lс╗Чi ─С├│ng g├│i, sau ─С├│ thс║│ng tay n├йm t├┤ m├м xuс╗Сng s├аn khiс║┐n n╞░с╗Ыc s├║p n├│ng bс║пn l├кn ng╞░с╗Эi nс╗п shipper. T├аi xс║┐ giao h├аng cс╗С gс║пng trс║еn an v├а giс║гi th├нch rс║▒ng sс╗▒ cс╗С c├│ thс╗Г xuс║еt ph├бt tс╗л nh├а h├аng. C├┤ ─Сс╗Б nghс╗Л tс╗▒ chi tiс╗Бn v├а giao lс║бi cho kh├бch h├аng mс╗Щt t├┤ m├м kh├бc. Ng╞░с╗Эi phс╗е nс╗п ─С├бp lс║бi: \\"T├┤i cho c├┤ 5 ph├║t ─Сс╗Г giao lс║бi suс║еt m├м mс╗Ыi. Nс║┐u kh├┤ng, t├┤i sс║╜ khiс║┐u nс║бi vс╗Ыi c├┤ng ty cс╗зa c├┤\\". ─Рoс║бn video ghi lс║бi sс╗▒ viс╗Зc n├кu tr├кn ─С╞░с╗гc nс╗п shipper ─С─Гng tс║гi l├кn mс║бng x├г hс╗Щi. \\"Khi t├┤i quay lс║бi vс╗Ыi ─С╞бn h├аng mс╗Ыi tr├кn tay, vс╗Л kh├бch ─С├│ vс║лn rс║еt th├┤ lс╗Ч. Chс╗Л ta n├│i t├┤i kh├┤ng hс╗Нc h├аnh ch─Гm chс╗Й, lс║бi c├▓n kh├┤ng l├аm tс╗Сt c├┤ng viс╗Зc cс╗зa m├мnh\\", c├┤ bс║нt kh├│c trong video. Cс╗Щng ─Сс╗Уng mс║бng tс╗П ra bс╗йc x├║c, bс║еt b├мnh tr╞░с╗Ыc th├бi ─Сс╗Щ coi th╞░с╗Эng cс╗зa nс╗п kh├бch h├аng. Hс╗Н t├мm kiс║┐m ng╞░с╗Эi n├аy tr├кn Internet v├а kh├┤ng ngс╗Ыt lс╗Эi chс╗Й tr├нch. ─Рс║┐n ng├аy 30/7, nс╗п shipper n├аy phс║гi k├кu gс╗Нi c╞░ d├вn mс║бng kh├┤ng t├мm kiс║┐m hoс║╖c tс║еn c├┤ng ng╞░с╗Эi phс╗е nс╗п. \\"Mс╗Щt sс╗С kh├бch h├аng rс║еt xс║еu t├нnh. Hс╗Н x├║c phс║бm, thс║нm ch├н cс║гn trс╗Я c├┤ng viс╗Зc cс╗зa nhс╗пng t├аi xс║┐ giao h├аng\\", mс╗Щt ng╞░с╗Эi b├мnh luс║нn. Mс╗Щt ng╞░с╗Эi kh├бc cho rс║▒ng: \\"Ng╞░с╗Эi phс╗е nс╗п c╞░ xс╗н m├а kh├┤ng c├│ ch├║t t├┤n trс╗Нng n├аo. Chс║пc chс╗Л ta ngh─й m├мnh c├│ quyс╗Бn x├║c phс║бm ng╞░с╗Эi kh├бc\\". Theo SCMP, c├бc nс╗Бn tс║гng giao ─Сс╗У ─Гn trс╗▒c tuyс║┐n tс║бi Trung Quс╗Сc chс╗Й cung cс║еp chс╗йc n─Гng khiс║┐u nс║бi d├аnh cho kh├бch h├аng. Nhс╗пng tr╞░с╗Эng hс╗гp shipper bс╗Л bс║бo h├аnh th╞░с╗Эng xс║гy ra, nh╞░ng ch╞░a c├│ chс║┐ t├аi bс║гo vс╗З. Th├бng 5 vс╗лa qua, kh├бch h├аng с╗Я tс╗Йnh Giang T├┤ y├кu cс║зu shipper mua gi├║p mс╗Щt th├╣ng bia kh├┤ng c├│ trong ─С╞бn ─Сс║╖t h├аng ban ─Сс║зu, sau ─С├│ y├кu cс║зu anh leo bс╗Щ 6 tс║зng nh├а ─Сс╗Г giao h├аng. N─Гm ngo├бi, mс╗Щt kh├бch h├аng kh├бc с╗Я miс╗Бn Nam Trung Quс╗Сc ─Сe dс╗Нa khiс║┐u nс║бi khi nс╗п shipper tс╗л chс╗Сi quan hс╗З t├мnh dс╗еc vс╗Ыi anh ta."},{"question":"Amaka Igwe","answer":"Amaka Igwe (t├н a b├н n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kej├м oс╣г├╣ с╣в├йс║╣╠Бrс║╣╠Б с╗Нd├║n 1963 - ├│ di ol├│├▓gb├й n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kej├мd├нnlс╗Н╠Бgbс╗Н╠Аn oс╣г├╣ Igbe, с╗Нd├║n 2014). Amaka Igwe jс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├й с╗Нmс╗Н or├нlс║╣╠А├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а ├аti с╗Н╠Аg├б sс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠Аsс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А. ├Тun ni al├бс╣гс║╣ il├йeс╣гс║╣╠Б r├йd├н├▓ Top 90.8 ├Иk├│ ├аti il├йeс╣гс║╣╠Б Amaka Igwe Studio. Ipa rс║╣╠А l├бs├мk├▓ ├мgb├йd├мde f├н├мm├╣ ├аgb├йl├йw├▓ l├бy├й sinim├б n├н N├а├мj├нr├н├а k├▓ с╣г├й ├й fс╗Нwс╗Н╠Б rс╗Н╠Б sс║╣╠Бy├мn. ├И├иk├аn n├н ni agbo ├▓с╣г├иr├й n├нgb├а ay├й rс║╣╠А k├н ├│ t├│ di w├н p├й ├а├мs├аn ikс╗Н╠Б s├йm├м├нs├йm├м├н m├║ с║╣╠Аm├н rс║╣╠А lс╗Н.N├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kej├м, Oс╣г├╣ с╣в├йс║╣╠Бrс║╣╠Б wс╗Н╠Бn d├б с╣гe ├мr├бnt├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Бс╗Н╠Аb├н rс║╣╠А, wс╗Н╠Бn s├м fi Google Doodle da lс╗Н╠Бla.Uzomaka Audrey \\"Amaka\\" Igwe jс║╣╠Б с╗Нmс╗Н Isaac ├аti Patience Ene n├н ├мl├║ Port-Harcourt. Ipo kar├╣n-├║n ni Igwe n├нn├║ ├аwс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н m├йje, ├│ s├м jс║╣╠Б с╗Нmс╗Нb├мnrin kс║╣r├мn n├нn├║ ob├мnrin mс║╣╠Бf├а. \\"GCO\\" с╗М╠Аg├б Ap├ас╣гс║╣╠А ni b├аb├б rс║╣╠А m├бa  ┼Д p├и ├й, t├н ├мy├а rс║╣╠А s├м ┼Д p├и ├й ni \\"├мj├м\\" (storm) tor├н p├й с╗Нwс╗Н╠Б rс║╣╠А k├м ├н dilс║╣╠А. ├У lс╗Н s├н il├й с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б All Saints ├аti Il├йс║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б G├нga Awkunanaw ├аwс╗Нn ob├мnrin n├н Enugu.├У ja с║╣╠Ас╣гс║╣╠Б, ├│ gba bс╗Н╠Бс╗Н╠Аl├╣ ├аfс╗Нwс╗Н╠Бgb├б, ├▓un s├м ni ol├│r├н ikс╗Н╠А agb├бbс╗Н╠Бс╗Н╠Бl├╣ ├аwс╗Нn ob├мnrin. N├нgb├а t├н ├│ ┼Д с╣гe A-level n├н Kс╗Н╠Бlс║╣╠Бj├м Idia, ├│ bс║╣╠Аrс║╣╠А s├н n├н с╣гe ├аw├бr├н с║╣╠Аb├╣n rс║╣╠А. ├У kс╗Н╠Б ├аwс╗Нn ├и├иy├аn n├н ij├│ Atilogwu,├│ s├м d├нj├й or├нlс║╣╠А├иd├и. ├У bс║╣╠Аrс║╣╠А s├н n├н kс╗Н er├й-on├нt├аn ├аti orin. с║╕╠Аkс╗Н╠Б ├Мmс╗Н╠А ├▓fin l├│ wu Amaka Igwe l├бti с╣гe с╣г├╣gbс╗Н╠Бn ├аwс╗Нn ├▓с╣г├мс╣гс║╣╠Б Ajс╗Н╠Б JAMB f├║n n├н *├Мmс╗Н╠А с║╕╠Аkс╗Н╠Б ├аti с║╕╠Аs├мn (Theology). F├║n ├мd├н ├иy├н, ├│ kс║╣╠Бkс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Б ├Мmс╗Н╠А с║╕╠Аkс╗Н╠Б ├аti с║╕╠Аs├мn n├б├а n├н Yunif├бs├нt├м Ifс║╣╠А (Yunif├бs├нt├м с╗Мb├бfс║╣╠Бmi Aw├│lс╗Н╠Бwс╗Н╠А b├бy├м├н)L├бti OAU, Igwe darapс╗Н╠А mс╗Н╠Б MNET short celluloid film \\"Barbers Wisdom\\" gс║╣╠Бgс║╣╠Б b├нi ol├╣dar├н, ├│ tс║╣╠Аs├нw├бj├║ l├бti lс╗Н s├н Yunif├бs├нt├м ├Мjс╗Нba ├Аpapс╗Н╠А t├н ├мl├║ ├Мb├аd├аn, n├нbi t├н ├│ ti gba ├▓ye EM-EE (MA) n├нn├║ ├Мmс╗Н╠А Library and Information Sciences. L├бs├мk├▓ t├н ├│ jс║╣╠Б ├аg├╣nb├бnirс╗Н╠А ├│ jс║╣╠Б akс╗Н╠Аw├й ar├мnr├мn-├аj├▓ f├║n Scripture Union. ├У s├м с╣г├нс╣гe gс║╣╠Бgс║╣╠Б b├нi Al├бс╣гс║╣ ol├╣dar├н n├н Il├йс║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б Yunif├бs├нt├м ├Мmс╗Н╠А ├Иrс╗Н Anambra ni Eida Information Systems k├н ├│ t├│ fi ├аd├аgb├а ├иt├▓ rс╗Н╠А s├н agbo ├аwс╗Нn al├бtin├║d├б├а. ├У fс║╣╠Б с╗Нkс╗Н rс║╣╠А Charles Igwe n├н Oс╣г├╣ Igbe ni с╗Нd├║n 1993, wс╗Н╠Бn s├м b├н с╗Нmс╗Н mс║╣╠Бta.Al├бс╣гeyor├н ├▓╟╣kс╗Н╠Аw├й, ol├│t├╣├║, ol├╣dar├н, on├нс╣г├▓w├▓ ├аti ol├╣kс╗Н╠Б ni Igwe. Aс╣г├б├бj├║ F├н├мm├╣ ├аti Dirama ay├й ├▓de ├▓n├н t├н N├а├мj├нr├н├а ni. ├У di gbaj├║gbaj├а gс║╣╠Бgс║╣╠Б b├н ├▓╟╣kс╗Н╠Аt├аn ├аti ol├│t├╣├║ er├й \\"Checkmate\\" ├аti *Fuji House of Commotion\\". L├бra ├аwс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣╠Б rс║╣╠А ni Nollywood ni Rattle snake ├аti Violated t├н ├│ ya il├йeс╣гс║╣╠Б Amaka Igwe Studio sс╗Н╠Бtс╗Н╠А l├бs├мk├▓ f├н├мm├╣ ├аgb├йl├йw├▓ l├бy├й sinim├б n├н N├а├мj├нr├н├а. ├Тun l├│ d├б BOBTV Exp s├нlс║╣╠А, ├Тun s├м ni ol├╣d├бs├нlс║╣╠А ├аti Al├бс╣гс║╣ R├йd├н├▓ TOP 90.9Fam t├│ w├а n├н ├мgboro ├Иk├│, The quality content production House, Amaka Igwe Studios ├аti Q Entertainment Networks and ├мk├аnn├м DSTV.├Аw├╣jс╗Н k├▓ n├н gb├аgb├й ipa ribiribi t├н Igwe k├▓ l├бti m├║ ├мgb├йga b├б f├н├мm├╣ с╣г├нс╣гe, b├н ├│ tilс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б p├й wс╗Н╠Бn k├▓ ka agbo ├▓с╣г├иr├й s├н p├аt├аk├м n├нgb├а kan, s├нbс║╣╠А Il├йeс╣гс║╣╠Б Amaka Studio gb├мy├аnj├║ p├║pс╗Н╠А l├бti m├║ ├мd├аgb├аs├│k├и ba, ├аti ├ас╣гeyс╗Нr├н k├н wс╗Н╠Бn s├м jс║╣╠Б ├мw├║r├н f├║n с╗Н╠Аpс╗Н╠Аlс╗Нpс╗Н╠А n├нn├║ ├аwс╗Нn ├▓с╣г├иr├й n├нlс║╣╠А N├а├мj├нr├н├а, ├аwс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н or├нlс║╣╠А├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а ├аti ├аgb├бy├й l├бpapс╗Н╠А.├Мbс║╣╠Аr├╣ ├аti ├мbс╗Н╠Аwс╗Н╠А f├║n с╗Мlс╗Н╠Бrun, ├аwс╗Нn с║╣b├м rс║╣╠А, ├ас╣гeyege, iс╣гс║╣╠Б gidi rс║╣╠А, ├аti ├ас╣г├а l├бk├▓├│t├бn jс║╣╠Б ├аb├╣d├б p├аt├аk├м Amaka. ├У fс║╣╠Бr├аn ├аwс╗Нn с║╣╠Аb├н rс║╣╠А, ├│ s├м pinnu l├бti m├б fi wс╗Н╠Бn s├нlс║╣╠А n├нgb├а kankan. Amaka Igwe m├║ ├мd├аgb├аs├│k├и ba awon ├и├иy├аn, ├аwс╗Нn s├м ni с║╣╠Аr├н rс║╣╠А d├▓n├н. ├У s├бb├а m├бa ┼Д sс╗Н f├║n ├аwс╗Нn t├н ├│ ┼Д kс╗Н╠Б n├нс╣гс║╣╠Б t├а├аr├а p├й ├▓un y├│├▓ fi ohunk├│hun t├н ├▓un b├б n├н с╣гe ├аl├йk├║n ├▓un ti o w├а lс╗Н╠Бwс╗Н╠Б tiwс╗Нn k├н wс╗Н╠Бn l├и d├бra ju ├▓un lс╗Н. K├▓ h├╣w├а ├аf├иmi-├аf├иmi, ├│ s├м faraj├мn f├║n ├мd├аgb├аs├│k├и ├аti ├мsс╗Нlс╗Н╠Бjс╗Н agbo ├аwс╗Нn al├бtin├║d├б.Igwe gba ├аwс╗Нn ├аm├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ n├нgb├а ay├й rс║╣╠А. N├н с╗Нd├║n 2011, Or├нlс║╣╠А├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а fi oy├и MFR - с╗Мmс╗Н с║╕gbс║╣╠Б Or├нlс║╣╠А├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а (Member of the Federal Republic of Nigeria) da lс╗Н╠Бl├б f├║n ├мmс╗Нr├нr├м akitiyan ├аti ipa p├аt├аk├м rс║╣╠А s├н ├аw├╣jс╗Н ├аwс╗Нn al├бtin├║d├б.Ni с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kej├м, Oс╣г├╣ с╣в├йс║╣╠Бrс║╣╠Б, Google fi Google Doddle с╣гe ├аjс╗Нyс╗Н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Бс╗Н╠Аb├н Kс║╣t├аd├нnlс╗Н╠Бgс╗Н╠Бta f├║n-un.Igwe k├║ n├н Enugu n├н с╗Нjс╗Н╠Б kс║╣t├аd├нnlс╗Н╠Бgbс╗Н╠Аn, Oс╣г├╣ Igbe с╗Нd├║n 2014, ni alс║╣╠Б aago mс║╣╠Бjс╗Н ├аbс╗Н╠А. Gbogbo ├мgb├мy├аnj├║ l├бti d├│├▓l├а с║╣m├н rс║╣╠А lс╗Н╠Бwс╗Н╠Б p├нpel├йke ikс╗Н╠Б-s├иm├м├н-s├иm├м├н t├н ├│ ┼Д b├б f├нnra l├│ j├б s├н p├аb├│. G├│m├мn├а ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А Imo n├нgb├а n├б├а Rochas Okorocha lс╗Н s├н ├иt├▓ ├мs├мnk├║ rс║╣╠А, b├бkan n├б├а ni ├аwс╗Нn ├и├иk├аn n├н agbo ├аwс╗Нn ├▓с╣г├иr├й."},{"question":"╨н╨╗ ╨╢╨╛╨╝╨╛╨│╤Г╨╜╨░╨╜: ╨е╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨Ъ╨░╤А╨░╤З╨░╤З ╤Б╤Г╤А╨░╨│╨░╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╥г╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤В╨░╨▒╤Л╤И╨╝╨░╨║╤В╤Л╨╜ ╤З╨╡╤З╨╝╨╡╨╗╨╡╨╜╨╕╤И╨╕ ╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣?","answer":"╨Р╤В╨░╨╗╨░╤А, ╨░╨│╨░╨╗╨░╤А, ╨╝╨╡╨╜ ╨╢╤Л╤А╤В╨║╤Л╤З ╨░╨╣╨▒╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╤Б╤Г╤А╨░╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╡╤Б ╤Н╨╗╨╡╨╝. ╨Ъ╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л╨╝╨░ ╨▒╨╛╤И╤В╨╛╨╜╨┤╤Г╨║ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╡ ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨┐, ╨▒╨╛╤И╤В╨╛╨╜╨┤╤Г╨║ ╤Б╤Г╤А╨░╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Н╨╗╨╡╨╝. ╨Ь╨╡╨╜ ╨░╨╣╤В╨║╨░╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╥г ╨╝╨░╨╗ ╤Н╨╝╨╡╤Б, ╤Б╨╕╨╗╨╡╤А ╙й╨╖╥п╥г╙й╤А ╨╛╨╣╨╗╨╛╨┐ ╨║╙й╤А╤Б╙й╥г╥п╨╖╨┤╙й╤А, ╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Н╨║╙й╙й╨▒╥п╨╖╨┤╥п╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л╨▒╤Л╨╖╨│╨░ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨╡ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╤В╨░╨▒╤Л╤И╨╝╨░╨║. ╨Ъ╨░╨╗╤Л╥г ╨╝╨░╨╗╨│╨░ ╨╛╨╜ ╤Г╨╗╨░╨║ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╕╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨╢╨░╤И╤Л╨╝ ╨╛╨╜╨┤╨╛, ╤Г╨╗╨░╨║╤В╨░╨╣ ╨╛╨╣╨╜╨╛╨│╨╛╨╜ ╨║╤Л╨╖ ╨║╨╡╨╖╨╕╨╝, ╨╢╤Л╨╣╤Л╤А╨╝╨░ ╤В╥п╨╗╨║╥п ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╕╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕ ╨╢╤Л╨╣╤Л╤А╨╝╨░╨│╨░ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░ ╤В╥п╨╗╨║╥п╨┤╙й╨╣ ╨▒╤Г╨╗╨░╨║╤В╨░╨▒╨░╨╣╨▒╤Л, ╨╛╤В╤Г╨╖ ╨║╨░╤А╤Л╤И╨║╤Л╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨╛╤В╤Г╨╖╨│╨░ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨║╨░╤А╤Л╤И╨║╤Л╤А╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨╢╥п╤В╨║╥п╨╜╨▒╙й╨╣╨▒╥п. ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨║ ╨░╤А╤Б╤В╨░╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╨║╤Л╤А╨║╨║╨░ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨░╤А╤Б╤В╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨║╥п╤З╥п╨╜╙й ╨║╨╡╨╗╨▒╨╡╨╣╨▒╨╕, ╤Н╨╗╥п╥п ╨░╤В ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╕╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╤Н╨╗╥п╥п╨┤╙й ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨░╤В ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╨▒╤Г. ╨Р╨╗╤В╤Л╨╝╤Л╤И ╤З╨╕╨┤╨╡╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╨░╨╗╤В╤Л╨╝╤Л╤И╤В╨░╨│╤Л ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨▒╤Г╤В╤Г╨╜╨░ ╤З╨╕╨┤╨╡╤А ╤В╥п╤И╥п╨┐, ╙й╨╖╥п╨╜╤З╙й ╨▒╨░╤Б╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╡ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝. ╨Ц╨╡╤В╨╕╨╝╨╕╤И ╨░╤А╨║╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╕╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨╕╨╝╨╕╤И╨║╨╡ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨░╤А╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╨▒╤Л. ╨б╨╡╨║╤Б╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╜╤Л ╨╢╨╛╨║ ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╨║ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╕╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╤Б╨╡╨║╤Б╨╡╨╜╨│╨╡ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨║╨░╨╜╤Л ╨╢╨╛╨║ ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╨║╤В╙й╨╣ ╨║╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨▒╨░╨╣╨▒╤Л. ╨Ь╤Г╥г╤Г ╨╢╨╛╨║ ╨║╨░╤А╤В╨░╥г ╨╝╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╨│╨╛ ╨╜╨╕╨║╨╡╨╝╨┤╨╕ ╨║╤Л╨╣╨┤╤Л╤А╤Б╤Л╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝, ╨║╨░╤А╤В╨░╥г ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨╕╤З╨╕╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨░╨┐╨░- ╨║╨░╨╣╨│╤Л╤Б╤Л ╨╢╨╛╨║, ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨┤╨░ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╤В. ╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╜╨┤╤Г╨║╤В╨░╨╜, ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨╜╨╕╨║╨╡╨╝╨┤╨╕ ╨║╤Л╨╣╨┤╤Л╤А╨░ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣, ╨╝╨░╨│╨░ ╤Г╤А╤Г╨║╤Б╨░╤В ╨▒╨╡╤А╨▒╨╡╨╣╨▒╨╕,- ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╜╨│╨░ ╨║╨░╤А╨░╤В╨░ ╨░╨╣╤В╨║╨░╨╜ ╤В╨░╨▒╤Л╤И╨╝╨░╨║╤В╤Г╤Г ╤Б╤Г╤А╨╛╨╛╨╝ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╤З╤Г. ╨г╤И╤Г╨╗ ╨╛╨╗╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╨░╨║╤Б╨░╨║╨░╨╗╨┤╨░╤А, ╨║╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐, ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╤Б╤Г╤А╨╛╨╛╨╝╨┤╤Г ╤В╨╡╨║╤И╨╡╤А╨╕╨┐ ╨║╙й╤А╨│╥п╨╗╙й╤З╥п, ╨░╨╣╤В╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п╨╝╨┤╥п╨╜ ╨║╨░╤В╨░╤Б╤Л ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛ ╨║╨░╨╣╤В╨░ ╨░╨╗╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜. ╨С╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛, ╨║╨░╨╜╨│╨░ ╤В╨╕╨╣╨▒╨╡╨╣╨╝╨╕╨╜! ╨Ъ╨░╨╜ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п╨╝ ╤Н╨╝╨╡╤Б╨┐╨╕. ╨С╤Г╨╗ ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п╨╝╨┤╥п ╨╛╨╣╨╗╨╛╨┐ ╤З╨╡╤З╨╕╨┐, ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╨║╤Л╨╣╨╜╨╛╨╛╨┤╨╛╨╜ ╨▒╨╛╤И╨╛╤В╤Г╨┐, ╤Г╤А╤Г╨║╤Б╨░╤В ╨▒╨╡╤А╥п╥п╥г╥п╨╖╨┤╙й╤А╨┤╥п ╤Б╤Г╤А╨░╨╣╨╝╤Л╨╜,- ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨║╤Л╨╖ ╨░╨╣╤В╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜.╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╜╨┤╨╛ ╨╛╨╗╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╤Н╨╗╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨╕╤З╨╕╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨░╨║╤Б╨░╨║╨░╨╗ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝:- ╨С╨░╨╗╨░╨╝, ╨║╤Л╨╖ ╨Ъ╨░╤А╨░╤З╨░╤З, ╨▒╨░╨║╤В╤Л╥г ╨░╤З╤Л╨╗╤Б╤Л╨╜, ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г╥г ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╤Г╨╜,- ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╜ ╤Г╤А╤Г╨║╤Б╨░╤В╤Б╤Л╨╖ ╤Н╨╗╨╡, ╨║╤Л╨╖╨│╨░ ╨▒╨░╤В╨░ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╡╤В.╨Ъ╨░╨╜ ╨░╨║╤Б╨░╨║╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п╨╜ ╨║╤Г╨▒╨░╤В╤В╨░╨┐, ╨╛╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨║ ╤Н╨┤╨┤╨╡╤А ╤З╤Г╤А╤Г╨╗╨┤╨░╨┐ ╨║╨╛╤И╨╛ ╨▒╨░╤В╨░ ╨║╤Л╨╗╨░╤В. ╨Ъ╨░╨╜ ╨║╙й╨┐╤З╥п╨╗╥п╨║ ╤Н╨╗╨┤╨╡╨╜ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨║╤Л╨╖╨│╨░ ╤Г╤А╤Г╨║╤Б╨░╤В ╨▒╨╡╤А╥п╥п╨│╙й ╨░╨╝╨░╨╗╤Б╤Л╨╖╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨╝╨░╨║╤Г╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В. ╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╗ ╨║╤Л╨╖ ╨Р╨║╤Л╨╗ ╨Ъ╨░╤А╨░╤З╨░╤З ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨░╨║╤Л╨╗╨┤╤Г╤Г╨╗╤Г╨│╤Г╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐, ╤Н╨╗ ╨╛╨╛╨╖╤Г╨╜╨┤╨░ ╤Б╙й╨╖ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ╪з┘Д╪з╪│┘Е ╪з┘Д╪н╪п┘К╪л ┘Д╪г╪▒╪╢ ┘Б╪з┘Ж ╪п┘К┘Е ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪г╪╡╪и╪н╪к ╪з┘Д╪в┘Ж ╪м╪▓╪б┘Л╪з ┘Е┘Ж ╪м╪▓┘К╪▒╪й ┘Е┘Ж ╪г╪▒╪з╪╢┘К ╪г╪│╪к╪▒╪з┘Д┘К╪з╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪к╪│┘Е╪з┘Ж┘К╪з"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Gear├│id Mac Gearailt. ","answer":"Ba ├й an Dr. Gear├│id Mac Gearailt (B├йarla: Garret Fitzgerald; 9 Feabhra 1926 - 19 Bealtaine 2011) an seacht├║ Taoiseach ar Phoblacht na h├Йireann. Bh├н s├й mar Aire Gn├│tha├н Eachtracha ├│ 1973 go 1977, nuair a ceapadh mar cheannaire ar Fhine Gael ├й. Chaith s├й dh├б th├йarma mar Thaoiseach, an ch├йad cheann idir I├║il 1981 agus Feabhra 1982, agus an dara ceann idir m├н na Nollag 1982 agus m├н an Mh├бrta 1987.Ceaptar go forleathan san 1980id├н gurbh eisean an ceannaire ab fhearr de chuid Fhine Gael le blianta. Le linn a shaoil mar pholaiteoir bh├н an-ghnaoi air - ghlaoigh gach taobh an t-ainm 'Garret' air, mar shampla. Lena n├бd├║r cuideacht├║il, an cumas a bh├н aige labhairt n├нos tap├║la n├б mar a cheap daoine a d'fh├йadfa├н a dh├йanamh agus an dealramh a bh├н aige le hollamh dearmadach, ba pholaiteoir feidhmi├║il ├й ├│ th├бinig s├й isteach sa saol polaiti├║il i l├бr na 1960├н go dt├н gur ├йirigh s├й as sa bhliain 1992.Ba mhac le Desmond Mac Gearailt ├й, a bh├н ina Aire Gn├│tha├н Seachtracha (an seanainm a bh├н ar an Roinn Gn├│tha├н Eachtracha roimh 1972) i rith na 1920id├н. Bh├н Desmond ar dhuine de bhunaitheoir├н Chumann na nGaedhael, p├бirt├н polaiti├║il a buna├нodh chun taca├нocht a thabhairt don Chonradh Angla-├Йireannach a s├нn├нodh i 1921 idir an Bhreatain agus ├Йire chun Saorst├бt ├Йireann a bhun├║.C├й gur dhuine sinsearach ├й a athair ar thaobh an chonartha i ndeighilt pholaiti├║il na h├Йireann (troideadh Cogadh Cathartha idir lucht an chonartha agus an dream a bh├н ina choinne i 1922 agus 1923), choinnigh s├й a chuid cairde i measc an dreama a bh├н i gcoinne an chonartha, leith├йid├н Se├бn Mac an tSaoi, a bh├н ina Aire i rialtas ├Йamoin de Valera. I gcontr├бrthacht lena athair, ba Phrotast├║nach ├н a mh├бthair Mabel, a bh├н n├н ba phoblachta├н n├б a athair. Is isteach sa mheasc├бn sin, trasna na deighilte polaiti├║la, a rugadh Gear├│id."},{"question":"Siapakah Chelsia Ng? ","answer":"Chelsia Ng ialah seorang pelakon dan penyanyi wanita Malaysia yang berasal dari Pulau Pinang."},{"question":"рк╣рк╛ркИркХрлБ ркПркЯрк▓рлЗ рк╢рлБ ?","answer":"рк╣рк╛ркИркХрлБ ркЕркерк╡рк╛ рк╕ркдрлНркдрк░рк╛ркХрлНрк╖рк░рлА ркП рккрк╛ркВркЪ, рк╕рк╛ркд ркЕркирлЗ рккрк╛ркВркЪ ркЕркХрлНрк╖рк░рлЛркирлА ркЕркирлБркХрлНрк░ркорлЗ ркдрлНрк░ркг рккркВркХрлНркдрк┐ркУркирлЛ ркмркирлЗрк▓рлЛ ркЬрк╛рккрк╛ркирлА ркХрк╡рк┐ркдрк╛ркирлЛ ркЕркдрк┐ркЯрлВркВркХрлЛ ркЕркирлЗ ркЕркдрк┐ рккрлНрк░ркдрк┐рк╖рлНркарк╛ рккрк╛ркорлЗрк▓рлЛ ркХрк╛рк╡рлНркпрккрлНрк░ркХрк╛рк░ ркЫрлЗ. рк╕ркдрлНркдрк░ ркЕркХрлНрк╖рк░рлЛркирлЛ ркмркирлЗрк▓рлЛ ркЖ ркХрк╛рк╡рлНркпрккрлНрк░ркХрк╛рк░ ркХрлЛркИ ркПркХ ркнрк╛рк╡, ркХрк▓рлНрккрки ркХрлЗ рк╕ркВрк╡рлЗркЧ ркЬркЧрк╛ркбрлЗ ркЫрлЗ. ркЕркВркЧрлНрк░рлЗркЬрлА рк╕рк╛рк╣рк┐ркдрлНркпркорк╛ркВ рккркг ркЖ ркХрк╛рк╡рлНркпрккрлНрк░ркХрк╛рк░ ркЦрлЗркбрк╛ркпрлЛ ркЫрлЗ. ркЧрлБркЬрк░рк╛ркдрлА ркЕркирлЗ ркЕркирлНркп ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп ркнрк╛рк╖рк╛ркУркорк╛ркВ рккркг ркПркирк╛ рккрлНрк░ркпрлЛркЧрлЛ ркеркпрк╛ ркЫрлЗ. ркЧрлБркЬрк░рк╛ркдрлА рк╕рк╛рк╣рк┐ркдрлНркпркорк╛ркВ рк╣рк╛ркИркХрлБ ркХрк╛рк╡рлНркпрккрлНрк░ркХрк╛рк░ркирлЗ рккрлНрк░ркдрк┐рк╖рлНркарк┐ркд ркХрк░рк╡рк╛ркорк╛ркВ рк╕рлНркирлЗрк╣рк░рк╢рлНркорк┐ркирлЛ ркорк╣ркдрлНрк╡ркирлЛ рклрк╛рк│рлЛ ркЫрлЗ. рк╕рлНркирлЗрк╣рк░рк╢рлНркорк┐ркирлЛ рк╣рк╛ркИркХрлБ рк╕ркВркЧрлНрк░рк╣ рк╕рлЛркирлЗрк░рлА ркЪрк╛ркВркж рк░рлВрккрлЗрк░рлА рк╕рлВрк░ркЬ рлзрлпрлмрлмркорк╛ркВ рккрлНрк░ркЧркЯ ркеркпрлЛ рк╣ркдрлЛ."},{"question":"╬Я╬╗╬┐╬║╬╗╬о╧Б╧Й╧Г╬╡ ╧Д╬╖╬╜ ╬▒╬║╧М╬╗╬┐╧Е╬╕╬╖ ╧Ж╧Б╬м╧Г╬╖: O Piquet Jr. ╧Г╧Е╬╜╬╡╧Д╧Б╬п╬▓╬╖ ╧Г╧Д╬┐ 2008 Grand Prix ╧Д╬╖╧В ╬г╬╣╬│╬║╬▒╧А╬┐╧Н╧Б╬╖╧В","answer":"╬С╬╝╬н╧Г╧Й╧В ╬╝╬╡╧Д╬м ╬▒╧А╧М ╬╝╬╣╬▒ ╧А╧Б╧М╧Й╧Б╬╖ ╧Г╧Д╬м╧Г╬╖ ╬│╬╣╬▒ ╧Д╬┐╬╜ ╬ж╬╡╧Б╬╜╬м╬╜╧Д╬┐ ╬С╬╗╧М╬╜╧Г╬┐, ╬▓╬│╬м╬╢╬┐╬╜╧Д╬▒╧В ╧Д╬┐ ╬▒╧Е╧Д╬┐╬║╬п╬╜╬╖╧Д╬┐ ╬▒╧Г╧Ж╬▒╬╗╬╡╬п╬▒╧В. ╬Ъ╬▒╬╕╧О╧В ╧Д╬▒ ╬▒╧Е╧Д╬┐╬║╬п╬╜╬╖╧Д╬▒ ╬╝╧А╧Б╬┐╧Г╧Д╬м ╬▒╧А╧М ╧Д╬┐╬╜ ╬С╬╗╧М╬╜╧Г╬┐ ╧А╬о╬│╬▒╬╜ ╬│╬╣╬▒ ╬║╬▒╧Н╧Г╬╣╬╝╬▒ ╬║╬м╧Д╧Й ╬▒╧А╧М ╧Д╬┐ ╬▒╧Е╧Д╬┐╬║╬п╬╜╬╖╧Д╬┐ ╬▒╧Г╧Ж╬▒╬╗╬╡╬п╬▒╧В, ╧А╧Б╬┐╧З╧О╧Б╬╖╧Г╬╡ ╧Г╧Д╬╖╬╜ ╬┐╬╝╬м╬┤╬▒ ╬│╬╣╬▒ ╬╜╬▒ ╧А╬м╧Б╬╡╬╣ ╧Д╬╖ ╬╜╬п╬║╬╖. ╬Я ╬а╬╣╬║╬н ╬д╬╢╬┐╧Н╬╜╬╣╬┐╧Б ╬▒╧А╬┐╬╗╧Н╬╕╬╖╬║╬╡ ╬╝╬╡╧Д╬м ╧Д╬┐ 2009 ╧Г╧Д╬┐ Grand Prix ╧Д╬╖╧В ╬Я╧Е╬│╬│╬▒╧Б╬п╬▒╧В."},{"question":"Ki sa fotosent├иz ye?","answer":"Gen plizy├и milya kreyati ki abs├▓be oksij├иn e ki rejte diyoksid kab├▓n. Malgre sa, toujou gen oksij├иn, e gaz yo rejte a, anpalan de diyoksid kab├▓n nan, pa janm toufe atmosf├и a. Sa k f├и sa? N ap jwenn repons lan nan yon pwosesis estraw├▓din├и ki rele fotosent├иz. Grasa pwosesis sa a, plant ki v├иt yo pran nan diyoksid kab├▓n, nan dlo, nan limy├и sol├иy la ak nan bagay ki p├иm├иt plant yo grandi a e yo pwodui idrat kab├▓n ak oksij├иn. Nou konplete sik la l├и nou respire oksij├иn nan."},{"question":"с╗Мwс╗Н с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ti tс║╣ mс║╣ta ninu awс╗Нn Fulani to fibс╗Нn fс╗Н с║╣nu iya oniyaa nтАЩIjс║╣bu-Oru","answer":"Kс╗Нmandi с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ipinlс║╣ Ogun ti mu mс║╣ta ninu awс╗Нn Fulani to kс╗Н lu iya kan, Morounkeji Salami, lopin с╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja yii, ti wс╗Нn yinbс╗Нn fun un, ti wс╗Нn tun с╣гa a ladaa kari ara lagbegbe Ijс║╣bu-Oru, nipinlс║╣ Ogun.Nigba to n sс╗Н bi с╗Нwс╗Н с╣гe ba wс╗Нn, Alukoro с╗Нlс╗Нpaa nipinlс║╣ Ogun, DSP Abimbс╗Нla Oyeyс║╣mi, с╣гalaye fтАЩALAROYE pe lс║╣yin tawс╗Нn Fulani naa yinbс╗Нn mс╗Н iya yii tan ni wс╗Нn sa wс╗Нgbo lс╗Н, ti wс╗Нn si fi awс╗Нn maaluu wс╗Нn silс║╣. O ni nigba ti olobo ta awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa agbegbe yii lori ikс╗Нlu naa, wс╗Нn lс╗Н sibс║╣, wс╗Нn si fara с╣гoko sibi kan lati mс╗Н boya awс╗Нn Fulani naa yoo tun yс╗Нju lati waa ko awс╗Нn maaluu wс╗Нn nigba ti ilс║╣ ba rс╗Н.Bс║╣с║╣ naa lo si ri, awс╗Нn Fulani с╗Нhun pada wa lati ko maaluu wс╗Нn, nigba naa lс╗Нwс╗Н ba mс║╣ta ninu wс╗Нn. Alukoro ti ni awс╗Нn yoo ri i daju pe с╗Нwс╗Н ba awс╗Нn marun-un yooku laipс║╣.с╣вe с╣гaaju ni iroyin ti tan kalс║╣ pс║╣lu fidio kan to с╣гafihan Abilekс╗Н Morunkeji pс║╣lu bandeeji lori, ati с╗Нgbс║╣ oriс╣гiiriс╣гii lara rс║╣.Lasiko yii si ree, Alukoro sс╗Н pe boya yoo ku tabi yoo ye ni mama naa wa lс╗Нsibitu (Danger list), nitori yatс╗Н si pe wс╗Нn yinbс╗Нn fun un ti atanpako osi rс║╣ si ge danu lori ere, awс╗Нn Fulani naa tun с╣гa a ladaa kaakiri ara, iyс║╣n lo si fa с╗Нgbс║╣ oriс╣гiiriс╣гii to wa lara obinrin naa.Oko ni iya yii n lс╗Н nigba to с╣гalabapade awс╗Нn Fulani с╗Нhun, inu mс╗Нto rс║╣ lo wa lasiko to ri awс╗Нn maaluu rс║╣pс║╣tс║╣. Ara fu u, o si fс║╣с║╣ с╣гс║╣ri mс╗Нto rс║╣ pada, с╣гugbс╗Нn niс╣гe lawс╗Нn Fulani naa ya jade lati inu igbo, wс╗Нn yinbс╗Нn si taya mс╗Нto rс║╣ mс║╣rс║╣с║╣rin ko maa baa le lс╗Н mс╗Н, awс╗Нn taya naa jo lс║╣sс║╣kс║╣sс║╣, nigba naa lawс╗Нn Fulani с╗Нhun dana ibс╗Нn bo iya yii, ti wс╗Нn tun с╣гa a ladaa mс╗Н с╗Нn.Atanpako osi pс║╣lu a╠Аgbс╗Нn╠А iya to n jс║╣ Morunkeji yii ni wс╗Нn yinbс╗Нn mс╗Н с╗Нn, bi ko si jс║╣ pe с╗Мlс╗Нrun ni с║╣mi rс║╣ i lo ni, awс╗Нn to yinbс╗Нn fun un ko fс║╣ ko ye rara, nitori wс╗Нn tun n yс║╣ с║╣ wo ninu mс╗Нto naa pe boya o ti ku, bс║╣с║╣ naa ni wс╗Нn si n pe e wo lati mс╗Н boya с║╣mi ti bс╗Н lara с║╣.Nitori mama yii pirс╗Нrс╗Н fun wс╗Нn bii с║╣ni to ti ku loootс╗Н ni wс╗Нn с╣гe fi i silс║╣ ti wс╗Нn sa wс╗Нgbo lс╗Н, ko too di pe iya naa pada ri aanu gba latс╗Нwс╗Н awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нkс╗Н mi-in to n kс╗Нja, ti wс╗Нn gbe e lс╗Н sс╗Нsibitu bii meji nтАЩIjс║╣bu, ti wс╗Нn ko gba a nibс║╣, ki wс╗Нn too waa gba a lтАЩEkoo, ni jс║╣nс║╣ra to wa nтАЩIkс║╣ja.с╣вugbс╗Нn titi ta a fi pari iroyin yii, с║╣sс║╣ kan aye, с║╣sс║╣ kan с╗Нrun, ni Abilekс╗Н Morounkeji Salami wa."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe demokrasia?","answer":"Rafitra fitondrana izay ampiasainтАЩny vahoaka ny fahefana, matetika aminтАЩny alalanтАЩny solombavambahoaka voafidy."},{"question":"р╢╢р╖Фр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╖Фр╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢Вр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ ( р╢┤р╢╗р╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢о ) р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║ р╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕ р╖Ар╖Рр╢йр╖У р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ер╢║р╢з р╢┤р╢╕р╢лр╖Т .\\" р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║ р╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕ \\" р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢п ?","answer":"р╖Гр╢пр╖Кр╢░р╖П , р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢║ , р╖Гр╢нр╖Т , р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢░р╖Т , р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢ер╖П ."},{"question":"Siapakah Pete Teo? Jelaskan dalam ayat-ayat yang tidak melebihi 480 patah perkataan. ","answer":"Pete Teo (Cina: х╝ахнРхдл, lahir 26 Disember 1972 di Tawau, Sabah), ialah seorang penyanyi-penggubah lagu Malaysia, dan juga seorang penerbit filem dan penerbit muzik yang tersanjung dalam persada 'Perfileman Malaysia Alaf Baru'.Selama kerjayanya, beliau telah menghasilkan dua buah album - Rustic Living for Urbanites (2003, diterbit oleh Ronan Chris Murphy) dan Television (2006, diterbit oleh Nick Lee dan Pete Teo) di bawah naungan label yang didirikan beliau sendiri Redbag Music. Kini bertapak di Kuala Lumpur, Teo kini merupakan salah seorang penyanyi-komposer paling dikenali di Malaysia. Beliau juga menceburi bidang lakonan dalam persada yang dikenali sebagai \\"Sinema Malaysia Gelombang Baru\\" (New Wave Malaysian Cinema).Album pertamanya Rustic Living For Urbanites memenangi kategori Kulit Album Terbaik manakala salah satu daripada lagunya Arms of Marianne merangkul gelaran Video Muzik Terbaik di Anugerah Industri Muzik pada tahun 2004. Album keduanya, Television - album berunsur lagu rakyat alternatif yang diisi dengan refleksi terhadap dunia yang kuat dipengaruhi media dan gelombang Americana - memenangi ketiga-tiga kategori yang mencalonkannya pada AIM 2007, iaitu Kulit Album Terbaik, Video Muzik Terbaik dan Album Bahasa Inggeris Terbaik - yang mana beliau paling banyak menerima anugerah pada malam itu, menjadikan beliau artis indie bukan berarus perdana yang memenangi anugerah terbanyak dalam sejarah AIM.Tambahan pula, video muzik bagi salah satu lagu dari Television, Carnival Hall, membawa kejayaan kepada Kamal Sabran yang memenangi pertandingan merakam video muzik serantau You Make It Reel! (peringkat negara, Malaysia) anjuran Nokia pada awal tahun 2006.Teo juga kerap bermain di konsert-konsert muzik di luar negara. Beliau ialah pemuzik Malaysia yang pertama sekali untuk dijemput untuk membuat persembahan di Konsert South By Southwest (2007). Selain itu dia juga kerap mengunjungi Jepun untuk menjalankan jelajah.Pada tahun 2008, Teo mengelola satu inisiatif bernama \\"Malaysian Artistes for Unity\\" yang disertai 52 artis Malaysia kesemuanya untuk tujuan memupuk perpaduan yang merentasi sempadan kaum dan rasa setia kepada negara di kalangan rakyat Malaysia. Ini disusuli pada tahun seterusnya oleh projek 15Malaysia yang memaparkan 15 buah filem pendek dari pengarah terkenal negara yang mencerminkan isu sosiopolitik semasa. Pada tahun 2009 juga, Teo menyumbangkan beberapa buah lagu untuk filem Talentime.In November 2009, on the strength of the influential 'Malaysian Artistes For Unity' music video and the seminal '15Malaysia' project, CNN listed Teo as amongst the top 135 People To Watch in Asia.Pada Januari 2010, lagu \\"Pergi\\" iaitu versi bahasa Melayu untuk I Go nyanyian Aizat Amdan memenangi Anugerah Juara Lagu 2009.Pada September 2011, Teo melancarkan satu lagi kempen iaitu Undilah! yang menyeru rakyat Malaysia, khususnya golongan belia, supaya berdaftar sebagai pengundi dan bersedia untuk pilihan raya umum yang seterusnya. Kempen ini mengundang kontroversi apabila berdepan dengan sekatan oleh media arus perdana.Teo memegang watak sebagai Tony dalam filem Amerika Syarikat 2017, Ghost in the Shell, arahan Rupert Sanders lakonan Scarlett Johansson, yang ditayangkan di seluruh dunia pada Mac 2017."},{"question":"╨Ф╥п╨╣╨╜╙й╨┤╙й ╤Н╥г ╨║╙й╨┐ ╤Н╨│╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕ ╤В╙й╤А╙й╨│╙й╨╜ ╨░╤П╨╗ ╨║╨╕╨╝ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜?","answer":"╨Э╨░╨┤╤П ╨б╤Г╨╗╨╡╨╣╨╝╨░╨╜ 2009- ╨╢╤Л╨╗╤Л 8 ╤Н╨╝ ╤Н╨│╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕ ╤В╙й╤А╙й╨┐ ╨┤╥п╨╣╨╜╙й╨│╙й ╨┤╨░╥г╨║╤Л ╤В╨░╤А╨░╨┐ ╨╝╨░╨░╨╗╤Л╨╝╨░╤В ╨║╨░╤А╨░╨╢╨░╤В╤В╨░╤А╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ( ╤В╨╡╨╗╨╡╨▓╨╕╨╖╨╛╤А) ╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜. ╨Э╨░╨┤╤П╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨▒╤Г╨│╨░ ╤З╨╡╨╣╨╕╨╜ 6 ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л ╨▒╨░╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤З╤Г 8 ╤Н╨│╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╤А╨╕ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ 14 ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╤Н╨╜╨╡╤Б╨╕ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л. ╨Ф╨╛╨│╨┤╤Г╤А╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╤И╤Л╨┐ ╨║╙й╨┐ ╤Н╨╝╨▒╤А╨╕╨╛╨╜ ╨║╨╛╤О╨┐ ╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜╨░ ╨▒╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л╤И╤В╤Г╤Г, ╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╙й╨╖╥п ╤З╨╡╤З╨╕╨╝ ╨║╨░╨▒╤Л╨╗ ╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨░╨░╤А╤Л╨╜ ╤В╙й╤А╙й╨╣╨╝╥п╨╜ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╤З╨╡╤З╨╕╨╝ ╨║╨░╨▒╤Л╨╗ ╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜. ╨Ф╨╛╨│╨┤╤Г╤А╨│╨░ ╨┤╨╛╨╛╨╝╨░╤В╤Л ╨╢╨╛╨║ ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╤В╨░╨╜╨┤╨╛╨╛╨╝ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨░╨╣╤В╨░╤В, ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╨╛ ╨┤╨╛╨│╨┤╤Г╤А ╨░╨┤╨░╤И╨║╨░╨╜╤Л ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╝╨░╨╗╨╝╨░╨║. \\"╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╜╤З╨╛ ╤Н╨│╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╕ ╨║╨░╨╣╤Б╤Л ╨░╨║╤Л╨╗╤Л ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╤В╙й╤А╙й╨┤╥п ╨░╨║╤Л╨╗╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨░╨╢╤Л╤А╨░╨┐╤В╤Л╤А, ╨║╨░╨╜╤В╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╝╤Б╤Л╨╖╨┤╨░╨╣╤В\\"- ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨░╤А ╤В╥п╤А╨║╥п╨╜ ╤Б╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╤А ╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╨╗╨│╨░╨╜. \\" ╨Ь╨╡╨╜ ╨╢╙й╨╜ ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╤Б╥п╨╣╥п╨║╤В╥п╥п ╨╝╤Н╤Н╤А╨╕╨╝╨┤╥п╥п ╤Н╨╜╨╡ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨│╤Г╨╝ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨┤╨╕ ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨╢╨░╤И╨╛╨╛╨┤╨╛, ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╤В╨░╨╜╨┤╨╛╨╛╨╝ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╤Н╤З╨║╨╕╨╝ ╤В╨╛╤Б╨║╨╛╨╛╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В\\"-╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨░╨╣╤В╨║╨░╨╜. ╨н╥г ╨║╙й╨┐ ╤Н╨│╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕ ╤В╙й╤А╙й╨│╙й╨╜ ╨░╤П╨╗ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨У╨╕╨╜╨╜╨╡╤Б ╨║╨╕╤В╨╡╨▒╨╕╨╜╨╡ ╨║╨╕╤А╨│╨╡╨╜. ╨Р╨╖╤Л╤А╨║╤Л ╤Г╤З╤Г╤А╨┤╨░ ╨Э╨░╨┤╤П  ╤Н╨│╨╕╨╖ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨┤╨░╤А╤Л 14 ╨╢╨░╤И╤В╨░ ╤Б╨░╨║ ╤Б╨░╨╗╨░╨╝╨░╤В╤В╨░ ╤З╨╛╥г╨╛╤О╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╤И╤В╤Л."},{"question":"Schreiben Sie eine Fortsetzung f├╝r diesen Absatz. Der Kontext ist die Geschichte der \\"Academia Sinica\\", eine taiwanesische Universit├дt:Initiiert durch Li Shizeng, wurde die Academia Sinica am 9. Juni 1928 in der Republik China (mit Niederlassungen in Peking und Shanghai) offiziell gegr├╝ndet. Sein Weggef├дhrte Cai Yuanpei, der nach der Revolution von 1911 erster Erziehungsminister der Republik gewesen war, wurde ihr Pr├дsident.","answer":" Im Zuge des B├╝rgerkrieges und dem Einmarsch japanischer Streitkr├дfte, zog die Academia Sinica mehrmals um. Nachdem im Jahre 1949 die Kommunisten die Kontrolle ├╝ber das Festland gewonnen hatten, wurde die Academia Sinica von der republikanischen Regierung in Taiwan neu etabliert. In den folgenden Jahren der politischen Instabilit├дt ging ihre Entwicklung nur schleppend voran."},{"question":"\\"╨Р╨┤╨░╨╝╨│╨░ ╤Н╥г ╨╛╨╛╤А╤Г - ╨║╥п╨╜ ╤Б╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╤Г\\" ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖ ╨║╨╕╨╝╨│╨╡ ╤В╨░╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║?","answer":"\\"╨Р╨┤╨░╨╝╨│╨░ ╤Н╥г ╨╛╨╛╤А╤Г - ╨║╥п╨╜ ╤Б╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╤Г\\" ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖ ╨з╤Л╨╜╨│╤Л╨╖ ╨Р╨╣╤В╨╝╨░╤В╨╛╨▓╨│╨╛ ╤В╨░╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║."},{"question":"р▓ор│Бр▓Вр▓жр▓┐р▓и р▓кр│Нр▓░р▓╢р│Нр▓ир│Жр▓Чр│Ж р▓Йр▓др│Нр▓др▓░р▓┐р▓╕р▓┐ :  р▓ор│Кр▓жр▓▓ р▓кр▓░р│Нр▓╖р▓┐р▓пр▓ир│Н р▓Чр▓▓р│Нр▓лр│Н р▓пр│Бр▓жр│Нр▓з р▓Ор▓▓р│Нр▓▓р▓┐ р▓ир▓бр│Жр▓пр▓┐р▓др│Б?","answer":"р▓ор│Кр▓жр▓▓ р▓кр▓░р│Нр▓╖р▓┐р▓пр▓ир│Н р▓Чр▓▓р│Нр▓лр│Н р▓пр│Бр▓жр│Нр▓зр▓╡р│Б р▓Зр▓░р▓╛р▓Хр│НтАМр▓ир▓▓р│Нр▓▓р▓┐ р▓ир▓бр│Жр▓пр▓┐р▓др│Б"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп рокро╛ро░роорпНрокро░ро┐ропроорпН роОроирпНрод ро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБ ро╡ро╛ропрпНроирпНродродрпБ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ :родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп рокро╛ро░роорпНрокро░ро┐ропроорпН рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБ ро╡ро╛ропрпНроирпНродродрпБ. родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН рокро▓ рокро┤роорпИропро╛рой роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЙро│рпНро│рой. родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрооро┐ро┤рпН роороХрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИ роорпБро▒рпИ, рокрогрпНрокро╛роЯрпБ, роЪроорпВроХроорпН, роЕро░роЪро┐ропро▓рпН роЖроХро┐ропро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпИ рокро┐ро░родро┐рокро▓ро┐роХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЙро▓роХрпЖроЩрпНроХро┐ро▓рпБроорпН рокроЯро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой."},{"question":"р░Ер░Хр▒Мр░Вр░Яр░┐р░Вр░Чр▒Н р░╕р░ор▒Ар░Хр░░р░г р░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╕р░Вр░Хр▒Нр░▓р░┐р░кр▒Нр░др░Вр░Чр░╛ р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐","answer":"р░Ер░Хр▒Мр░Вр░Яр░┐р░Вр░Чр▒Н р░╕р░ор▒Ар░Хр░░р░г р░жр▒Нр░╡р░Вр░жр░░р▒Вр░к р░нр░╛р░╡р░ир░кр▒И (р░бр▒Жр░мр░┐р░Яр▒Н, р░Хр▒Нр░░р▒Жр░бр░┐р░Яр▒Н) р░Жр░зр░╛р░░р░кр░бр░┐ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░жр░┐. р░Ер░Хр▒Мр░Вр░Яр░┐р░Вр░Чр▒Н р░╕р░ор▒Ар░Хр░░р░г р░╕р░Вр░╕р▒Нр░е р░Жр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓ р░ор▒Кр░др▒Нр░др░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐, р░Ер░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░▓ р░ор▒Кр░др▒Нр░др░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░ор░зр▒Нр░п р░Йр░ир▒Нр░и р░╕р░Вр░мр░Вр░зр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░╡р▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░др░кр░░р▒Бр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐.р░Жр░░р▒Нр░ер░┐р░Х р░╡р░ир░░р▒Бр░▓р▒Б (р░Жр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Б) = р░мр░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░др░▓р▒Б (р░Ер░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░▓р▒Б)р░╕р░ор▒Ар░Хр░░р░г р░жр░┐р░Чр▒Бр░╡ р░╡р░┐р░зр░ор▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐.р░Жр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Б = р░╕р░Вр░╕р▒Нр░ер░Хр▒Бр░ир▒Нр░и р░мр░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░др░▓р▒Бр░▓р▒Зр░жр░╛р░Жр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Б = р░ор▒Вр░▓р░зр░ир░ор▒Б + р░Ер░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░▓р▒Б"},{"question":"рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╛ро░ро┐ройрпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ  роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"роОро╡ройрпН роТро░рпБро╡ройрпН роороХрпНроХро│рпИ ро╡роЮрпНроЪро┐роХрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ройрпЛ, родройродрпБ родрпЗро╡рпИроХрпНроХрпБ роорпАро▒ро┐роп роЪрпКродрпНродрпБ роЪрпЗро░рпНроХрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ройрпЛ роЕро╡ройрпНродро╛ройрпН родро┐ро░рпБроЯройрпН."},{"question":"р░Хр░╡р░┐р░Хр░┐ тАУ р░╢р░┐р░▓р▒Нр░кр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░Чр░▓ р░кр▒Лр░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓р▒Б р░Пр░ор░┐р░Яр░┐?","answer":"р░Хр░╡р░┐ р░Хр░▓р░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Л р░Ер░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░ р░░р░Ър░и р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ер░Яр▒Бр░╡р░Вр░Яр░┐ р░Ер░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░ р░░р░Ър░и р░╢р░┐р░▓р▒Нр░кр░┐ р░Йр░▓р░┐р░▓р▒Л р░Хр▒Вр░б р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ж . р░Ер░Вр░жр▒Бр░╡р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░ир▒З р░╢р░┐р░▓р▒Нр░кр░┐, р░░р░╛р░др░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░Вр░нр░╛р░▓р░кр▒И р░кр▒Вр░▓р░Чр▒Бр░др▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Ър▒Жр░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░др░╛р░бр▒Б.р░╢р░┐р░▓р▒Нр░кр░┐ р░мр▒Кр░ор▒Нр░ор░▓р▒Б р░Ър▒Жр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░┐ р░Тр░Х р░░р░╛р░Ьр▒Б р░Хр░ер░ир▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░кр░░р▒Бр░▓р░Ър▒З р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░Чр░▓р░бр▒Б. р░Хр░╡р░┐р░др▒Нр░╡р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Ър░┐р░др▒Нр░░р░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Хр▒Вр░░р▒Нр░Ър▒З р░Хр░╡р░┐р░Хр▒А, р░╢р░┐р░▓р▒Нр░кр░┐р░Хр▒А р░ир░┐р░Ьр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░др▒Зр░бр░╛ р░▓р▒Зр░жр▒Б. р░Хр░╡р░┐р░др▒Нр░╡р░В р░жр▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р░╛ р░Хр░╡р░┐ р░░р░╛р░Ьр▒Б р░Хр░е р░░р░╛р░пр░Чр░▓р░бр▒Б. р░╢р░┐р░▓р▒Нр░кр░┐ р░др░и р░╢р░┐р░▓р▒Нр░кр░В р░жр▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р░╛ р░░р░╛р░│р▒Нр░│р░кр▒И р░░р░╛р░Ьр▒Бр░Хр░е р░Ър▒Жр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░Чр░▓р░бр▒Б."},{"question":"роХрпАро┤рпЗ роХрпКроЯрпБроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│ рокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроХро│рпИро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ 65 роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ роОрокрпНрокроЯро┐?родрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой рокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроХро│рпН:6 роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ100 роХро┐ро░ро╛роорпН роЪрпЛро│ рооро╛ро╡рпБ50 роХро┐ро░ро╛роорпН роорпИродро╛ рооро╛ро╡рпБ6 роорпЗроЬрпИроХрпНроХро░рогрпНроЯро┐ родропро┐ро░рпН1 роХрпБроЯрпИ рооро┐ро│роХро╛ропрпН3 рокрпВрогрпНроЯрпБ рокро▓рпН1 роЗроЮрпНроЪро┐ родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБ2 роорпЗроЬрпИроХрпНроХро░рогрпНроЯро┐ 65 роороЪро╛ро▓ро╛┬╜ роорпЗроЬрпИроХрпНроХро░рогрпНроЯро┐ рооро┐ро│роХрпБ родрпВро│рпНродрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЕро│ро╡рпБ рооро┐ро│роХро╛ропрпН родрпВро│рпНродрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЕро│ро╡рпБ роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпНродрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЕро│ро╡рпБ роЙрокрпНрокрпБроЪро┐ро▒ро┐родро│ро╡рпБ ро╕рпНрокро┐ро░ро┐роЩрпН роЖройро┐ропройрпН","answer":"роЪрпЖропрпНроорпБро▒рпИ:1. роорпБродро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роХрпБроЯрпИ рооро┐ро│роХро╛ропрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╕рпНрокро┐ро░ро┐роЩрпН роЖройро┐ропройрпИ роиро▒рпБроХрпНроХро┐, рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЗроЮрпНроЪро┐ рокрпВрогрпНроЯрпИ рокрпЗро╕рпНроЯрпН роЖроХрпНроХро┐ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН.2. роЕроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роТро░рпБ роХро┐рогрпНрогродрпНродрпИ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИроХро│рпИ роТро╡рпНро╡рпКройрпНро▒ро╛роХ роЙроЯрпИродрпНродрпБ роКродрпНродро┐ роЕродройрпБроЯройрпН родрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЕро│ро╡рпБ роЙрокрпНрокрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рооро┐ро│роХрпБ родрпВро│рпИ роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роЕродрпИ роиройрпНроХрпБ роЕроЯро┐родрпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН.3. рокро┐ройрпНрокрпБ роТро░рпБ роХро┐рогрпНрогродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роиройрпНро▒ро╛роХ роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпНропрпИ родроЯро╡ро┐ роиро╛роорпН роЕроЯро┐родрпНродрпБ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБро│рпНро│ роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИропрпИ роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роКро▒рпНро▒ро╡рпБроорпН.4. рокро┐ро▒роХрпБ роТро░рпБ роХрпБроХрпНроХро░рпИропрпЛ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЗроЯрпНро▓ро┐ рокро╛родрпНродро┐ро░родрпНродрпИропрпЛ рооро┐родрооро╛рой роЪрпВроЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роЕроЯрпБрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роХро╛ро▓рпН рокро╛роХроорпН роЕро│ро╡рпБ родрогрпНрогрпАро░рпН роКро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роиро╛роорпН роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИропрпИ роКро▒рпНро▒ро┐ ро╡рпИродрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роХро┐рогрпНрогродрпНродрпИ роЕродройрпБро│рпН ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роорпВроЯро┐ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯрпБ роЕродрпИ роЪрпБрооро╛ро░рпН 15 ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ 20 роиро┐рооро┐роЯроорпН ро╡ро░рпИ ро╡рпЗроХ ро╡ро┐роЯро╡рпБроорпН.5. 20 роиро┐рооро┐роЯродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ рокро┐ро▒роХрпБ роорпВроЯро┐ропрпИ родро┐ро▒роирпНродрпБ роТро░рпБ рокро▓рпН роХрпБродрпНродрпБроорпН роХрпБроЪрпНроЪро┐ропрпИ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ роиройрпНроХрпБ ро╡рпЖроирпНродродрпИ роЙро▒рпБродро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНрод рокро┐ройрпН роЕродрпИ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропрпЗ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роЪро┐ро▒ро┐родрпБ роирпЗро░роорпН роЖро▒ ро╡ро┐роЯро╡рпБроорпН.6. роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ роЖро▒ро┐ропро╡рпБроЯройрпН роЕродрпИ роЕро╡ро░ро╡ро░рпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпЗро▒рпНрок ро╡роЯро┐ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роЪро┐ро▒рпБ родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро╛роХ роиро▒рпБроХрпНроХро┐ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН.7. роЗрокрпНрокрпКро┤рпБродрпБ роТро░рпБ роХро┐рогрпНрогродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЛро│ рооро╛ро╡рпБ, роорпИродро╛ рооро╛ро╡рпБ, родропро┐ро░рпН, роЕро╡ро░ро╡ро░рпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпЗро▒рпНрок рооро┐ро│роХро╛ропрпН родрпВро│рпН, рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роиро╛роорпН роЕро░рпИродрпНродрпБ ро╡рпИродрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЗроЮрпНроЪро┐ рокрпВрогрпНроЯрпБ рокрпЗро╕рпНроЯрпНроЯрпИ роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роЕродрпИ роиройрпНроХрпБ роХро▓роирпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐роЯро╡рпБроорпН.8. рокро┐ройрпНройро░рпН роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роХрпКроЮрпНроЪроорпН роХрпКроЮрпНроЪрооро╛роХ родрогрпНрогрпАро░рпН роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роЕродрпИ рокроЬрпНроЬро┐ рооро╛ро╡рпБ рокродродрпНродрпИ ро╡ро┐роЯ роЪро┐ро▒ро┐родрпБ родрогрпНрогро┐ропро╛роХ роХро▓роирпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН.9. роЕроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роТро░рпБ роХроЯро╛ропрпИ рооро┐родрооро╛рой роЪрпВроЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роЕроЯрпБрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯрпБ рокрпКро░ро┐родрпНродрпБ роОроЯрпБрокрпНрокродро▒рпНроХрпБ родрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЕро│ро╡рпБ роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН роКро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роЕродрпИ роЪрпБроЯ ро╡рпИроХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН.10. роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН роЪрпБроЯрпНроЯ рокро┐ройрпН роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роиро╛роорпН ро╡рпЖроЯрпНроЯро┐ ро╡рпИродрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИ роТро╡рпНро╡рпКройрпНро▒ро╛роХ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роиро╛роорпН роЪрпЖропрпНродрпБ ро╡рпИродрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН рооро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпНропро┐ро▓рпН рокрпЛроЯро╡рпБроорпН. (роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИ рооро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН ро▓рпЗроЪро╛роХ роЕроорпБроХрпНроХро┐ройро╛ро▓рпН рокрпЛродрпБроорпН роЕродро┐роХ рооро╛ро╡рпБроЯройрпН роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпНропро┐ро▓рпН рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро╛ро▓рпН роЕродрпБ рокроЬрпНроЬро┐ рокрпЛро▓рпН роЖроХро┐ро╡ро┐роЯрпБроорпН.)11. рокро┐ройрпНрокрпБ роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ роТро░рпБ рокрпБро▒роорпН ро╡рпЖроирпНродродрпБроорпН роЕродрпИ рооро▒рпБ рокрпБро▒роорпН родро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокро┐ ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЕродрпБ роиройрпНроХрпБ рокрпКройрпНройро┐ро▒рооро╛ройродрпБроорпН роЕродрпИ роТро░рпБ роХро░рогрпНроЯро┐ропро┐ройрпН роорпВро▓роорпН роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роОрогрпНрогрпЖропрпНропрпИ роиройрпНроХрпБ ро╡роЯро┐родрпНродрпБ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роТро░рпБ родроЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН.12. роЗро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпЗ роорпАродроорпБро│рпНро│ роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роХроЯро╛ропро┐ройрпН роЕро│ро╡ро┐ро▒рпНроХрпЗро▒рпНрок 2 роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ 3 роорпБро▒рпИропро╛роХ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯрпБ рокрпКро░ро┐родрпНродрпБ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН.13. рокро┐ро▒роХрпБ роЕроЯрпБрокрпНрокрпИ роЕрогрпИродрпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роиро╛роорпН роиро▒рпБроХрпНроХро┐ ро╡рпИродрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роХрпБроЯрпИ рооро┐ро│роХро╛ропрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╕рпНрокро┐ро░ро┐роЩрпН роЖройро┐ропройрпИ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро▒рпБродрпНродрпЖроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роиро╛роорпН рокрпКро░ро┐родрпНродрпБ ро╡рпИродрпНродро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИропрпЛроЯрпБ роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роиройрпНроХрпБ роХро┐ро│ро▒ро┐ роЕродрпИ роЪрпБроЯ роЪрпБроЯ рокро░ро┐рооро╛ро▒ро╡рпБроорпН.14. роЗрокрпНрокрпКро┤рпБродрпБ роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЪрпВроЯро╛рой рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роорпКро▒рпБ роорпКро▒рпБрокрпНрокро╛рой роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпИ 65 родропро╛ро░рпН. роЗродрпИ роХроЯрпНроЯро╛ропроорпН роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН ро╡рпАроЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНродрпБ рокро╛ро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роЙроЩрпНроХро│рпН роХрпБроЯрпБроорпНрокродрпНродро╛ро░рпБроЯройрпН роЪрпЗро░рпНроирпНродрпБ роЙрогрпНроЯрпБ роороХро┐ро┤рпБроЩрпНроХро│рпН."},{"question":"рждрж╛рзЬрж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржмрж░рзНржгржирж╛ ржжрж╛ржУред","answer":"ржжрзБржЯрж┐ ржЖрж╣рж┐ржд ржХржгрж╛ рждрж╛ржжрзЗрж░ ржЖржзрж╛ржирзЗрж░ ржХрж╛рж░ржгрзЗ ржПржХрзЗ ржЕржкрж░рзЗрж░ ржУржкрж░ ржпрзЗ ржЖржХрж░рзНрж╖ржг ржмрж╛ ржмрж┐ржХрж░рзНрж╖ржг ржмрж▓ ржкрзНрж░ржпрж╝рзЛржЧ ржХрж░рзЗ рждрж╛ржХрзЗ рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓ ржмрж▓рзЗред рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржмрж▓ ржПржмржВ ржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓ ржШржирж┐рж╖рзНржаржнрж╛ржмрзЗ рж╕ржорзНржкрж░рзНржХрж┐рждред ржпржЦржи ржжрзБржЯрж┐ ржЖрж╣рж┐ржд ржХржгрж╛ рж╕рзНржерж┐рж░ ржерж╛ржХрзЗ рждржЦржи рждрж╛ржжрзЗрж░ ржУржкрж░ ржХрзЗржмрж▓ рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржмрж▓ ржХрзНрж░рж┐ржпрж╝рж╛ ржХрж░рзЗред ржпржЦржи ржЖрж╣рж┐ржд ржХржгрж╛ржЧрзБрж▓рзЛ ржЧрждрж┐рж╢рзАрж▓ ржерж╛ржХрзЗ рждржЦржи рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржЕрждрж┐рж░рж┐ржХрзНржд ржХрзНрж░рж┐ржпрж╝рж╛рж╢рзАрж▓ ржЖрж░ ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржмрж▓ рж╣ржЪрзНржЫрзЗ ржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓редрж╕рж╛ржзрж╛рж░ржгржнрж╛ржмрзЗ рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржкрзНрж░ржнрж╛ржм ржУ ржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржкрзНрж░ржнрж╛ржм ржЕржмрж┐ржЪрзНржЫрзЗржжрзНржп рж╕рзЗ ржХрж╛рж░ржгрзЗ ржмрж▓ржЯрж┐ржХрзЗ рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓ ржирж╛ржорзЗ ржЕржнрж┐рж╣рж┐ржд ржХрж░рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ред ржорж╣рж╛ржХрж░рзНрж╖ ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржирзНржпрж╛ржпрж╝ рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржкрж╛рж▓рзНрж▓рж╛ржУ ржЕрж╕рзАржо ржкрж░рзНржпржирзНржд ржмрж┐рж╕рзНрждрзГржд ржПржмржВ ржП ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржХрзНрж░рж┐ржпрж╝рж╛рж░ ржЬржирзНржп ржХрзЛржирзЛ ржорж╛ржзрзНржпржорзЗрж░ржУ ржкрзНрж░ржпрж╝рзЛржЬржи рж╣ржпрж╝ ржирж╛ред ржХрж┐ржирзНрждрзБ ржорж╛ржзрзНржпржо ржерж╛ржХрж▓рзЗ ржПржЗ ржмрж▓ ржорж╛ржзрзНржпржо ржжрзНржмрж╛рж░рж╛ ржкрзНрж░ржнрж╛ржмрж┐ржд рж╣ржпрж╝ред рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓ ржорж╣рж╛ржХрж░рзНрж╖ ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржЪрзЗржпрж╝рзЗ ржЕржирзЗржХ ржмрзЗрж╢рж┐ рж╢ржХрзНрждрж┐рж╢рж╛рж▓рзАред ржЙржжрж╛рж╣рж░ржгрж╕рзНржмрж░рзВржк ржжрзБржЯрж┐ ржкрзНрж░рзЛржЯржирзЗрж░ ржоржзрзНржпржХрж╛рж░ рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓ ржПржжрзЗрж░ ржоржзрзНржпржХрж╛рж░ ржорж╣рж╛ржХрж░рзНрж╖ ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ рззрзжрзйрзм ржЧрзБржгредржЖржорж░рж╛ ржЬрж╛ржирж┐ ржкржжрж╛рж░рзНрже ржЗрж▓рзЗржХржЯрзНрж░ржи, ржкрзНрж░рзЛржЯржи ржирж╛ржоржХ ржЖрж╣рж┐ржд ржХржгрж╛ ржПржмржВ ржирж┐ржЙржЯрзНрж░ржи ржирж╛ржоржХ ржЕржирж╛рж╣рж┐ржд ржХржгрж╛ ржжрж┐ржпрж╝рзЗ ржЧржарж┐рждред ржПржжрзЗрж░ ржоржзрзНржпрзЗ ржЗрж▓рзЗржХржЯрзНрж░ржи ржорзМрж▓рж┐ржХ ржХржгрж╛ред ржпрзЗрж╣рзЗрждрзБ рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓ ржорж╣рж╛ржХрж░рзНрж╖ ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржЪрзЗржпрж╝рзЗ ржЕржирзЗржХ ржмрзЗрж╢рж┐ рж╢ржХрзНрждрж┐рж╢рж╛рж▓рзА рждрж╛ржЗ ржкрж╛рж░ржорж╛ржгржмрж┐ржХ ржУ ржЖржгржмрж┐ржХ ржХрзНрж╖рзЗрждрзНрж░рзЗрж░ рж╕ржХрж▓ ржШржЯржирж╛ ржПржЗ ржмрж▓ ржжрзНржмрж╛рж░рж╛ржЗ ржирж┐ржпрж╝ржирзНрждрзНрж░рж┐ржд рж╣ржпрж╝ред ржЕржмрж╢рзНржп ржЕржирзНржп ржжрзБржЯрж┐ ржмрж▓ ржХрзЗржмрж▓ржорж╛рждрзНрж░ ржирж┐ржЙржХрзНрж▓рж┐ржпрж╝ ржХрзНрж╖рзЗрждрзНрж░рзЗ ржкрзНрж░ржпрзЛржЬрзНржпред рждрж╛ржЗ ржмрж▓рж╛ ржпрж╛ржпрж╝, ржЕржгрзБ ржкрж░ржорж╛ржгрзБрж░ ржЧржаржи, рж░рж╛рж╕рж╛ржпрж╝ржирж┐ржХ ржмрж┐ржХрзНрж░рж┐ржпрж╝рж╛, ржкржжрж╛рж░рзНржерзЗрж░ рждрж╛ржкрзАржпрж╝ ржУ ржЕржирзНржпрж╛ржирзНржп ржзрж░рзНржо рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ ржлрж▓ред рж▓ржХрзНрж╖рзНржпржгрзАржпрж╝ ржпрзЗ, ржЖржорж╛ржжрзЗрж░ ржПржЗ рж╕рзНржерзБрж▓ ржЬржЧрждрзЗрж░ ржпрж╛ржмрждрзАржпрж╝ ржмрж▓рж╕ржорзВрж╣ (ржорж╣рж╛ржХрж░рзНрж╖ ржмрж▓ ржмрзНржпрждрзАржд) рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ржЗ ржмрж╣рж┐ржГржкрзНрж░ржХрж╛рж╢ред ржШрж░рзНрж╖ржг рж╕рзНржкрж░рзНрж╢ ржмрж▓, рж╕рзНржкрзНрж░рж┐ржВ ржмрж▓, ржмрж╛ ржЕржирзНржпрж╛ржирзНржп ржмрж┐ржХрзГржд ржмрж╕рзНрждрзБрж░ ржоржзрзНржпржХрж╛рж░ ржмрж▓ ржЖрж╣рж┐ржд ржХржгрж╛ржЧрзБрж▓рзЛрж░ рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржмрж▓рзЗрж░ржЗ ржлрж▓рж╢рзНрж░рзБрждрж┐ред ржлрзЛржЯржи ржирж╛ржоржХ ржПржХ ржкрзНрж░ржХрж╛рж░. ржнрж░рж╣рзАржи ржУ ржЖржзрж╛ржирж╣рзАржи ржХржгрж╛рж░ ржкрж╛рж░рж╕рзНржкрж░рж┐ржХ ржмрж┐ржирж┐ржоржпрж╝рзЗрж░ ржлрж▓рзЗ ржПржЗ ржмрж▓ ржХрж╛рж░рзНржпржХрж░ рж╣ржпрж╝редржорж╣рж╛ржХрж░рзНрж╖ ржмрж▓ рж╕рж░рзНржмржжрж╛ ржЖржХрж░рзНрж╖ржгржзрж░рзНржорзАред ржкржХрзНрж╖рж╛ржирзНрждрж░рзЗ рждрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рждржЪрзМржорзНржмржХ ржмрж▓ ржЖржХрж░рзНрж╖ржг ржмрж┐ржХрж░рзНрж╖ржг ржЙржнржпрж╝ржзрж░рзНржорзА рж╣рждрзЗ ржкрж╛рж░рзЗред ржЖржмрж╛рж░ ржХрзЛржирзЛ ржмрж╕рзНрждрзБрж░ ржнрж░ ржХрзЗржмрж▓ржорж╛рждрзНрж░ ржзржирж╛рждрзНржоржХ рж╣рждрзЗ ржкрж╛рж░рзЗ ржХрж┐ржирзНрждрзБ ржЖржзрж╛ржи ржзржирж╛рждрзНржоржХ ржмрж╛ ржЛржгрж╛рждрзНржоржХ ржЙржнржпрж╝ рж╣рждрзЗ ржкрж╛рж░рзЗред ржмрзЗрж╢рж┐рж░ржнрж╛ржЧ ржХрзНрж╖рзЗрждрзНрж░рзЗ ржкржжрж╛рж░рзНрже рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржирж┐рж░ржкрзЗржХрзНрж╖ ржЕрж░рзНржерж╛рзО рждржбрж╝рж┐рзО ржмрж▓ рж╢рзВржирзНржп ржЖрж░ ржнрзВ-ржкрзГрж╖рзНржарзАржпрж╝ ржШржЯржирж╛ржмрж▓рж┐рж░ ржХрзНрж╖рзЗрждрзНрж░рзЗ ржорж╣рж╛ржХрж░рзНрж╖ ржмрж▓ржЗ ржкрзНрж░рж╛ржзрж╛ржирзНржп ржкрж╛ржпрж╝ред"},{"question":"Inona avy ny vokatra ratsy ateraky ny finonana ny anjara?","answer":"Ny finona ny anjara dia mety mahatonga fisarahana sy fialonanтАЩny fiarahamonina ireo manana lafim-piainana tsaratsara; Mitarika finoanoam-poana; Fanomezan-tsiny ny Razana; Fanararaotam-pahefana ataonтАЩny tsara fari-piainana; Miteraka tsy fandraisana andraikitra; Miteraka famoizam-po; Mahatonga fanilikilihana."},{"question":"H├гy ─Сс║╖t mс╗Щt ti├кu ─Сс╗Б ph├╣ hс╗гp vс╗Ыi ─Сoс║бn v─Гn sau: Nhс║бc s─й ─С├аn guitar, thс╗Г hiс╗Зn ca kh├║c vс╗Ыi bс║гn phс╗Сi rс╗Щn r├аng h╞бn. Mс╗Щt ─С├кm say ─С╞░с╗гc Thс╗Лnh Suy s├бng t├бc khi mс╗Ыi 19 tuс╗Хi, anh thс╗Г hiс╗Зn ca kh├║c vс╗Ыi t├вm thс║┐ ch├аng trai trс║╗ c├▓n nhiс╗Бu e d├и, gс╗нi gс║пm kh├бt vс╗Нng ─Сс║┐n ng╞░с╗Эi m├мnh thс║зm th├нch. ─Рс╗йc Huy h├бt lс║г l╞бi, t├мnh tс╗й h╞бn, vс╗Ыi t├вm thс║┐ cс╗зa ng╞░с╗Эi ─С├аn ├┤ng tr╞░с╗Яng th├аnh. ─Рс╗йc Huy n├│i: \\"T├┤i cс║гm thс║еy nh╞░ ─С╞░с╗гc trс║╗ lс║бi vс╗Ыi ca kh├║c cс╗зa Thс╗Лnh Suy. T├┤i phс║зn n├аo t├мm lс║бi ─С╞░с╗гc m├мnh trong cс╗Сt c├бch ├вm nhс║бc cс╗зa cс║нu. Mс╗Щt ─С├кm say chс╗йa ─Сс╗▒ng nhс╗пng ─Сiс╗Бu giс║гn dс╗Л, tinh tс║┐ trong cuс╗Щc sс╗Сng, kh├┤ng c├│ sс╗▒ m├аu m├и\\". Thс╗Лnh Suy n├│i ─Рс╗йc Huy l├а thс║зn t╞░с╗гng cс╗зa anh. Anh v├а nhс║бc s─й c├│ sс╗▒ gс║зn g┼йi bс╗Яi ─Сс╗Бu c├│ c├бi nh├мn trong trс║╗o, v├┤ t╞░ vс╗Б t├мnh y├кu. Hai nghс╗З s─й c├╣ng thс╗Г hiс╗Зn bс║гn mash-up V├а t├┤i c┼йng y├кu em (─Рс╗йc Huy) - T├мnh y├кu m├аu xanh l├б (Thс╗Лnh Suy). Bс║гn nhс║бc mang ─Сс║┐n cс║гm x├║c vui t╞░╞бi cho ng╞░с╗Эi nghe. Ca s─й trс║╗ c├▓n cover hit Y├кu em d├аi l├вu cс╗зa nhс║бc s─й ─Рс╗йc Huy, mash-up mс╗Щt ─Сoс║бn ─Сiс╗Зp kh├║c trong b├аi Chuyс╗Зn rс║▒ng cс╗зa ch├нnh anh. Sс╗▒ kс║┐t hс╗гp cho thс║еy ─Сiс╗Гm chung trong ├вm nhс║бc cс╗зa hai nghс╗З s─й h╞бn k├йm nhau 52 tuс╗Хi. Hс╗Н ─Сс╗Бu y├кu hс║┐t m├мnh, thс║│ng thс║пn bс╗Щc lс╗Щ t├вm trс║бng, cс║гm x├║c qua ca tс╗л ngс║пn gс╗Нn, trс╗▒c tiс║┐p. Kс║┐t th├║c ch╞░╞бng tr├мnh, hai nghс╗З s─й h├бt Lemon tree cс╗зa Fool's Garden. Ca kh├║c n├│i vс╗Б nс╗Чi buс╗Уn cс╗зa mс╗Щt ch├аng trai khi t├мnh y├кu, cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Эi li├кn tс╗еc ─Сс╗Хi thay. Nhс║бc s─й ─Рс╗йc Huy n├│i: \\"Sau dс╗Лch bс╗Зnh, nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi trс║╗ sa s├║t tinh thс║зn. Ch├║ng t├┤i muс╗Сn nhс║пn nhс╗з vс╗Ыi kh├бn giс║г rс║▒ng cuс╗Щc sс╗Сng vс║лn vс║нn h├аnh b├мnh th╞░с╗Эng, c├│ l├║c thс╗Лnh l├║c suy. H├гy ra ─С╞░с╗Эng, ngс║пm nh├мn cuс╗Щc sс╗Сng, tr├▓ chuyс╗Зn vс╗Ыi ng╞░с╗Эi n├аy, ng╞░с╗Эi kia ─Сс╗Г thс║еy с╗У cuс╗Щc ─Сс╗Эi vс║лn с╗Хn ─Сс║еy chс╗й\\". ─Рс╗йc Huy sinh n─Гm 1947 с╗Я H├а Nс╗Щi. Thс║нp ni├кn 1980, anh bс║пt ─Сс║зu viс║┐t nhс║бc v├а biс╗Гu diс╗Еn tr├кn c├бc s├вn khс║еu hс║гi ngoс║бi. Nhс╗пng ca kh├║c nс╗Хi tiс║┐ng cс╗зa nhс║бc s─й l├а V├а t├┤i c┼йng y├кu em, Bay ─Сi c├бnh chim biс╗Гn, ─Рс╗лng xa em ─С├кm nay, ─Р╞░с╗Эng xa ╞░с╗Ыt m╞░a, V├а con tim ─С├г vui trс╗Я lс║бi, Y├кu em d├аi l├вu... Thс╗Лnh Suy sinh n─Гm 1999 tс║бi TP HCM, theo ─Сuс╗Хi ├вm nhс║бc tс╗л cс║еp ba. N─Гm 2019, khi ─Сang hс╗Нc ─Рс║бi hс╗Нc S╞░ phс║бm Kс╗╣ thuс║нt TP HCM, anh trс╗Я th├аnh hiс╗Зn t╞░с╗гng vс╗Ыi nhс║бc phс║йm Mс╗Щt ─С├кm say. Hai MV cс╗зa ca kh├║c ─Сс║бt tс╗Хng cс╗Щng h╞бn 70 triс╗Зu l╞░с╗гt xem. Sau ─С├│, anh tiс║┐p tс╗еc g├вy ch├║ ├╜ vс╗Ыi c├бc bс║гn hit Chuyс╗Зn rс║▒ng, Thс║пc mс║пc... Giao lс╗Щ thс╗Эi gian do nhс║бc s─й D╞░╞бng Cс║зm phс╗е tr├бch ├вm nhс║бc, ph├бt s├│ng l├║c 20h tс╗Сi thс╗й bс║гy tuс║зn thс╗й hai v├а tuс║зn cuс╗Сi mс╗Чi th├бng, tr├кn с╗йng dс╗еng FPT Play. Ban bi├кn tс║нp ch╞░╞бng tr├мnh chс╗Нn c├бc nghс╗З s─й thuс╗Щc hai thс║┐ hс╗З kh├бc biс╗Зt, c├│ n├йt t╞░╞бng ─Сс╗Уng vс╗Б ├вm nhс║бc ─Сс╗Г kс║┐t hс╗гp nh╞░ Thanh H├а - L├вn Nh├г, Thanh Lam, B├╣i C├┤ng Nam, Thu Minh - Orange...","answer":"─Рс╗йc Huy h├бt nhс║бc Thс╗Лnh Suy"},{"question":"рззрзпрзпрзж-ржПрж░ ржЧржгржЕржнрзНржпрзБрждрзНржерж╛ржи ржХрзА? ржмрзНржпрж╛ржЦрзНржпрж╛ ржХрж░ред","answer":"рж╕рзНржмрзИрж░рж╛ржЪрж╛рж░рзА ржПрж░рж╢рж╛ржжржмрж┐рж░рзЛржзрзА рззрзпрзпрзж рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗрж░ ржЧржгржЖржирзНржжрзЛрж▓ржиржХрзЗ ржиржмрзНржмржЗ-ржПрж░ ржЧржгржЕржнрзНржпрзБрждрзНржерж╛ржи ржмрж▓рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝редрззрзпрзорзи рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗрж░ рж╢рзЗрж╖ ржжрж┐ржХрзЗ ржЬрзЗржирж╛рж░рзЗрж▓ рж╣рзБрж╕рзЗржЗржи ржорзБрж╣ржорзНржоржж ржПрж░рж╢рж╛ржжрзЗрж░ рж╢рж┐ржХрзНрж╖рж╛ржирзАрждрж┐ ржмрж╛рждрж┐рж▓рзЗрж░ ржжрж╛ржмрж┐рждрзЗ рж╕рж╛ржорж░рж┐ржХ рж╢рж╛рж╕ржирзЗрж░ ржмрж┐рж░рзБржжрзНржзрзЗ рж╕рж░рзНржмржкрзНрж░ржержо ржЖржирзНржжрзЛрж▓ржи рж╢рзБрж░рзБ ржХрж░рзЗ ржЫрж╛рждрзНрж░ рж╕ржорж╛ржЬред рззрзпрзпрзж рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗрж░ рзирзжрж╢рзЗ ржиржнрзЗржорзНржмрж░ ржЧрзБрж▓рж┐ржмрж┐ржжрзНржз ржорж┐рж▓ржирзЗрж░ ржорзГрждрзНржпрзБ ржПржмржВ ржврж╛ржХрж╛ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржмрж┐ржжрзНржпрж╛рж▓ржпрж╝рзЗ рж╢рж┐ржХрзНрж╖ржХржжрзЗрж░ ржПржХржпрзЛржЧрзЗ ржкржжрждрзНржпрж╛ржЧ ржПржмржВ рж░рж╛ржЬржирзИрждрж┐ржХ ржжрж▓ржЧрзБрж▓рзЛрж░ ржЕржнрж┐ржирзНржи ржХрж░рзНржорж╕рзВржЪрж┐рж░ ржХрж╛рж░ржгрзЗ рззрзпрзпрзж рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗрж░ рзкржарж╛ ржбрж┐рж╕рзЗржорзНржмрж░ ржПрж░рж╢рж╛ржж ржкржжрждрзНржпрж╛ржЧ ржХрж░рзЗржиред ржЖрж░ рждрж╛рж░ ржмрж┐рж░рзБржжрзНржзрзЗ рж╕ржВржШржЯрж┐ржд рззрзпрзпрзж рж╕рж╛рж▓рзЗрж░ ржЖржкрж╛ржорж░ ржЬржирждрж╛рж░ ржП ржЖржирзНржжрзЛрж▓ржиржЗ рззрзпрзпрзж-ржПрж░ ржЧржгржЕржнрзНржпрзБрждрзНржерж╛ржи ржирж╛ржорзЗ ржкрж░рж┐ржЪрж┐рждред"},{"question":"Pananya: Saha anu ngarumuskeun kawijakan fiskal di Am├йrika Serikat?","answer":"Anu ngarumuskeun kawijakan fiskal di Am├йrika Serikat nya├йta Kongr├йs."},{"question":"Ko le с╣гс║╣lс║╣ laelae, Amс╗Нtс║╣kun ko ni i si labс║╣ ijс╗Нba apapс╗Н -Makinde","answer":"Gomina ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н, с║╕njinnia с╣вeyi Makinde, naa ti darapс╗Н mс╗Н awс╗Нn to sс╗Н pe ala ti ko le с╣гс║╣ ni ki ikс╗Н Amс╗Нtс║╣kun wa labс║╣ с╗Нga с╗Нlс╗Нpaa patapata nilс║╣ wa.с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, с╗Нsс║╣ yii, ni gomina sс╗Нrс╗Н naa lasiko to n с╣гepade pс║╣lu gbogbo awс╗Нn alaga ijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ mejidinlaaadс╗Нrin to wa nipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н. Makinde, с║╣ni ti Akс╗Нwe iroyin rс║╣, Taiwo Adisa, gbс║╣nu rс║╣ sс╗Нrс╗Н sс╗Н pe тАШтАЩEto aabo jс║╣ с╗Нkan ninu awс╗Нn afojusun ijс╗Нba yii, gbogbo ohun to ba wa nikaapa wa la si maa с╣гe lati ri i pe eto aabo fun с║╣mi ati dukia to fс║╣sс║╣ rinlс║╣ wa fun awс╗Нn olugbe ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н. A si fс║╣ ki gbogbo wa sun, ka le han-an-run lai si ibс║╣ru tabi ifoya kankan. Ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н jс║╣ ipinlс║╣ to tobi, to si paala pс║╣lu oriс╣гiiriс╣гii ilu, nitori naa la с╣гe gbс╗Нdс╗Н mu eto aabo ni pataki.тАШтАШLaipс║╣ yii ti awс╗Нn adigunjale с╣гс╗Нс╣гс║╣ niluu Okeho, awс╗Нn с╗Нdс║╣ agbegbe naa ni wс╗Нn dide, ti wс╗Нn koju awс╗Нn oniс╣гс║╣ ibi naa. Awс╗Нn ni wс╗Нn fс╗Н gbogbo inu igbo kaakiri, ti wс╗Нn si ri i pe с╗Нwс╗Н tс║╣ wс╗Нn.Idi niyi ti mo fi n sс╗Н с╗Н, ti mo n tс║╣nu mс╗Н с╗Нn, ti mo si n pariwo fun gbogbo aye pe mimi kan ko le mi ikс╗Н Amс╗Нtс║╣kun, bс║╣с║╣ ni wс╗Нn ko ni i si labe akoso tabi idari с╗Нga с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ilс║╣ wa. Awa la oo maa dari rс║╣, aabo awс╗Нn eeyan wa с╣гe pataki si wa, nitori ko si aс╣гeyс╗Нri kankan ta a le с╣гe nibi ti ko ba ti si aabo to daju.Bakan naa ni gomina rс╗Н awс╗Нn alaga ijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ yii lati pada si agbegbe wс╗Нn, ki wс╗Нn lс╗Нс╗Н mojuto eto aabo ibс║╣, ki awс╗Нn araalu le fс║╣dс╗Н lori oronro. Makinde ni eto aabo jс║╣ с╗Нkan pataki ninu ipenija ti ipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н ni. O waa rс╗Н awс╗Нn eeyan naa ki wс╗Нn lс╗Нс╗Н da igbimс╗Н alakooso eleto aabo silс║╣ lawс╗Нn ijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ wс╗Нn kaakairi ni kiakia, pс║╣lu ileri pe oun yoo с╣гeto owo to yс║╣ lati с╣гe atilс║╣yin fun wс╗Нn lati mu ki eleyii с╣гeeс╣гe.O waa kilс╗Н fun awс╗Нn alaga naa pe bi ilu ati awс╗Нn agbegbe wс╗Нn ba с╣гe lalaafia si, ti aabo to dara si wa nibс║╣ ni yoo sс╗Н boya wс╗Нn yoo tun fa wс╗Нn kalс║╣ lati dije dupo tabi bс║╣с║╣ kс╗Н."},{"question":"риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риХри░риХрйЗ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐ри╕риери╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ ри╣рйЗриари╛риВ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗ рижри╛ риХрйА риЕри░рие ри╣рйИред\\"риЕри╕риЯрикрижрйА реериЖрикри┐ риХриерйИ риЖрикри┐ ри╕рйБриириирйИри╣ри╛ри░рйБ реериЖрикри╣ри┐ риПриХрйБ риЖрикри┐ римри┐ри╕риери╛ри░рйБ реериЬри╛ ридри┐ри╕рйБ ринри╛ри╡рйИ ридри╛ ри╕рйНри░ри┐ри╕риЯри┐ риЙрикри╛риП реериЖрикриирйИ ринри╛ригрйИ ри▓риП ри╕риори╛риП рееридрйБрио ридрйЗ ринри┐рй░рии риири╣рйА риХри┐риЫрйБ ри╣рйЛриЗ реериЖрикрии ри╕рйВридри┐ ри╕ринрйБ риЬриЧридрйБ рикри░рйЛриЗ реериЬри╛ риХриЙ рикрйНри░рин риЬрйАриЙ риЖрикри┐ римрйБриЭри╛риП реери╕риЪрйБ риири╛риорйБ ри╕рйЛриИ риЬриирйБ рикри╛риП реери╕рйЛ ри╕риорижри░ри╕рйА ридрид риХри╛ римрйЗридри╛ реериири╛риириХ ри╕риЧри▓ ри╕рйНри░ри┐ри╕риЯри┐ риХри╛ риЬрйЗридри╛ реерйзрее\\"","answer":"риЗри╣ ри╕рйНри░рйА риЧрйБри░рйВ риЧрйНри░рй░рие ри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐рим риЬрйА рижрйЗ рикрй░риири╛ 292 ридрйЛриВ ри▓ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риЧрйБри░рйВ риЕри░риЬрии рижрйЗри╡ риЬрйА риЗри╣риири╛риВ римри╛ригрйАриЖриВ рижрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЦри╛ри░рйА ри╣рииредриЗри╕ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйЗриа ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ риЕриирйБри╕ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЦри┐риЖрии риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ,\\"рикрйНри░ринрйВ риЖрик римрйЛри▓ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИ риЖрик ри╣рйА ри╕рйБригрии ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ ри╣рйИ, риЖрик ри╣рйА риЗрй▒риХ ри╣рйИ,риЖрик рижри╛ ри╣рйА ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ рикри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ ри╣рйИ,ридрйЗ риЖрик ри╣рйА ри╢рйНри░ри┐ри╕риЯрйА рикрйИрижри╛ риХри░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред ридрйЗ риЖрик ри╣рйА (риЬриЧрид риирйВрй░ риЖрикригрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ) ри╕риорйЗриЯ ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред(ри╣рйЗ рикрйНри░ринрйВ!) ридрйИриерйЛриВ ри╡рй▒риЦри░ри╛ риХрйБриЭ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйИ, ридрйВрй░ (риЖрикригрйЗ ри╣рйБриХрио-ри░рйВрик) ризри╛риЧрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риЬриЧрид риирйВрй░ рикрйНри░рйЛ ри░рй▒риЦри┐риЖ ри╣рйИ редриЬри┐ри╕ риориирйБрй▒риЦ риирйВрй░ рикрйНри░ринрйВ риЬрйА риЖрик ри╕рйВриЭ римрйЩри╢рижрйЗ ри╣рии, риЙри╣ риориирйБрй▒риЦ рикрйНри░ринрйВ рижри╛ ри╕рижри╛-риери┐ри░ ри░ри╣ри┐риг ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ риири╛рио ри╣ри╛ри╕ри▓ риХри░ ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ редриЙри╣ риориирйБрй▒риЦ ри╕рин ри╡ри▓ риЗриХ риирйЫри░ риири╛ри▓ ридрй▒риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ, риЕриХри╛ри▓ рикрйБри░риЦ рижри╛ риори╣ри░рио ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╣рйИ ред ри╣рйЗ риири╛риириХ! риЙри╣ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риЬриЧрид рижри╛ риЬри┐рй▒ридриг ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ ри╣рйИ редрйзред\\""},{"question":"Ramai saintis berpendapat bahawa pembakaran bahan api fosil telah meningkatkan jumlah karbon dioksida di atmosfera. Apakah kesan peningkatan karbon dioksida yang paling ketara pada planet ini? Pilihan yang ada: 1) iklim yang lebih sejuk 2). iklim yang lebih hangat 3). kelembapan relatif yang lebih rendah 4). lebih banyak ozon di atmosfera","answer":"2). iklim yang lebih hangat"},{"question":"щжЩц╕пчЪДхЬ░чРЖф╜Нч╜оя╝Я","answer":"чнФя╝ЪщжЩц╕пф╜Нф║Оф╕нхЫ╜чЪДхНЧщГия╝МхЬ░хдДчПац▒ЯхПгф╗еф╕Ья╝МхНЧф╕┤хНЧц╡╖я╝Мф╕ЬцОехдзщ╣Пц╣╛я╝Мше┐чХМчПац▒ЯхПгя╝МхМЧф╕Оц╖▒хЬ│х╕ВцОехгдуАВ"},{"question":"Inona no bibikely haingam-pandeha amin'ny fanidinana indrindra eto an-tany?","answer":"Ny angidina no bibikely haingam-pandeha indrindra amin'ny fanidinana  eto an-tany."},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai.  Juliana gemar memakai pakaian yang berwarna __. Pilihan:  A) nipis-nipisB) segar-segarC) mahal-mahal D) garang-garang","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah D) garang-garang"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ┘З┘И ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н╪з╪и┘К ╪з┘Д╪м┘Д┘К┘Д ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ╪к╪▓┘И╪м ╪з╪л┘Ж╪к┘К┘Ж ┘Е┘Ж ╪и┘Ж╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪▒╪│┘И┘Д ╪╡┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ┘И╪│┘Д┘Е╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪╣╪л┘Е╪з┘Ж ╪и┘Ж ╪╣┘Б╪з┘Ж."},{"question":"EFCC lс╗Нс╗Н jalс║╣kun ile awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н yahoo loru, lawс╗Нn yс║╣n ba kс╗Нju ija si wс╗Нn lтАЩс╗Мс╣гogbo","answer":"с╗Мrс╗Н di bo o lс╗Н o ya lс╗Нna laaarс╗Н с╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun lagbegbe Lameco, kс╗Нja si Oke-fia, niluu Oс╣гogbo, lasiko ti awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н Yahoo ti wс╗Нn to с╗Нgс╗Нrun-un fс╗Нn soju titi pс║╣lu onuruuru nnkan ija lс╗Нwс╗Н wс╗Нn.Wс╗Нn dana sun taya, bс║╣с║╣ ni wс╗Нn wс╗Н oriс╣гiiriс╣гii nnkan soju popo, ti gbogbo awс╗Нn onimс╗Нto ti wс╗Нn n gbe awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н lс╗Н sileewe atawс╗Нn onikorope si n lс╗Нri pada sс║╣yin.Ohun ti a gbс╗Н ni pe с╣гe lawс╗Нn ajс╗Н to n gbogun ti jibiti ori с║╣rс╗Н ayelujara, Economic and Financial Crimes Commission, lс╗Н sile awс╗Нn kan laago kan aabс╗Н oru, ti wс╗Нn si jalс║╣kun wс╗Нle.Bi wс╗Нn с╣гe ja geeti awс╗Нn ile kan pс║╣lu okuta, ni wс╗Нn yс╗Н bulс╗Нс╗Нku ferese awс╗Нn kan wс╗Нle, ti wс╗Нn si n ko wс╗Нn sinu mс╗Нto, bс║╣с║╣ ni wс╗Нn gba mс╗Нto wс╗Нn.Idi niyс║╣n tawс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н Yahoo с╗Нhun fi pe ara wс╗Нn jс╗Н, ti wс╗Нn si lс╗Нс╗Н dana soju с╗Нna ti wс╗Нn yoo gba kс╗Нja. Pс║╣lu ibс╗Нn, igi, ada, okuta ati bс║╣с║╣ bс║╣с║╣ lс╗Н lawс╗Нn с╗Нdс╗Н naa fi koju awс╗Нn EFCC.Nigba tawс╗Нn EFCC ri i pe с╗Нrс╗Н naa kс╗Нja agbara, wс╗Нn fi diс║╣ silс║╣ lara awс╗Нn mс╗Нto ti wс╗Нn gba, wс╗Нn si sa lс╗Н pс║╣lu mс╗Нto diс║╣ ti wс╗Нn fi gbe awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н ti wс╗Нn ko.Awс╗Нn с╗Нdс╗Н naa pejс╗Н si Freedom Park, ni Old Garage, ariwo ti wс╗Нn n pa ni pe kijс╗Нba с╗Мс╣гun lс╗Нс╗Н gba awс╗Нn ara wс╗Нn ti EFCC ko lс╗Н ti wс╗Нn ko ba fс║╣ wahala nla niluu Oс╣гogbo.A gbс╗Н pe ijс╗Нba ti ran Kс╗Нmiс╣гanna fс╗Нrс╗Н с╗Нdс╗Н ati ere idaraya, Yс║╣mi Lawal, lс╗Н si с╗Нfiisi awс╗Нn EFCC lati le wa ojutuu si с╗Нrс╗Н naa."},{"question":"╬г╧Е╬╝╧А╬╗╬о╧Б╧Й╧Г╬╡ ╬▒╧Е╧Д╬о╬╜ ╧Д╬╖╬╜ ╧А╧Б╧М╧Д╬▒╧Г╬╖. \\"╬Я ╬М╬╝╬╖╧Б╬┐╧В ╬╡╬п╬╜╬▒╬╣ ╬н╬╜╬▒╧В ╬▒╧А╧М ╧Д╬┐╧Е╧В ╬┤╧Н╬┐ ╬╝╬╡╬│╬м╬╗╬┐╧Е╧В ╬╡╧А╬╣╬║╬┐╧Н╧В ╧А╬┐╬╣╬╖╧Д╬н╧В ╧Д╬╖╧В ╬▒╧Б╧З╬▒╬п╬▒╧В\\"","answer":"╬С╧А╬м╬╜╧Д╬╖╧Г╬╖: \\"╬Х╬╗╬╗╬м╬┤╬▒╧В\\""},{"question":"Napisz ci─Еg dalszy: Ratusz zosta┼В wybudowany w latach 1561тАУ1565 i otwarty 27 lutego 1565 roku. Autorem projektu by┼В Cornelis Floris de Vriendt we wsp├│┼Вpracy z innymi, w tym z W┼Вochem Nicolo Scarinim. Pierwotnie budow─Щ ratusza planowano ju┼╝ oko┼Вo roku 1540 (w├│wczas mia┼В powsta─З w stylu gotyckim), jednak z powodu braku ┼Ыrodk├│w do prac nie przyst─Еpiono. W 1576 roku, podczas hiszpa┼Дskiej furii","answer":"budynek zosta┼В podpalony; ze zniszcze┼Д odbudowano go trzy lata p├│┼║niej. Obiekt reprezentuje cechy renesansu flamandzkiego i w┼Вoskiego, cho─З jego ┼Ыrodkowa cz─Щ┼Ы─З nawi─Еzuje jeszcze do architektury gotyckich ratuszy Flandrii i Brabancji. Ryzalit na fasadzie przedniej zawiera rze┼║b─Щ Maryi, poni┼╝ej kt├│rej znajduj─Е si─Щ dwie kolejne kobiece sylwetki reprezentuj─Еce roztropno┼Ы─З i sprawiedliwo┼Ы─З, a tak┼╝e herby ksi─Щstwa Brabancji, Filipa II Habsburga i markizatu antwerpskiego. Statua Maryi zosta┼Вa ustawiona przez Jezuit├│w w okresie kontrreformacji, wcze┼Ыniej w jej miejscu mie┼Ыci┼Вa si─Щ rze┼║ba Silviusa Brabo. Wn─Щtrze budynku zosta┼Вo ukszta┼Вtowane podczas przebudowy w XIX wieku. Jedn─Е ze znacz─Еcych zmian by┼Вo zadaszenie wewn─Щtrznego dziedzi┼Дca, kt├│ry dot─Еd pozostawa┼В otwarty."},{"question":"роЕройрпНрокро│ро┐рокрпНрокрпБ (роЪро┐ро▒рпБроХродрпИроХро│рпН )роОройрпБроорпН роирпВро▓рпИ роЗропро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропро╡ро░рпН? ","answer":" ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ : роХрпБ. роЕро┤роХро┐ро░ро┐роЪро╛рооро┐"},{"question":"р╢Ер╢┤р╖Ъ р╢Ър╢║ р╖Гр╖Д р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╢пр╖Щр╢Ъ р╖Др╖Ур╢╜р╖С р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ,","answer":"р╢Ер╢┤р╖Ъ р╢Ър╢║ р╖Гр╖Д р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╢пр╖Щр╢Ъ р╖Др╖Ур╢╜р╖С р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Бр╖Ур╢╜р╢║р╢║р╖Т. "},{"question":"родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН рокро╛ропрпН родропро╛ро░ро┐рокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН рокрпБроХро┤рпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ роЗроЯроорпН ропро╛родрпБ ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ :  рокродрпНродроороЯрпИ"},{"question":"Napisz ci─Еg dalszy: Curling zacz─Е┼В uprawia─З w 2003, wcze┼Ыniej gra┼В m.in. w koszyk├│wk─Щ i racquetball. Na arenie mi─Щdzynarodowej zadebiutowa┼В jako rezerwowy w zespole Chrisa Dawa na Mistrzostwach ┼Ъwiata 2005. W nast─Щpnym sezonie by┼В na trzeciej pozycji, reprezentowa┼В Kanad─Щ na","answer":"Zimowych Igrzyskach Paraolimpijskich 2006. Dru┼╝yna zaj─Щ┼Вa 1. miejsce w fazie grupowej wygrywaj─Еc pi─Щ─З a przegrywaj─Еc dwa spotkania. W p├│┼Вfinale zesp├│┼В Klonowego Li┼Ыcia pokona┼В 5:4 Norwegi─Щ (Geir Arne Skogstad), zdoby┼В z┼Вote medale triumfuj─Еc w ostatnim meczu turnieju 7:4 nad Wielk─Е Brytani─Е (Frank Duffy)."},{"question":" Qual pa├нs tem a maior linha costeira do mundo?","answer":"118 elementos qu├нmicos (92 naturais e 26 artificiais)."},{"question":"╪г┘Е╪к┘Й ┘Г╪з┘Ж╪к ╪г┘И┘Д ╪и╪п╪з┘К╪й ┘Д╪м┘И╪з┘К╪▓ ╪з┘Д╪м┘И┘Д╪п┘Ж ╪м┘Д┘И╪и╪Я","answer":"┘Г╪з┘Ж╪к ╪г┘И┘Д ╪и╪п╪з┘К╪й ┘Д╪м┘И╪з┘К╪▓ ╪з┘Д╪м┘И┘Д╪п┘Ж ╪м┘Д┘И╪и ╪│┘Ж╪й 1944.╪м┘И╪з┘К╪▓ ╪м┘И┘Д╪п┘Ж ╪м┘Д┘И╪и ┘З┘К╪з ╪м┘И╪з┘К╪▓ ╪и╪к┘Е┘Ж╪н┘З╪з ╪м┘Е╪╣┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н╪з┘Б┘З ╪з┘Д╪з╪м┘Ж╪и┘К┘З ┘Б┘Й ┘З┘И┘Д┘К┘И┘И╪п ┘Б┘Й ╪з┘Е╪▒┘К┘Г╪з ╪╣┘Д╪┤╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪з╪╣╪к╪▒╪з┘Б ╪и╪з┘Д╪з┘Ж╪м╪з╪▓╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪и╪з╪▒╪▓╪й ┘Б┘Й ╪╡┘Ж╪з╪╣╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪▒┘Б┘К┘З╪М ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪│╪к┘И┘К┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Е╪н┘Д┘Й ┘И ╪з┘Д╪г╪м┘Ж╪и┘Й. ╪м┘И╪з┘К╪▓ ╪м┘И┘Д╪п┘Ж ╪м┘Д┘И╪и ╪и╪к╪▒┘Г╪▓ ╪з┘З╪к┘Е╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д╪м┘Е┘З┘И╪▒ ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪г╪н╪│┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪з╪╣┘Е╪з┘Д ┘Б┘Й ╪з┘Б┘Д╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д╪│┘К┘Ж┘Е╪з ┘И ┘Б┘Й ╪и╪▒╪з┘Е╪м ╪з┘Д╪к┘Д┘Б╪▓┘К┘И┘Ж."},{"question":"Marina ve fa i Madagasikara no nosy lehibe indrindra maneran-tany?a) Eny, marina.b) Tsia, diso.","answer":"Tsia, mitana ny laharana fahaefatra i Madagasikara raha ny angezany no jerena."},{"question":"\\"р╢Ер╢нр╖Ъ р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Фр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╗р╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Фр╢╜р╖Рр╢Яр╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╢нр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Тр╢║ р╢Ер╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Щр╢В р╢Ер╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢з р╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Ф р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖П\\"р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢нр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢╕ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╢нр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Тр╢║ ( р╢пр╢лр╖Кр╢й р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Жр╖Ар╢Ър╖Т) р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢║р╖Т. р╢пр╢лр╖Кр╢й, р╢Ър╢│ ,р╢╜р╖Ур╢║ р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢Ер╢╗р╖Фр╢нр╢║р╖Т.р╢╢р╖Пр╢╜р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢┤р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢║ р╢пр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ар╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢нр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Т р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╢║ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Лр╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╢▒ р╢╢р╖А. р╢Ср╢║ р╢Ьр╖Гр╖К р╢Ър╢┤р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢▒р╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖П р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╢║р╢Ър╖К. р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Ср╢║р╢з р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ър╢│р╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢║р╖Т.р╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Фр╖Ер╢Яр╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╢нр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Тр╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ьр╖Ур╢нр╢║р╢Ър╢║р╖Т. р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢Ср╢▒ р╢Жр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢ор╢║ р╢пр╖Щр╢╜р╖К р╢Ър╖Рр╢йр╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Фр╖Ер╢Яр╖Тр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╢Ър╖К р╢нр╢╗р╢╕р╖К р╖Др╖Ур╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╖Ур╢║.р╢Ър╢╜р╖Ар╖Пр╖Ар╢╜р╢зр╢п р╢нр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒ р╢Ер╢║ р╢Зр╢н. р╢Ср╢║ р╢Ър╢│ р╢Ър╢╜р╖Ар╖П р╢║р╢▒ р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Фр╢╕р╢зр╢╕ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╢║."},{"question":"р░╡р░┐р░Ър░Хр▒Нр░╖р░гр░╛р░░р░╣р░┐р░др░Вр░Чр░╛ р░кр▒Жр░╕р▒Нр░Яр░┐р░╕р▒Ир░бр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░╡р░╛р░бр░Яр░В р░╡р░▓р░и р░Хр░▓р░┐р░Чр▒З р░ир░╖р▒Нр░Яр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Пр░ор░┐р░Яр░┐?","answer":"р░кр▒Жр░╕р▒Нр░Яр░┐р░╕р▒Ир░бр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░╡р░┐р░Ър░Хр▒Нр░╖р░гр░╛р░░р░╣р░┐р░др░Вр░Чр░╛ р░кр▒Нр░░р░нр░╛р░╡р░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Ър▒Вр░кр▒Бр░др▒В, р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡ р░╕р░Вр░Цр▒Нр░пр░▓р▒Л р░Зр░др░░ р░Ьр░Вр░др▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р░ир▒Б р░ир░╛р░╢р░ир░В р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░пр░┐. р░╡р▒Ар░Яр░┐р░▓р▒Л р░И р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░ор▒Бр░▓р░ир▒Б р░Жр░╣р░╛р░░р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░др▒Ар░╕р▒Бр░Хр▒Кр░ир▒З р░Ьр░Вр░др▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░Зр░др░░р▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░Жр░╣р░╛р░░р░ор░пр▒Нр░пр▒З р░Ьр░Вр░др▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р▒В р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░лр░▓р░┐р░др░Вр░Чр░╛ р░кр▒Жр░╕р▒Нр░Яр░┐р░╕р▒Ир░бр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░Жр░╣р░╛р░░р░кр▒Б р░Чр▒Кр░▓р▒Бр░╕р▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Л р░Ер░ир▒Вр░╣р▒Нр░пр░ор▒Ир░и р░ор░╛р░░р▒Нр░кр▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░жр░╛р░░р░┐р░др▒Ар░╕р▒Нр░др▒В, р░Жр░╡р░░р░г р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╕р▒Нр░е р░пр▒Кр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░╕р░ор░др▒Бр░▓р▒Нр░пр░др░ир▒Б р░жр▒Жр░мр▒Нр░мр░др▒Ар░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░пр░┐. р░Зр░╡р░┐ р░ир▒Зр░▓р░▓р▒Л р░Хр░▓р░┐р░╕р░┐р░кр▒Лр░пр░┐р░ир░кр▒Бр░бр▒Б р░Ер░╡р░┐ р░Хр░▓р░┐р░Чр░┐р░Вр░Ър▒З р░кр▒Нр░░р░нр░╛р░╡р░В р░Зр░Вр░Хр░╛ р░Ер░кр░╛р░пр░Хр░░р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐."},{"question":"риЧри╛риВризрйА риирйЗ ри╕рйВриЯ-римрйВриЯ риЫрй▒риб риХрйЗ тАШриЕризриирй░риЧри╛ рилри╝риХрйАри░тАЩ римригрии рижри╛ рилри╝рйИри╕ри▓ри╛ риХри┐риЙриВ ри▓ри┐риЖ?","answer":"тАЬриори┐ри╕риЯри░ риЧри╛риВризрйА ри╡ри░риЧрйЗ ри░ри╛риЬризрйНри░рйЛри╣рйА, риори┐рибри▓ риЯрйИриВрикри▓ ри╡риХрйАри▓ рижри╛ риЕри░риз риириЧрии ри╣ри╛ри▓рид ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╡ри╛риЗри╕ри░ри╛риП рижрйЗ риори╣ри┐ри▓ри╛риВ рижрйАриЖриВ рикрйМрйЬрйАриЖриВ риЪрйЬрйНри╣риири╛ риЕридрйЗ ри░ри╛риЬрйЗ рижрйЗ риирйБриори╛риЗрй░рижрйЗ риири╛ри▓ римри░ри╛римри░рйА рижрйЗ рикрй▒ризри░ тАЩридрйЗ риЧрй▒ри▓римри╛рид риХри░риири╛ римри╣рйБрид риЦри╝ридри░риири╛риХ риЕридрйЗ риШрйНри░ри┐ригри╛ ринри░ри┐риЖ ри╕рйАредтАЭримри░ридри╛риирйАриЖриВ рижрйЗ ридридриХри╛ри▓рйА рикрйНри░ризри╛рии риорй░ридри░рйА риЪри░риЪри┐ри▓ рижри╛ риЗри╣ римри┐риЖрии риЗридри┐ри╣ри╛ри╕ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижри░риЬ ри╣рйИредриЗри╣ риЙрижрйЛриВ рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╣рйИ риЬрижрйЛриВ риорйЛри╣рии рижри╛ри╕ риХри░рио риЪрй░риж риЧри╛риВризрйА римри░ридри╛риирйАриЖриВ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риХри┐рй░риЧ риЬри╛ри░риЬ рикрй░риЬри╡рйЗриВ рижрйЗ ри╕рй▒рижрйЗ ридрйЗ римриХри┐рй░риШрио рикрйИри▓рйЗри╕ риЧриП ри╕рииред риЙрижрйЛриВ риЧри╛риВризрйА риирйЗ риЖрикригрйА риЬри╛ригрйА-рикриЫри╛ригрйА риЫрйЛриЯрйА ризрйЛридрйА ри▓ри╛риИ ри╣рйЛриИ ри╕рйА риЬри┐ри╕ риирйВрй░ риЕрй░риЧри░рйЗриЬри╝ тАШри▓ри╛риЗриириХри▓ри╛риетАЩ риЬри╛ригрйА ри▓рй░риЧрйЛриЯ риХри╣ри┐рй░рижрйЗ ри╕рииредриЧри╛риВризрйА рижрйЗ рикрйЬрикрйЛридрйЗ риЕридрйЗ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ римри╛ри░рйЗ риХриИ риХри┐ридри╛римри╛риВ ри▓ри┐риЦ риЪрйБрй▒риХрйЗ ридрйБри╢ри╛ри░ риЧри╛риВризрйА риорй░риирижрйЗ ри╣рии риХри┐ риЖрикригрйА риЫрйЛриЯрйА ризрйЛридрйА риирйВрй░ риЧри╛риВризрйА риирйЗ риЕрй░риЧри░рйЗриЬри╝ри╛риВ рижрйЗ риЦри╝ри┐ри▓ри╛рилри╝ риЗрй▒риХ ри░ригриирйАридрйА ри╡риЬрйЛриВ ри╡ри░ридри┐риЖ ри╕рйАред риЙри╣ риХри╣ри┐рй░рижрйЗ ри╣рии, тАЬриЕрй░риЧри░рйЗриЬри╝ри╛риВ риирйВрй░ риЖрижрид ри╣рйЛ риЪрйБрй▒риХрйА ри╕рйА риХри┐ риЬрижрйЛриВ риХрйЛриИ ринри╛ри░ридрйА риЖриЧрйВ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риирйВрй░ риори┐ри▓риг риЖриЙриВрижри╛ ри╕рйА ридри╛риВ риЙри╣ риЕрй░риЧри░рйЗриЬри╝рйА ридрйМри░ ридри░рйАриХрйЗ риири╛ри▓ риЖриЙриВрижри╛ ри╕рйАред риЗри╕ риЕрй░риЧри░рйЗриЬри╝ риХри╛рилри╝рйА ри╕ри╣ри┐риЬ риори╣ри┐ри╕рйВри╕ риХри░рижрйЗ ри╕рйАредтАЭриЙри╣ риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ рижрй▒ри╕рижрйЗ ри╣рии,  тАЬриЬрижрйЛриВ риЧри╛риВризрйА риирйЗ риЕриЬри┐ри╣ри╛ риири╣рйАриВ риХрйАридри╛ ридри╛риВ риЕрй░риЧри░рйЗриЬри╝ рикрйНри░рйЗри╢ри╛рии ри╣рйЛ риЧриП риХри┐ риЗри╣ риЗриири╕ри╛рии ридри╛риВ ри╕ри╛рибрйЗ ри╡ри░риЧри╛ рижри┐ри╕риг рижрйА риХрйЛри╢ри┐ри╢ ри╡рйА риири╣рйАриВ риХри░ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛редтАЭтАЬри░ри╛риКриВрибриЯрйЗримри▓ риХри╛риирилри╝ри░рй░ри╕ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ридри╛риВ риЕрй░риЧри░рйЗриЬри╝ ри╕рижриорйЗ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╣рйА риЖ риЧриП ри╕рииред ри╕ри╛рибрйЗ ри░ри╛риЬрйЗ рижрйЗ ри╕риириорйБрй▒риЦ риЧри╛риВризрйА риЕризриирй░риЧрйЗ риЬри╛ригриЧрйЗред риЧри╛риВризрйА риЗрй▒риХ риориирйЛри╡ри┐риЧри┐риЖриириХ рижри╛риЕ ри╡рйА риЦрйЗриб ри░ри╣рйЗ ри╕рииред риЬрижрйЛриВ ридрйБри╕рйАриВ ри╡ри┐риЪри╛ри░-ри╡риЯри╛риВрижри░ри╛ риХри░рижрйЗ ри╣рйЛ ридри╛риВ риЙри╕ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риориирйЛри╡ри┐риЧри┐риЖриириХ рижри╛риЕ-рикрйЗриЪ риЦрйЗрибригрйЗ рикрйИриВрижрйЗ ри╣рииредтАЭ ==риЧри╛риВризрйА рижри╛ ри╕ри┐ри░рилри╝ риЫрйЛриЯрйА ризрйЛридрйА рикри╛риЙриг рижри╛ рилри╝рйИри╕ри▓ри╛==ри╡рйИри╕рйЗ риЧри╛риВризрйА рижрйАриЖриВ ри╢рйБри░рйВриЖридрйА ридри╕ри╡рйАри░ри╛риВ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ридрйБри╕рйАриВ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риирйВрй░ ри╕рйВриЯ-римрйВриЯ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрйЗриЦ ри╕риХрижрйЗ ри╣рйЛ риЕридрйЗ римри╛риЕриж ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЙри╣ риЧрйБриЬри░ри╛рид рижрйЗ риХри╛риарйАриЖри╡ри╛рйЬрйА рикри╣ри┐ри░ри╛ри╡рйЗ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╡рйА риириЬри╝ри░ риЖриП ри╕рииредри╕ри╡ри╛ри▓ риЗри╣ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЧри╛риВризрйА рижрйА рикриЫри╛риг римриг риЪрйБрй▒риХрйА риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйА риЕрй▒ризрйА ризрйЛридрйА риЕридрйЗ риЪри╛рижри░ риХрижрйЛриВ риЕридрйЗ риХри┐ри╡рйЗриВ ри╣рйЛриВриж ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЖриИ риЬрйЛ рижрйЗри╢-ри╡ри┐рижрйЗри╢ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижри╛ рикрйНри░ридрйАриХ римриг риЧриИред риЧрй▒ри▓ 1921 рижрйА ри╣рйИ риЬрижрйЛриВ риЧри╛риВризрйА ридри╛риори┐ри▓риири╛рибрйВ рижрйЗ риорижрйБри░риИ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри╕рииред риЙрижрйЛриВ ридрй▒риХ риЧри╛риВризрйА рилри╝рйИри╕ри▓ри╛ риХри░ риЪрйБрй▒риХрйЗ ри╕рии риХри┐ риЙри╣ ри╕ри┐ри░рилри╝ ри╕ри╡рижрйЗри╢рйА риХрй▒рикрйЬрйЗ ри╣рйА рикри╛риЙригриЧрйЗредриЗри╕ ридрйЛриВ рикри╣ри┐ри▓ри╛риВ ри╡ри┐рижрйЗри╢рйА риХрй▒рикрйЬрйЗ ри╕ри╛рйЬрии рижри╛ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижри╛ ри╕рй▒рижри╛ риЗрй▒риХ риЕрй░рижрйЛри▓рии рижри╛ ри░рйВрик ризри╛ри░рии риХри░ риЪрйБрй▒риХри┐риЖ ри╕рйАред ридри╛риори┐ри▓риири╛рибрйВ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ риЗрй▒риХ ри░рйЗри▓ рипри╛ридри░ри╛ рижрйМри░ри╛рии риЬрижрйЛриВ риЙри╣ риЖрио ри░рйЗри▓ риорйБри╕ри╛рилри╝ри░ри╛риВ риири╛ри▓ риЧрй▒ри▓римри╛рид риХри░ ри░ри╣рйЗ ри╕рииред риЗри╕ рижрйМри░ри╛рии риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риирйЗ рижрйЗриЦри┐риЖ риХри┐ римри╣рйБрид ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ ри▓рйЛриХри╛риВ риХрйЛри▓ рикрйИри╕рйЗ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рииред риЗри╕ ри▓риИ риЙри╣ рикрйБри░ри╛ригрйЗ риХрй▒рикрйЬрйЗ ри╕ри╛рйЬ риХрйЗ риЦри╛рижрйА рижрйЗ риири╡рйЗриВ риХрй▒рикрйЬрйЗ риири╣рйАриВ риЦри╝ри░рйАриж ри╕риХрижрйЗредриЖрикригрйЗ ри░рйЗри▓ ри╕рилри╝ри░ римри╛ри░рйЗ риЧри╛риВризрйА ри▓ри┐риЦрижрйЗ ри╣рии, тАЬриорйИриВ ри░рйЗри▓ рижрйА ринрйАрйЬ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрйЗриЦри┐риЖ риХри┐ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ ри▓рйЛриХри╛риВ рижри╛ ри╕ри╡рижрйЗри╢рйА риорйВри╡риорйИриВриЯ риири╛ри▓ риХрйЛриИ ри▓рйИриг-рижрйЗриг риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйАред риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риирйЗ ри╡ри┐рижрйЗри╢рйА риХрй▒рикрйЬрйЗ рикри╛риП ри╣рйЛриП ри╕рииред риЬрижрйЛриВ риорйИриВ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риири╛ри▓ риЧрй▒ри▓ риХрйАридрйА ридри╛риВ риХриИриЖриВ риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ риХри┐ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ ри▓риИ риори╣ри┐рй░риЧри╛ риЦри╛рижрйА риХрй▒рикрйЬри╛ риЦри░рйАрижригри╛ ри╕рй░ринри╡ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйИред риорйИриВ риЯрйЛрикрйА, рикрйВри░рйА ризрйЛридрйА риЕридрйЗ риХриорйАриЬри╝ рикри╛риИ ри╣рйЛриИ ри╕рйАредтАЭриЧри╛риВризрйА ри▓ри┐риЦрижрйЗ ри╣рии, тАЬриЙрижрйЛриВ риорйИриВ ри╕рйЛриЪри┐риЖ риХри┐ риорйИриВ риЗри╕ рижри╛ риХрйА риЬри╡ри╛рим рижрйЗ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣ри╛риВред ри╕ри┐ри╡ри╛риЗ риЗри╕ рижрйЗ риХри┐ ри╢ри╛ри▓рйАрииридри╛ рижрйЗ риШрйЗри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижрйЗ ри╣рйЛриП риорйИриВ риЖрикригрйЗ ри╕ри░рйАри░ риЙрй▒рикри░ риорйМриЬрйВриж риХрй▒рикрйЬрйЗ ридри┐риЖриЧ рижрйЗри╡ри╛риВред риЕридрйЗ риЦри╝рйБриж риирйВрй░ риЗриирйНри╣ри╛риВ ри▓рйЛриХри╛риВ рижрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри╣риоригрйЗ ри▓рйИ риЬри╛ри╡ри╛риВред риЕриЧри▓рйЗ ри╣рйА рижри┐рии риорйБрижри░риИ рижрйА римрйИриариХ ридрйЛриВ римри╛риЕриж риорйИриВ риЗри╕ риЙрй▒рикри░ риЕриори▓ риХри░ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛редтАЭ"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛: роИро░ро╛роХрпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░роорпН роОродрпБ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ:роИро░ро╛роХрпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░роорпН рокро╛роХрпНродро╛роХрпН.рокроХрпБродро╛родрпБ (рокроХрпНродро╛родрпН) роОройрпНрокродрпБ роИро░ро╛роХрпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░рооро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗрокрпНрокрпЖропро░рпН, рокро╛ро░роЪрпАроХ роорпКро┤ро┐роЪрпН роЪрпКро▓рпНро▓ро╛рой, рокроХрпН-родро╛родрпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ рокроХрпН-родро╛-родрпБ роОройрпНрокродро┐ройрпН роЕроЯро┐ропро╛роХрокрпН рокро┐ро▒роирпНродродрпБ. роЗродройрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН роЗро▒рпИро╡ройро┐ройрпН рокрпВроЩрпНроХро╛ роОройрпНрокродро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗродрпБ родрпЖройрпНроорпЗро▒рпНроХрпБ роЖроЪро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН родрпЖро╣рпНро░ро╛ройрпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЕроЯрпБродрпНрод роЗро░рогрпНроЯро╛ро╡родрпБ рокрпЖро░ро┐роп роироХро░рооро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЕро░рокрпБ роЙро▓роХродрпНродро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роОроХро┐рокрпНродро┐ро▓рпБро│рпНро│ роХрпЖропрпНро░рпЛро╡рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЕроЯрпБродрпНрод роЗро░рогрпНроЯро╛ро╡родрпБ рокрпЖро░ро┐роп роироХро░роорпН роЗродрпБро╡ро╛роХрпБроорпН. 2003 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роОроЯрпБроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роХрогроХрпНроХрпЖроЯрпБрокрпНрокро┐ройрпН рокроЯро┐ 5,772,000 роороХрпНроХро│рпНродрпКроХрпИропрпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ роИро░ро╛роХрпНроХро┐ройрпН рооро┐роХрокрпНрокрпЖро░ро┐роп роироХро░рооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЗроирпНроироХро░роорпН ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роЯрпИроХро┐ро░ро┐ро╕рпН роиродро┐роХрпНроХро░рпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ роЗроирпНрод роироХро░роорпН 33┬░20тА▓N 44┬░26тА▓E роТро░рпБ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роорпБро╕рпНро▓ро┐роорпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН рокрогрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роорпИропрооро╛роХ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХро┐ропродрпБ.роЙропро░рпН роЗроЯрпИроХрпНроХро╛ро▓роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН(Middle Age), рокро╛роХрпНродро╛родрпН роироХро░роорпН 1,200,000-3,000,000 роороХрпНроХро│рпН родрпКроХрпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роЙро▓роХро┐ройрпН рооро┐роХрокрпНрокрпЖро░ро┐роп роироХро░рооро╛роХроХрпН роХро░рпБродрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. 1258 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роороЩрпНроХрпЛро▓ро┐роп роЪро╛роорпНро░ро╛роЬрпНропродрпНродро┐ройро┐ройрпН рокро┐роЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐роХрпНроХро┐ роЗроирпНрод роироХро░роорпН роЕро┤ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ, роЗродройрпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИро╡ро╛роХ рокро▓ роирпВро▒рпНро▒ро╛рогрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро╛роХ роЕроЯро┐роХрпНроХроЯро┐ роХрпКро│рпНро│рпИ роирпЛропрпНроХро│рпН(plagues) рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро▓ родрпКроЯро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ропро╛рой рокрпЗро░ро░роЪрпБроХро│рпН роХро╛ро░рогрооро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЗроирпНроироХро░роорпН рокро▓ро╡рпАройрокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. 1938 ро▓рпН роТро░рпБ роЪрпБропро╛родрпАройрооро╛рой роиро╛роЯро╛роХ роИро░ро╛роХрпН роЕроЩрпНроХрпАроХро╛ро░роорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рокро┐ройрпН, рокро╛роХрпНродро╛родрпН рокроЯро┐рокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛роХ роЕродройрпН роорпБроирпНродрпИроп роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ропродрпНродрпБро╡рооро╛рой роЕро░рокрпБ роХро▓ро╛роЪрпНроЪро╛ро░родрпНродро┐ройрпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп роорпИропрооро╛роХ роорпАрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН роЙропро┐ро░рпНрокрпЖро▒рпНро▒родрпБ.роЕрогрпНроорпИ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН, роЗроирпНрод роироХро░роорпН роЕроЯро┐роХрпНроХроЯро┐ роХроЯрпБроорпИропро╛рой роЙро│рпНроХроЯрпНроЯроорпИрокрпНрокрпБ роЪрпЗродродрпНродрпИ роОродро┐ро░рпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯродрпБ. роЗродрпБ 2003 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роИро░ро╛роХрпНроХро┐ройрпН рокроЯрпИропрпЖроЯрпБрокрпНрокрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЯро┐роЪроорпНрокро░рпН 2011 ро╡ро░рпИ роирпАроЯро┐родрпНрод роИро░ро╛роХрпН рокрпЛро░ро┐ройро╛ро▓рпН роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпНроЯ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИро╡рпБроХро│рпН роЖроХрпБроорпН. роЪроорпАрокродрпНродро┐роп роЖрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН, роЗроирпНроироХро░роорпН роЕроЯро┐роХрпНроХроЯро┐ роХро┐ро│ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ родро╛роХрпНроХрпБродро▓рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЖро│ро╛роХро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.2012 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН, рокро╛роХрпНродро╛родрпН роироХро░роорпН роЙро▓роХро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпБроорпН роХрпБро▒рпИроирпНрод ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпЛроорпНрокро▓рпН роЗроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХ рокроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро▓ро┐роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. роорпЖро░рпНроЪро░рпН родро░ро╡ро░ро┐роЪрпИропро┐ро▓рпН 221 рокрпЖро░ро┐роп роироХро░роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роорпЛроЪрооро╛рой роироХро░роорпН роОрой роЗроирпНроироХро░роорпН роородро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ."},{"question":"Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi c├│ mс╗Щt vс╗г ngoс║бi quс╗Сc. B├а vс╗г ─С├│ l├а ng╞░с╗Эi xс╗й n├аo?","answer":"Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi c├│ vс╗г ng╞░с╗Эi Cao LySau khi so t├аi ─Сс╗Б quс║бt с╗Я n╞░с╗Ыc Nguy├кn, sс╗й thс║зn Cao Ly (Triс╗Бu Ti├кn b├вy giс╗Э) tuy bс╗Л thua nh╞░ng rс║еt cс║гm phс╗еc t├аi n─Гng cс╗зa Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi. Hai ng╞░с╗Эi ─С├г kс║┐t th├вn v├а trс╗Я th├аnh ─С├┤i bс║бn tri kс╗╖. Khi sс╗й thс║зn Cao Ly vс╗Б n╞░с╗Ыc, ├┤ng ─С├г mс╗Эi Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi sang th─Гm Cao Ly 4 th├бng. Lс║зn ─С├│, sс╗й thс║зn Cao Ly ─С├г l├аm mс╗Сi cho Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi vс╗Ыi ng╞░с╗Эi ch├бu g├бi ─Сс╗Г l├аm thiс║┐p. Ng╞░с╗Эi vс╗г Cao Ly theo Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi ─Сi sс╗й. Hai ng╞░с╗Эi c├│ vс╗Ыi nhau ba ng╞░с╗Эi con, hai trai v├а mс╗Щt g├бi.Ng╞░с╗Эi vс╗г sau ─С├│ trс╗Я vс╗Б qu├к h╞░╞бng, chс╗Лu th╞░╞бng chс╗Лu kh├│ nu├┤i nс║еng dс║бy bс║гo, dс╗▒ng vс╗г gс║г chс╗Уng cho c├бc con. Sau ─С├│, b├а tс╗л biс╗Зt con ch├бu, ─Сi v├аo ch├╣a с╗Я. Hai ng╞░с╗Эi con trai cс╗зa Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi sau n├аy trс╗Я th├аnh bс║нc kс╗│ t├аi cс╗зa xс╗й Cao Ly.Vс╗Б viс╗Зc n├аy, gia phс║г tс╗Щc Mс║бc c├│ viс║┐t: \\"Tr├кn ─С╞░с╗Эng vс╗Б n╞░с╗Ыc, nhс║нn lс╗Эi mс╗Эi cс╗зa sс╗й thс║зn Cao Ly, Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi c├│ gh├й B├мnh Nh╞░с╗бng. Qu├╜ trс╗Нng mс╗Щt t├аi n─Гng v├а nh├вn c├бch, sс╗й thс║зn Cao Ly gс║г ch├бu g├бi y├кu cс╗зa ng├аi cho sс╗й thс║зn ─Рс║бi Viс╗Зt l├аm vс╗г thiс║┐p. V├м nс║╖ng t├мnh ng╞░с╗Эi v├а mс║┐n cс║гnh ─Сс║еt n╞░с╗Ыc ─Рс║бi H├аn, Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi ─С├г l╞░u lс║бi Triс╗Бu Ti├кn sinh hс║б mс╗Щt d├▓ng con b├кn ─С├│. Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi l╞░u luyс║┐n gi├г biс╗Зt vс╗г con mс╗Щt m├мnh l├кn ─С╞░с╗Эng trс╗Я vс╗Б cс╗С quс╗Сc\\".Theo b├аi viс║┐t Ng╞░с╗Эi Triс╗Бu Ti├кn ─Сi b├бn s├вm l├а hс║нu duс╗З cс╗зa Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi ─С─Гng tr├кn An Nam tс║бp ch├н sс╗С 4 n─Гm 1926, ├┤ng L├к Khс║пc H├▓e cho biс║┐t c├│ mс╗Щt ng╞░с╗Эi Triс╗Бu Ti├кn x╞░ng l├а hс║нu duс╗З cс╗зa Mс║бc ─Р─йnh Chi qua Viс╗Зt Nam ─Сс╗Г t├мm kiс║┐m d├▓ng hс╗Н. Sau n├аy, t├бc giс║г V┼й Hiс╗Зp s╞░u tс║нp v├а ─С─Гng tr├кn tс║бp ch├н Nghi├кn cс╗йu Sс╗н sс╗С 2, 1996 tс║бi S├аi G├▓n."},{"question":"Dark Olive ne renk?","answer":"Alt─▒n-ye┼Яil bir ton."},{"question":"р╢Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢ар╖Тр╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖П р╖Ар╖Пр╢╗р╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ ","answer":"р╢Ер╢з р╢пр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ер╢з р╢Ър╖Ьр╢л р╖Ар╖Пр╢йр╖Т р╖Ар╖Щр╢║ р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢з р╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╜р╖Ф р╢┤р╖Пр╢Ь р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ар╖Фр╢╜р╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢Ър╖Рр╢╗р╢Ър╖Щр╢▒ р╢Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢ар╖Т р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖Пр╢Ер╢┤р╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╢пр╖Тр╢╕р╖Ф р╢пр╖Рр╢▒р╖К р╢╗р╢▒р╖К р╢Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢ар╖Т р╢╜р╖Кр╢╜р╖П"},{"question":"р╕Шр╕▓р╕Хр╕╕ F р╕бр╕╡р╕Кр╕╖р╣Ир╕нр╣Ар╕гр╕╡р╕вр╕Бр╣Гр╕Щр╕ар╕▓р╕йр╕▓р╣Др╕Чр╕вр╕зр╣Ир╕▓р╕Шр╕▓р╕Хр╕╕р╣Гр╕Ф","answer":"р╕Шр╕▓р╕Хр╕╕р╕Яр╕ер╕╣р╕нр╕нр╕гр╕╡р╕Щ"},{"question":"HALISTA AMA KHATARKA DAAWADA CILAANKA AMA XINIGA LOO ISTICMAALO EE DALWANDI AMA MAHLABIYAD.","answer":"Maanta waxaan ka hadlaynaa arrin kaloo bulshadu aad u isticmaasho halisna ku ah caafimaadkeeda, waana daawooyinka cillaanka lagu daro oo soomaalidu qaar u taqaano \\"Dalwandi\\" iyo \\"mahlabiyad\\" afka qalaadne daawooyinkaas waxay ka siman yihiin kiimikada loo yaqaano \\"Paraphenylenediamine\\" loona soo gaabiyo \\"PPD\\".Waxaa daawadaan cillaanka loogu darsadaa si ay midabka dhakhso u soo saarto,cillaankane uga dhigto mid tiq ah.Daawadaan waxaa badanaa lagu soo daraa madoobeysada la marsado, waxaa kaloo lagu daraa khadka daabacadda dharka iyo dunta laga sameeyo taayarrada gawaarida.Daawadaan kiimikada ah waxay leedahay halis caafimaadka u daran, waana muhiim in qofkasta oo isticmaalo ogaado, marmarka qaar halisteeda waa loo dhiman karaa.Dhibaatada ugu horeyso ee laga dhaxli karo waa xasaasiyadda ama allejiga oo gaarsiisan heerka loo yaqaano \\"Anaphlactic shock\\" oo ah mid qofka dili karto, xasaasiyadaas oo laga dareemo meelaha cillaanka la mariyay sida maqaarka, tinta, garka iyo sunniyaha, haddii sunniyaha la marsado cillaan leh daawo oo qofka xasaasiyad ku qaado in uu ku indho beelo iyadoo keento laba xaaladooda oo loo yaqaano \\"keratitis\\" iyo \\"Neuritis\\".Haddii aad daawadaan xasaasiyad horey ugu dareentay oo mar kale isticmaashid waa halis in aad u dhimato ayaa dhici karto oo neefsashada kugu dhegto ama cadaadiska dhiigaaga uu hoos u dhaco ama coma aad gasho.Xasaasiyada ugu horeyso waa qofka oo dareemo in maqaarka midabkiisu isbadalay, cuncun ama jirka oo biyo gashado oo bacoolo yeesho, marmarka qaar dubka ayaa ka kici karo maqaarka oo qofka wuu dhiigbixi karaa ama suntaa dhiiga u sii gudbi karto oo qofka caafimaadkiisa halis ayuu gali karaa.Dhibaatada kale ee la dareemo waa in daawada oo la joogteeyo keento in dareemaha lugaha ama faraha ay dhaawac gaarsiiso taasoo loo dareemo kabuubyo ahaan, xaaladaan oo loo yaqaano \\"Toxic Neuropathy\\", waa xaalad uusan qofka ku baraarugin marka hore.Dhibaatada kale ee keento daawada cillaanka \\"PPD\\" waxaa ka mid ah kansarrada qaar oo ay soo bandhigtay hay'adda daawooyinka mareykanka ee FDA, kuwaas oo kala ah, kansarka dhiigga, kansarka qanjirrada, kansarka maqaarka, kanasarka naasaha iyo kansarka kaadiheysta.Cilmibaaris lagu sameeyay xanuunka howlgabka kilyaha oo la arkay inuu ku badanayo dadka ka shaqeeyo saaluunnada iyo meelaha la isku qurxiyo ayaa waxaa la sheegay in lala xiriirnayo sababta ay kilyaha u beeleen daawadaan PPD oo ku badan waxyaabaha ay isticmaalaan.Halista kiimikadaan waa mid mar hore la ogaaday oo joogto looga digo, wadamo dhowr ah sida jarmalka, Sweden iyo faransiiska waa ka mamnuuc in lagu gado waxyaabo jirka lagu qurxiyo in lagu daro daawadaan.Jarmalka wuxuu mamnuucay sanadkii 1900-kii.Faransiisku wuxuu mamnuucay sanadkii 1909-kii.Sweden waxay mamnuucday sanadkii 1964-tii."},{"question":"р╖Ар╖Тр╢зр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К E р╢Мр╢▒р╢нр╖П р╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢л р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╖Ар╖Тр╢зр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К E р╢Мр╢▒р╢нр╖П р╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢л р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖Ъ.1)      р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢лр╢н р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╖Ц р╢пр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Лр╢┤р╢нр╖К2)      р╢╗р╢нр╖Ф р╢╗р╖Фр╢░р╖Тр╢╗р╖Пр╢лр╖Ф р╢╢р╖Тр╢пр╖У р╢║р╖Пр╢╕ р╖Ар╖Ър╢Ьр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕3)      р╖Гр╖Ыр╢╜ р╖Ар╖Тр╢╖р╖Пр╢вр╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╖Кр╖Ар╢╜р╢нр╖П4)      р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢вр╢▒р╢▒р╢║ р╖Др╖П р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╢Ьр╖Рр╢зр╢╜р╖Ф"},{"question":"Nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi quan t├вm ─Сс║┐n bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ph├бt m├гi bс╗Яi cho rс║▒ng gi├б rс║╗ h╞бn thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng, nh╞░ng thс╗▒c tс║┐ ─С├вy ch╞░a chс║пc l├а \\"m├│n hс╗Эi\\", theo chuy├кn gia.T├┤i xem ─С╞░с╗гc nhiс╗Бu th├┤ng tin vс╗Б c├бc ng├вn h├аng ph├бt m├гi bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn nh╞░ nh├а ─Сс║еt, chung c╞░. Gi├б rao b├бn t├┤i thс║еy kh├б hс║еp dс║лn v├м thс║еp h╞бn so vс╗Ыi thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng. Nh╞░ng do kh├┤ng c├│ nhiс╗Бu kinh nghiс╗Зm, t├┤i b─Гn kho─Гn c├│ n├кn mua nhс╗пng c─Гn nh├а ─С╞░с╗гc ng├вn h├аng ph├бt m├гi kh├┤ng? Giao dс╗Лch t├аi sс║гn n├аy cс║зn l╞░u ├╜ g├м?Mong chuy├кn gia v├а c├бc ─Сс╗Щc giс║г cho t╞░ vс║еn.","answer":"Bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ph├бt m├гi ─С╞░с╗гc hiс╗Гu l├а t├аi sс║гn thс║┐ chс║еp vay vс╗Сn cс╗зa c├б nh├вn, tс╗Х chс╗йc nh╞░ng kh├┤ng ─Сс╗з n─Гng lс╗▒c trс║г nс╗г c├бc khoс║гn vay. Nс║┐u chс╗з sс╗Я hс╗пu kh├┤ng thanh to├бn nс╗г ─С├║ng hс║бn, ng├вn h├аng sс║╜ tс╗Лch thu v├а thanh l├╜ t├аi sс║гn ─Сс║гm bс║гo ─Сс╗Г thu hс╗Уi nс╗г.Nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi quan t├вm ─Сс║┐n bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ph├бt m├гi cс╗зa ng├вn h├аng v├м mс╗Щt sс╗С ╞░u ─Сiс╗Гm. Thс╗й nhс║еt l├а giс║еy tс╗Э ph├бp l├╜ ─С├г ─С╞░с╗гc thс║йm ─Сс╗Лnh kс╗╣ c├аng, sс║╡n s├аng chuyс╗Гn nh╞░с╗гng cho ng╞░с╗Эi mua, v├н dс╗е nh╞░ c─Гn hс╗Щ phс║гi c├│ sс╗Х hс╗Уng. ─Рiс╗Бu n├аy sс║╜ gi├║p ng╞░с╗Эi mua hс║бn chс║┐ nhс╗пng rс╗зi ro vс╗Б ph├бp l├╜ khi mua bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn. Thс╗й hai, ng├вn h├аng th╞░с╗Эng cung cс║еp ng╞░с╗Эi mua c├бc g├│i vay t├аi ch├нnh ─Сс╗Г th├║c ─Сс║йy qu├б tr├мnh ph├бt m├гi t├аi sс║гn.Mс╗Щt l├╜ do quan trс╗Нng nс╗пa ─Сс║┐n tс╗л t├вm l├╜ cс╗зa nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi mua l├а gi├б bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ph├бt m├гi rс║╗ h╞бn h╞бn thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng. Tuy nhi├кn bс║бn cс║зn l╞░u ├╜ kh├┤ng phс║гi tr╞░с╗Эng hс╗гp n├аo c┼йng c├│ \\"gi├б hс╗Эi\\". L├╜ do l├а nhiс╗Бu bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ─С├г ─С╞░с╗гc ─Сс╗Лnh gi├б cao h╞бn thс╗▒c tс║┐ khi ng├вn h├аng duyс╗Зt khoс║гn vay, ─Сс║╖c biс╗Зt trong giai ─Сoс║бn thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng ph├бt triс╗Гn cao tr├аo.V├н dс╗е v├аo n─Гm 2021, mс╗Щt c─Гn nh├а ─С╞░с╗гc ng├вn h├аng ─Сс╗Лnh gi├б 10 tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng, khoс║гn vay 70% l├а 7 tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng. Tuy nhi├кn hiс╗Зn nay, khi thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng ─Сi xuс╗Сng, gi├б sс╗еt giс║гm c├▓n 8 tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng, 70% gi├б trс╗Л c─Гn nh├а chс╗Й c├▓n 5,6 tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng. Nс║┐u bс║бn xuс╗Сng tiс╗Бn, gi├б trс╗Л c─Гn nh├а n├аy vс║лn ─С╞░с╗гc t├нnh theo ─Сс╗Лnh gi├б n─Гm 2021. Ch╞░a kс╗Г, gi├б bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ph├бt m├гi th╞░с╗Эng bao gс╗Уm cс║г d╞░ nс╗г gс╗Сc cс╗Щng vс╗Ыi l├гi khoс║гn vay v├а tiс╗Бn phс║бt cс╗зa ng├вn h├аng. Bс╗Яi vс║нy, ng╞░с╗Эi mua n├кn tho├бt khс╗Пi t├вm l├╜ ─С├вy l├а \\"m├│n hс╗Эi\\", c├│ gi├б rс║╗ h╞бn thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng.Bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ph├бt m├гi c┼йng tiс╗Бm с║йn mс╗Щt sс╗С rс╗зi ro. Viс╗Зc mua nh├а ─Сс║еt ph├бt m├гi li├кn quan ─Сс║┐n ba b├кn gс╗Уm ng├вn h├аng, chс╗з sс╗Я hс╗пu v├а ng╞░с╗Эi mua. Nс║┐u ng╞░с╗Эi mua ├нt kinh nghiс╗Зm trong mua b├бn bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn, qu├б tr├мnh ho├аn tс║еt giao dс╗Лch sс║╜ tс╗Сn nhiс╗Бu thс╗Эi gian h╞бn. Trong tr╞░с╗Эng hс╗гp chс╗з sс╗Я hс╗пu ch╞░a ho├аn tс║еt ngh─йa vс╗е hay kh├┤ng hс╗гp t├бc b├аn giao, bс║бn sс║╜ phс║гi chс╗Э c╞б quan c├│ thс║йm quyс╗Бn tham gia c╞░с╗бng chс║┐. Bс║бn c├▓n phс║гi chс╗Лu th├кm mс╗Щt sс╗С khoс║гn chi ph├н ph├бt sinh nh╞░ thuс║┐ chuyс╗Гn nh╞░с╗гng hoс║╖c c├бc ph├н tс╗Уn ─Сс╗Нng li├кn quan.Do ─С├│, ng╞░с╗Эi mua bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn ph├бt m├гi cс╗зa ng├вn h├аng cс║зn l╞░u ├╜ mс╗Щt sс╗С vс║еn ─Сс╗Б sau:Thс╗й nhс║еt, bс║бn n├кn ─Сс╗Лnh gi├б lс║бi bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn, ─Сс╗Уng thс╗Эi so s├бnh vс╗Ыi mс║╖t bс║▒ng thс╗Л tr╞░с╗Эng hiс╗Зn tс║бi ─Сс╗Г x├бc ─Сс╗Лnh gi├б ph├бt m├гi cс╗зa ng├вn h├аng c├│ thс╗▒c sс╗▒ hс║еp dс║лn. Nс║┐u kh├┤ng c├│ nhiс╗Бu kinh nghiс╗Зm, bс║бn n├кn thu├к ─С╞бn vс╗Л t╞░ vс║еn ─Сс╗Г c├│ thс╗Г ─Сс╗Лnh gi├б t├аi sс║гn ch├нnh x├бc.Thс╗й hai, ng╞░с╗Эi mua cс║зn y├кu cс║зu ng├вn h├аng cung cс║еp th├┤ng tin v├а hс╗У s╞б ph├бp l├╜ cс╗зa t├аi sс║гn ─Сс╗Г nс║пm ─С╞░с╗гc l├╜ do bс╗Л ph├бt m├гi, tr├бnh tr╞░с╗Эng hс╗гp c├│ tranh chс║еp vс╗Ыi b├кn thс╗й ba hay bс║еt ─Сс╗Щng sс║гn nс║▒m trong diс╗Зn quy hoс║бch.Thс╗й ba, bс║бn cс║зn nс║▒m r├╡ thс╗з tс╗еc ─Сс╗Лnh gi├б v├а quy tr├мnh ph├бt m├гi ─Сс╗Г tr├бnh nhс╗пng rс╗зi ro sau khi mua. Mс╗Щt l╞░u ├╜ l├а khi mua th├┤ng qua ─Сс║еu gi├б, ng╞░с╗Эi mua sс║╜ phс║гi trс║г th├кm mс╗Щt sс╗С khoс║гn ph├н ph├бt sinh. Viс╗Зc thanh to├бn n├аy cс║зn phс║гi thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn theo ba b├кn tс║бi ng├вn h├аng thay v├м thanh to├бn trс╗▒c tiс║┐p cho chс╗з sс╗Я hс╗пu c┼й"},{"question":"рдордХрд╛рд▓реБ рдХреНрд╖реЗрддреНрд░рдХреЛ рдХреБрди рдкрджрдпрд╛рддреНрд░рд╛ рдЧрдиреНрддрд╡реНрдпрд▓реЗ рд╕рдВрд╕рд╛рд░рдХреЛ рдкрд╛рдБрдЪреМрдВ-рдЕрдЧреНрд▓реЛ рд╣рд┐рдорд╛рд▓ рдордХрд╛рд▓реБрдХреЛ рджреГрд╢реНрдпрдХреЛ рд╕рд╛рде рдкреБрд░рд╛рдиреЛ рдЙрдЬрд╛рдбрд╕реНрдерд╛рдирдХреЛ рдЕрдиреБрднрд╡ рдкреНрд░рджрд╛рди рдЧрд░реНрджрдЫ?","answer":"рдордХрд╛рд▓реБ рдХреНрд╖реЗрддреНрд░рдХреЛ рдордХрд╛рд▓реБ рдЖрдзрд╛рд░ рд╢рд┐рд╡рд┐рд░ рдкрджрдпрд╛рддреНрд░рд╛рд▓реЗ рд╡рд┐рд╢реНрд╡рдХреЛ рдкрд╛рдБрдЪреМрдВ-рдЕрдЧреНрд▓реЛ рд╣рд┐рдорд╛рд▓ рдордХрд╛рд▓реБрдХреЛ рдордирдореЛрд╣рдХ рджреГрд╢реНрдпрд╣рд░реВрдХреЛ рд╕рд╛рде рдПрдХ рдкреБрд░рд╛рдиреЛ рдЙрдЬрд╛рдбрд╕реНрдерд╛рдирдХреЛ рдЕрдиреБрднрд╡ рдкреНрд░рджрд╛рди рдЧрд░реНрджрдЫред"},{"question":"р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢▒ р╢╜р╖Пр╢╢р╖Пр╢╜р╢нр╢╕ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢вр╢▒р╢┤р╢п р╖Др╖Тр╢зр╢┤р╖Ф р╢вр╢▒р╖Пр╢░р╖Тр╢┤р╢нр╖Тр╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖П р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п, р╖Гр╖Д 2023 р╢Фр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Эр╢╢р╢╗р╖К 12 р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢нр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Ар╢║р╖Г р╢Ър╖Ур╢║р╢п?","answer":"2023 р╢Фр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Эр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢╗р╖К 12 р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з, р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢▒ р╢╜р╖Пр╢╢р╖Пр╢╜р╢нр╢╕ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢вр╢▒р╢┤р╢п р╖Др╖Тр╢зр╢┤р╖Ф р╢вр╢▒р╖Пр╢░р╖Тр╢┤р╢нр╖Т р╢╢р╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╢Фр╢╢р╖Пр╢╕р╖П р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Фр╖Др╖Ф р╖Ар╢║р╖Г р╢Ер╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Ф 62 р╢Ър╖Т."},{"question":"Beqil ma mbind mii:Nu def ko muy mbugal, mu nekk luy waar ├▒i teew ak ├▒ay ├▒├лwi ca seen ginnaaw te di waaraateb way-g├лm ├▒a.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Nu def ko mu'y mbugal, mu nekk lu'y waar ├▒i teew ak ├▒a'y ├▒├лwi ca s├йen ginnaaw te di waaraateb wayg├лm ├▒a."},{"question":"с╗Мwс╗Н ba Fulani mс║╣ta nibi ti wс╗Нn ti n da awс╗Нn eeyan lс╗Нna niluu Tede","answer":"с╗Мwс╗Н awс╗Нn с║╣с╣гс╗Н fijilante ti ba awс╗Нn afurasi с╗Нdaran Fulani mс║╣ta kan, Yakubu Mohammed, с║╣ni ogun с╗Нdun, Saleh Magu, с╗Нmс╗Н с╗Нdun mс║╣tadinlogun ati Ibrahim Legi, с║╣ni с╗Нdun mс║╣talelogun. с╗Мna to lс╗Н lati ilu Tede si с╗Мjс║╣-Owode, nijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ Atisbo, nipinlс║╣ с╗Мyс╗Н, ni wс╗Нn ti mu wс╗Нn.Gс║╣gс║╣ ba a с╣гe gbс╗Н, wс╗Нn ni niс╣гe lawс╗Нn afurasi mс║╣tс║╣с║╣ta yii n fibс╗Нn ati ada halс║╣ mс╗Н awс╗Нn arinrin-ajo atawс╗Нn agbс║╣ to n gba с╗Нna naa kс╗Нja lс╗Н soko wс╗Нn, wс╗Нn si n ja wс╗Нn lole dukia wс╗Нn.LтАЩс╗Мjс╗Нruu, Wс║╣sidee, с╗Нsс║╣ yii, tс╗Нwс╗Н palaba wс╗Нn segi, itosi abule Ayefс║╣lс║╣ ni wс╗Нn lawс╗Нn janduku naa duro si, ti wс╗Нn si n ba iс╣гс║╣ laabi wс╗Нn lс╗Н.с╗Мgbс║╣ni Ademс╗Нla с╗Мlaworс║╣, to jс║╣ с╗Нga agba awс╗Нn fijilante agbegbe naa с╣гalaye fakс╗Нroyin wa pe o ti to с╗Нsс║╣ mс║╣ta sс║╣yin tawс╗Нn ti gbс╗Н oriс╣гiiriс╣гii iroyin buruku nipa iwa с╗Нdaran tawс╗Нn amookunс╣гika с║╣da naa n hu lagbegbe с╗Нhun, с╣гugbс╗Нn bawс╗Нn с╣гe n dс╗Нdс║╣ wс╗Нn ni wс╗Нn sa kiri lati ibikan si omi-in.с╗Мlawс╗Нс╗Нre ni oju с╗Нna kan to lс╗Н si adugbo Ayefс║╣lс║╣ lawс╗Нn Fulani с╗Нdaran yii fс║╣с║╣ fi с╣гe ibuba wс╗Нn, wс╗Нn ti n mura lati kс╗Н Gaa kan sibс║╣ kс╗Нwс╗Н too tс║╣ wс╗Нn.O ni igba kс║╣ta ree tawс╗Нn n gba adugbo naa kс╗Нja, tawс╗Нn n wa wс╗Нn kiri, laimс╗Н pe ori igi ni wс╗Нn sa pamс╗Н si.Lс╗Нjс╗Н ti wс╗Нn mu wс╗Нn yii, с╗Мlawс╗Нс╗Нre ni awс╗Нn ko gba с╗Нna ti gbogbo eeyan maa n gba, ki wс╗Нn ma baa fura, lojiji si lawс╗Нn yс╗Н si wс╗Нn, bi wс╗Нn с╣гe ri awс╗Нn ni wс╗Нn bс║╣rс║╣ si i yinbс╗Нn, bo tilс║╣ jс║╣ pe ibс╗Нn naa ko le jiс╣гс║╣ ti wс╗Нn ran an.с║╕yin naa ni wс╗Нn gba awс╗Нn ohun ija oloro ti wс╗Нn gbe dani, lara rс║╣ ni ibс╗Нn, ida oloju meji, ada, ati с╗Нpс╗Н oogun abс║╣nugс╗Нngс╗Н. Wс╗Нn lawс╗Нn Fulani yii jс║╣wс╗Н pe ipinlс║╣ Katsina lawс╗Нn ti wa, ati pe loootс╗Н lawс╗Нn n da awс╗Нn eeyan lс╗Нna lagbegbe naa.с╗Мlawс╗Нre ni gbara tawс╗Нn ba ti pari iwadii lawс╗Нn yoo fa wс╗Нn le awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa teс╣гan Tede lс╗Нwс╗Н, awс╗Нn si nigbagbс╗Н pтАЩawс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa yoo fс║╣sс║╣ ofin to с╗Нrс╗Н naa bo с╣гe yс║╣.с╗Мlawс╗Нс╗Нre waa gba awс╗Нn araalu nimс╗Нran lati yс║╣ra fun irin alс║╣ ati aajin lasiko yii, nitori awс╗Нn apamс╗Нlс║╣kun-jaye wс╗Нnyi."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д:  ╪┤┘Ж┘И ┘З┘К ╪з┘Д╪│┘И╪▒╪й ╪з┘Д┘Е┘Д┘В╪и┘З ╪и╪╣╪▒┘И╪│ ╪з┘Д┘В╪▒╪в┘Ж╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪з┘Д╪▒╪н┘Е┘Ж"},{"question":"рокрпВройрпИропро┐ройрпН роЖропрпБроЯрпНроХро╛ро▓роорпН?","answer":"12 ро╡ро░рпБроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпН."},{"question":" роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН рокро┐ро░родрооро░рпН ропро╛ро░рпН ?","answer":"роЗроирпНродро┐ропрокрпН рокро┐ро░родрооро░рпН роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЗроирпНродро┐ропродрпН родро▓рпИроорпИ роЕроорпИроЪрпНроЪро░рпН роОройрпНрокро╡ро░рпН роЗроирпНродро┐роп роЕро░роЪро┐ройрпН роЪрпЖропро▓ро╛роХрпНроХродрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпН роЖро╡ро╛ро░рпН. роЗро╡ро░рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропроХрпН роХрпБроЯро┐ропро░роЪрпБродрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░ро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроорпИ роЖро▓рпЛроЪроХро░рпБроорпН роородрпНродро┐роп роЕроорпИроЪрпНроЪро░ро╡рпИропро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпБроорпН роЖро╡ро╛ро░рпН. роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН рокро┐ро░родрооро░рпН рокродро╡ро┐ роОройрпНрокродрпБ рооро┐роХ роЙропро░рпНроирпНрод, роЕродро┐роХ роЕродро┐роХро╛ро░роЩрпНроХро│рпН роЙро│рпНро│ рокродро╡ро┐ропро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗроирпНродро┐роп рокро╛ро░ро╛ро│рпБрооройрпНро▒родрпНродро┐ройрпН роороХрпНроХро│ро╡рпИ роЙро▒рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройро░рпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропрокрпН рокро┐ро░родрооро░рпН родрпЗро░рпНроирпНродрпЖроЯрпБроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡ро╛ро░рпН. роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роорпБродро▓рпН рокро┐ро░родрооро░рпН роЬро╡ро╣ро░рпНро▓ро╛ро▓рпН роирпЗро░рпБ роЖро╡ро╛ро░рпН, родро▒рпНрокрпЛродрпИроп рокро┐ро░родрооро░ро╛роХ роиро░рпЗроирпНродро┐ро░ роорпЛродро┐ рокродро╡ро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ро╛ро░рпН.рокро┐ро░родрооро░рпН рокро╛ро░ро╛ро│рпБрооройрпНро▒родрпНродро┐ройрпН роороХрпНроХро│ро╡рпИ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ рооро╛роиро┐ро▓роЩрпНроХро│ро╡рпИропро┐ройрпН роЙро▒рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройро░ро╛роХ роЗро░рпБродрпНродро▓рпН ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. роЗро▓рпНро▓рпИропрпЖройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН роЖро▒рпБ рооро╛родродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБро│рпН роороХрпНроХро│ро╡рпИроорпЗро▓ро╡рпИропро┐ройрпН роЙро▒рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройро░ро╛роХ родрпЗро░рпНроирпНродрпЖроЯрпБроХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯ ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. роТро░рпБ рокро┐ро░родрооро░ро┐ройрпН рокродро╡ро┐роХрпНроХро╛ро▓роорпН роРроирпНродрпБ роЖрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роЖроХрпБроорпН.рокро┐ро░родрооро░рпН, роЗроирпНродро┐ропроХрпН роХрпБроЯро┐ропро░роЪрпБродрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░ро╛ро▓рпН роиро┐ропрооро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ро▒ро╛ро░рпН. рокро╛ро░ро╛ро│рпБрооройрпНро▒родрпНродро┐ройрпН роороХрпНроХро│ро╡рпИропро┐ройрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпНрокро╛ройрпНроорпИ роЙро▒рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройро░рпНроХро│рпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роХроЯрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпИ роороЯрпНроЯрпБроорпЗ роХрпБроЯро┐ропро░роЪрпБродрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпН роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐ роЕроорпИроХрпНроХ роЕро┤рпИрокрпНрокро╛ро░рпН. роОроирпНродроХрпН роХроЯрпНроЪро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпНрокро╛ройрпНроорпИ рокро▓роорпН роЗро▓рпНро▓рпИропрпЖройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН роХрпВроЯрпНроЯрогро┐роХрпНроХроЯрпНроЪро┐родрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпИропрпЛ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЕродро┐роХ роороХрпНроХро│ро╡рпИ роЙро▒рпБрокрпНрокро┐ройро░рпНроХро│рпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роТро░рпБ роХроЯрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпИропрпЛ роЕро┤рпИрокрпНрокро╛ро░рпН."},{"question":"р╢╜р╖Др╢нр╖К р╢нр╖Тр╢╣р╢║р╖Т, р╢нр╖Тр╢╣р╢нр╖К р╢╜р╖Др╢║р╖Т р╢║р╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Рр╢╕р╖Т р╖Ар╖Др╢╗р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Тр╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢Ър╢нр╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Д р╢нр╖Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╖Др╢нр╢╗ р╢Ър╖Эр╢╗р╢╜р╢║р╖Щ р╢Ер╢║ р╢нр╖Тр╢╣ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Ър╢╗р╖Ф 3 р╢з р╢╜р╖Пр╖Д р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Ър╢╗р╖Ф 4р╢з р╖Гр╖Ър╢╗р╖Фр╖А р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Др╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢йр╖Ф 4 р╢з"},{"question":"р░░р░╛р░Ьр░╛ р░мр░╣р░жр▒Нр░жр▒Вр░░р▒Н р░╡р▒Жр░Вр░Хр░Я р░░р░╛р░ор░╛р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐ р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╕р▒Нр░ер░▓р░ир▒Б р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐?","answer":"р░╡р▒Жр░Вр░Хр░Я р░░р░╛р░ор░╛р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐ р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р░┐ р░ор░ир▒Нр░ир░ир░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Кр░Вр░жр░┐р░и р░╡р▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐. р░мр░╣р▒Бр░нр░╛р░╖р░╛р░╡р▒Зр░др▒Нр░д. р░др░и р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р░┐р░др░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ -р░кр▒Нр░░р░Ьр░╛р░╕р▒Зр░╡р░Хр▒З р░Ер░Вр░Хр░┐р░др░В р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐р░и р░╡р▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐. р░Жр░пр░ир░Хр▒Б р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░кр░Яр▒Нр░▓ р░╢р▒Нр░░р░жр▒Нр░зр░Чр░▓р░╡р░╛р░░р▒Б. р░кр░▓р▒Б р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╕р░Вр░╕р▒Нр░ер░▓р░ир▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░Ьр░╛р░╕р▒Зр░╡ р░Ър▒Зр░╢р░╛р░░р▒Б.1. р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░д р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ :р░ор▒Кр░др▒Нр░др░В р░╣р▒Ир░жр░░р░╛р░мр░╛р░жр▒Б р░░р░╛р░╖р▒Нр░Яр▒Нр░░р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░ор░и р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░ор░╛р░др▒Гр░нр░╛р░╖р░╛ р░мр▒Лр░зр░ир░Хр▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р░нр▒Бр░др▒Нр░╡ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░д р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ р░▓р▒Зр░Хр░кр▒Лр░╡р░Яр░В р░жр▒Бр░░р░жр▒Гр░╖р▒Нр░Яр░Хр░░р░ор░ир░┐ р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░нр░╛р░╡р░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░д р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Л р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░Йр░░р▒Нр░жр▒В, р░Жр░Вр░Чр▒Нр░▓ р░ор░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░о р░мр▒Лр░зр░и р░Ьр░░р▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Хр░╛р░╡р▒Бр░и р░╣р▒Ир░жр░░р░╛р░мр░╛р░жр▒Бр░▓р▒Л р░Тр░Х р░ор░╛р░др▒Гр░нр░╛р░╖р░╛ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓ р░Хр▒Лр░╕р░В р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░ир░┐ р░др░▓р░Ър░┐ р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Нр░░р▒А р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛ р░кр▒Нр░░р▒Лр░др▒Нр░╕р░╛р░╣р░Хр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░ор░╛р░бр░кр░╛р░Яр░┐ р░╣р░ир▒Бр░ор░Вр░др░░р░╛р░╡р▒Бр░Чр░╛р░░р░┐р░ир░┐ р░Хр░▓р░┐р░╕р░┐ р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Зр░жр░┐ р░мр▒Кр░Вр░мр░╛р░пр░┐р░▓р▒Л тАШр░Хр░╛р░░р▒Нр░╡р▒ЗтАЩ р░ор░╣р░╛р░╢р░пр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░ор░╣р░┐р░│р░╛р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░кр▒Ар░ар░Вр░др▒Л р░Ьр░д р░Ър▒Зр░╢р░╛р░░р▒Б. р░жр▒Ар░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░Ер░зр▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Бр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░░р░╛р░ор░╛р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б.2. р░кр░░р▒Лр░кр░Хр░╛р░░р░┐р░гр▒А р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░╛ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ :р░╣р▒Ир░жр░░р░╛р░мр░╛р░жр▒Н р░░р░╛р░ор░╛р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░ор░░р▒Кр░Х р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ р░кр░░р▒Лр░кр░Хр░╛р░░р░┐р░гр▒А р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░╛ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓. р░Зр░жр░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р▒Ир░ор░░р▒А р░др░░р░Чр░др░┐ р░╡р░░р░Хр▒Б р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░жр░┐. р░жр▒Ар░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░Ер░зр▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Бр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░░р░╛р░ор░╛р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐ р░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б.3. р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░╕р▒Жр░▓р▒Н р░╕р░┐р░пр░░р▒Н р░ор░┐р░бр░┐р░▓р▒Н р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓:р░И р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б 1945р░▓р▒Л р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░жр▒Ар░ир░┐ р░кр░╛р░▓р░Х р░╡р░░р▒Нр░Ч р░Ер░зр▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░░р░╛р░ор░╛р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р▒З! р░жр▒Ар░ир░┐р░▓р▒Л р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░Чр▒Б р░мр░╛р░▓р▒Бр░░р░Хр▒З р░кр▒Нр░░р░╡р▒Зр░╢р░ор▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Жр░Вр░Чр▒Нр░▓, р░Йр░░р▒Нр░жр▒В р░ор░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░ор░╛р░▓р▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░Хр░кр▒Лр░╡р░Яр░Вр░др▒Л р░Ер░Вр░др░Чр░╛ р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Жр░╕р░Хр▒Нр░др░┐ р░Ър▒Вр░кр░▓р▒Зр░жр▒Б.4. р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░╛ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ (р░Чр▒Кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░мр░┐р░бр▒Нр░Хр░┐) :р░╣р▒Ир░жр░░р░╛р░мр░╛р░жр▒Б р░Чр▒Кр░▓р▒Нр░▓р░Цр░┐р░бр▒Нр░Хр░┐р░▓р▒Л р░Тр░Х р░Жр░Вр░зр▒Нр░░р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░╛ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р░Ьр░╛р░╕р▒Зр░╡р░Хр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Хр▒Кр░Вр░жр░░р▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░жр▒Ар░ир░┐ р░мр░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░др░ир▒Б р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р▒З р░╕р▒Нр░╡р▒Ар░Хр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б.5. р░кр░░р▒Лр░кр░Хр░╛р░░р░┐р░гр▒А р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░╛ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ :р░╕р░┐р░Хр░┐р░Вр░жр░░р░╛р░мр░╛р░жр▒Б р░ир░Чр░░р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Хр▒Ареер░╢р▒Зрее р░╕р▒Ар░др░ор▒Нр░ор░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░Ж р░Хр░╛р░▓р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Йр░Вр░бр▒Зр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Жр░ор▒Ж р░др░и р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р░┐р░др░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░зр░╛р░░р░кр▒Лр░╕р░┐ р░Тр░Х р░ор░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░ор░┐р░Х р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Ж р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ р░Ер░нр░┐р░╡р▒Гр░жр▒Нр░зр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░╕р░╣р░╛р░п р░кр░бр▒Нр░бр░╛р░░р▒Б.6. р░Жр░Вр░зр▒Нр░░р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р░пр░В :р░╣р▒Ир░жр░░р░╛р░мр░╛р░жр▒Б р░ир░Чр░░р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░Чр▒Б р░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓р░Хр▒Б р░ор░╛р░др▒Гр░нр░╛р░╖ р░жр▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р░╛ р░Ър░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Б р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░Яр░Хр▒Б р░Тр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░ор░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░ор░┐р░Х р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓ р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░▓р▒Зр░жр▒Б. 1931р░▓р▒Л р░жр▒Зр░╡р░░р░Хр▒Кр░Вр░б р░╕р░нр░▓р▒Л р░И р░╡р░┐р░╖р░пр░В р░кр▒Нр░░р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░╡р░ир░Хр▒Б р░╡р░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. р░░р░╛р░Ьр░╛р░мр░╣р░жр▒Нр░жр▒Вр░░р▒Н р░╡р▒Жр░Вр░Хр░Я р░░р░╛р░ор░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░Ж р░╕р░нр░Хр▒Б р░Ер░зр▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░╖р░д р░╡р░╣р░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Ор░▓р░╛р░Чр▒Ир░ир░╛ р░Тр░Х р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░ир░┐ р░др▒Ар░░р▒Нр░ор░╛р░ир░В р░Ър▒Зр░╢р░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Ер░жр░┐ р░Ър░┐р░╡р░░р░Хр▒Б р░╕р▒Жр░кр▒Нр░Яр▒Жр░Вр░мр░░р▒Б1, 1944р░Хр▒Б р░Хр░╛р░ир▒А р░╕р░╛р░ир▒Бр░Хр▒Вр░▓р░В р░Хр░╛р░▓р▒Зр░жр▒Б. р░Ж р░др░░р▒Бр░╡р░╛р░д р░Ер░жр░┐ 1947 р░ир░╛р░Яр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р░┐ р░Ър░▓р░╡р░др▒Л р░Й р░ир▒Нр░ир░д р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░Чр░╛ р░Ор░жр░┐р░Чр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐.р░Зр░▓р░╛ р░░р░╛р░Ьр░╛р░мр░╣р░жр▒Нр░жр▒Вр░░р▒Н р░░р░╛р░ор░╛р░░р▒Жр░бр▒Нр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░╡р░┐р░жр▒Нр░пр░кр░Яр▒Нр░▓ р░ор░┐р░Хр▒Нр░Хр░┐р░▓р░┐ р░Жр░╕р░Хр▒Нр░др░┐р░ир░┐ р░Хр░ир░кр░░р░Ър░┐, р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░Чр▒Б р░ор░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░ор░Вр░▓р▒Л р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓р▒Б р░Ър░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Б р░Хр▒Лр░╡р░Яр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓р░▓р░ир▒Б р░╕р▒Нр░ер░╛р░кр░┐р░Вр░Ър░Яр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Нр░╖р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░кр░░р▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░╖р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Хр░╛р░░р░Хр▒Бр░▓р░пр▒Нр░пр░╛р░░р▒Б."},{"question":"N├кu nguy├кn nh├вn, diс╗Еn biс║┐n, kс║┐t quс║г cс╗зa mс╗Чi ph├бt minh trong b├аi Nhс╗пng ph├бt minh t├мnh cс╗Э v├а bс║еt ngс╗Э Ngс╗п v─Гn lс╗Ыp 6.","answer":"Nguy├кn nh├вn, diс╗Еn biс║┐n, kс║┐t quс║г cс╗зa mс╗Чi ph├бt minh:- ─Рс║еt nс║╖n:+ Nguy├кn nh├вn: Ng╞░с╗Эi d├вn c├│ xu h╞░с╗Ыng sс╗н dс╗еng ga dс║лn ─Сс║┐n loс║бi bс╗Щt ─Сс║еt s├йt ─Сс║╖c biс╗Зt c├│ c├┤ng dс╗еng loс║бi bс╗П c├бc vс║┐t ─Сen do bс╗У h├│ng kh├┤ng c├▓n ─С╞░с╗гc b├бn chс║бy, c├┤ng ti c├│ nguy c╞б thua lс╗Ч nghi├кm trс╗Нng.+ Diс╗Еn biс║┐n: V├нch-c╞б nhс╗Ы lс║бi b├аi hс╗Нc ng├аy x╞░a chс╗Л dс║бy vс╗Б viс╗Зc sс╗н dс╗еng nhс╗пng chс║еt bс╗Щt nh├гo ─Сс╗Г m├┤ phс╗Пng ─Сс╗Щ dс║╗o cс╗зa ─Сс║еt s├йt.+ Kс║┐t quс║г: N─Гm 1957, ├┤ng biс║┐n thiс║┐t kс║┐ cс╗зa m├мnh th├аnh mс╗Щt loс║бi ─Сс╗У ch╞бi trс║╗ em vс╗Ыi nhiс╗Бu m├аu sс║пc, ─Сem lс║бi lс╗гi nhuс║нn cao h├аng triс╗Зu ─С├┤ la Mс╗╣.- Kem que:+ Nguy├кn nh├вn: ├Йp-p╞б-x╞бn v├┤ t├мnh d├╣ng mс╗Щt chiс║┐c que trс╗Щn bс╗Щt soda kh├┤ v├а n╞░с╗Ыc lс║бi vс╗Ыi nhau trong mс╗Щt chiс║┐c cс╗Сc ─Сс╗Г nghс╗Лch, sau ─С├│, bс╗П qu├кn ch├║ng.+ Diс╗Еn biс║┐n: H├┤m sau, ├Йp-p╞б-x╞бn ph├бt hiс╗Зn ra mс╗Щt тАЬque kс║╣o b─ГngтАЭ с╗Я ─С├│ v├а khoe c├бc bс║бn. V├м ─С╞░с╗гc l├аm tс╗л soda n├кn khi nс║┐m sс║╜ c├│ hiс╗Зn t╞░с╗гng nс╗Х li ti.+ Kс║┐t quс║г: N─Гm 1923, ├Йp-p╞б-x╞бn ─С├г k├н bс║▒ng s├бng chс║┐ cho thiс║┐t kс║┐ cс╗зa m├мnh, ─С├бnh dс║еu ra ─Сс╗Эi kem que тАУ sс║гn phс║йm b├бn chс║бy nhс║еt m├╣a h├и.- L├бt khoai t├вy chi├кn+ Nguy├кn nh├вn: Cr─Гm khi с║еy ─Сang cс╗С phс╗еc vс╗е m├│n khoai t├вy Ph├бp do mс╗Щt kh├бch h├аng ─Сс║╖t v├аo m├╣a h├и.+ Diс╗Еn biс║┐n: Kh├бch h├аng li├кn tс╗еc trс║г m├│n v├а y├кu cс║зu phс║гi th├бi l├бt mс╗Пng h╞бn v├а gi├▓n h╞бn. + Kс║┐t quс║г: Cr─Гm ─С├г mс║еt b├мnh t─йnh, cс║пt l├бt khoai mс╗Пng h╞бn rс╗Уi chi├кn ch├║ng sao cho kh├┤ cс╗йng nhс║еt c├│ thс╗Г. Ch├║ng trс╗Я n├кn phс╗Х biс║┐n.- Giс║еy nhс╗Ы:+ Nguy├кn nh├вn: Xin-v╞б tс║бo ra mс╗Щt chс║еt d├нnh tс║бm trong ph├▓ng th├н nghiс╗Зm nh╞░ng kh├┤ng biс║┐t sс╗н dс╗еng n├│ v├аo viс╗Зc g├м.+ Diс╗Еn biс║┐n: Chс║еt d├нnh c├│ thс╗Г d├нnh mс╗Щt vс║нt c├│ trс╗Нng l╞░с╗гng nhс╗П, d├нnh l├кn bс╗Б mс║╖t m├а kh├┤ng l├аm h╞░ hс║бi g├м v├а rс║еt bс╗Бn, c├│ thс╗Г d├╣ng d├бn lс║бi nhiс╗Бu lс║зn.+ Kс║┐t quс║г: Khi ─Сс╗Уng nghiс╗Зp cс╗зa ├┤ng ─Сang bс╗▒c tс╗йc v├м kh├┤ng thс║┐ t├мm c├бch g├м d├бn mс╗Щt sс╗С tс╗Э giс║еy l├кn cuс╗Сn s├бch cс╗зa m├мnh v├а tс╗л ─С├│ ├╜ t╞░с╗Яng ra ─Сс╗Эi."},{"question":"ри╡ри╛ри╢ри┐рй░риЧриЯрии, 5 риори╛ри░риЪриЕриори░рйАриХри╛ ри╡ри┐риЪ рикри╛риХри┐ри╕ридри╛рии рижрйЗ ри░ри╛риЬрижрйВрид риЕри╕риж риориЬрйАриж риЦри╝ри╛рии рижри╛ риХри╣ри┐ригри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ рикрйБри▓ри╡ри╛риори╛ ри╣риори▓рйЗ ридрйЛриВ римри╛риЕриж рикри╛риХри┐ риирйВрй░ риири┐ри╢ри╛риирйЗ тАЩридрйЗ ри▓рйИ риХрйЗ ринри╛ри░рид тАШриЦри╝рйБриж ри╣рйА риЕрижри╛ри▓рид, риЬрй▒риЬ ридрйЗ рилри╛ри╣рйЗ риЯрй░риЧригтАЩ ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ римриг римрйИриари╛ ри╣рйИред риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижри╛риЕри╡ри╛ риХрйАридри╛ риХри┐ тАШри╕рй░риЧриари┐рид рикрй▒ризри░ риЙрй▒ридрйЗтАЩ рикри╛риХри┐ри╕ридри╛рии ри╡ри┐риЪ риХрйЛриИ риЕридри┐ри╡ри╛рижрйА риЬриерйЗримрй░рижрйА риорйМриЬрйВриж риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйИред ри░ри╛риЬрижрйВрид риирйЗ риири╛ри▓ ри╣рйА риХри┐ри╣ри╛ риХри┐ рикри╛риХри┐ ри╡рй▒ри▓рйЛриВ ринри╛ри░рид риЦри╝ри┐ри▓ри╛рилри╝ риРрй▒рил-16 риЬри╣ри╛риЬри╝ри╛риВ рижрйА ри╡ри░ридрйЛриВ римри╛ри░рйЗ риЕриори░рйАриХри╛ ри╡рй▒ри▓рйЛриВ риорй░риЧрйА риХри┐ри╕рйЗ ри╡рйА ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйА риЬри╛ригриХри╛ри░рйА римри╛ри░рйЗ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риирйВрй░ риХрйЛриИ риЗри▓рио риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйИред риЬри╝ри┐риХри░рипрйЛриЧ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ ринри╛ри░ридрйА ри╣ри╡ри╛риИ рилри╝рйМриЬ риирйЗ риЗриХ риЦри╝ри╛ри╕ риХри┐ри╕рио рижрйА риори┐риЬри╝ри╛риИри▓ рикри╛риХри┐ ри╣риори▓рйЗ ридрйЛриВ римри╛риЕриж ри╕римрйВрид ри╡рй▒риЬрйЛриВ рикрйЗри╢ риХрйАридрйА ри╕рйА ридрйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйА риХри┐ риЗри╣ риРрй▒рил-16 ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╣рйА ри╡ри░ридрйА риЬри╛риВрижрйА ри╣рйИред риЬрижриХри┐ рикри╛риХри┐ риирйЗ риЗриирйНри╣ри╛риВ риЬри╣ри╛риЬри╝ри╛риВ рижрйА ри╡ри░ридрйЛриВ ридрйЛриВ рикрй▒ри▓ри╛ риЭри╛рйЬри┐риЖ ри╕рйАред риЕриори░рйАриХрйА ри╡ри┐рижрйЗри╢ ри╡ри┐ринри╛риЧ риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЙри╣ риирйЗриори╛риВ рижри╛ риЙри▓рй░риШриг риХри░ риХрйЗ рикри╛риХри┐ри╕ридри╛рии ри╡рй▒ри▓рйЛриВ риРрй▒рил-16 ри╡ри░ридриг римри╛ри░рйЗ рикри╛риХри┐ ридрйЛриВ риЬри╛ригриХри╛ри░рйА риорй░риЧ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИред риЦри╝ри╛рии риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ риХри┐ рикри╛риХри┐ри╕ридри╛рии ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╡рйЬ риХрйЗ ри╣ри╡ри╛риИ ри╣риори▓ри┐риЖриВ ри░ри╛ри╣рйАриВ 300 риЕридри┐ри╡ри╛рижрйА риори╛ри░рии рижри╛ рижри╛риЕри╡ри╛ риХри░ риХрйЗ ринри╛ри░рид риирйЗ рикри╣ри┐ри▓ри╛риВ ридрйЛриВ ри╣рйА ри╕ри┐риЦри╝ри░ри╛риВ тАЩридрйЗ рикрйБрй▒риЬрйЗ риЯриХри░ри╛риЕ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйЛри░ ри╣ри╡ри╛ рижрйЗ рижри┐рй▒ридрйАред ри░ри╛риЬрижрйВрид риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ риХри┐ риХрйМриори╛риВридри░рйА риорй░риЪ риЙрй▒ридрйЗ риЕридрйЗ ринри╛ри░рид ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╡рйА ри╣рйБриг риЗриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижри╛риЕри╡ри┐риЖриВ риирйВрй░ риЦри╛ри░риЬ риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИред риЕриори░рйАриХрйА риХри╛риВриЧри░ри╕ ри╡рй▒ри▓рйЛриВ риЪри▓ри╛риП риЬри╛риВрижрйЗ риери┐рй░риХ риЯрйИриВриХ рипрйВриРрй▒ри╕ риЗрй░ри╕риЯрйАриЪри┐риКриЯ риЖрилри╝ рикрйАри╕ риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ рикрйЗри╢ ри╣рйБрй░рижри┐риЖриВ риЦри╝ри╛рии риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ риХри┐ рикри╛риЗри▓риЯ риирйВрй░ ри░ри┐ри▓рйАриЬри╝ риХрйАридрйЗ риЬри╛риг ридрйЛриВ римри╛риЕриж ри╣рйБриг риРри▓риУри╕рйА тАЩридрйЗ ридригри╛риЕрикрйВри░рии риори╛ри╣рйМри▓ ри╣рйИред риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рикри╛риХри┐ рикрйНри░ризри╛рии риорй░ридри░рйА риЗриори░ри╛рии риЦри╝ри╛рии ри╡рй▒ри▓рйЛриВ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗ риЧрй▒ри▓римри╛рид рижрйЗ ри╕рй▒рижрйЗ риирйВрй░ ри╡рйА рижрйБри╣ри░ри╛риЗриЖред                                                     рикри╛риХри┐ри╕ридри╛рии ри╡рй▒ри▓рйЛриВ ринри╛ри░рид ри╡ри┐ри░рйБрй▒риз риРрил-16 риЬри╣ри╛риЬри╝ри╛риВ рижрйА ри╡ри░ридрйЛриВ римри╛ри░рйЗ рижрйВридри╛ри╡ри╛ри╕ риирйВрй░ риХрйА рикридри╛ ри╣рйИ?                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    ","answer":"рижри┐рй▒ридрйА риЧриИ риЦримри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри░ри╛риЬрижрйВрид риирйВрй░ риЕриори░рйАриХри╛ рижрйБриЖри░ри╛ риорй░риЧрйА риЧриИ риХри┐ри╕рйЗ ри╡рйА риЬри╛ригриХри╛ри░рйА римри╛ри░рйЗ рикридри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйИред"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н  р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕ р╢┤р╢пр╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢пр╖Пр╖Е р╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╖Тр╢Вр╢Ь р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Пр╢пр╢Ъ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?р╢▒р╖Ер╖Фр╖Ар╖П ","answer":"р╢▒р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢║ "},{"question":"р░Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐р░и р░кр░жр▒Нр░пр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░нр░╛р░╡р░В р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐:р░╡р░┐р░кр░┐р░и р░мр░Вр░зр▒Бр░░ р░╡р▒Гр░Хр▒Нр░╖р░╡р░╛р░Яр░┐р░Хр░Йр░кр░ир░┐р░╖р░ир▒Нр░ор░зр▒Б р░╡р▒Кр░▓р░┐р░Хр▒Ж р░ир░┐р░Ър▒Нр░Ър░Яр░╡р░┐р░кр▒Бр░▓ р░др░др▒Нр░др▒Нр░╡р░ор▒Б р░╡р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░ир░╡р░┐р░ор░▓ р░др░▓ р░ор░┐р░жр▒Ж р░др░ор▒Нр░ор▒Бр░бр░╛ !","answer":"р░др░ор▒Нр░ор▒Бр░бр░╛ ! р░И р░жр▒Зр░╢р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░жр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░ор▒Ир░и р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░▓р░др▒Л р░Хр▒Вр░бр░┐р░и, р░╡р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░░р░ор▒Ир░и р░Ер░░р░гр▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░Йр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░┐. р░ор░зр▒Бр░░р░ор▒Ир░и р░Йр░кр░ир░┐р░╖р░др▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Зр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░бр▒З р░кр▒Бр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░Зр░жр░┐ р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░╛р░▓р░др▒Л р░Хр▒Вр░бр░┐р░и р░др░др▒Нр░др▒Нр░╡р░мр▒Лр░зр░и р░╡р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░кр░╡р░┐р░др▒Нр░░р░нр▒Вр░ор░┐.р░Йр░кр░ир░┐р░╖р░др▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Б : р░╡р▒Зр░жр░╛р░▓ р░Ер░Вр░др▒Нр░пр░нр░╛р░Чр░╛р░▓р▒Б. (р░╡р▒Ар░Яр░┐р░ир░▓р▒Нр░▓ р░мр▒Нр░░р░╣р▒Нр░ор░Ьр▒Нр░Юр░╛р░ир░В р░Хр░▓р▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐.)1) р░Ыр░╛р░Вр░жр▒Лр░Чр▒Нр░пр░ор▒Б,2) р░Ир░╢р░╛ р░╡р░╛р░╕р▒Нр░пр░ор▒Б,3) р░Хр░ар▒Лр░кр░ир░┐р░╖р░др▒Нр░др▒Б,4) р░Хр▒Зр░ир▒Лр░кр░ир░┐р░╖р░др▒Нр░др▒Б р░ор▒К||р░╡р░┐."},{"question":"чЫ╕цТ▓уБзуАБф╜УхЛвуБМх┤йуВМуАБуБЩуБзуБлчлЛуБжчЫ┤уБЩуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуБкуБДчК╢цЕЛуБоуБУуБиуВТф╜ХуБиуБДуБЖуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"цн╗уБлф╜УуБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"Vraag: Wie maakte het schilderij Het Joodse Bruidje? A. Rembrandt, B. Vermeer, C. Van Gogh. D. Rubens","answer":"Antwoord: A. Rembrandt"},{"question":"роТро▒рпНро▒рпИ роТро▓ро┐роорпНрокро┐роХрпНроХро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХ роТро▓ро┐роорпНрокро┐роХрпН рокродроХрпНроХроорпН ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒ роиро╛роЯрпБ роОродрпБ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛"},{"question":"G├╢z tansiyonu ne gibi belirtiler olur?","answer":"G├╢z tansiyonu nas─▒l anla┼Я─▒l─▒r? Ba┼Яlang─▒├зta g├╢z tansiyonu belirti vermez ancak rutin muayenede g├╢z tansiyonu olup olmad─▒─Я─▒ anla┼Я─▒l─▒r. ─░lerleyen durumlarda g├╢z a─Яr─▒s─▒, g├╢z k─▒zar─▒kl─▒─Я─▒, ani g├╢rme sorunlar─▒, renkli halkalar g├╢rmek, baz─▒ durumlarda mide bulant─▒s─▒ ve istifra ile de belirti verebilir."},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕ р╢┤р╢пр╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢пр╖Пр╖Е р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╖В р╢╜р╖Тр╢Вр╢Ь р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Пр╢пр╢Ъ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п? р╢пр╖Фр╖А ","answer":"р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╖П"},{"question":"─Рoс║бn v─Гn sau ─Сang n├│i vс╗Б vс║еn ─Сс╗Б g├м?  Nguс╗Уn: https://arttimes.vn/video/to-hop-vu-khi-34ho-bay34-chuyen-diet-phi-co-tam-thap-cua-han-quoc-c13a...Nguс╗Уn: https://arttimes.vn/video/to-hop-vu-khi-34ho-bay34-chuyen-diet-phi-co-tam-thap-cua-han-quoc-c13a8434.html ","answer":"Tс╗Х hс╗гp v┼й kh├н \\"hс╗Х bay\\" chuy├кn diс╗Зt phi c╞б tс║зm thс║еp cс╗зa H├аn Quс╗Сc"},{"question":"ркЕрк╡рк┐ркирк╛рк╢ рк╡рлНркпрк╛рк╕ ркирлА \\"ркПркХ рккрк╛ркЯркг рк╢рк╣рлЗрк░ркирлА\\" ркХрк╡рк┐ркдрк╛ рк▓ркЦрлЛ.","answer":"ркПркХ рккрк╛ркЯркг рк╢рк╣рлЗрк░ркирлА ркирк╛рк░ рккркжркоркгрлА,ркЖркВркЦ ркиркЪрк╛рк╡ркдрлА ркбрк╛ркмрлА ркирлЗ ркЬркоркгрлА,рк╕рлВрк░ркд ркЬрк╛ркгрлЗ ркЪркВркжрк╛ рккрлВркиркоркирлА, ркмрлАркЪ ркмркЬрк╛рк░рлЗ ркЬрк╛ркп..ркнрк╛ркдрлАркЧрк│ ркЪрлВркВркжрк▓ркбрлА рк▓рк╣рлЗрк░рк╛ркп,ркЭрк╛ркВркЭрк░рлАркпрлБркВ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркерк╛ркп..ркПркХ рк╡рк╛ркЧркб ркжрлЗрк╢ркирлЛ ркмркВркХрлЛ ркЬрлБрк╡рк╛ркирлАркпрлЛ,рк░ркВркЧ ркЬрк╛ркгрлЗ ркПркирлЛ рк▓рк╛рк▓ рклрк╛ркЧркгрлАркпрлЛ,ркХркВркарлЗ ркЧрк░ркЬркдрлЛ ркЬрк╛ркгрлЗ рк╢рлНрк░рк╛рк╡ркгрк┐ркпрлЛ, рк╕рк╛рк╡ркЬркбрлЛ рк╡рк░рлНркдрк╛ркп,ркиркЬрк░рлНркпрлБркВркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлА ркПрк╡рлЛ ркиркЬрк░рк╛ркп,ркжрк▓ркбрлБркВ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркерк╛ркп..рк░ркВркЧркорк╛ркВ ркиркЦрк░рлЛ, рквркВркЧркорк╛ркВ ркиркЦрк░рлЛ,рк░рлВркк ркПрк╡рлБркВ ркЕркВркЧ ркЕркВркЧркорк╛ркВ ркиркЦрк░рлЛ;рккрк╛ркдрк│рлА ркХрлЗркбркирлЗ ркнрк╛рк░ ркЬрлЛркмркиркирлЛ ркЬрлАрк░рк╡рлНркпрлЛ ркирк╛ ркЬрлАрк░рк╡рк╛ркп,ркнрк╛ркдрлАркЧрк│ ркЪрлВркВркжрк▓ркбрлА рк▓рк╣рлЗрк░рк╛ркп,ркЭрк╛ркВркЭрк░рлАркпрлБркВ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркЭркоркХ ркерк╛ркп..ркмркВркХркбрлА ркорлВркЫрлЛ ркЕрк░рлЗ ркмркВркХркбрлА рккрк╛ркШркбрлА,рк░ркВркЧ ркХрк╕рлБркВркмрк▓ ркнрк░рлА ркЖркВркЦрк▓ркбрлА,рк╣рк╛рк▓ркХ ркбрлЛрк▓ркХ ркбрлБркВркЧрк░рлЗ ркЪркбрлЗ рккркб ркЫрлЛ ркирк╛ рккрк░ркЦрк╛ркп,ркиркЬрк░рлНркпрлБркВркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлА ркПрк╡рлЛ ркиркЬрк░рк╛ркп,ркжрк▓ркбрлБркВ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркзркмркХ ркерк╛ркп.."},{"question":" Inona no vanim-potoana manaraka ny fahavaratra araka ny filaharanтАЩny fizaran-taona?","answer":" Ny fararano no vanim-potoana manaraka ny fahavaratra araka ny filaharan'ny fizaran-taona."},{"question":"Gс╗Лnс╗Л bс╗е okpukpe с╗Нdс╗Лnala ndс╗Л Igbo?","answer":"Okpukpe с╗Нdс╗Лnala nke ndс╗Л Igbo bс╗е nke a na-akpс╗Н Odinani, nke gс╗еnyere ikwere chi dс╗Л iche iche na mmс╗ес╗Н ndс╗Л nna ochie."},{"question":"рдмрд╣реБрддреЗрдХ рдХреЛрд│рд╕рд╛ рд╕рд╛рдард╛ рднрд╛рд░рддрд╛рдд рдХреБрдареЗ рдЖрдврд│реВрди рдпреЗрддреЛ?(A) рдУрдбрд┐рд╢рд╛(B) рдЫрддреНрддреАрд╕рдЧрдб(C) рдЭрд╛рд░рдЦрдВрдб(D) рдкрдВ. рдмрдВрдЧрд╛рд▓=> ","answer":"(C) рдЭрд╛рд░рдЦрдВрдб"},{"question":" роЪроорпАрокродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗро╕рпНро░рпЛ рокро┐роОро╕рпНроОро▓рпНро╡ро┐-роЪро┐29 роорпВро▓роорпН роЖро▒рпБ роЪрпЖропро▒рпНроХрпИроХрпН роХрпЛро│рпНроХро│рпИ ро╡ро┐рогрпНрогро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖро▓рпБродрпНродро┐роп роиро╛роЯрпБ?","answer":"роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН родрпБро░рпБро╡ роЪрпЖропро▒рпНроХрпИроХрпНроХрпЛро│рпН роПро╡рпБродро▓рпН ро╡ро╛роХройроорпН, роЕродройрпН роорпБрокрпНрокродрпНродро┐ роЗро░рогрпНроЯро╛ро╡родрпБ ро╡ро┐рооро╛ройродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН (рокро┐роОро╕рпНроОро▓рпНро╡ро┐-роЪро┐29), рокрпВроородрпНродро┐роп ро░рпЗроХрпИроХрпНроХрпБ 15 роЯро┐роХро┐ро░ро┐ роЪро╛ропрпНроирпНрод 550 роХро┐роорпА ро╡роЯрпНроЯ роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБрокрпНрокро╛родрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐роЩрпНроХрокрпНрокрпВро░ро┐ройрпН роЖро▒рпБ роЪрпЖропро▒рпНроХрпИроХрпНроХрпЛро│рпНроХро│рпИ роПро╡ро┐ропродрпБ.  рокро┐роОро╕рпНроОро▓рпНро╡ро┐-роЪро┐29 ро╕рпНро░рпАро╣ро░ро┐роХрпЛроЯрпНроЯро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ роЪродрпАро╖рпН родро╡ро╛ройрпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роорпИропродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН (роОро╕рпНроЯро┐роОро╕рпНроЪро┐) роорпБродро▓рпН роПро╡рпБродро│родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роПро╡рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. роЗродрпБ 'роХрпЛро░рпН-роЕро▓рпЛройрпН' роХроЯрпНроЯроорпИрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН (родро┐роЯрооро╛рой ро╕рпНроЯрпНро░ро╛рокрпН-роЖройрпН роорпЛроЯрпНроЯро╛ро░рпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро╛рооро▓рпН) рокро┐роОро╕рпНроОро▓рпНро╡ро┐ропро┐ройрпН рокродро┐ройрпКройрпНро▒ро╛ро╡родрпБ ро╡ро┐рооро╛ройрооро╛роХрпБроорпН."},{"question":"┘Е╪к┘Й ╪г╪│╪│ ╪з╪▒┘Е╪з┘Ж┘К ╪╣┘Д╪з┘Е╪к┘З ╪з┘Д╪к╪м╪з╪▒┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪о╪з╪╡╪й тАЭ ╪м┘И╪▒╪м┘И ╪з╪▒┘Е╪з┘Ж┘К тАЭ╪Я","answer":"╪г╪│╪│ ╪м┘И╪▒╪м┘И ╪г╪▒┘Е╪з┘Ж┘К ╪╣┘Д╪з┘Е╪к┘З ╪з┘Д╪к╪м╪з╪▒┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪о╪з╪╡╪й ╪и┘З ┘Б┘К ╪╣╪з┘Е 1975."},{"question":"╪з┘Г┘Е┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Б┘В╪▒╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К╪й:┘И┘З╪░╪з ╪г┘Е╪▒ ╪╖╪и┘К╪╣┘К╪Ы ┘Б╪з┘Д╪│┘Е╪з╪б -╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪к╪н┘К╪╖ ╪и╪з┘Д╪г╪▒╪╢ ┘Ж┘З╪з╪▒┘Л╪з ╪и╪│╪╖┘И╪╣ ╪┤┘Е╪│┘З╪з ┘И┘Д┘К┘Д╪з ╪и┘Д┘Е╪╣╪з┘Ж ┘Ж╪м┘И┘Е┘З╪з- ╪к╪м╪╣┘Д ╪з┘Д╪е┘Ж╪│╪з┘Ж ┘К╪к╪│╪з╪б┘Д ╪╣┘Ж","answer":"┘Е╪з┘З┘К╪к┘З╪з ┘И╪г╪│╪▒╪з╪▒┘З╪з╪М ┘Б┘Г┘К┘Б ╪г┘П╪║╪╖┘Р╪┤ ┘Д┘К┘Д┘П┘З╪з ┘И╪г┘П╪о╪▒┘Р╪м ╪╢┘П╪н╪з┘З╪з╪М ┘И┘Г┘К┘Б ┘К╪и╪▓╪║ ┘В┘Е╪▒┘З╪з ┘И┘К╪к╪н╪▒┘Г ┘Б┘К┘Ж╪к┘В┘Д ┘Е┘Ж ╪╖┘И╪▒ ╪е┘Д┘Й ╪в╪о╪▒ ┘Е┘Ж╪░ ┘Д╪н╪╕╪й ┘Е┘К┘Д╪з╪п┘З╪М ┘Е╪▒┘И╪▒╪з ╪и┘Г┘И┘Ж┘З ╪и╪п╪▒┘Л╪з ┘К┘Е┘Д╪г ╪з┘Д╪│┘Е╪з╪б ┘Ж┘И╪▒┘Л╪з ┘Б┘К ╪╕┘П┘Д┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д┘Д┘К╪з┘Д┘К╪М ┘И╪з┘Ж╪к┘З╪з╪б┘Л ╪и╪о┘Б┘И╪к ┘Ж┘И╪▒┘З ┘Б┘К╪к╪и╪п┘С╪п ╪з╪╢┘Е╪н┘Д╪з┘Д╪з ╪л┘Е ┘К╪к╪м╪п┘С╪п ╪з╪│╪к┘З┘Д╪з┘Д╪з.. ┘И┘З┘Г╪░╪з ╪п┘И╪з┘Д┘К┘Т┘Г┘О!!"},{"question":"р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Гр╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢вр╢▒р╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Ар╖К р╢╢р╖Г р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╖Ар╖Щр╢║р╖Т. р╢Ер╢п р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢лр╢Ю 20 р╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╖Гр╖Д р╢╕р╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╢д 3р╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╢▒ р╢вр╢▒р╢Ьр╖Др╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╢Ър╢╗р╢нр╖Т. р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜тАН р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢║р╖Фр╢╗р╖Эр╢┤р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢╜ р╢Лр╢┤ р╢Ьр╢лр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢Жр╢╗р╖Кр╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢Ьр╢лр╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢║р╖Тр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜ р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╢║р╖Тр╢▒ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╢р╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Ер╢Яр╢╕ р╖Гр╖Др╖Эр╢пр╢╗р╖Тр╢║ р╖Ар╖Щр╢║р╖Т. р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Тр╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢║р╖Т .р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Пр╢Ьр╖К р╢Ур╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢║р╖Фр╢Ьр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╢зр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢нр╖Т р╖Др╖Щр╖Ер╢╢р╖Г р╢Ир╢н р╢Ер╢нр╖Ур╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Др╖П р╢║р╢зр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢вр╖Тр╢н р╖Гр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╢╢р╢зр╖Др╖Тр╢╗ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Гр╢╕р╢Ь р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╖Тр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢лр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢╢р╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╖Ар╖У р╢Зр╢н. р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╗ 18 р╢Ър╖Т. р╢Йр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Гр╢╕р╢Ь р╖Гр╖Гр╢│р╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢Ер╢Ър╖КтАНр╖Вр╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Ър╖В р╢╜р╢Ър╖КтАНр╖Вр╢л р╢Ър╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢┤р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ. р╢Тр╖Ар╖П р╢▒р╢╕р╖К 'р╢З', 'р╢И' р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╗ р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Ур╢╕, р╖Бр╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢╕р╖Др╖Пр╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Пр╢л р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Ер╖Ар╖Бр╖КтАНр╢║ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕ р╢Жр╢пр╖У р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ. р╢пр╢Ър╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Ар╢╜ р╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒, р╢л, р╢╜, р╖Е р╢║р╢▒ р╢Ер╢Ър╖КтАНр╖Вр╢╗ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢║ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╢р╖Гр╖Щр╖Др╖Тр╢п р╢Зр╢н. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢Ер╢Ър╖КтАНр╖Вр╢╗ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢║ р╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒ р╖Ар╢╜ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Фр╢н р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Гр╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ."},{"question":"ulimi wa mpunga mu dziko la Malawi","answer":"Dziko la Malawi lili ndi malo okwana mahekitala 600,000 omwe angagwiritsidwe ntchito polima mpunga. Derali likadagwiritsidwa ntchito mokwanira, dziko likhoza kutulutsa matani oposa 2,000,000 a mpunga pachaka. Pakali pano, kuchuluka kwa mpunga ndi matani 150,000 pachaka, zomwe zikutanthauza kuti 7.5 peresenti yokha ya zomwe zingathe kupanga."},{"question":"р╖Гр╢│ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╖ р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф р╢┤р╖Др╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╖Гр╢│ р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╖ р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф р╢┤р╖Др╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢пр╖Т р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢║.- р╖Гр╢│ р╢нр╢╗р╖Ф р╢▒р╖Тр╖Др╢мр╢║р╖Т - р╢┤р╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢Ер╢╕р╢╗р╢пр╖Ър╖А- р╖Гр╢│ р╢╗р╖Ър╢лр╖Ф р╢Ьр╢╜р╢▒ - р╢нр╖Ур╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢л р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╢╗р╖Пр╢░- р╖Гр╢│ р╢╜р╢нр╖П р╢┤р╖Пр╢║р╢▒р╖П - р╢Ър╖Ур╢╗р╖Кр╢нр╖Т р╢┤р╖Рр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖К- р╖Гр╢│ р╢╜р╖Ър╢Ыр╖П - р╢╗р╖Цр╢Ър╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢н р╢Ьр╖Фр╢лр╢нр╖Тр╢╜р╢Ъ р╖Др╖П р╢ар╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╜р╖Ър╢Ыр╖П р╢┤р╖Щр╢╗р╖Ър╢╗р╖П- р╖Гр╢│р╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ - р╢╗р╖Тр╢пр╖Кр╢╕ р╖Ар╖Ур╢╗р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢░р╢▒ "},{"question":"Markasta waxeynu iska jecelnahay?","answer":"Markasta waxaynu iska jecelnahay innaynu helno wax kasta oo aynnu u niyoono, weliba si deg deg ah. Laakiin taa baddelkeeda waxa jira qorshayaal uu il Ilaahay innoo sameeyey, kuwaas oo kasii wanaagsan kana sii qiimo badan adiga kuwaaga yar yar ee ku qancin kara. Sidaa aawadeed haddii qorshe aad niyad iyo dadaal badan gelisay kuu suurto geli waayo, naftaada haku cannaanan innay tahay mida ugu nasiibka xun adduunka, ee waxaad ogaataa innuu soo socdo qorshihii Eebbe oo ka qiimo badan midkaas aad weyday insha allah. Noloshu mar kasta oo ay innagu adkaato waxaynu ku mashquulnaa dhibaatada iyo culayskeeda, laakiin taa baddelkeeda haddii aynnu ku mashquuli lahayn xal u helida dhibaatada ina haysata, waxa iman lahayd innaanay dhibaatadaasi innagaga badateen muddada aynnu xalka helayno uun. Sidaa aawadeed illaahay la kaasho dhibaatadaada oo isaga bari, adiguna baadi-goob u gal innaad xal u hesho dhibaatada ku haysata. Ogow xalka ugu wanaagsani waa ka Rabbi kula rabo, ee maaha midkaad adigu rabto."},{"question":"Manana teny mikorontana ianao: \\"kasitra\\" Alamino io teny io. ","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"sitraka\\". "},{"question":"inona avy no karazana fifamangiana?","answer":"ireto avy no karazana fifamangiana: ny fifamangiana amin'ny fifaliana, ny fifamangiana amin'ny fahoriana, ny fifamangiana amin'ny fiainana andavanandro"},{"question":"Inoa avy ireo sakafo tsara hoanin'ny mpiasa birao ?","answer":"Ny vitamine A no anisanтАЩny sakafo atao loha laharana ho anтАЩireo mpiasa birao mampiasa solosaina. Izany dia mba hiarovana ny fahasalamanтАЩny maso. Efa voaporofo ara-tsiansa tokoa fa ny fihinanana sakafo be vitamine A dia mampatanjaka ny maso ka mahatonga azy tsy ho mora simbanтАЩny solosaina. AnisanтАЩireo sakafo ahitana vitamina A ny karaoty, voankazo sy legioma miloko mavo, ny atin-kena, ny voatabiaтАж Mba hisorohana ny aretin-damosina kosa dia ilaina ny mihinana sakafo manankarena antioxydant sy ny manankarena omega 3, toy ny tongolo gasy, ny legioma, ny tamenakтАЩatody, ny trondro matavyтАж"},{"question":"чВ║ф╗Ащ║╝хЬичЭбшж║цЩВцЬГхБЪхдв","answer":"уААуААуААуААхдЬц╖▒ф║Жя╝Мф║║хАСщГ╜щА▓хЕечФЬшЬЬчЪДхдвщДЙя╝МцЬЙчЪДхЬихдвф╕нщЬ▓хЗ║х╛очмСя╝МцЬЙчЪДхЬихдвф╕нхТ┐хТ┐хСАхСАф╜ОшкЮуАВф║║чВ║ф╗Ащ║╝хЬичЭбшж║цЩВцЬГхБЪхдвхСвя╝ЯщАЩшжБхХПцИСхАСцпПхАЛф║║чЪДхдзшЕжф║ЖуАВцИСхАСцпПхАЛф║║чЪДхдзшЕжщЗМцЬЙшСЧши▒ши▒хдЪхдЪчЪДшЕжч┤░шГЮя╝МщАЩф║ЫшЕжч┤░шГЮцЬЙчЪДчобцИСхАСшккшй▒я╝МцЬЙчЪДчобцИСхАСчЭбшж║я╝МцЬЙчЪДчобцИСхАСш╡░ш╖пчнЙчнЙя╝МцИСхАСф╕НчобхБЪф╗Ащ║╝ф║ЛщГ╜шжБч╢УщБОхдзшЕжуАВцЩЪф╕КчЭбшж║цЩВя╝МцЬЙчЪДшЕжч┤░шГЮхТМцИСхАСф║║ф╕Ацигф╣Яф╝СцБпф║Жя╝МхПпцШпя╝МцЬЙчЪДшЕжч┤░шГЮхН╗ц▓ТцЬЙф╝СцБпя╝МцЙАф╗ея╝МцИСхАСхЬичЩ╜хдйцГ│чЪДф║ЛцИЦчЬЛхИ░чЪДф║Лх░▒цЬГхЬичЭбшж║цЩВщЗНчП╛хЬишЕжф╕ня╝МщАЩх░▒цШпхдвуАВуААуААф┐Чшй▒шкктАЬхдвцШпх┐Гф╕нцГ│тАЭя╝Мх░▒цШпщАЩф╣ИхЫЮф║ЛуАВхБЪхдвцШпхЫачВ║цЬЙчЪДшЕжч┤░шГЮц▓ТцЬЙф╝СцБпчЪДч╖гцХЕуАВ"},{"question":"с╗Мkan ninu awс╗Нn tina jo lтАЩAbс║╣okuta lс╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun ti ku o","answer":"с╗Мsibitu тАШFederal Medical CenterтАЩ(FMC), lтАЩAbс║╣okuta, ti fidi с║╣ mulс║╣ pe с╗Нkan ninu awс╗Нn tina jo nibi ijamba to с╣гс║╣lс║╣ ni Kutс╗Н lтАЩAbс║╣okuta, lс╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun, Tusidee, с╗Нsс║╣ yii ti dagbere faye.Agbс║╣nusс╗Н с╗Нsibitu yii, с╗Мgbс║╣ni с╣вс║╣gun Orisajo, lo sс╗Н eyi di mimс╗Н ninu atс║╣jade to fi sita laaarс╗Н с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, с╗Нjс╗Н kс╗Нkanlelogun, oс╣гu kin-in-ni, с╗Нdun 2021 yii.O с╣гalaye pe с╗Нkunrin ni с║╣ni с╗Нdun mejilelogoji to doloogbe naa. Orisajo с╣гalaye pe ina jo с╗Нkunrin naa pupс╗Н, ida mс║╣rindinlс╗Нgс╗Нrun-un (96%) lo pe apa ibi ti ina ti jo o.O tс║╣siwaju pe nigba ti wс╗Нn gbe e de pс║╣lu awс╗Нn meji mi-in ti ina yii jo, awс╗Нn n fa omi ti oogun wa ninu rс║╣ si wс╗Нn lara gс║╣gс║╣ bi с╗Нna itс╗Нju kan ni. Nigba ti с╗Нkunrin naa ni iс╣гoro ati tс╗Н, awс╗Нn bс║╣rс║╣ eto lati с╣гe itс╗Нju ti wс╗Нn n pe ni тАШDialisisтАЩ fun un, с╣гugbс╗Нn aarс╗Н с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н yii lo ku ki wс╗Нn too с╣гeto itс╗Нju naa fun un rara.Tс║╣ o ba gbagbe, с╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun, с╗Нjс╗Н kс╗Нkandinlogun, oс╣гu kin-in-ni yii, ni ina sс╗Н lagbegbe banki GTB, ni Kutс╗Н, lтАЩAbс║╣okuta, lasiko ti tanka epo kan padanu ijanu с║╣ nigba to fс║╣с║╣ sс╗Нkalс║╣ lori afara Kutс╗Н.Eeyan mс║╣ta lo ku loju-с║╣sс║╣ nibс║╣, mс╗Нto ati с╗Нkada jona, awс╗Нn mi-in si fara pa, wс╗Нn gbe wс╗Нn lс╗Н si FMC, с╗Нkan ninu awс╗Нn to fara pa lo dagbere faye yii."},{"question":"E okuldan nakil verilir mi?","answer":"Kesin kay─▒t i┼Яleminden ├╢nce aday kayd─▒ iptal edilebilir. Aday ├╢─Яrenciler daha sonra kesin kay─▒t yap─▒lmal─▒d─▒r. Kesin kay─▒t i┼Яleminden sonra ├╢─Яrenci kayd─▒ silinemez, ba┼Яka okula nakil verilebilir."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan yang bertajuk Faedah-Faedah Program Motivasi kepada Diri Pelajar.","answer":"Mutakhir ini, sama ada kita sedar atau tidak lantaran terlalu dihidangkan dengan kerancakan pembangunan negara yang semakin gah di persada dunia. Namun disebalik itu, kita acapkali tersentak oleh pelbagai permasalahan sosial yang dicetuskan oleh rakyat kita sendiri. Kes-kes seperti pergaulan bebas, lumba haram dan sebagainya telah memberikan imej buruk kepada masyarakat kita kerana pelakunya terdiri daripada generasi muda yang merupakan pelajar-pelajar di sekolah. Pelbagai punca dan faktor permasalahan ini berlaku namun pihak sekolah lazimnya menganjurkan program motivasi kepada pelajar di sekolah bagi memupuk sikap madani dalam diri mereka. Penganjuran program ini memakan perbelanjaan wang yang banyak dan mengambil masa dan tenaga daripada para guru bagi memastikan anak-anak murid mereka mendapat manfaat daripada penyertaan mereka. Persoalan yang timbul adalah apakah faedah-faedah program motivasi kepada diri pelajar?Faedah yang paling mustahak dalam penganjuran program atau kem motivasi adalah ia membuka mata dan minda pelajar tentang kepentingan motivasi diri. Mungkin ibu dan bapa atau ahli keluarga di rumah terlepas pandang akan perkara ini tetapi pihak sekolah yang merupakan institusi pendidikan perdana seharusnya mendidik tentang pentingnya motivasi diri. Hal ini demikian kerana ia bukan sahaja penting semasa pelajar di sekolah tetapi ia adalah santapan rohani untuk sepanjang kehidupan kita. Kebanyakan di antara pelajar yang tidak mempunyai pencapaian yang baik dalam bidang akademik mahupun kokurikulum didapati kurang mendapat motivasi diri. Sekiranya mereka didedahkan dan sedar betapa mustahak untuk mempunyai motivasi diri yang utuh dalam menempuhi apa jua perkara pasti masyarakat yang inteligensia dan cakna dapat dilahirkan. Pelajar masa kini seharusnya sudah mengetahui minat dan masa hadapan yang diinginkan agar ibu bapa dapat membantu dalam merancang perjalanan yang menepati kehendak dan kemampuan pelajar. Intihannya, jika pelajar mempunyai kemahuan dan disertakan dengan motivasi, anda pasti dapat mencapai cita-cita tersebut walau apa jua rintangan yang datang. Persis peribahasa Melayu, belakang parang pun kalau diasah nescaya tajam.Faedah lain yang akan diperoleh pelajar apabila menyertai program motivasi adalah membentuk disiplin diri. Pelajar akan didedahkan tips-tips atau cara untuk belajar dengan lebih mudah oleh perunding atau pakar motivasi yang terlatih. Perkongsian ini adalah kritikal kerana pelajar tidak tahu-menahu cara pembelajaran yang efektif kerana latar belakang dan kemampuan mereka adalah berbeza. Maka, fasilitator yang bertanggungjawab dalam program motivasi pelajar seharusnya memberikan solusi atau pendekatan kepada pelajar untuk menelaah atau mengulang kaji pelajaran dengan lebih baik. Ibarat jauhari mengenal manikam. Sebagai contoh, teknik penulisan nota ringkas, penggunaan kad-kad untuk menguatkan hafalan dan cara mengenal pasti corak soalan yang bakal dikeluarkan dalam peperiksaan peringkat sekolah mahupun awam. Kesannya, pelajar akan bertambah rajin dan tercelik hati bahawa setiap di antara mereka mampu mencapai kejayaan dari segi akademik ataupun aktiviti di luar bilik darjah. Berbekalkan motivasi yang kuat, pelajar akan menjadi seorang yang tidak mengenal erti putus asa bak kata pepatah Melayu, alah bisa tegal biasa.Pada masa yang sama, semangat kepimpinan dapat dipupuk dalam kalangan pelajar jika mereka menyertai program motivasi diri. Nilai kepimpinan diri seharusnya dimiliki oleh setiap individu menjelang kedewasaan kerana semakin kita membesar, semakin banyak tanggungjawab dan amanah yang akan dipikul dan perlu dilunaskan dengan baik. Dengan adanya kepimpinan diri yang tinggi pelajar akan mengutamakan perkara yang mustahak berbanding perkara remeh dan yang tidak mendatangkan manfaat kepada diri mereka. Selain itu, penyertaan dalam kem-kem motivasi akan mendedahkan diri pelajar untuk menjadi seorang ketua. Hal ini kerana peserta akan dibahagikan kepada kumpulan-kumpulan kecil secara rawak dan peluang untuk mengetuai kumpulan masing-masing wajar diambil supaya pelajar tahu bagaimana untuk menjadi seorang pemimpin. Secara tidak langsung, pelajar akan menjadi seorang yang lebih baik berbanding ahli kumpulan masing-masing supaya menjadi contoh tauladan kepadda semua. Izharnya, penyertaan pelajar dalam kem motivasi dapat mencungkil potensi serta bakat pelajar dalam kepimpinan kerana manfaatnya kelak adalah berbaloi. Ibarat peribahasa Melayu, kalau tidak dipecahkan ruyung, manakan dapat sagunya.Di samping itu, pelajar juga dapat memperbaiki kemahiran komunikasi apabila menyertai program motivasi anjuran sekolah mahupun swasta. Tahukah anda bahawa kemahiran komunikasi adalah sangat penting khususnya apabila pelajar akan memasuki alam pekerjaan. Umum sedia maklum, manusia mempunyai pelbagai ragam dan sekiranya kita ingin menjadi seorang yang professional kita harus menguasai kemahiran komunikasi yang baik. Selalunya program motivasi akan menjalankan aktiviti-aktiviti yang memerlukan penglibatan aktif daripada semua peserta. Maka, pelajar perlu meningkatkan keyakinan diri untuk menyumbang tenaga dan idea bagi menjayakan kumpulan dalam aktiviti yang dijalankan. Setelah meningkatkan tahap keyakinan, pelajar juga akan didedahkan untuk menyampaikan persembahan atau bercakap dihadapan khalayak ramai. Dengan bimbingan dan dorongan daripada fasilitator para pelajar pasti dapat memecahakn tembok yang sebelum ini menjadi penghalang kepada mereka dan tampil dengan sifat dan sikap yang lebih positif. Natijahnya, penyertaan rogram motivasi yang menjalankan pelbagai aktiviti dapat memperbaiki kemahiran komunikasi dalam kalangan pelajar kerana yang elok itu budi, yang indah itu bahasa.Sebagai konklusi, penganjuran program atau kem motivasi adalah medan terbaik untuk pelajar membentuk ketrampilan diri yang lebih unggul dan cemerlang. Pelajar seharusnya bersikap terbuka dan gemar untuk menyertai inisiatif-inisiatif yang direncana oleh pihak sekolah dalam membantu pelajar menjadi seorang manusia yang lebih baik. Guru-guru, ibu dan bapa serta perunding motivasi pula seharusnya sentiasa menggunakan pendekatan yang lebih menarik dan sesuai dengan persekitaran pelajar dalam menganjurkan program motivasi supaya dapat menarik minat mereka. Persis kata peribahasa, melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Sesungguhnya jika usaha ini diperkasa dan dilaksana dengan efisien, generasi muda kita akan bebas dari dibelenggu masalah sosial serta melonjak kemampuan masyarakat tempatan untuk menjadi komuniti madani. Semoga iltizam dalam membawa diri, masyarakat dan juga negara kita untuk berdiri sama tinggi dan duduk sama rendah dengan negara lain dapat dihasilkan dan memebri manfaat kepada kesejahteraan hidup rakyat sejagat."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'bawa nasib'?","answer":"Ia bermaksud menjauhkan diri daripada kaum keluarga dan sahabat untuk mencari kehidupan sendiri."},{"question":"l, m ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨╜╨░╤В╤Г╤А╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╨║ ╤Б╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А:l ╨╢╤Г╨┐ m ╤В╨░╨║ ╤Б╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А╤Л ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ l*m=36 ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛, l+m ╨║╨░╨╜╤З╨░ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╤И╤Г ╨╝╥п╨╝╨║╥п╨╜ ?","answer":"l+m = 13"},{"question":" ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪г┘К ╪и╪н╪▒ ┘Г╪з┘К┘Ж╪й ┘Е╪п┘К┘Ж╪й ╪и┘К╪▒┘И╪к ╪Я","answer":"  ╪з┘Д╪и╪н╪▒╪з┘Д╪г╪и┘К╪╢ ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к┘И╪│╪╖"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢пр╖Пр╖Е р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╢┤р╢п р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?р╢Жр╢Ър╢╗р╖Кр╖Вр╢лр╢║ ","answer":"р╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╖Кр╖Вр╢лр╢║"},{"question":"╨С╤Г╨╗ ╨╢╨╛╨╝╨╛╨║╤В╤Г╨╜ ╤Г╨╗╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╤Б╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤З╨╕: ╨Р╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨║╨░╨╣╤Л╤А╤З╤Л ╨║╨░╨╜: тАФ \\"╨Ь╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╨│╥п╨╜ ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╨╢╨╡╤З╥п ╤Н╨╗╨╡╨╝. ╨С╨╕╤А ╨║╨╛╨╣ ╤Б╨╛╨╣╤Б╨╛╥г, ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╨│╥п╨╜╙й ╨╝╨╡╨╜ ╤В╨╛╨╣╨▒╨╛╨╣╨╝, ╤Н╤В╨╕╨╜ ╨╢╨╡╨▒╨╡╨╣╨╝\\",- ╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В.","answer":"╨С╤Г╨╗ ╨╢╨╛╨╝╨╛╨║╤В╤Г╨╜ ╤Г╨╗╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╤Б╤Л ╨╝╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╤И╤Г ╨╝╥п╨╝╨║╥п╨╜: ╨Р╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨╢╨╕╨│╨╕╤В, ╤Н╤И╨╕╨║╨║╨╡ ╨╢╥п╨│╥п╤А╥п╨┐ ╤З╤Л╨│╤Л╨┐, ╤Н╨╜╨╡╤Б╨╕╨╜╨╡: тАФ \\"╨н╨╜╨╡, ╨║╨░╨╣╤Л╤А╤З╤Л ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╨║ ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╨╢╨╡╨╣╨╝ ╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В. ╨С╨╕╤А ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╨│╥п╨╜╙й ╤В╨╛╨╣╨▒╨╛╨╣╨╝ ╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В. ╨Ъ╨░╨╣╤Л╤А╤З╤Л╨│╨░ ╨▒╨╡╤И ╨║╨╛╤О╨▒╤Г╨╖╨┤╤Г ╤В╨╡╥г ╤Б╨╛╤О╨┐, ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╨│╥п╨╜ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡╨╗╨╕, ╨║╨░╨╣╤Л╤А╤З╤Л ╨▒╨╡╤З╨░╤А╨░ ╤В╨╛╨╣╤Б╤Г╨╜, ╤Н╤В╨╕╨╜ ╙й╨╖╥п╨▒╥п╨╖ ╨╢╨╡╨┐, ╨╢╨╡ ╤Б╨░╤В╨░╤А╨▒╤Л╨╖\\",-  ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨┤╨╡ ╤Н╨╜╨╡╤Б╨╕ ╨╝╨░╨║╤Г╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В."},{"question":"ркирлАркЪрлЗркирк╛ ркЧрлБркЬрк░рк╛ркдрлА ркЙркЦрк╛ркгрк╛ркВ ркирлЛ ркЬрк╡рк╛ркм ркЖрккрлЛ:ркерк╛ркХрк╡рк╛ркирлБркВ рки ркорк╛рк░рлЗ ркирк╛рко, рк░рк╛ркд ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ рк╣рлБркВ ркЪрк╛рк▓ркдрлА рк░рк╣рлЗркдрлА ркЬрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ рккрлВркЫрлЛ ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ рк╕ркоркп ркмркдрк╛рк╡ркдрлА, ркЖркЧрк│ рк╡ркзрк╡рк╛ркирлЛ рк╕ркВркжрлЗрк╢рлЛ рк╣рлБркВ ркЬрк╛ркдрлА.","answer":"ркШркбрк┐ркпрк╛рк│"},{"question":"рднрд╛рд░рддреАрдп рдореБрджреНрд░реЗрдЪреЗ рдирд╛рд╡ тАЬрд░реВрдкрдпрд╛тАЭ рд╕рд░реНрд╡рд╛рдд рдкрд╣рд┐рд▓реЗ рдХреЛрдгрддреНрдпрд╛ рд╢рд╛рд╕рдХрд╛рдиреЗ рдареЗрд╡рд▓реЗ ?","answer":"рднрд╛рд░рддреАрдп рдореБрджреНрд░реЗрдЪреЗ рдирд╛рд╡ тАЬрд░реВрдкрдпрд╛тАЭ рд╕рд░реНрд╡рд╛рдд рдкрд╣рд┐рд▓реЗ рд╢реЗрд░рд╢рд╣рд╛ рд╕реБрд░реА рд╢рд╛рд╕рдХрд╛рдиреЗ рдареЗрд╡рд▓реЗ."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ┘Е┘В┘К╪з╪│ ╪з┘Д╪е╪┤╪╣╪з╪╣. ╪и╪н╪л╪к ╪╣┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ┘И┘И╪м╪п╪к ┘З╪░╪з ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡:┘З┘И ╪м┘З╪з╪▓ ┘К╪│╪к╪о╪п┘Е ┘Д┘В┘К╪з╪│ ╪┤╪п╪й ╪з┘Д╪е╪┤╪╣╪з╪╣ ╪з┘Д┘Г┘З╪▒┘И┘Е╪║┘Ж╪з╪╖┘К╪│┘К ┘Е╪л┘Д ╪з┘Д╪╢┘И╪б. ┘З┘Ж╪з┘Г ┘Е┘Г╪з╪┤┘К┘Б ┘Е╪о╪к┘Д┘Б╪й ╪н╪│╪и ╪з┘Д┘Е╪м╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Г┘З╪▒┘И┘Е╪║┘Ж╪з╪╖┘К╪│┘К ┘Е╪л┘Д ┘Е╪м╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д╪г╪┤╪╣╪й ╪к╪н╪к ╪з┘Д╪н┘Е╪▒╪з╪б ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪к┘В┘К╪│ ╪┤╪п╪й ╪з┘Д╪е╪┤╪╣╪з╪╣ ┘Б┘К ╪░┘Д┘Г ╪з┘Д┘Е╪м╪з┘Д╪Ы ┘Г┘Е╪з ╪к┘И╪м╪п ╪г┘К╪╢╪з┘Л ┘Е┘Г╪з╪┤┘К┘Б ╪к┘В┘К╪│ ╪┤╪п╪й ╪з┘Д╪е╪┤╪╣╪з╪╣ ┘Б┘К ┘Е╪м╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д╪г╪┤╪╣╪й ┘Б┘И┘В ╪з┘Д╪и┘Ж┘Б╪│╪м┘К╪й ┘И┘Б┘К ┘Е╪м╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Е┘И╪м╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Е┘К┘Г╪▒┘И┘К╪й. ┘З┘Д ╪к╪│╪к╪╖┘К╪╣ ╪з╪│╪к╪о╪▒╪з╪м ╪м┘И╪з╪и ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡╪Я ╪з╪░┘Г╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й","answer":"╪м┘З╪з╪▓ ┘К╪│╪к╪о╪п┘Е ┘Д┘В┘К╪з╪│ ╪┤╪п╪й ╪з┘Д╪е╪┤╪╣╪з╪╣ ╪з┘Д┘Г┘З╪▒┘И┘Е╪║┘Ж╪з╪╖┘К╪│┘К ┘Е╪л┘Д ╪з┘Д╪╢┘И╪б."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo dingana tena ilaina amin'ny fametrahana ny demokrasia marin-toerana?","answer":"AnisanтАЩny dingana tena ilaina aminтАЩny fametrahana ny demokrasia marin-toerana : ny fametrahana ny lal├аm-panorenana mifanaraka amin'ny firenena iray, ny fifidianana mangarahara , ny fitsarana amin'ny rariny ary ny fiarovana ny zo fototra."},{"question":"Apakah gasing? ","answer":"Gasing merupakan sejenis permainan yang boleh berputar pada paksinya, sambil mengimbang pada satu titik. Gasing merupakan permainan tradisional orang-orang Melayu sejak dahulu lagi. Biasanya dimainkan selepas musim menuai. Permainan gasing dipertandingkan antara kampung. Pemenang dikira berdasarkan tempoh masa gasing mampu berputar.Istilah \\"gasing\\" gunaan masyarakat Semenanjung Melayu, Sumatera dan Kepulauan Riau turunan kata akar Proto-Austronesia *gasi┼Л. "},{"question":"Manana teny mikotorana ianao manao hoe : ATROVAOmeo ary teny marina .","answer":"Ny teny marina dia \\"avotra \\" ."},{"question":"Daga cikin wa╔Чannan bukukuwa a wanne ne ake ╔Чauri?A) kalankuwaB) bu╔Чar dawaC) Sallar ganiD) Sallar idi","answer":"A) kalankuwa"},{"question":"Hiс╗Зn tс║бi em ─Сang bс╗Л cс║нn loс║бn kh├б nс║╖ng, cс╗е thс╗Г l├а mс║пt tr├бi cс║нn 11 diop v├а loс║бn 1.25 diop, mс║пt phс║гi cс║нn 8 v├а loс║бn 1, ─Сс╗Щ d├аy gi├бc mс║бc 500 Mm. Tr╞░с╗Ыc ─С├вy em c├│ ─Сi kh├бm v├а ─С╞░с╗гc b├бc s─й t╞░ vс║еn l├а kh├┤ng thс╗Г mс╗Х ─С╞░с╗гc bс║▒ng ph╞░╞бng ph├бp lasik do cс║нn loс║бn nс║╖ng. Vс║нy cho em hс╗Пi liс╗Зu mс║пt em cс║нn nс║╖ng nh╞░ vс║нy c├│ thс╗Г mс╗Х bс║▒ng ph╞░╞бng ph├бp smile ─С╞░с╗гc kh├┤ng?","answer":"Vс╗Ыi mс║пt b├кn tr├бi, bс║бn c├│ thс╗Г phс║лu thuс║нt ─С╞░с╗гc bс║▒ng ph╞░╞бng ph├бp Smile. C├▓n vс╗Ыi mс║пt phс║гi, ph╞░╞бng ph├бp Smile c┼йng c├│ thс╗Г thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn ─С╞░с╗гc nh╞░ng sau phс║лu thuс║нt, sс║╜ tс╗Уn d╞░ h╞бn 1 ─Сс╗Щ cс║нn. V├м thс║┐ Femto-Lasik sс║╜ l├а lс╗▒a chс╗Нn tс╗Сi ╞░u cho mс║пt phс║гi cс╗зa bс║бn. Tuy nhi├кn bс║бn n├кn ─Сс║┐n bс╗Зnh viс╗Зn ─Сс╗Г ─С╞░с╗гc b├бc s─й phс║лu thuс║нt kiс╗Гm tra lс║бi ch├нnh x├бc t├мnh trс║бng mс║пt, ─Сс╗Г c├│ t╞░ vс║еn ph├╣ hс╗гp nhс║еt."},{"question":"Tsumo inotevera inorevei?Bofu kuti huya tirwe hunge rakatsika pfuti.","answer":"Ukawona munhu achitanga  kudenha nezvakawoma anenge aine zvaakatemba."},{"question":"р╢╕р╖Ър╖Ар╢╗ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢Лр╢пр╖Пр╖Др╢╗р╢лр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒. ","answer":"р╢╕р╖Ър╖Ар╢╗ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢Лр╢пр╖Пр╖Др╢╗р╢лр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢пр╖У р╢Зр╢н.\\"р╢╕р╖Фр╢В р╖Ар╢нр╖Ф р╢Ър╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Фр╢В р╢▒р╖Щр╢╜р╢▒р╖П р╢пр╖П  р╖Ар╢╜ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Э р╢╕р╢Ьр╖Щ р╢╕р╖Ър╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ср╢▒р╖Э р╢▒р╖Фр╢╣ р╢┤р╢╜р╖К р╢▒р╖Фр╢╣р╖Щ р╢пр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╢╜р╖К  р╢╕р╖П р╢пр╖Фр╢зр╖Фр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Рр╢н р╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Ар╢╗р╢║р╖П\\""},{"question":"Maputo moy p├йeyu ban r├йw?","answer":"Maputo moy p├йeyu r├йwum Mozambique"},{"question":"риХри┐ри░рикри╛ риХри░риХрйЗ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐ри╕риери╛ри░ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ ри╣рйЗриари╛риВ рижри┐рй▒ридрйЗ рижри╛ риХрйА риЕри░рие ри╣рйИред\\"риЖри╕ри╛ риори╣ри▓ри╛ рйл реериЖрикрйБриирйА ринриЧридри┐ риири┐римри╛ри╣ри┐ реериари╛риХрйБри░ риЖриЗриУ риЖри╣ри┐ реерйзрее ри░ри╣ри╛риЙ реериири╛риорйБ рикрижри╛ри░риерйБ ри╣рйЛриЗ ри╕риХри╛ри░риерйБ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйИ риЪри░рии римри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐ реерйзреериПри╣ риорйБриХридри╛ риПри╣ риЬрйБриЧридри╛ ри░ри╛риЦри╣рйБ ри╕рй░рид ри╕рй░риЧри╛ри╣ри┐ реерйиреериири╛риорйБ ризри┐риЖри╡риЙ ри╕ри╣риЬри┐ ри╕риори╛ри╡риЙ риири╛риириХ ри╣ри░ри┐ риЧрйБрии риЧри╛ри╣ри┐ реерййреерймреерйзрйкрймрее\\"","answer":"риЗри╣ ри╕рйНри░рйА риЧрйБри░рйВ риЧрйНри░рй░рие ри╕ри╛ри╣ри┐рим риЬрйА рижрйЗ рикрй░риири╛ 407 ридрйЛриВ ри▓ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риЧрйБри░рйВ риЕри░риЬрии рижрйЗри╡ риЬрйА риЗри╣риири╛риВ римри╛ригрйАриЖриВ рижрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЦри╛ри░рйА ри╣рииредриЗри╕ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйЗриа ри▓ри┐риЦрйЗ риЕриирйБри╕ри╛ри░ ри╡ри┐риЦри┐риЖрии риХрйАридри╛ риЬри╛ ри╕риХрижри╛ ри╣рйИ,\\"ри╣рйЗ риорйЗри░рйЗ риори╛ри▓риХ! риорйИриВ ридри╛риВриШ риХри░ риХрйЗ (ридрйЗри░рйА ри╕ри░рии) риЖриЗриЖ ри╣ри╛риВ, риорйИриирйВрй░ риЖрикригрйА ринриЧридрйА ри╕рижри╛ рижрйЗриИ ри░рй▒риЦ редрйзредри░ри╣ри╛риЙредри╣рйЗ риорйЗри░рйЗ риори╛ри▓риХ! риЖрикригрйЗ риЪри░рии риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╣ри┐ри░рижрйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╡ри╕ри╛риИ ри░рй▒риЦ, риорйИриирйВрй░ риЖрикригри╛ риХрйАриоридрйА риири╛рио рижрйЗриИ ри░рй▒риЦ, ридри╛риХри┐ риорйЗри░ри╛ риЬрйАри╡рии ри╕рилри▓ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риП редрйзредри╣рйЗ риорйЗри░рйЗ риори╛ри▓риХ! риорйИриирйВрй░ риЖрикригрйЗ ри╕рй░ридри╛риВ рижрйА ри╕рй░риЧридри┐ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри░рй▒риЦрйА ри░рй▒риЦ, риЗри╣рйА риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╡ри╛ри╕ридрйЗ риорйБриХридрйА ри╣рйИ, ридрйЗ риЗри╣рйА риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╡ри╛ри╕ридрйЗ риЬрйАри╡рии-риЪрй▒риЬ ри╣рйИ редрйиредри╣рйЗ риири╛риириХ! (риЖриЦтАФ) ри╣рйЗ ри╣ри░рйА! (риорйЗри╣ри░ риХри░) ридрйЗри░рйЗ риЧрйБригри╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЪрйБрй▒ринрйА ри▓ри╛ риХрйЗ риорйИриВ ридрйЗри░ри╛ риири╛рио ри╕ри┐риори░рижри╛ ри░ри╣ри╛риВ ридрйЗ риЖридриориХ риЕрибрйЛри▓ридри╛ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЯри┐риХри┐риЖ ри░ри╣ри╛риВ редрййредрймредрйзрйкрймред\\""},{"question":"уАМуБиуВКуБВуБИуБЪуАНуБиуАМуБДуБ╛уБоуБиуБУуВНуАНуБпхРМуБШуБзуБЩуБЛуАВ","answer":"ф╛ЛуБИуБ░уАБуАМщг▓уБ┐чЙйуБпш╢│уВКуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуБЛуАНуБиуБДуБЖш│кхХПуБлхп╛уБЧуБжуАМуБиуВКуБВуБИуБЪш╢│уВКуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАНуАМф╗КуБоуБиуБУуВНш╢│уВКуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАНчв║уБЛуБлуБйуБбуВЙуБзуВВхРМуБШуВИуБЖуБкцДПхС│уБлуБкуВКуБ╛уБЩуАВуБйуБбуВЙуВВф╜┐уБИуВЛха┤хРИуБиуАБуБйуБбуВЙуБЛуБЧуБЛф╜┐уБИуБкуБДха┤хРИуБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЩуАВуАМф╜ХуБЛш│кхХПуБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЩуБЛуАНуБлхп╛уБЧуБжуАМуБиуВКуБВуБИуБЪхдзф╕ИхдлуБзуБЩуАНуБзуВВуАМф╗КуБоуБиуБУуВНхдзф╕ИхдлуБзуБЩуАНуБзуВВуБДуБДуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖуАВуБЧуБЛуБЧуАБуАМуБиуВКуБВуБИуБЪуАНуБпуВВуБиуВВуБиуАМуБиуВЛуВВуБоуВВуБиуВКуБВуБИуБЪуАНуАБуБдуБ╛уВКцАеуБДуБзуБДуВЛуГЛуГеуВвуГ│уВ╣уБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЩуАВуБзуБЩуБЛуВЙуАМчФ░шИОуБочИ╢уБМхАТуВМуБЯуБиуБДуБЖчЯеуВЙуБЫуБМуБВуБгуБжуАБшй│ч┤░уБпуВПуБЛуВЙуБкуБДуБМуБиуВКуБВуБИуБЪцЭ▒ф║мщзЕуБлхРСуБЛуБгуБЯуАНуБиуБДуБЖуБиуБНуАБуАМуБДуБ╛уБоуБиуБУуВНуАНуБпуБКуБЛуБЧуБДуБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"рокрпЖро░ро┐ропро╛ро░ро┐ройрпН роОро┤рпБродрпНродрпБроХро│ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ  роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"роЗройрпНро▒рпИроп рокрпЛро░ро╛роЯрпНроЯроорпЗ роЪро╛родро┐ропрпИроХрпН роХро╛рокрпНрокро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпБро╡родрпБ роОройрпНрокродрпБроорпН, роЪро╛родро┐ропрпИ роТро┤ро┐рокрпНрокродрпБ роОройрпНрокродрпБроорпНродро╛ройрпН."},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Erwin Rommel. ","answer":"Bh├н Erwin Johannes Eugen Rommel (rugadh 15 Samhain 1891 agus d'├йag 14 Deireadh F├│mhair 1944) ina cheannasa├н ar an arm Gearm├бnach i rith an Dara Cogadh Domhanda.Th├│g s├й p├бirt in san Ch├йad Chogadh Domhanda. "},{"question":"┘Г┘Е┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Б┘В╪▒╪й:┘И╪г┘Е╪з ╪╣┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪╣┘Д╪з┘В╪з╪к ┘Е╪╣ ╪п┘И┘Д ┘Е┘Ж╪╕┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪╣╪з┘И┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪е╪│┘Д╪з┘Е┘К╪М ┘Б┘В╪з┘Д ╪и┘И┘Д╪з╪к ╪е┘Ж ╪н╪м┘Е ╪з┘Д╪╡╪з╪п╪▒╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪к╪▒┘Г┘К╪й ╪з╪▒╪к┘Б╪╣ ┘Е┘Ж 4.7 ┘Е┘Д┘К╪з╪▒╪з╪к ╪п┘И┘Д╪з╪▒ ╪╣╪з┘Е 2002 ╪е┘Д┘Й 65 ┘Е┘Д┘К╪з╪▒╪з ╪з┘Д╪╣╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д┘Е╪з╪╢┘К.","answer":"┘И╪г┘Г╪п ┘И╪▓┘К╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪к╪м╪з╪▒╪й ╪г┘Ж ╪к╪▒┘Г┘К╪з ┘И╪╢╪╣╪к ╪е╪│╪к╪▒╪з╪к┘К╪м┘К╪й ╪м╪п┘К╪п╪й ┘Д╪▓┘К╪з╪п╪й ╪н╪м┘Е ╪з┘Д╪к╪м╪з╪▒╪й ╪и┘Е╪з ┘К╪к┘Е╪з╪┤┘Й ┘Е╪╣ ╪к┘Г╪л┘К┘Б ╪з┘Д╪╣┘Д╪з┘В╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪л┘Ж╪з╪ж┘К╪й ┘Е╪╣ ╪з┘Д╪╣╪з┘Д┘Е ╪з┘Д╪е╪│┘Д╪з┘Е┘К╪М ╪и┘Е╪з ┘Б┘К ╪░┘Д┘Г ╪п┘И┘Д ╪з┘Д╪о┘Д┘К╪м."},{"question":"Jawab teka teki yang lawak ini: Orang beli benda ini untuk makan, tetapi benda ini tidak dimakan.","answer":"Jawapan: Pinggan dan sudu."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk kuih beko nyor yang merupakan kuih-muih tradisional Melayu? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 2 cawan kelapa parut, 1 cawan tepung pulut, 2 sudu makan gula (boleh tambah mengikut kemanisan)1 cubit garam, Air untuk menguliCara-cara:1. Gaul semua bahan hingga sebati. Pastikan adunan tidak terlalu pekat atau cair.2. Masukkan ke dalam bekas.3. Bakar selama 30 minit menggunakan api atas bawah pada suhu 180┬░C.4. Sedia untuk dihidang."},{"question":"ржЯрж╛ржЗржо ржЯрзНрж░рж╛ржнрзЗрж▓рзЗрж░ рж╕рж╛ржерзЗ рж╕ржорзНржкрж░рзНржХрж┐ржд ржЯрзБржЗржи ржкрзНржпрж╛рж░рж╛ржбржХрзНрж╕рзЗрж░ ржмрж░рзНржгржирж╛ ржжрж╛ржУред","answer":"ржХрж╛рж▓ ржжрзАрж░рзНржШрж╛ржпрж╝ржирзЗрж░ ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржоржЬрж╛рж░ ржлрж▓рж╛ржлрж▓ ржмрж╛ ржкрж░рж┐ржгрждрж┐ рж╣рж▓рзЛ ржЯрзБржЗржи ржкрзНржпрж╛рж░рж╛ржбржХрзНрж╕ ржмрж╛ ржпржоржЬ ржХрзВржЯрж╛ржнрж╛рж╕ред рзирзж ржмржЫрж░ ржмржпрж╝рж╕рзА ржжрзБржЗ ржпржоржЬ ржнрж╛ржЗ рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХ ржУ ржЗржХржмрж╛рж▓ржХрзЗ ржирж┐ржпрж╝рзЗ ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржирж┐ржпрж╝ржирзНрждрзНрж░рж┐ржд ржкрж░рзАржХрзНрж╖ржг ржмрж┐ржмрзЗржЪржирж╛ ржХрж░рж╛ ржпрж╛ржХред рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХ ржнрзНрж░ржоржгржмрж┐рж▓рж╛рж╕рзА рж╕рзЗ ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзА ржерзЗржХрзЗ рзйрзж ржЖрж▓рзЛржХ ржмрж░рзНрж╖ ржжрзВрж░рзЗ ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржЧрзНрж░рж╣рзЗ ржпрзЗрждрзЗ ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзА ржерзЗржХрзЗ рж░ржУржирж╛ рж╣рж▓рзЛред рждрж╛рж░ ржорж╣рж╛рж╢рзВржирзНржп ржпрж╛ржи ржкрзНрж░рж╛ржпрж╝ ржЖрж▓рзЛрж░ рж╕ржорж╛ржи ржжрзНрж░рзБрждрж┐рждрзЗ ржпрзЗрждрзЗ рж╕ржХрзНрж╖ржоред ржЧрзНрж░рж╣рзЗ ржкрзМржЫрж╛рж░ ржкрж░ рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХрзЗрж░ ржоржи ржмрж╛ржбрж╝рж┐рж░ ржЬржирзНржп ржЖржиржЪрж╛ржи ржХрж░рждрзЗ рж▓рж╛ржЧрж▓ред рждрж╛ржЗ рж╕рзЗ ржПржХржЗ ржжрзНрж░рзБрждрж┐рждрзЗ (ржЖрж▓рзЛрж░ ржХрж╛ржЫрж╛ржХрж╛ржЫрж┐ ржжрзНрж░рзБрждрж┐рждрзЗ) ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрждрзЗ ржлрж┐рж░рзЗ ржПрж▓рзЛ ред ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрждрзЗ ржлрж┐рж░рзЗ рж╕рзЗ ржжрзЗржЦрзЗ ржЕржмрж╛ржХ рж╣рж▓рзЛ ржпрзЗ, ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрж░ ржЕржирзЗржХ ржХрж┐ржЫрзБржЗ ржкрж░рж┐ржмрж░рзНрждрж┐ржд рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗ ржЧрзЗржЫрзЗред рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХрзЗрж░ ржпржоржЬ ржнрж╛ржЗ ржЗржХржмрж╛рж▓рзЗрж░ ржмржпрж╝рж╕ ржкрзНрж░рж╛ржпрж╝ рзорзж ржмржЫрж░ред ржЖрж░ рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХрзЗрж░ ржмржпрж╝рж╕ рждрж╛рж░ ржЪрзЗржпрж╝рзЗ ржХржо рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗржЫрзЗ ржкрзНрж░рж╛ржпрж╝ рззрзж ржмржЫрж░ред рж╕рзНржмрж╛ржнрж╛ржмрж┐ржХржнрж╛ржмрзЗржЗ ржкрзНрж░рж╢рзНржи ржЬрж╛ржЧрждрзЗ ржкрж╛рж░рзЗ ржХрзЛржи ржпржоржЬ ржнрж╛ржЗ (рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХ ржирж╛ ржЗржХржмрж╛рж▓) ржПржХрзЗ ржЕржкрж░рзЗрж░ рждрзБрж▓ржирж╛ржпрж╝ ржЖрж▓рзЛрж░ ржХрж╛ржЫрж╛ржХрж╛ржЫрж┐ ржжрзНрж░рзБрждрж┐рждрзЗ ржнрзНрж░ржоржг ржХрж░рзЗржЫрзЗ, рж╕рзБрждрж░рж╛ржВ ржХрж╛рж░ ржмржпрж╝рж╕ ржмрж╛ржбрж╝рзЗржирж┐ред ржПржЦрж╛ржирзЗржЗ рж░ржпрж╝рзЗржЫрзЗ ржХрзВржЯрж╛ржнрж╛рж╕ред ржЗржХржмрж╛рж▓рзЗрж░ ржкрзНрж░рж╕ржЩрзНржЧ ржХрж╛ржарж╛ржорзЛрж░ рж╕рж╛ржкрзЗржХрзНрж╖рзЗ ржЗржХржмрж╛рж▓ ржирж┐рж╢рзНржЪрж▓ ржХрж┐ржирзНрждрзБ рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХ ржЕрждрзНржпржирзНржд ржмрзЗрж╢рж┐ ржмрзЗржЧ ржирж┐ржпрж╝рзЗ ржнрзНрж░ржоржг ржХрж░рзЗржЫрзЗред рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХрзЗрж░ ржорждрзЗ, ржпржжрж┐ржУ ржЗржХржмрж╛рж▓ ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрждрзЗ рж╕рж╛ржжрж┐ржХрзЗрж░ рж╕рж╛ржкрзЗржХрзНрж╖рзЗ ржжрзВрж░рзЗ ржЪрж▓рзЗ ржпрж╛ржЪрзНржЫрзЗ ржПржмржВ ржкрж░рзЗ ржлрж┐рж░рзЗ ржЖрж╕ржЫрзЗред ржПржЯрж╛ржЗ рж╣рж▓рзЛ ржЕрж╕ржЩрзНржЧрждрж┐ ржпрзЗ ржЖржорж╛ржжрзЗрж░ ржЙржкрж░рж┐ржЙржХрзНржд ржнржмрж┐рж╖рзНржпржжрзНржмрж╛ржгрзА ржмрж╛ ржзрж╛рж░ржгрж╛ржпрж╝ ржХрзЛржирзЛ ржпржоржЬ ржнрж╛ржЗ ржкрзНрж░ржХрзГрждржкржХрзНрж╖рзЗ ржмрзЗрж╢рж┐ ржмржпрж╝рж╕рзНржХред"},{"question":"Yaraanta Iodine.","answer":"Calaamadaha ugu waa weyn waa (qanjirkathyroidka oo balaarta), indhaha oo soo baxa (koru soo taagma), hypothyroidism (Daal, culeyskaqofka oo kordha, tabar darri iyo iskuyaacsanaanmaskaxeed) and hyperthyroidism (miisaanlumin, wadna garraacid aad ah, iyo dhibaatooyinla xiriira rabitaanka cuntada). IDD (iskudhexyaacsanaanta ka timaadda laтАЩaanta iodine)xilliga uurka waxay sababtaa cillinimo (dib udhac baтАЩan oo ku yimaada maskaxda,hagaasnimo ku timaada koritaanka jirka, madax ballaarnaan iyo dhagoolnimo) ilmaha dhashay ilmaha dhashay."},{"question":" Inona no firenena sadnany Eoropa no any Azia?","answer":"Torkia no firenena izay samy any Eoropa sy Azia. Ny ampahany amin'i Torkia dia any Eoropa ary ny ampahany hafa any Azia."},{"question":"сЛисИШсЛ░сИШсИн сИШсМ╜сИРсНН сМ╕сИРсНК сИЫсКРсЛН?","answer":"сМасЙЕсИЛсЛн сИЪсКТсИ╡сЙ╡сИн сЛРсЙвсЛн сКасИХсИШсЛ╡"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:роЪроирпНродро┐ро░ро┐роХрпИропро┐ройрпН роХродрпИ роирпВро▓ро┐ройрпН роЖроЪро┐ро░ро┐ропро░рпН тАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАж.роЕ) рокро╛ро░родро┐ропро╛ро░рпНроЖ) рокро╛ро░родро┐родро╛роЪройрпНроЗ) родрооро┐ро┤рогрпНрогро▓рпНроИ) роХрпБ.рокро╛.ро░ро╛.","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ:роЕ) рокро╛ро░родро┐ропро╛ро░рпН"},{"question":"waa maxay Suuqgeyn?","answer":"Suuqgeyntu waa hab loo maro ka iibinta alaab ama adeeg la doonayo in laga iibiyo macmiil"},{"question":"р░╢р▒Нр░░р▒Ар░░р░╛р░ор▒Бр░ир░┐ р░ор▒Бр░жр▒Нр░░р░┐р░Хр░ир▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░╕р░┐ р░╕р▒Ар░д р░╣р░ир▒Бр░ор░др▒Л р░Пр░ор░ир▒Нр░ир░жр░┐ ?","answer":"р░╢р▒Нр░░р▒Ар░░р░╛р░ор▒Бр░ир░┐ р░ор▒Бр░жр▒Нр░░р░┐р░Хр░ир▒Б р░╣р░ир▒Бр░о р░Ър▒Вр░кр░Чр░╛, р░Ер░др░ир░┐р░др▒Л р░╕р▒Ар░др░╛р░жр▒Зр░╡р░┐ р░Зр░▓р░╛ р░кр░▓р░┐р░Хр▒Жр░ир▒Б. р░ир░╛ р░нр░░р▒Нр░д р░Ер░пр░┐р░и р░╢р▒Нр░░р▒Ар░░р░╛р░ор▒Бр░ир░┐ р░╕р░ор░╛р░Ър░╛р░░р░ор▒Бр░ир▒Б р░ир▒А р░╡р░▓р░и р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░╕р▒Бр░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░ир▒Б. р░Хр░╛р░ир▒А р░ир▒А р░ир░┐р░Ьр░░р▒Вр░кр░ор▒Бр░ир▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░бр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░ир░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир▒Б р░ир░ор▒Нр░ор░┐ р░ир░╛ р░╢р░┐р░░р▒Лр░░р░др▒Нр░ир░ор▒Бр░ир▒Б р░ир▒Ар░Хр░┐р░╡р▒Нр░╡р░ир▒Б р░Ер░ир░┐ р░╣р░ир▒Бр░ор░др▒Л р░╕р░Вр░╢р░пр░ор▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░кр░▓р░┐р░Хр░┐р░ир░жр░┐. р░Ер░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░бр▒Б р░╣р░ир▒Бр░о р░Жр░Хр░╛р░╢р░ор▒Бр░ир▒Б р░Ер░Вр░Яр▒Бр░ир░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░др░и р░ир░┐р░Ь р░╕р▒Нр░╡р░░р▒Вр░кр░ор▒Бр░ир▒Б р░╕р▒Ар░др░╛р░жр▒Зр░╡р░┐ р░Ор░жр▒Бр░Я р░кр▒Нр░░р░жр░░р▒Нр░╢р░┐р░Вр░Ър▒Жр░ир▒Б."},{"question":" тАЬр░Ер░ир▒Бр░Ър▒Бр░ир▒Н р░Ьр▒Зр░╡р▒Бр░░р▒Б р░ор▒Ар░▒р▒Б р░Хр░ир▒Нр░ир▒Бр░Чр░╡р░др▒Л, р░ир░╛р░╕р▒Нр░кр░Вр░жр░жр▒Лр░╖р▒Нр░гр░Вр░мр▒Бр░др▒Л, р░Шр░ир░╣р▒Бр░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░ор▒Бр░др▒Л, р░ир░Яр░жр▒Нр░░р▒Нр░нр▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░Яр░┐р░др▒Л р░Чр░░р▒Нр░Ьр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░ир░╛ р░лр▒Лр░ир▒Н р░╕р░▓р▒Зр░╢р▒Бр░ир░┐тАЭ р░И р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Ер░▓р░Вр░Хр░╛р░░р░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Нр░др░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.A) р░Йр░кр░оB) р░Йр░др▒Нр░кр▒Нр░░р▒Зр░Хр▒Нр░╖C) р░╕р▒Нр░╡р░нр░╛р░╡р▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐D) р░╡р▒Гр░др▒Нр░др▒Нр░пр░ир▒Бр░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░╕","answer":"C) р░╕р▒Нр░╡р░нр░╛р░╡р▒Лр░Хр▒Нр░др░┐"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ┘З┘И ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪и┘К ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ┘Г╪з┘Ж╪к ┘Е╪╣╪м╪▓╪к┘З ╪е╪н┘К╪з╪б ╪з┘Д┘Е┘И╪к┘Й╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й:  ┘Ж╪и┘К ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╣┘К╪│┘Й ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д╪з┘Е."},{"question":"р░кр▒Бр░Вр░кр▒Нр░╡р░╛р░жр▒Зр░╢ р░╕р░Вр░зр░┐ р░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Йр░жр░╛р░╣р░░р░гр░▓р▒Б р░Зр░╡р▒Нр░╡р░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░кр▒Бр░Вр░кр▒Нр░╡р░╛р░жр▒Зр░╢ р░╕р░Вр░зр░┐ :р░Хр░░р▒Нр░о р░зр░╛р░░р░пр░ор▒Бр░▓р░Вр░жр░▓р░┐ тАШр░ор▒БтАЩ р░╡р░░р▒Нр░гр░ор▒Бр░ир░Хр▒Б р░кр▒Бр░Вр░кр▒Бр░▓р░Чр▒Б.р░Йр░жр░╛ :р░╕р░░р░╕р░ор▒Б + р░╡р░Ър░ир░ор▒Б тАУ р░╕р░░р░╕р░кр▒Бр░╡р░Ър░ир░ор▒Б тАУ р░╕р░░р░╕р░Вр░кр▒Бр░╡р░Ър░ир░ор░╡р░┐р░░р░╕р░ор▒Б + р░ор░╛р░Я тАУ р░╡р░┐р░░р░╕р░кр▒Бр░ор░╛р░Я , р░╡р░┐р░░р░╕р░Вр░кр▒Бр░ор░╛р░Я"},{"question":"╨Э╨╡╨╛╨╗╨╛╨│╨╕╨╖╨╝╨┤╨╡╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜╨┤╨╡ ╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╤В╥п╤И╥п╨╜╙й╤Б╥п╨╖?","answer":"╨Э╨╡╨╛╨╗╨╛╨│╨╕╨╖╨╝╨┤╨╡╤А (╨╜╨╡╨╛... ╨╢╨░╨╜╤Л ╨│╤А. logos тАУ ╤Б╙й╨╖) тАУ ╨║╨╛╨╛╨╝╨┤╤Г╨║ ╤В╤Г╤А╨╝╤Г╤И╤В╨░╨│╤Л ╨░╤А ╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨╖╨░╤А╤Л╨╗╤З╤Л╨╗╤Л╨║╤В╨░╨╜ ╤Г╨╗╨░╨╝ ╨┐╨░╨╣╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜ ╨╢╨░╥г╤Л ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А. ╨Р╨╗╨░╤А ╨╢╨░╨╗╨┐╤Л ╤В╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╕╨║ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨░╨▓╤В╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨║ (╨╢╨╡╨║╨╡ ╤Б╤В╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╕╨║) ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨▒╙й╨╗╥п╨╜╙й╤В. ╨Ц╨░╨╗╨┐╤Л ╤В╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╕╨║ ╨Э. ╨╢╨░╥г╤Л ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜ ╨╖╨░╤В╤В╤Л ╨╢╨╡ ╨║╙й╤А╥п╨╜╥п╤И╤В╥п ╨░╤В╨╛╨╛ ╨╖╨░╤А╤Л╨╗╤З╤Л╨╗╤Л╨│╤Л╨╜╨░ ╨▒╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л╤И╤В╤Г╤Г ╨┐╨░╨╣╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В (╨╝╨╕╤Б╨░╨╗╤Л,╨╝╨╛╨╜╨╕╤В╨╛╤А╨╕╨╜╨│, ╨╕╨╜╨╜╨╛╨▓╨░╤Ж╨╕╤П, c╨░╨╣╤В ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨▒╨░╤И╨║╨░) ╨┤╨░, ╤В╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╡ ╤В╨╛╨╗╤Г╨║ ╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤И╤В╥п╤А╥п╨╗╨│╙й╨╜ ╤Б╨╛╥г ╨╜╨╡╨╛╨╗╨╛╨│╨╕╨╖╨╝ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╤Г╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╗╨░╤В. ╨Р╨▓╤В╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨║ ╨╜╨╡╨╛╨╗╨╛╨│╨╕╨╖╨╝ ╨║╙й╨▒╥п╨╜╤З╙й ╤Б╤В╨╕╨╗╨┤╨╕╨║ ╨╝╨░╨║╤Б╨░╤В╤В╨░ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤А╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐, ╨║╨╛╨╜╤В╨╡╨║╤Б╤В╤В╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╤Л╤А╤В╨║╨░╤А╤Л ╨┤╤Н╤Н╤А╨╗╨╕╨║ ╨║╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╨╜╤Г╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░╨░╨╜╤З╨░ ╨║╨╡╥г╨╕╤А╨╕ ╤В╨░╤А╨░╨╗╨░ ╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В. ╨Ь╨╕╤Б╨░╨╗╤Л:╨Ш╨╜╤В╤А╨╛╨▓╨╡╤А╤Б╨╕╤П, ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨┤╨╕╥г?╨Р╨╝╨╛╤А╨░╨╗╨┤╤Г╤Г ╨╛╨╣╨╗╨╛╤А ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜╨Ь╨╕╨╖╨░╨╜╤В╤А╨╛╨┐╨╕╤П ╤В╨░╨╝╤З╤Л╨╗╨░╨┐╨Э╨╕╨│╨╕╨╗╨╕╤Б╤В╤В╨╕╨║ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╤А ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜╨ж╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╖╨╝╨╕╥г ╨║╨░╨╝╤З╤Л╨╗╨░╨┐╨Р╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨┤╨╕╥г, \\"╨Р╨▒╤Б╤Г╤А╨┤!\\" ╨┤╨╡╨┤╨╕╥г╨С╨░╨░╤А╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨╛╨║╨║╨╛ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤А╤Л╨┐╨Ш╤И╨╡╨╜╨╕╨╝ ╨┤╨░, ╨Ъ╤Г╨┤╨░╨╣ ╨┤╨░╨│╤Л╨Ъ╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л ╨░╤А╤В╤В╨░ ╨║╤Л╨╖╨░╤А╤Л╨┐╨С╨░╤В╨║╨░╨╜ ╨║╥п╨╜╨┤╙й╨╣ ╨║╤Л╨╖╨░╤А╤Л╨┐╨Р╨╖╤Л╤А ╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╨╣╨╝ ╨╛╤И╨╛╨╗╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨У╨░╤А╨╝╨╛╨╜╨╕╤П╨╜╤Л, ╤Г╨▒╨░╨╣╨┤╤Л╨г╨╜╤Г╤В╤Г╨╗╨│╨░╨╜, ╨╢╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╨▒╨░╨╗╨║╨╕╨╝ ╙й╨╗╨│╙й╨╜ ╨Ъ╤Г╨┤╨░╨╣╨┤╤Л╨Ш╨╖╨┤╨╡╨╣╨╝ ╨░╨╜╤Л ╤В╨╛╨╛╨┤╨╛╨╜, ╤В╨░╤И╤В╨░╨╜╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╨╣╨╝ ╤Б╤Г╤Г╨┤╨░╨╜, ╨░╨▒╨░╨┤╨░╨╜╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╨╣╨╝ ╤Г╤И╤Г ╤В╨░╨▒╨╕╨│╨░╤В╤В╨░╨╜╨╕╨╖╨╕ ╤Б╤Г╤Г╨│╨░╨╜ ╨░╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╨░╨╜.╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╡╨╣╨╝ ╤В╨╛╨╗╨╛ ╨╕╨╖╨╝╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╡╨╜╤Н╨║╨╖╨╕╤Б╤В╨╡╨╜╤Ж╨╕╤П, ╨░╤Б╨║╨╡╤В╨╕╨╖╨╝╨┤╨░╨╛╤Б╨╕╨╖╨╝, ╤Б╤Г╤Д╨╕╨╖╨╝╨╢╨░╤И╨╛╨╛╨╕╨╖╨╝, ╙й╨╝╥п╤А╨╕╨╖╨╝╨╕╨╖╨╝ ╨╕╨╖╨╝ ╨╕╨╖╨╝ ╨╕╨╖╨╝╨▒╤Г ╨▒╨░╨░╤А╤Л╨╜╨░ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨╝╨╡╨║ ╨║╨░╨╣╨┤╨░╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╤В╤Г╤А╤Б╨░ ╨╝╨╡╨╗╨░╨╜╤Е╨╛╨╗╨╕╤П ╨░╨╖╤Л╤А╤Л╨╜╤З╨░ ╨╝╨╡╨╗╨░╨╜╤Е╨╛╨╗╨╕╤П..."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Д╪г┘К┘С ┘Ж╪и┘К┘С┘Н ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪г┘Ж╪и┘К╪з╪б ╪з┘Ж╪┤┘В┘С ╪з┘Д╪и╪н╪▒╪Я","answer":"      ╪з┘Д╪м┘И╪з╪и: ┘Ж╪и┘К┘С ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ┘Е┘И╪│┘Й ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д╪з┘Е."},{"question":"Sheeg cuduradda ugu caansan ee la is qaadsiiyo?","answer":"Waxaa kamid ah cuduradda ugu caansan ee la is qaadsiiyo:b) Kuwa hawadaa isuku mariyo, sida Hargabka, Burukiitada, Iyo Tiibishada.t) Kuwa galmada lagu kala qaado, sida Isfiilitada, Jabtada, iyo Aydhiska (AIDS).j) Kuwa lagu kala qaado cuntada iyo biyaha wasakheysan, sida Daacuunka iyo Tiifowga.x) Kuwa cayayaanka u Kala gudbiyo, sida Duumada ay soo gudbiso Kaneecada."},{"question":"╨Т╨╛╨┐╤А╨╛╤Б: ╨╛╨▒╤К╤П╤Б╨╜╨╕ ╨╛╨▒╤А╨░╨╖╨╛╨▓╨░╨╜╨╕╨╡ ╤Б╨╗╨╛╨▓╨░ ╤Б╨╡╨╝╤М╤П","answer":"╨б╨╡╨╝╤М╤П,  \\"╤Б╨╡╨╝╤М\\" - ╨╖╨╜╨░╤З╨╕╤В 7, \\"╤П\\" - ╨╛╨╖╨╜╨░╤З╨░╨╡╤В me, I ╤Б ╨░╨╜╨│╨╗╨╕╨╣╤Б╨║╨╛╨│╨╛"},{"question":"Viс║┐t mс╗Щt v├аi v├н dс╗е sс╗н dс╗еng t├бc phс║йm Truyс╗Зn Kiс╗Бu cс╗зa Nguyс╗Еn Du ─Сс╗Г thс╗Г hiс╗Зn c├бch n├│i khi C├БC NH├ВN Vс║мT V─ВN Hс╗МC VIс╗ЖT NAM H├УA \\"NG├ФN T├МNH\\"","answer":"- Th├║y Kiс╗Бu n├│i vс╗Ыi Th├║y V├вn: тАЬC├┤ b├й cс╗зa t├┤i, ch├║c em mс╗Щt ─Сс╗Эi b├мnh an vui vс║╗.тАЭ- Kim Trс╗Нng n├│i vс╗Ыi Thu├╜ V├вn: тАЬSau n├аy em sс║╜ hiс╗Гu, с╗Я n╞бi n├аo ─С├│ tr├кn thс║┐ giс╗Ыi n├аy c├│ Kiс╗Бu xuс║еt hiс╗Зn, th├м nhс╗пng ng╞░с╗Эi kh├бc chс╗Й l├а tс║бm bс╗г. Anh kh├┤ng muс╗Сn tс║бm bс╗г.тАЭ- Th├║y Kiс╗Бu n├│i vс╗Ыi Kim Trс╗Нng: тАЬGс║╖p anh l├а ─Сiс╗Бu bс║еt ngс╗Э tuyс╗Зt vс╗Эi nhс║еt. Y├кu anh l├а ╞░с╗Ыc nguyс╗Зn cс║г ─Сс╗Эi kh├┤ng hс╗Сi tiс║┐c. Vс╗йt bс╗П anh l├а ─Сiс╗Бu d┼йng cс║гm nhс║еt!тАЭ"},{"question":"╪┤┘Ж┘И ┘З┘И ╪г╪и╪▒╪п ╪м╪│┘Е ┘Б╪з┘Д┘Е╪м┘Е┘И╪╣╪й ╪з┘Д╪┤┘Е╪│┘К╪й ╪Я","answer":"┘В┘Е╪▒ ┘Г┘И┘Г╪и ┘Ж╪и╪к┘И┘Ж (╪к╪▒╪з┘К╪к┘И┘Ж)"},{"question":"aiza avy no toerana azo iompiana trondro?","answer":"ireto avy no azo iompiana trondro: ny farihy, ny dobo, ny tanimbary"},{"question":"No contexto da computa├з├гo, explique o significado de Realidade Virtual (VR) e Realidade Aumentada (AR).","answer":"Realidade Virtual (VR) ├й uma tecnologia que cria um ambiente digital imersivo, permitindo que os usu├бrios interajam com esse ambiente como se estivessem realmente l├б. J├б a Realidade Aumentada (AR) combina elementos do mundo real com elementos virtuais, sobrepondo informa├з├╡es digitais ao ambiente f├нsico, melhorando assim a experi├кncia do usu├бrio."},{"question":"цмбуБоуВ┐уВдуГИуГлуБлхЯ║уБеуБДуБжуАБуБУуБоуГИуГФуГГуВпуБлщЦвуБЩуВЛшиШф║ЛуВТцЫ╕уБНуБкуБХуБДя╝Ъ цЧецЬмуБоуГнуВ▒уГГуГИуАМH2AуАНуААцЬИуВТшк┐уБ╣уВЛцОвцЯ╗цйЯуВТхоЗхоЩуБлщБЛуВУуБа","answer":"цЧецЬмуБоJAXAуБп7цЧеуБоцЬЭуАБуГнуВ▒уГГуГИуБоуАМH2AуАНуВТцЙУуБбф╕КуБТуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВH2AуБпуАБцЬИуВТшк┐уБ╣уВЛцОвцЯ╗цйЯуАМSLIMуАНуВТщлШуБХч┤Д620kmуБ╛уБзщБЛуВУуБзуАБш╗МщБУуБлхЕеуВМуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВхоЗхоЩуВТшк┐уБ╣уВЛф║║х╖ешбЫцШЯуАМXRISMуАНуВВш╗МщБУуБлхЕеуВМуБжуАБцЙУуБбф╕КуБТуБпцИРхКЯуБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВJAXAуБпф╗Кх╣┤3цЬИуАБцЦ░уБЧуБДуГнуВ▒уГГуГИуАМH3уАНуБоцЙУуБбф╕КуБТуБлхд▒цХЧуБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВуБУуБоуБЯуВБуАБH2AуБМцИРхКЯуБЩуВЛуБЛуБйуБЖуБЛуАБхдЪуБПуБоф║║уБМц│ичЫоуБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВH2AуБМщБЛуВУуБаSLIMуБпуАБ3уБЛцЬИуБЛ4уБЛцЬИуБВуБиуБлцЬИуВТхЫЮуВЛш╗МщБУуБлхЕеуБгуБжуАБцЭех╣┤1цЬИуБЛ2цЬИуБФуВНцЬИуБлф╕ЛуВКуВЛуБУуБиуВТшиИчФ╗уБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВцЧецЬмуБоцОвцЯ╗цйЯуБпуБ╛уБацЬИуБлф╕ЛуВКуБЯуБУуБиуБМуБВуВКуБ╛уБЫуВУуАВSLIMуБМшк┐уБ╣уВЛуГЗуГ╝уВ┐уБпуАБуВвуГбуГкуВлуБоуАМуВвуГлуГЖуГЯуВ╣шиИчФ╗уАНуБзф║║уБМцЬИуБлшбМуБгуБжшк┐уБ╣уВЛуБУуБиуБлуВВх╜╣уБлчлЛуБжуВЛф║ИхоЪуБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"Ban xaaliss la├▒uy j├лf├лndiko reewum Itaali?","answer":"Euro "},{"question":"S├│k├│t├│","answer":"Sokoto je ilu pataki kan ni ariwa iwo oorun Naijiria, nitosi idapomora Odo Sokoto ati Odo Rima. Ni Odun 2006, olugbe ti o wa ni be ju 427,760. Sokoto ni oluilu Ipinle Sokoto, o si je oluilu awon ipinle ti o wa ni ariwa iwo oorun Naijiria tele.Oruko Sokoto (oruko atijo re ni Sakkwato) ni ipilese Larubawa, je sooq ti o tunmo si oja ni Yoruba. Atun mo si Sakkwato, Birnin Shaihu da Bello tabi \\"Sokoto, Oluilu Shaihu ati Bello\\" Bello Umar Maikaset.Ibujoko Kalifu Sokoto teleri, esin musulumi ni o bori ni ilu naa ti o si je ibujoko pataki ti won ti n ko eko Islam. Sultanu ti o je oludari Kalifu ni adari elesin awon Musulumi Naijiria.Sokoto ni oju ojo ologbele-ogbele (Isori oju ojo K├╢ppen BSh). O wa ni apa Sahel to gbe, Savana oniyanrin ati oke die si yiika. Pelu iwon igbona tabi otutu odoodun to saba ma n je 28.3┬░C (82.9┬░F), Sokoto je ikan lara awon ilu to gbona julo ni Naijiria, sibesibe iwon igbona tabi otutu ni osan saba ma n je 40┬░C (104.0┬░F) fun pupo igba lodun, gbigbe re kii je ki ooru poju. Osu keji titi de Osu kerin ni o ma n gbona julo, ti gbigbona re le ju 40┬░C lo. Iwon igbona tabi otutu ti o ga julo ni 45┬░C. Igba ojo beere lati Osu kefa titi de Osu kewa, nigbati ojo ma n ro lojoojumo. Ojo naa kii saba ma n pe, oyato si bi ojo ti ma n ro ni awon agbegbe ti ojo ti man ro daradara. Lati opin Osu kewa de Osu keji, ni 'igba otutu', ategun oye ti o n fe eruku Sahara ma n bo oju ojo. Eruku yii ma n bo oorun, o si ma n di iwon igbona tabi otutu ku lopolopo.Anfani ti agbegbe naa ni lati gbin irugbin ni ibi isan omi odo Sokoto-Rima, ti o ni ile olora. Awon irugbin ti won ma n gbin ni Sokoto ni jero, oka baba, ewa to fere poju, leyin re ni agbado, iresi, yamati/eeku, awon irugbin oka ati ewebe miran ni alubosa, tomati, ata, igba/ikan, letusi, ati kabeeji. Yato si jero, Sokoto ni o n pese alubosa julo ni Naijiria. Ni ti eweko, Sokoto bosi agbegbe Savana. Eyi jс║╣ ilс║╣-koriko ti ko ni eс╣гinс╣гin tse-tse, o dara fun ogbin awс╗Нn irugbin с╗Нk├а ati osin с║╣ran. ├Тj├▓ m├бa ┼Д pe bс║╣╠Аrс║╣╠А ├│ s├м ma n tete dawoduro pс║╣╠Аl├║ ├мwс╗Н╠Аn idaji ├▓j├▓ odoodun l├б├а├бr├нn 500mm ati 1,300mm. Awс╗Нn igba meji pataki lo wa ni Sokoto, igba otutu ati ogbele. Ogbele ma n bс║╣rс║╣ lati Oс╣гu Kс║╣wa titi di Oс╣гu Kс║╣rin ni awс╗Нn apa kan o si le di Osu Karun tabi Osu Kefa ni apa miiran. Igba otutu ni apa keji bс║╣rс║╣ ni Osu Karun titi di Oс╣гu Kс║╣san tabi Oс╣гu Kс║╣wa ni opo ibi ni ipinle naa. Oye, gbigbс║╣, otutu, ati afс║╣fс║╣ eruku ni iriri ipinle naa laarin Oс╣гu Kс╗Нkanla ati Osu keji. Ooru ma n po ni ipinlс║╣ naa ni Oс╣гu Kс║╣ta ati Oс╣гu Kс║╣rin. с╣вugbс╗Нn oju ojo ni ipinle naa ma tutu ni owurс╗Н o si ma n gbona ni awс╗Нn с╗Нsan, yato si igba oye lile. Petele ti o wopo ni ile Hausa, apa ariwa Naijiria ni o poju ni ipinle naa. Ilс║╣ fadama ti o tobi pupo ti awс╗Нn с╗Нna Odo Sokoto-Rima wa ni pс║╣tс║╣lс║╣ ti o si pese ilс║╣ olora ti o dara fun ogbin с╗Нpс╗Нlс╗Нpс╗Н irugbin ni ipinle naa. Awс╗Нn oke ati oke-nla wa kaakiri ipinlс║╣ naa.Shehu Usmanu Dan Fodiyo ti lo Sokoto ni ibere osu kewaa odun 1804 gege bi ibi ipade pelu Galadima, Yunfa's Vizier. Lс║╣yin naa, Muhammad Bello lo o gс║╣gс║╣bi ibi ikс╗Нlu Dufua ni ibere с╗Нdun 1806. Bovil daba pe won ti mo agbegbe naa si Sokoto lati ibс║╣rс║╣ awon с╗Нdun kс║╣tadinlogun. Ni iwoye itan, Sokoto ni a da sile bi agс╗Н ologun ni с╗Нdun 1809, nigbati Shehu Usmanu wa ni Sifawa. Lс║╣hinna o di olu-ilu kalifu lс║╣hin iku Shehu.Ni awс╗Нn с╗Нdun 1820, Sokoto wa ni ipo giga rс║╣ ti aisiki ni ibamu pс║╣lu ipo giga ti awс╗Нn agbara 'awс╗Нn alaс╣гс║╣' ni aarin kalifu, ti o n gba isakole lododun lati с╗Нdс╗Н gbogbo awс╗Нn fiifu с╣гaaju ki agbara won to dinku. Oluwakiri Hugh Clapperton (1827) ni iwunilori pupс╗Н nipasс║╣ aisiki yii ati awс╗Нn ipa rс║╣ lori ilu naa.Clapperton с╣гe akiyesi pataki bi agbegbe Sokoto se sunmora won: awс╗Нn odo, dipo iс╣гowo jijinna, ni с╗Нrс╗Н-aje ilu naa. с╣вugbс╗Нn iс╣гowo Sokoto ko da bii ti tele mo, nitori ipo idamu ti orilс║╣-ede ti o sunmo wa.Ni akoko ti oluwakiri Heinrich Barth de ni 1853, die eniyan lo n gbe Sokoto o si ti bajс║╣ pupс╗Н. Barth ni 1857 с╣гe iс╣гiro awс╗Нn olugbe ni 20,000-22,000, с╣гugbс╗Нn с╗Нja naa si n se daadaa, ati agbegbe eyin odi ti o dara ju Sokoto funrararс║╣.Bovil с╣гapejuwe ni deede Sokoto gс║╣gс║╣bi ipo ti o lagbara, pс║╣lu awс╗Нn apata giga lati ila-oorun si ariwa-iwс╗Н-oorun ati afonifoji kekere kan ni iwс╗Н-oorun ati guusu iwс╗Н-oorun ti o daabobo lodi si awс╗Нn ikс╗Нlu alagbara aimotele. Ilu naa jс║╣ gaba lori ilс║╣ pс║╣tс║╣lс║╣ ti o gbooro nibiti awс╗Нn odo meji, Rima ati Sokoto pade, ti o jс║╣ ipade с╗Нna lati Gobir ni ariwa, Kebbi ni guusu ati Burmi Zamfara ni ila-oorun.Ni ibс║╣rс║╣ orundun kс╗Нkandinlogun, ilu naa (Sokoto) ti pin si awс╗Нn eka. Ir├║ ├аwс╗Нn eka bс║╣╠Бс║╣╠А ni с║╣╠Аka Magajin Gari, с║╣╠Аka Waziri, с║╣╠Аka Sarkin Musulumi, с║╣╠Аka Sarkin Adar, с║╣╠Аka Magajin Rafi, ├аti eka Sarkin Zamfara. Ni akoko yii awс╗Нn wс╗Нс╗Нdu naa jс║╣ kekere ti wс╗Нn si fi odi yi wс╗Нn ka, pelu eyiti o wa ninu mс╗Нс╣гalaс╣гi Sultan Bello ati Shehu, Aafin Sultan ati awс╗Нn ile miiran ati agbo ile Shehu.Ni с╗Нdun 1818, won fe odi naa si iwс╗Нn ti o ni awс╗Нn с║╣nu-с╗Нna ti o wс╗Нle ati jade lati odi Birni. Iru ibode ni Kofar-Kade, Kofar-Kware, Kofar-Rini, Kofar-Dundaye, Kofar-Taramniya, Kofar-Aliyu Jedo, ati Kofar-Marke.Agbegbe Sokoto ti o wa lс╗Нwс╗Нlс╗Нwс╗Н jс║╣ ile ti с╗Нpс╗Нlс╗Нpс╗Н awс╗Нn ijс╗Нba ti ├мwс╗Н╠А o├▓r├╣n Sudan с╣гaaju ikonileru. Awс╗Нn yii ni ijс╗Нba Gobir ati Kebbi pс║╣lu kalifu olokiki agbaye ti olu-ilu ti с║╣mi ati ti iс╣гelu jс║╣ olu-ilu ipinlс║╣ naa.Lс║╣╠Бy├мn ├мс╣гс║╣╠Бgun kalifu l├бtс╗Нwс╗Н╠Б ├аwс╗Нn Gс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Бs├м lс╗Н╠Бd├║n 1903, or├нс╣гir├нс╣гi с║╣╠Аy├а ara rс║╣╠А ni wс╗Н╠Бn fi с╣гe ├аd├бс╣гe t├н wс╗Н╠Бn s├м darapс╗Н╠А mс╗Н╠Б ├мjс╗Нba ├Аr├нw├б N├а├мj├нr├н├а. с║╕k├╣n ├аr├нw├б tipa bс║╣╠Бс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б ap├б kan kalifu Sokoto ├аti ijoba Kanem-Bornu. Eyi tс║╣siwaju titi di Oс╣гu Kini с╗Нdun 1967 nigbati a с╣гс║╣da awс╗Нn ipinlс║╣ lati rс╗Нpo awс╗Нn ijс╗Нba agbegbe nipasс║╣ Ajagun Yakubu Gowon. Sokoto di olu-ilu ipinlс║╣ ├аr├нw├б ├мwс╗Н╠А o├▓r├╣n ti a с╣гс║╣da ni с╗Нdun 1967. Ni с╗Нdun 1976 lс║╣yin idasile ipinlс║╣ Niger kuro ni ipinlс║╣ ├аr├нw├б ├мwс╗Н╠А o├▓r├╣n, ipinlс║╣ Sokoto farahan pс║╣lu olu ile rс║╣. Sibс║╣sibс║╣ ni Sokoto, ipinle Kebbi ati Zamfara ni won yo kuro ni Sokoto, ni 1991 ati 1996 lс║╣sс║╣sс║╣.Ilu Sokoto ti jс║╣ olu-ilu fun с╗Нpс╗Нlс╗Нpс╗Н awс╗Нn ijс╗Нba lati igba idasile rс║╣ nipasс║╣ Kalifu Muhammad Bello ni с╗Нdun 1809.Ipinle Sokoto ni iye eniyan bii 3.7 milionu ti o da lori ikaniyan с╗Нdun 2006 ti с║╣ya meji ti o jс║╣ Fulani ati Hausa . Ilu Sokoto, olu ilu ipinle Sokoto, ni iye eniyan ti o to 2.5 milionu. Yatс╗Н si Fulani ati Hausa, eya kekere Zabarmawa ati Tuareg wa ni awс╗Нn aala ti ijс╗Нba ibilс║╣. Gbogbo awс╗Нn с║╣gbс║╣ wс╗Нnyi n sс╗Н Hausa gс║╣gс║╣bi ede ti o wс╗Нpс╗Н. Fulfulde ni awс╗Нn Fulani n sс╗Н.Awon Hausa ni ipinle naa je Gobirawa, Zamfarawa, Kabawa, Adarawa ati Arawa. Awс╗Нn Fulani ni apa keji jс║╣ ti awс╗Нn с║╣gbс║╣ pataki meji; ilu Fulani (Hausa: Fulanin Gida; Fula: Fulbe Wuro) ├аti awon awс╗Нn alarinkiri. Awс╗Нn akoko ni Torankawa, awс╗Нn idile ti Shehu Usmanu Danfodiyo, Sullubawa ati Zoramawa. Awon Torankawa jс║╣ kilasi aristocratic lati с╗Нdun 1804.Ni aс╣гa, ipinle na jс║╣ isokan. Awс╗Нn eniyan ti ipinle na jс║╣ Musulumi, ati pe с║╣sin Islam n fun wс╗Нn ni eto ti iwa ati ihuwasi. Ilana imura wс╗Нn tun jс║╣ ti orisun Islam. Awс╗Нn ayс║╣yс║╣ pataki meji ti o jс║╣, Eid-el-Fitri ati Eid-el-Kabir ni won ma n se ni ipinle na ni odoodun. Ayeye akoko duro fun opin awe Ramadan, nigba ti ikeji wa fun pipa ├аgbo ni iranti ise Anabi Ibrahim (Abraham).Ijakadi ibilс║╣ (Kokawa) ati ese (Dambe) ni ere idaraya meji ti Hausa n gbadun nigba ti Fulani ati Sullubawa ma n daraya pс║╣lu Sharo ati Doro lс║╣sс║╣sс║╣. Awс╗Нn alejo ti o с╣гe pataki si ipinlс║╣ naa ni won ma n pe si ibi ayeyedurbar nla tabi kekere, ayeye ti o wa fun iwode с║╣с╣гin ti a с╣гe lс╗Нс╣гс╗Н daradara ati awс╗Нn ibakasiс║╣ ti awс╗Нn с╗Нkunrin ti o wo aso ogun ibile ati aso asa maa n gun.O ju с╗Нgс╗Нrin ninu с╗Нgс╗Нrun (80%) awс╗Нn olugbe ilu Sokoto ti o n с╣гe iru iс╣гс║╣-ogbin kan tabi omiran. Wс╗Н╠Бn ┼Д pese ir├║gb├мn bii j├йr├│, okababa, ├аgb├аdo, ├мrс║╣s├м, anoman, ege, с║╣╠Аp├а, ├аti с║╣╠Аw├а f├║n o├║njс║╣, wс╗Н╠Бn s├м ┼Д pese ├аl├мk├бm├а, ├▓w├║, ├аti с║╣fс╗Н╠А j├бde f├║n ow├│. Iс╣гс║╣╠Б с╗Нn├а abс║╣╠Бlс║╣╠А b├нi al├бgbс║╣╠Аdс║╣, aso h├нhun, pipa aso laro, gb├нgbс║╣╠Б ona ├аti iс╣гс║╣╠Б ├бwс╗Н╠А t├║n k├│ ipa p├аt├аk├м n├нn├║ ├иt├▓ с╗Нrс╗Н╠А aj├й ├аwс╗Нn ar├б Sokoto; nitori eyi, awс╗Нn agbegbe oriс╣гiriс╣гi bii Makera, Marina, Takalmawa ati Majema di pataki. Sokoto tun jс║╣ с╗Нkan ninu awс╗Нn agbegbe ti o n pese с║╣ja ni orilс║╣-ede. Nitori naa, opolopo eniyan lс║╣ba agbada odo ma n peja pс║╣lu.Bakanna ni Sokoto ni awс╗Нn ohun elo adayeba ati erupс║╣. Awon ile ise ogbin ti o n lo owu, epa, oka, goomu, agbado, iresi, ireke, alikama, ege, goomu Arab ati taba bi awс╗Нn ohun elo ise ni won le dasilс║╣ ni agbegbe naa. Ogbin aladanla ni won tun le с╣гe ni ipinlс║╣ na nipa lilo omi irigeson lati Daamu Goronyo, Lugu, Kalmalo, Wammakko ati adagun Kwakwazo laarin awс╗Нn miiran.Awс╗Нn ohun alumс╗Нni bii kaolini, gipisum, okuta-efun, lateraiti, awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Н pupa, fosifeti mejeeji ofeefee ati alawс╗Н ewe, amс╗Н iboji, iyanrin ati bс║╣bс║╣ lс╗Н, wa ni awс╗Нn iwс╗Нn iс╣гowo. Awс╗Нn ile-iс╣гс║╣ ti o nlo awс╗Нn ohun elo ise wс╗Нnyi le ti fi idi mulс║╣ ni ipinlс║╣ naa.├А├мs├н esinsin tse-tse l├│r├н ilс║╣╠А p├бp├б oko t├н ├│ с╣г├н s├нlс║╣╠А n├н ├иr├и fun ├аwс╗Нn с║╣ranko igb├│ ├аti с║╣ran agb├йl├йjс║╣╠А. Sokoto wa ni ipo keji ni ipese с║╣ran-с╗Нsin ni iye с║╣ranko ti orilс║╣-ede ti o ju miliс╗Нnu mс║╣jс╗Н lс╗Н.Wiwa awс╗Нn agbara eto-aje wс╗Нnyi n pese awс╗Нn anfani idoko-owo to dara, ni pataki ni awс╗Нn ile-iс╣гс║╣ ogbin gс║╣gс║╣bi bii с╗Нlс╗Н iyс║╣fun, с╣гiс╣гe awс╗Нn tomati, isс╗Нdс╗Нtun suga, awс╗Нn aс╣гс╗Н, goomu, soradi, с║╣ja agolo, ati bс║╣bс║╣ lс╗Н.Sokoto ko ni eto irinna gbogbo eniyan. Gbigbe laarin ilu naa (nigbati kii с╣гe nipasс║╣ с║╣sс║╣) ni nipasс║╣ okada eyiti o с╣гiс╣гс║╣ bi takisi eniyan kan ati nigbamiran awс╗Нn kс║╣kс║╣ с║╣lс║╣sс║╣ mс║╣ta ma n gbe eniyan lati ibi kan si ekeji; eyi ngbanilaaye fun gbigbe eniyan diс║╣ sii ju с╗Нkan lс╗Н ni akoko kan (sibс║╣ ni idiyele olowo poku bi awс╗Нn okada). Awс╗Нn с╗Нkс╗Н akero ati awс╗Нn takisi kii с╣гe loorekoore ati pe wс╗Нn lo fun gbigbe laarin awс╗Нn ilu.Papa с╗Нkс╗Н ofurufu agbaye pс║╣lu asopс╗Н deede si Abuja, Kano ati Eko wa ni kilomita mewa guusu si Sokoto.Ni Oс╣гu Kс║╣jс╗Н с╗Нdun 2008, won se adehun fun kikс╗Н awс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣ simenti ni Sokoto.Didi ilu nla ni ├Мt├аn t├│ ti pс║╣╠Б gan-an n├н ilс║╣╠А Hausa. Eto naa bс║╣rс║╣ nigbati awс╗Нn agbegbe ilana kan ti ilс║╣ Hausa ni idagbasoke lati Kauyuka si Birane. Sibс║╣sibс║╣ с╗Нkan ninu awс╗Нn abajade pataki ti jihadi ni iyara ti iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ yii kii с╣гe ni ilс║╣ Hausa nikan с╣гugbс╗Нn ni gbogbo awс╗Нn agbegbe ti iс╣гakoso kalifu. Awс╗Нn ilu tuntun dide ati ilu Birane to ti pe wс╗Н inu akoko idagbasoke ti a ko ri tс║╣lс║╣, diс║╣ ninu won bi awс╗Нn agbegbe tuntun ti awс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣ iс╣гowo, awс╗Нn miiran bi awс╗Нn olu-ilu Emirati ati aarin gungun iс╣гakoso ati iс╣гowo.с╗Мkan ninu awс╗Нn с║╣ya olaju ninu itan kalifu Sokoto bс║╣rс║╣ pс║╣lu idasile ilu Sokoto (olu-ilu kalifu). Ki jihadi to sele, agbegbe laarin Ijс╗Нba Gobir ati Kebbi ni agbegbe ti a n pe ni тАЬilс║╣ awon arinkiriтАЭ. Sugbon pelu aseyori jihad ti Shehu Usmau dan Fodiyo (1804тАУ1808) dari ati isegun ti awon jihadi lori awon olori ile Hausa, ilu Sokoto (olori ile ijoba kalifu) ni Muhammad Bello ko. Pс║╣lupс║╣lu, gс║╣gс║╣bi Abdul-Razaq Shehu с╣гe akiyesi ninu iwe rс║╣ Sakkwato Birnin Shehu ), won ti ya aworan ilu Sokoto lori iwe nipasс║╣ Muhammad Bello paapaa с╣гaaju ki won to kс╗Н с╗Н. Bello, с╗Нmс╗Н Sheikh, wa ninu awс╗Нn ogagun baba rс║╣ ati awс╗Нn adari ogun. O ja ogun ti o lera julo ti o si gun julo, o si je ayaworan kalifu Sokoto Birnin Shehu.Ilu Sokoto gс║╣gс║╣ bi a ti ya aworan re nipasс║╣ ayaworan Muhammad Bello ni gbogbo awс╗Нn с║╣ya ara ti ilu ode oni pс║╣lu awс╗Нn с╗Нna, awс╗Нn afara, с╗Нja, ganuwa (awс╗Нn ibi agbara kaakiri ilu) ati pс║╣lu awс╗Нn ile-iс╣гс║╣ iс╣гakoso ati iс╣гowo. Lara awс╗Нn ile-iс╣гс║╣ iс╣гakoso ti Muhammad Bello с╣гe ni Kanwuri, Binanchi, Galadanci, Alkalanci, Dogarawa ati bс║╣bс║╣ lс╗Н. Sibesibe, yato si с╗Нja aarin ti a mс╗Н si Yardole, awс╗Нn agbegbe iс╣гowo miiran ti a с╣гe nipasс║╣ Muhammad Bello ni Makera, Madinka, Marina, Siriddawa, Takalmawa, Runji ati Jirgawa. Ni afikun, ninu awс╗Нn ohun miiran ko si ilu ni boya с╣гaaju jihadi tabi orundun kokandinlogun ile Hausa ti o le di ilu nla laisi odi ti o munadoko (ganuwa). Eyi ni a kс╗Н pс║╣lu с╗Нpс╗Нlс╗Нpс╗Н awс╗Нn ibi agbara bi Kofar Aliyu Jedo, Kofar Dundaye, Kofar Marke, Kofar Rini, Kofar Kware, ati Kofar Taramniya, ati pe idagbasoke pataki yii fa с╗Нpс╗Нlс╗Нpс╗Н eniyan lati lс╗Н kuro ni agbegbe wс╗Нn si ilu Sokoto fun iwalaaye.Lati akiyesi ti o wa loke lori bi kalifu Muhammad Bello с╣гe ya aworan ilu Sokoto, a o ri pe Sokoto jс║╣ri sii awс╗Нn aс╣гikiri ti o ni ifс║╣ si awс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣ alagbс║╣dс║╣, ise awo, ohun elo amс╗Н ati bс║╣bс║╣ lс╗Н. Fun apс║╣с║╣rс║╣, diс║╣ ninu awс╗Нn eniyan wс╗Нnyi с╣гe iс╣гowo ti alagbс║╣dс║╣ tabi ni iс╣гowo miiran ti o jс╗Нmс╗Н bi Makera Assada. Awon eniyan kan wa ti won maa n rin irin ajo lo si orisiirisii ilu Naijiria ati awon orile-ede to wa nitosi lati ra awon ohun elo irin to baje bii oko to yonu, oko ayokele, oko nla, oko ofurufu ati beebee, paipu irin, ati tanki epo ki won le tu won ka, ti won si n ta won fun с║╣nikс║╣ni ti o fс║╣ lati loo tabi yi wс╗Нn pada si с╗Нja miiran."},{"question":"рдореБрдЭреЗ рдЗрд╕ рд╢реНрд░реЗрдгреА рдореЗрдВ рдПрдХ рдкреНрд░рд╢реНрди рдФрд░ рдЙрддреНрддрд░ рджреАрдЬрд┐рдП: рднреВрдЧреЛрд▓","answer":"рдХреМрдирд╕реЗ рдХрд╛рдВрдЯреАрдиреЗрдВрдЯ рдореЗрдВ рд╢рд╣рд░ рдирд╣реАрдВ рд╣реИрдВ? рдЕрдВрдЯрд╛рд░реНрдЯрд┐рдХрд╛ "},{"question":"Mene ne Bayanau?","answer":"Bayanau kalmomi ne da ke yin ╞Щarin bayani game da aikatau. Wannan bayani da suke yi shi ya ke fito da aikin a fili. Sukan fa╔Чi gurin da aka yi aikin, lokacin da aka yi aiki ko kuma yadda aka yi, ake yi ko za a yi aiki."},{"question":"Dapс╗Н Abiс╗Нdun kilс╗Н fawс╗Нn to n da rogbodiyan silс║╣ ni Yewa","answer":"Latari rogbodiyan to mu с║╣mi lс╗Н to n waye lawс╗Нn a╠Аgbegbe Yewa, nipinlс║╣ Ogun, lasiko yii, Gomina Dapс╗Н Abiс╗Нdun ti kilс╗Н fawс╗Нn to wa nidii iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ naa. O ni ijс╗Нba oun ko ni i faaye gba palapala bс║╣с║╣. с║╕ni tс╗Нwс╗Н ba si ba nidii с║╣ yoo jс║╣ buruku iya.с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, с╗Нjс╗Н kс╗Нkanla, oс╣гu keji yii, ni gomina kilс╗Н bс║╣с║╣, ninu atс║╣jade kan lati с╗Нfiisi Akс╗Нwe iroyin с║╣, с╗Мgbс║╣ni Kunle с╣вomс╗Нrin.с╣вe lс╗Нjс╗Н naa ni iroyin jade pe awс╗Нn Fulani paayan ni Owode-Ketu, pe wс╗Нn tun daamu awс╗Нn eeyan Igan -Alade, Eegua ati Igbogila.Yatс╗Н si ikilс╗Н yii, ikс╗Н alaabo ti i с╣гe с╗Нlс╗Нpaa, fijilante, otelemuye atawс╗Нn с║╣с╣гс╗Н mi-in nijс╗Нba la╠Аwс╗Нn ti da sawс╗Нn agbegbe ti rogbodiyan ti n с╣гс║╣lс║╣, awс╗Нn agbegbe b├нi Ariwa Yewa, I╠Аmс║╣╠Аkс╗Н-Afс╗Нn ati Guusu Yewa.Wahala naa pс╗Н lawс╗Нn agbegbe yii to bс║╣с║╣ ti wс╗Нn ti ileewe ati с╗Нpс╗Нlс╗Нpс╗Н ibi pa. Eyi lo fa a ti Gomina fi ni ki iwadii bс║╣╠Аrс║╣╠А kia lori awс╗Нn to lс╗Нwс╗Н si ikс╗Нlu to mu с║╣mi lс╗Н naa, wс╗Нn ni ijс╗Нba yoo gbe с║╣ni tс╗Нwс╗Н ba tс║╣ pe o lс╗Н╠Бwс╗Н╠Б si wahala naa lс╗Н si kootu k├н├б ni.тАЬGbogbo ohun to ba gba la maa fun un lati mu alaafia duro nipinlс║╣ Ogun, koda bo gba ifiyajс║╣ni gidi, a o ni i woju с║╣nikс║╣ni ka too lo o lati mu ifс╗Нkanbalс║╣ wa nipinlс║╣ yiiтАЭBс║╣с║╣ ni apa kan atс║╣jade naa wi."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fambara ho an'ny malagasy?","answer":"Ny fambara izay dia zava-mitranga tsapan' ny olona (hita maso na ren' ny sofina sns) ka manampy azy hahalala mialoha ny zavatra hitranga amin' ny hoavy akaiky na lavitra. Mety ho zava-tsoa no hitranga nefa matetika dia zava-dratsy no ahenoana ny teny hoe fambara, toy ny hoe fambara loza. Tsy voatery ho ny razana ihany no mandefa fambara fa mety ho i Zanahary na ny fanahy hafa rehetra."},{"question":"E-imza en kolay nereden al─▒n─▒r?","answer":"e-─░mza Ba┼Яvuru ─░┼Яlemlerie-─░mza i┼Яlemlerinizi ger├зekle┼Яtirebilmek i├зin size en yak─▒n PTT M├╝d├╝rl├╝─Я├╝m├╝ze https://pttkep.gov.tr/basvuru-merkezleri-2/ adresinden тАЬMerkezтАЭleri filtreleyerek ula┼Яabilirsiniz."},{"question":"╨н╤В╨╜╨╛╨╜╨╕╨╝╨╕╨║╨░ ╨▒╤Г╨╗тАж","answer":"╨н╤В╨╜╨╛╨╜╨╕╨╝╨╕╨║╨░ (╤Н╤В╨╜╨╛╨╜╨╕╨╝╨╕╤П) тАУ ╤Н╤В╨╜╨╕╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╨║ ╨│╨╗╨╛╨▒╨░╨╗╨╕╨╖╨░╤Ж╨╕╤П ╨╢╨╡ ╤З╨░╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Н╨╗╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜, ╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г╨╗╨░╤А╨┤╤Л╨╜, ╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г╨╗╤Г╨║ ╤В╨╛╨┐╤В╨╛╤А╨┤╤Г╨╜ ╤З╨╛╥г ╤Н╨╗╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╜ ╨░╤А╨░╤Б╤Л╨╜╨░ ╤Б╨╕╥г╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨╡╤В╥п╥п ╨║╨╛╤А╨║╤Г╨╜╤Г╤З╤Г, ╨║╨╛╨╛╨┐╤В╨╛╨╜╤Г╤Г ╨╢╨░╤А╨░╤В╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║╤В╨░╨╜, ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╤В╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨║╨║╨░ ╤В╨░╤А╤Л╤Е╤З╤Л╨╗╨░╤А ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨║╨╛╨╗╨╛╨│╨┤╨╛╤А ╨║╤Л╨╖╤Л╨│╤Г╤Г╨┤╨░."},{"question":"╪г╪м╪и ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К : ┘Е╪з┘З┘К ╪▒╪з╪ж╪п╪з╪й ╪з┘Д╪┤╪▒┘Г╪й ╪з┘Д╪г┘И╪▒┘И╪и┘К╪й ┘Д┘Д╪╡┘Ж╪з╪╣╪з╪к ╪з┘Д╪м┘И┘К╪й ┘Б┘К ╪╣╪з┘Е 2009 ╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н┘К╪н╪й ┘З┘К ╪е┘К╪▒╪и╪з╪╡."},{"question":"Tс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б Tedela","answer":"Temitope Christopher Tedela t├н gbogbo ├иn├мy├аn mс╗Н╠А s├н Tс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б Tedela jс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├й or├н-├мt├аg├й ├аti ol├╣gb├йr├й-j├бde с╗Нmс╗Н or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а.Wс╗Н╠Бn b├н Tс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б gс║╣╠Бgс║╣╠Б b├н ├аkс╗Н╠Бb├н ├аwс╗Нn ├▓b├н rс║╣╠А s├н ├мl├║ ├Иk├│. ├Аwс╗Нn ├▓b├н rс║╣╠А jс║╣╠Б с╗Нmс╗Н b├нb├н ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├мt├м. ├У lс╗Н s├н il├й с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б girama ti Model College, t├н ├│ w├а n├н ├мl├║ Mс║╣ran n├н ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├│. ├У kс║╣╠Бkс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Б gboy├и akс╗Н╠Бkс╗Н╠Б n├нn├║ ├мmс╗Н╠А Mass Communication n├н il├й-с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б f├бsit├м ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А ├Иk├│.├У ti gba с╗Н╠Аpс╗Н╠А am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ f├║n ├аeс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣╠Б takun takun t├н ├│ ┼Д gb├й с╣гe n├н in├║ agbo ├аwс╗Нn ├▓с╣г├иr├й Nollyeood. L├бra awс╗Нn am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ y├н ni: Africa Magic Viewers Choice Award, Nigeria Entertainment Award, Best of Nollywood Award ├аti Nollywood Movies Award. Wс╗Н╠Бn i wo ├аwс╗Нn er├й с╗Нlс╗Н╠Бkan-├▓-jс╗Нkan t├н Tades ti gb├й j├бde n├н ├аwс╗Нn sinim├б k├б├аkiri n├н ilс║╣╠А Ad├║l├бwс╗Н╠А ati n├н ├▓k├и ├▓kun b├нi Cannes Film Festival, Toronto International Film Festival ├аti BFI London Film Festival. L├бra ├аwс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣╠Б rс║╣╠А t├н ├│ ti gb├й j├бde ni: The Lost Okoroshi (2019), What Lies Within (2017), Slow Country (2017), Ojukokoro (2017), Suru L'ere (2016), Out of Luck (2015), A Soldier's Story (2015) ├аti A Mile from Home t├н ├│ jс║╣╠Б er├й t├н ├│ ti fi gba am├м-с║╣╠Аyс║╣ or├нс╣гir├нс╣гi.N├нgb├а t├н ├│ kс║╣╠Бkс╗Н╠Б n├нl├й с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б f├бsit├м lс╗Н╠Бwс╗Н╠Б, Tс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б k├│pa l├а├аm├м-laaka n├нn├║ er├й ├аt├мgb├а-d├йgb├а on├нpele t├н ├аkс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А ┼Д jс║╣╠Б Edge of Paradise. ├У j├бwс╗Н╠Б n├нn├║ ├мk├│pa n├нn├║ er├й f├║ngb├а d├нс║╣╠А l├бti l├и foj├║ s├нnс║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б rс║╣╠А , lс║╣╠Бy├мn t├н ├│ s├м k├аw├й j├б, ├│ с╣гiс╣гс║╣╠Б f├║gb├а d├нс║╣╠А n├н il├й iс╣гс║╣╠Б r├йd├н├▓ ti UNILAG FM. Tс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б f├мgb├а kan r├н с╣гe ol├│├▓t├║ ├иt├▓ l├│r├н ├мkan├м NTA. ├У ti k├│pa n├нn├║ ├аwс╗Нn er├й or├нс╣гir├нс╣гi. ├У k├│pa n├нn├║ er├й, A Mile from Home. N├н с╗Нd├║n 2015, Tс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б t├║n k├│pa n├нn├║ er├й A Soldier's Story ├аti er├й Out of Luck. Ipa rс║╣╠А t├н ├│ k├│ n├нn├║ er├й Suru Le're n├н с╗Нd├║n 2016, gс║╣╠Бgс║╣╠Б с║╣╠Аd├б ├мt├аn Kyle Steven-Adedoyin jс║╣╠Б k├н awс╗Нn ├иn├мy├аn ├│ fс║╣╠Б l├бti m├бa wo er├й t├н ├│ b├б ti k├│pa. Tс╗Н╠Бp├и k├│pa n├нn├║ er├й apanilс║╣╠Бr├нn kan t├н wс╗Н╠Бn p├и Oj├║k├▓k├▓r├▓ ├аti Slow Country n├н с╗Нd├║n 2017. ├У t├║n di gbaj├║-gbaj├а ol├╣gb├йr├й-j├бde pс║╣╠Аl├║ er├й t├мrс║╣ ty ├│ gb├й j├бde t├н ├│ pe ├аkс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А n├н What Lies Within. N├н с╗Нd├║n 2018, k├│pa n├нn├║ er├й с╗Н╠Аdar├аn kan t├н akс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А ┼Д jс║╣╠Б Knock Out Blessing. ├У t├║ k├│pa b├н с║╣╠Аd├б-├мt├аn Dr. Dauda n├нn├║ er├й The Lost of Okoroshi He alEall-shades-of-amazing-in-whumanizer-toni-kan/</ref> Tedela t├║n k├│pa n├нn├║ er├й t├н ├аkс╗Н╠Бl├й rс║╣╠А ┼Д jс║╣╠Б The Ghost and the House of Truth.N├н с╗Нd├║n 2016, wс╗Н╠Бn fi Tс╗Н╠Бpс║╣╠Б Tedela с╣гe aс╣гoj├║ f├║n il├й-iс╣гс║╣╠Б Global Rights, il├й-iс╣гс║╣╠Б t├н ├│ ┼Д r├н s├н с║╣╠Аtс╗Н╠Б с╗Нmс╗Нn├мy├аn l├бti l├и jс║╣╠Б k├н ├│ l├и с╣гe ├мpolongo tako ├мw├а ├мfip├бb├бnol├▓pс╗Н╠А awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н ob├мnrin n├н or├нlс║╣╠А-├иd├и N├а├мj├нr├н├а."},{"question":"рднрд╛рд░рддреАрдп рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддреАрдЪреЗ рдЧрд╛рдвреЗ рдЕрднреНрдпрд╛рд╕рдХ рдЬрд░реНрдорди рдкрдВрдбрд┐рдд рдХреЛрдг рд╣реЛрддреЗ ?","answer":"рднрд╛рд░рддреАрдп рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддреАрдЪреЗ рдЧрд╛рдвреЗ рдЕрднреНрдпрд╛рд╕рдХ рдЬрд░реНрдорди рдкрдВрдбрд┐рдд рдореЕрдХреНрд╕ рдореБрд▓рд░ рд╣реЛрддреЗ."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ╪╣╪з╪╡┘Е╪й ╪▒┘И╪│┘К╪з ╪Я","answer":"┘Е┘И╪│┘Г┘И"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛ : роЙроЯро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░родрпНродроорпН рокро╛ропро╛род рокроХрпБродро┐ роОродрпБ ?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ : роХро░рпБро╡ро┐ро┤ро┐,"},{"question":"╨Р╨╜╤В╨╛╨╜╨╕╨╝╨┤╨╡╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡?","answer":"╨С╨╕╤А╨╕-╨▒╨╕╤А╨╕╨╜╨╡ ╨║╨░╤А╨░╨╝╨░-╨║╨░╤А╤И╤Л ╨╝╨░╨░╨╜╨╕╨┤╨╡╨│╨╕ ╤Б╙й╨╖╨┤╙й╤А╨┤╥п ╨░╨╜╤В╨╛╨╜╨╕╨╝╨┤╨╡╤А╨┤╨╡╨╣╨▒╨╕╨╖.╨Ь ╨╕ ╤Б ╨░ ╨╗ ╤Л: ╨╢╨░╨║╤И╤Л тАУ ╨╢╨░╨╝╨░╨╜, ╤З╨╛╥г тАУ ╨║╨╕╤З╨╕╨╜╨╡, ╨╛╨╛╤А тАУ ╨╢╨╡╥г╨╕╨╗"},{"question":"V─Гn bс║гn thuс║нt lс║бi mс╗Щt sс╗▒ kiс╗Зn theo mс╗Сi quan hс╗З nguy├кn nh├вn тАУ kс║┐t quс║г th╞░с╗Эng bao gс╗Уm nhс╗пng phс║зn n├аo?","answer":"V─Гn bс║гn thuс║нt lс║бi mс╗Щt sс╗▒ kiс╗Зn theo mс╗Сi quan hс╗З nguy├кn nh├вn тАУ kс║┐t quс║г th╞░с╗Эng bao gс╗Уm ba th├┤ng tin ch├нnh: nguy├кn nh├вn тАУ diс╗Еn biс║┐n тАУ kс║┐t quс║г, nhс║▒m trс║г lс╗Эi ba c├вu hс╗Пi lс╗Ыn: V├м sao lс║бi xс║гy ra sс╗▒ viс╗Зc с║еy?, Sс╗▒ viс╗Зc с║еy diс╗Еn ra thс║┐ n├аo?, Kс║┐t quс║г ra sao?."},{"question":"Oraci├│n 1: Oaklyn est├б ubicada en el 1er distrito electoral y es parte del 6to distrito legislativo estatal de Nueva Jersey.Oraci├│n 2: Oaklyn se ubica en el 6to Distrito del Congreso y forma parte del 1er Distrito Legislativo de Nueva Jersey.Pregunta : ┬┐la oraci├│n 1 parafrasea la oraci├│n 2?. ","answer":"No, expresan lo mismo. "},{"question":"рждржерзНржп ржкрзНрж░ржпрзБржХрзНрждрж┐ржирж┐рж░рзНржнрж░ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржЗ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржЧрзНрж░рж╛ржотАФ ржоржирзНрждржмрзНржпржЯрж┐ ржмрзНржпрж╛ржЦрзНржпрж╛ ржХрж░ред","answer":"рждржерзНржп ржкрзНрж░ржпрзБржХрзНрждрж┐ржЗ ржкрзНрж░ржХрзГрждржкржХрзНрж╖рзЗ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржЧрзНрж░рж╛ржорзЗрж░ ржзрж╛рж░ржгрж╛рж░ ржорзВрж▓ ржнрж┐рждрзНрждрж┐ред ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржЧрзНрж░рж╛ржо ржПржоржи ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржкрж░рж┐ржмрзЗрж╢, ржпрзЗржЦрж╛ржирзЗ ржкрзГржерж┐ржмрзАрж░ рж╕ржХрж▓ ржорж╛ржирзБрж╖ ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржПржХржХ рж╕ржорж╛ржЬрзЗрж░ ржирзНржпрж╛ржпрж╝ ржмрж╕ржмрж╛рж╕ ржХрж░рзЗ ржПржмржВ ржЗрж▓рзЗржХржЯрзНрж░ржирж┐ржХ ржорж┐ржбрж┐ржпрж╝рж╛ ржУ рждржерзНржп ржкрзНрж░ржпрзБржХрзНрждрж┐ ржмрзНржпржмрж╣рж╛рж░рзЗрж░ ржорж╛ржзрзНржпржорзЗ ржПржХрзЗ ржЕржкрж░ржХрзЗ рж╕рзЗржмрж╛ ржкрзНрж░ржжрж╛ржи ржХрж░рзЗред рждржерзНржп ржУ ржпрзЛржЧрж╛ржпрзЛржЧ ржкрзНрж░ржпрзБржХрзНрждрж┐рж░ ржмрж┐рж╕рзНрждрзГржд ржмрзНржпржмрж╣рж╛рж░ рждржерж╛ рждржерзНржп ржЖржжрж╛ржи-ржкрзНрж░ржжрж╛ржирзЗрж░ ржЬржирзНржп ржЗржиржлрж░ржорзЗрж╢ржи рж╕рзБржкрж╛рж░ рж╣рж╛ржЗржУржпрж╝рзЗрж░ рж╕рж╛ржерзЗ рж╕ржВржпрзЛржЧ ржЫрж╛ржбрж╝рж╛ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржЧрзНрж░рж╛ржорзЗрж░ ржзрж╛рж░ржгрж╛ ржЕрж╕ржорзНржнржмред рждржерзНржп ржкрзНрж░ржпрзБржХрзНрждрж┐рж░ ржмрж┐рж╕рзНржоржпрж╝ржХрж░ ржЙрзОржХрж░рзНрж╖рждрж╛рж░ ржХрж╛рж░ржгрзЗ рж╕ржоржЧрзНрж░ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржм ржПржХ ржмрж┐ржирж┐рж╕рзБрждрж╛рж░ ржмрж╛ржБржзржирзЗ ржкрж░рж╕рзНржкрж░рзЗрж░ ржерзЗржХрзЗ ржнрзМржЧрзЛрж▓рж┐ржХржнрж╛ржмрзЗ ржжрзВрж░рзЗ ржерзЗржХрзЗржУ ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржПржХржХ рж╕ржорж╛ржЬрзЗрж░ ржмрж╛рж╕рж┐ржирзНржжрж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗ ржУржарж╛ржЗ ржкрзНрж░ржорж╛ржг ржХрж░рзЗ рждржерзНржп ржкрзНрж░ржпрзБржХрзНрждрж┐ржЗ ржкрзНрж░ржХрзГрждржкржХрзНрж╖рзЗ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмржЧрзНрж░рж╛ржорзЗрж░ ржзрж╛рж░ржгрж╛рж░ ржорзВрж▓ ржнрж┐рждрзНрждрж┐ред"},{"question":"рд░рд╛рд╕рд╛рдпрдирд┐рдХ рдИрдиреНрдЬрд┐рдирд┐рдпрд░рд┐рдЩреН рдорд╛ рд░рд┐рдПрдХреНрдЯрд░ рдХреЛ рднреВрдорд┐рдХрд╛ рдЪрд░реНрдЪрд╛ рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реНред","answer":"рд░рд╛рд╕рд╛рдпрдирд┐рдХ рдИрдиреНрдЬрд┐рдирд┐рдпрд░рд┐рдЩреНрдорд╛ рд░рд┐рдПрдХреНрдЯрд░рд╣рд░реВ рдкреЛрддрд╣рд░реВ рд╣реБрдиреН рдЬрд╣рд╛рдБ рд░рд╛рд╕рд╛рдпрдирд┐рдХ рдкреНрд░рддрд┐рдХреНрд░рд┐рдпрд╛рд╣рд░реВ рд╣реБрдиреНрдЫрдиреНред рддрд┐рдиреАрд╣рд░реВ рдХрдЪреНрдЪрд╛ рдорд╛рд▓рд▓рд╛рдИ рдЗрдЪреНрдЫрд┐рдд рдЙрддреНрдкрд╛рджрдирд╣рд░реВрдорд╛ рдХреБрд╢рд▓рддрд╛рдкреВрд░реНрд╡рдХ рд░реВрдкрд╛рдиреНрддрд░рдг рдЧрд░реНрди рдорд╣рддреНрддреНрд╡рдкреВрд░реНрдг рдЫрдиреНред рд░рд┐рдПрдХреНрдЯрд░рдХреЛ рдбрд┐рдЬрд╛рдЗрди рд░ рдкреНрд░рдХрд╛рд░, рдЬрд╕реНрддреИ рдмреНрдпрд╛рдЪ рд╡рд╛ рдирд┐рд░рдиреНрддрд░ рдкреНрд░рд╡рд╛рд╣, рд╡рд┐рд╢рд┐рд╖реНрдЯ рдкреНрд░рддрд┐рдХреНрд░рд┐рдпрд╛ рдЧрддрд┐рд╡рд┐рдЬреНрдЮрд╛рди рд░ рдкреНрд░рдХреНрд░рд┐рдпрд╛ рдЖрд╡рд╢реНрдпрдХрддрд╛рд╣рд░реВрдорд╛ рдирд┐рд░реНрднрд░ рдЧрд░реНрджрдЫред"},{"question":"Lista ug lima ka tawo na mao pinaka daghan ug silver medals sa Olympics.","answer":"Kini ang lima ka tawo na naay pinaka daghan silver medals sa Olympics:1. Larisa Latynina - 5 medals2. Nikolai Andrianov - 5 medals3. Edoardo Mangiarotti - 5 medals4. Ireen Wust - 5 medals5. Isabell Werth - 5 medals"},{"question":"Fan mooy g├лblag r├йewum Afghanistan ?","answer":"G├лblag r├йewum Afghanistan mu ngi tuddu Kaboul."},{"question":"Omeo ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny teny hoe \\"Faly\\".","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny hoe faly dia :  Ravo."},{"question":"роороЯрпНроЯрпИрокрпН рокроирпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рогрпНроЯрпБ роорпБро▒рпИ 20/20 роЙро▓роХ роХрпЛрокрпНрокрпИропрпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒ роорпБродро▓рпН роЕрогро┐ роОродрпБ?","answer":"роЗро░рпБроорпБро▒рпИ роЯро┐20 роЙро▓роХроХрпН роХрпЛрокрпНрокрпИропрпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒ роорпБродро▓рпН роЕрогро┐ роОройрпНро▒ рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпИ ро╡рпЖро╕рпНроЯрпН роЗрогрпНроЯрпАро╕рпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒родрпБ. роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН 2016 роЯро┐20 роЙро▓роХроХрпН роХрпЛрокрпНрокрпИропрпИ роХро░рпАрокро┐ропройрпН роЕрогро┐ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒родрпБ. роЕро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЗроЩрпНроХро┐ро▓ро╛роирпНродрпИ родрпЛро▒рпНроХроЯро┐родрпНродройро░рпН."},{"question":"Awс╗Нn agbebс╗Нn ji alakooso kansu lтАЩEkiti","answer":"Awс╗Нn agbebс╗Нn ti ji alakooso fun eto с╗Нgbin nijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ Iwс╗Н-Oorun Ekiti, Ebenezer Busuyi, lс║╣yin с╗Нsс║╣ kan ti wс╗Нn ji с╗Мbadu tilu Ilс║╣mс║╣с╣гс╗Н, с╗Мba David Oyewumi.Lalс║╣ с╗Мjс╗Нbс╗Н, Tс╗Нsidee, niс╣гс║╣lс║╣ naa waye loju с╗Нna Ilawс║╣-Ekiti si с║╕rijiyan-Ekiti, lasiko ti с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu All Progresives Congress (APC) naa n lс╗Н pс║╣lu mс╗Нto с║╣.A gbс╗Н pe lс║╣yin ti wс╗Нn ji i gbe tan lawс╗Нn eeyan too mс╗Н nigba ti wс╗Нn deede ri mс╗Нto с║╣ lс║╣gbс║╣с║╣ titi, to si han gbangba pe wс╗Нn ti wс╗Н с╗Н wс╗Н inu igbo.Nigba to n fidi iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ naa mulс║╣, Alukoro с╗Нlс╗Нpaa Ekiti, ASP Sunday Abutu, sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa Rapid Response Squad, ikс╗Н Amс╗Нtс║╣kun, atawс╗Нn с╗Нdс║╣ ti n с╣гiс╣гс║╣ takuntakun ninu gbogbo igbo to wa lagbegbe naa.O ni aago mс║╣fa irс╗Нle niс╣гс║╣lс║╣ naa waye, ko si sс║╣ni to mс╗Н ibi ti wс╗Нn gbe oloс╣гelu naa lс╗Н.O waa ni ileeс╣гс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ko ni i gba kawс╗Нn ajinigbe sс╗Н Ekiti di ibugbe wс╗Нn, bс║╣с║╣ lo gba awс╗Нn eeyan niyanju lati maa с╣гс╗Нra ni gbogbo igba."},{"question":"Zer da teknologia 5G, eta nola eragiten du komunikazioen abiadura?","answer":"Teknologia 5G da hainbat komunikazio teknologia konbinatzen dituen sare berria. Komunikazioen abiadura eragiteko, 5G teknologiak erakusten du nola datuak abiadura handiagoz bidali daitezkeen, latentzia gutxituz."},{"question":"Bada misalin Maha╔Чi mai Ha╔Чe ibara da Ibara.","answer":"1. Gidan Bala da gidan Sani2. Naman akuya ko naman Saniya.3. Hawa mota ko hawa Jaki. "},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Gny nahalava moko gn'akanga .....................  \\" ","answer":"\\"  Gny nahalava moko gn'akanga dra gny mitao \\" "},{"question":"р╢ар╖Тр╢Вр╢ар╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╖Ф р╖Др╖Э  р╢╕р╖Тр╢Вр╢ар╖Кр╢Ър╢╗р╖Ф р╢║р╖Рр╢║р╖Т р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П  р╖Др╖Э  р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Ъ р╢п ? р╢Ср╢║ р╢╗р╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢нр╢╕р╖П  р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖П  р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ. р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢Ер╢пр╖Др╖Г р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╢п ?","answer":"р╖Ар╢╗р╖Пр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢Жр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╖А р╖Др╖Э р╢┤р╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒ р╢║р╖Пр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖П  р╢Жр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Др╖Э  р╢Ьр╖Ьр╢й р╢╢р╖Тр╢╕р╖К р╢Жр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╖А р╢╢р╢йр╖Фр╢╢р╖Пр╖Др╖Тр╢╗р╖Пр╢пр╖Тр╢║ р╢╢р╖Ср╢╕ р╢┤р╖Рр╢зр╖Ар╖Ур╢╕ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П  р╢║р╖Ьр╢пр╖Пр╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П  р╢пр╖Ьр╢╣р╢Ър╢╗ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╢║р╖Ъ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П  р╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢ар╖Тр╢Ър╢╗р╖Ф(Winchman,winch operator )р╢Ср╢║ р╖Ар╖Шр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╢Ър╖Т.р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╢пр╖Фр╢╕р╖Кр╢╗р╖Тр╢║ р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╖Ар╢╜ р╢Ер╢пр╢нр╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ."},{"question":"Kan moy njiitou reew u Gambi?","answer":"Adama Barrow "},{"question":"Yan r├йew ├▒ooy l├аkk wolof ?!","answer":"Senegaal , M├│ritani ak G├аmbi."},{"question":"р░Хр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░П р░Ер░░р▒Нр░ер░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░╕р▒Вр░Ър░┐р░Вр░Ър▒З р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Л р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.р░жр░пр░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░╕р▒Жр░▓р░╡р▒Б р░Зр░╡р▒Нр░╡р░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░ир░╛р░жр▒Нр░пр░░р▒Нр░ер░Х р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░В."},{"question":"Inona ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mahatakatra\\"?","answer":"Ny teny mitovy hevitra amin'ny \\"Mahatakatra\\" dia \\"Mahatratra\\"."},{"question":"╪з┘К╪┤ ┘Е╪╣┘Ж┘Й ╪з┘Д╪м┘Е┘Д╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К╪й \\"╪┤╪║┘Е ╪┤╪║┘Е┘З ┘В╪з╪к\\" ╪и╪з┘Д┘Б╪╡╪н┘Й.","answer":"┘К╪┤╪║┘Е: ┘К╪з╪о╪░ ┘Е┘Д╪ж ┘Г┘Б┘К┘З ┘Е┘Ж ╪┤┘К╪б ┘Е╪з . ┘Е╪л╪з┘Д (╪┤╪║┘Е ╪┤╪║┘Е┘З ┘В╪з╪к) ╪з╪о╪░ ┘Е┘Д╪ж ┘К╪п┘З ┘В╪з╪к╪з."},{"question":"р░И р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░╢р▒Нр░ир░▓р░Хр▒Б р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.р░Тр░Хр░╡р▒Зр░│ р░ор▒А р░╢р░░р▒Ар░░р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Ор░ор▒Бр░Хр░▓р▒Б, р░Хр▒Ар░│р▒Нр░│р▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░ир░Яр▒Нр░▓р░пр░┐р░др▒З р░Пр░ор░┐ р░Ьр░░р▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр▒Л р░Кр░╣р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░ор░и р░╢р░░р▒Ар░░р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Ор░ор▒Бр░Хр░▓р▒Б, р░Хр▒Ар░│р▒Нр░│р▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░Хр░кр▒Лр░др▒Зр░ор░и р░╢р░░р▒Ар░░р░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░пр▒Зр░Хр░ор▒Ир░и р░Жр░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░Йр░Вр░бр░жр▒Б.р░Хр░жр░▓р░┐р░Хр░▓р▒Б р░ор░░р░┐р░пр▒Б р░Ър░▓р░ир░ор▒Б р░╕р░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░Вр░Хр░╛р░жр▒Б.р░Тр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░ор░╛р░Яр░▓р▒Л р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░╛р░▓р░Вр░Яр▒З р░ор░ир░В р░Жр░Хр░╛р░░р░В р░▓р▒Зр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░Чр▒Бр░Вр░бр▒Нр░░р░ир░┐ р░мр░Вр░др░┐р░▓р░╛ р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░ор▒Б."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mandi darah'? Berikan satu contoh ayat.","answer":"Ia bermaksud berlumuran darah. Contoh ayat: Perajurit itu mandi darah kerana cedera terkena tembakan musuh."},{"question":"уВ╕уГгуГЛуГ╝уВ║ф║ЛхЛЩцЙАуБоуВ┐уГмуГ│уГИуБзуАБуВнуГауВ┐уВпуБиуБДуБИуБ░цЬицЭСцЛУхУЙуБзуБЩуБМуАБуГЮуГДуВ╕уГеуГ│уБиуБДуБИуБ░х╡РуБлцЙАх▒ЮуБЩуВЛшк░уБоуБУуБиуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"цЭ╛цЬмц╜дуБзуБЩуАВ"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Б╪з╪ж╪▓ ┘Б┘К ╪и╪╖┘И┘Д╪й ╪▒┘И┘Д╪з┘Ж ╪║╪з╪▒┘И╪│ ┘Д╪╣╪з┘Е ┘в┘а┘а┘з ┘Д┘Д╪▒╪м╪з┘Д╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ┘Б╪з╪▓ ╪▒╪з┘Б╪з┘К┘К┘Д ┘Ж╪з╪п╪з┘Д ╪г┘Е╪з┘Е ╪▒┘И╪м╪▒ ┘Б┘К╪п╪▒┘К╪▒ "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai berseru di padang pasir\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud seruan yang tidak diendahkan orang"},{"question":"р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╢╗р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒. ","answer":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢░р╖Пр╢▒ р╢╗р╖Пр╢вр╖КтАНр╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ср╢╗р╢з р╢╢р╖Др╖Фр╢нр╢╗ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ър╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Ар╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢Ер╢п р╖Ар╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢╕р╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢▒ 20 р╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╖Гр╖Д р╢╕р╖Тр╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢▒ 3р╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╢▒ р╢вр╢▒р╢Ьр╖Др╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╢Ър╢╗р╢нр╖Т. р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜тАН р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢║р╖Фр╢╗р╖Эр╢┤р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢╜ р╢Лр╢┤ р╢Ьр╢лр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢Жр╢╗р╖Кр╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢Ьр╢лр╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢║р╖Тр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜ р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╢║р╖Тр╢▒ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╢р╖Гр╢з р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢з р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖Т.р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Пр╢Ьр╖К р╢Ур╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢║р╖Фр╢Ьр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╢зр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢нр╖Т р╖Др╖Щр╖Ер╢╢р╖Г р╢Ир╢н р╢Ер╢нр╖Ур╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Др╖П р╢║р╢зр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢вр╖Тр╢н р╖Гр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╢╢р╢зр╖Др╖Тр╢╗ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Гр╢╕р╢Ь р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╖Тр╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢лр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Цр╢нр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢╢р╖Тр╖Др╖Т р╖Ар╖У р╢Зр╢н.р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╕р╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╢╕ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢Жр╢╗р╖Кр╢║ (р╢Ср╖Ер╖Ф) \\"р╖Гр╖Тр╖Др╢╜\\" р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╢╗р╖Цр╢┤ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢н р╢┤р╢пр╢║ р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢╕р╖Щр╢║ \\"р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Д\\" р╢║р╢▒ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢н р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Кр╢┤р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Ъ. \\"р╢╖р╢Ьр╖Ар╢н р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Пр╢лр╢║р╖Щ\\" р╖Др╖Т р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜р╢║, р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢н р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕р╢║ р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢╗ р╢Зр╢н. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢▒р╢╕ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╖Ар╢╜р╢пр╖У \\"р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║\\" р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╢п р╢Ер╢╗р╖Кр╢о р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖П р╢Зр╢н. р╢╕р╖Щр╢║ р╢Ер╢нр╖Ур╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Др╖Фр╢╜ р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╢Зр╢нр╖Рр╢║р╖Т р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╢║ р╢╕р╢н р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╢Ър╖К р╢║р╖Рр╢║р╖Т р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╖Гр╖Ъ.р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А р╢Лр╢┤ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢╢р╖Щр╢пр╖Ур╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Пр╢╜ р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╕р╖Рр╢н. р╢▒р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╖Ур╢║ р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╢╜р╖Пр╖Бр╢║ р╖Др╖П р╢Жр╖Ар╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╖Ц р╖Ар╢ар╢▒ р╖Др╖П р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╢╜ р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║. р╢╗р╢вр╢╗р╢з (р╢Лр╢нр╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Рр╢п р╢┤р╖Ер╖Пр╢н), р╢╗р╖Фр╖Др╖Фр╢л (р╢пр╢Ър╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢┤р╖Ер╖Пр╢н), р╢Мр╖А (р╢Мр╖А р╢┤р╖Ер╖Пр╢н) р╢╕р╖Щр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╢пр╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢┤р╖Ер╖Пр╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢┤р╢║р╢Ър╖Т. р╢▒р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Ър╖Вр╖Тр╢н р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╖Др╖П р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╢╜р╖Пр╖Б р╢Ер╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖Фр╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢┤р╖Др╖Гр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢нр╖Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢╕р╖Кр╢Ьр╢н р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ."},{"question":"рдЕрдиреНрдирдкреВрд░реНрдг рдХреНрд╖реЗрддреНрд░рдХреЛ рд╡рд╛рддрд╛рд╡рд░рдг рд░ рд╕рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐рдорд╛ рдкрд░реНрдпрдЯрдирд▓реЗ рдкрд╛рд░реЗрдХреЛ рдкреНрд░рднрд╛рд╡рдХреЛ рдЪрд░реНрдЪрд╛ рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реНред","answer":"рдЕрдиреНрдирдкреВрд░реНрдг рдХреНрд╖реЗрддреНрд░рдорд╛ рдкрд░реНрдпрдЯрдирд▓реЗ рдЖрд░реНрдерд┐рдХ рдЕрд╡рд╕рд░рд╣рд░реВ рд▓реНрдпрд╛рдПрдХреЛ рдЫ рддрд░ рджрд┐рдЧреЛ рд╡реНрдпрд╡рд╕реНрдерд╛рдкрди рдЖрд╡рд╢реНрдпрдХ рд╡рд╛рддрд╛рд╡рд░рдгреАрдп рд░ рд╕рд╛рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐рдХ рдЪреБрдиреМрддреАрд╣рд░реВ рдкрдирд┐ рдЫрдиреНред"},{"question":"Cabdi raxmaan daakhil .","answer":"9) Cabdi raxmaan Bin Mucaawiya Bin Haashim Bin Cabdi malik ( Cabdi raxmaan daakhil ), wuxuu ka mid ahaa dadkii reer Banii ummaya ee ka haray xasuuqii ay u gaysteen cabbaasiyiintu markay xukunka kala wareegeen Banii ummaya, cabdi raxmaan daakhil wuxuu usoo cararay  magaalada Qayrawaan ee ka tirsan wadanka Tuunis, markuu imaanayay magaalada Qayrawaan wuxuu jirey 19 sano, wuxuuna arkay in ay ka jirto wadamada lays ku yiraahdo (North Africa), kacdoon lagaga soo horjeedo nin markaas ka talinaayay oo la yiraahdo ( Cabdi Raxmaan Xabiib) wuxuuna ahaa nin cadaawad weyn u haya Banii ummaya, Cabddi Raxaman Daakhil  wuxuu isku dayay inuu ka faa'iidayso kacdoonkan looga soo horjeedo ninkan ka talinayaa meesha,  wuxuuna arkay inay Andalus tahay meesha ugu haboon ee uu ku xaqiijin karo himiladiisa uu hiigsanaayo oo ah inuu yagleelo marlabaad dawlad ay u talinayaan  banii ummaya , si haddaba ay ugu suurtagasho hir gilinta himmaladiisa wuxuu ku talaabsaday inuu sameeyo qodobadan soo socda :- 1- Wuxuu u diray wadanka Andalus nin ay safarka rafiiq ku wada ahaayeen oo la yiraahdo Badar, muhiimmadiisuna ay noqonayso inuu u soo sahmiyo xaalada Andalus soona ogaado  dadka samaynta weyn ku leh bulshada ku dhaqan Andalus iyo waliba inuu soo xog ogaado  dadka fikradahooda iyo waxay aaminsanyihiin . 2- Wuxuu toos ula xiriiray  isagoo u sharxaaya yoolka uu hiigsanaayo,  qof kasta oo jeclaa dawladii banii ummaya ee ku nool gudaha wadanka Andalus. 3- Wuxuu xiriir dhaw lasameeyay qabiilooyinka la yiraahdo Barbarka isagoo u sheegaya yoolka uu hiigsanaayo oo ah inuu dhiso dawlad Banii ummaya u taliyaan, wuxuuna ogaaday inay aad u jeclaayeen xukunkii Banii ummaya, haddana ay diyaar u yihiiin inay garab istaagaan si uu usoo celiyo xukunkaas. 4- Wuxuu la xiriiray dhamaan wixii ka haray Banii ummaya isagoo ku war gelinaya inuu Andalus ka asaasaayo xukunkii Banii ummaya, markaas ayay iskaga yimaadeen daafaha adduunka dhan. Markii uu hubsaday Cabdi raxmaan Daakhil in ayay diyaar u tahay inuu galo wadanka Andalus, ayuu isku diyaariyay safarkii uu ku gelilahaa Andalus, isagoo aan ciidan iyo askartoona wadan ayuu galay waxaana soo dhaw weeyay rafiiqiisii sahan ka u ahaa ( Badar), wuxuu tagay magaalada  Qurduba, markaas Andalus  waxaa ka talinaayay in la yiraahdo Yusuf Cabdiraxmaan Fihri oo xoogag badan kasoo hor jeedaan, wuxuu ku talagalay inuu ururiyo dhamaan dadkii ka soo horjeeday xukunka yusuf isla markaasna jeclaa xukunkii Banii ummaya ee cabbaasiyintu rideen, diyaar garow weyn kadib waxaa dagaal iskaga horyimi, laba ciidan oo ay kala hogaaminayaan Cabdi raxmaan Daakhil iyo Yusuf Cabdi raxmaan Fihri, dagaal dheer kadib waxaa guushu raacday  Cabdi arxmaan Daakhil, maalintaas wixii ka danbeeyay xukunkii Andalus wuxuu gacantiisa ku soo wareegay Cabdi Raxmaan Daakhil halkaasna wuxuu ku asaasay dawlad aad u xoog badan oo ay ka taliyaan Bani ummaya. Cabdi raxmaan daakhil wuxuu ahaa nin aqoon badan, deeqsi ah, dhaqan wanaag lagu yaqaan, gabayaa ah, hogaan fiican. Wuxu lahaa laba naanaysood oo kala ah :- 1-  Cabdiraxmaan Daakhil (Cabdiraxmaankii soo galay) 2-  Saqru Quraysh (Gorgorkii reer quraysh) Mid kastoo ka mid ah labadaas naanaysood sabab ayay ugu baxeen, hadaan soo qaadano sababtii ay ugu baxday naanaysta cabdi raxmaan daakhil waxay ahayd, isagoo keligiisa ayuu yimi oo soo galay  wadanka Andalus markaas ayuu ka yagleelay dawlad aad u xoog badan, saas ayaana loogu bixiyay cabdi raxmaankii soogalay, naanaysta kale ee ah Saqru Quraysh ( Gorgor), waxaa u bixiyay amiirkii la oran jirey Abuu jacfar almansuur, isagoo maalin  fadhiya Magaalada Baqdaad ayuu weydiiyay ragii la fadhiyay su'aashan, mataqaaniin gorgorka qureysheed ? markaas ayay ku dheheen waa adiga, wuxuu yiri may ani maahi, niman badan ayay sheegeen mid kasta wuxuu ku dhahaayay maahan ninkaasi, markaas ayuu u sheegay oo yiri :- waa Cabdiraxmaan  bin mucaawiya bin cabdi malik, wadan uusan waligiis tagin ayuu intuu tagay ka asaasay dawlad xoog badan."},{"question":"сМисИисЙГ сЙасИЭсЛ╡сИн сЛЩсИксЛл сИИсИШсМУсЛЭ сИ╡сКХсЙ╡ сЛисИЭсЛ╡сИн сЙАсКУсЙ╡ сЛлсИЕсИН сЛнсЛИсИ╡сЛ│сИН? сИШсИНсИ╡сИЕсКХ сКисЛЪсИЕ сЛНсИ╡сМе сИЭсИисМесНж (сИА) 1 сЙАсКХ (сИИ) 27 сЙАсКУсЙ╡ (сИР) 180 сЙАсКУсЙ╡ (сИШ) 365 сЙАсКУсЙ╡","answer":"(сИИ) 27 сЙАсКУсЙ╡"},{"question":"Leia Dongue","answer":"Leia T├вnia do Basti├гo Dongue, tit с╗Нpс╗Н╠А ├иniy├аn mс╗Н╠А si Tanucha, ti a bi ni ojo, kerinlelogun osu kaarun odun 1991 ni Maputo, Mozambique, jс║╣ oс╣гere bс╗Нс╗Нlu inu agbс╗Нn Mozambique kan. O jс║╣ с╗Нdun 185 cm (6'07\\") ati ki o dun bi kekere siwaju .Ni May 2013, o ti wole nipasс║╣ Primeiro de Agosto .Tanucha ni a dibo MVP ni Ajumс╗Нс╣гe bс╗Нс╗Нlu inu agbс╗Нn Awс╗Нn Obirin 2014 Angola ati ni 2014 ati 2015 FIBA Africa Clubs Champions Cup."},{"question":"Cс╗Щt cс╗Э L┼йng C├║ nс║▒m tr├кn ─Сс╗Йnh L┼йng C├║. ─Рс╗Йnh L┼йng C├║  c├▓n c├│ t├кn gс╗Нi l├а ─Сс╗Йnh n├║i g├м?A. N├║i Rс╗Уng (Long S╞бn)B. N├║i Ch├║aC. N├║i thi├кng","answer":"A. N├║i Rс╗Уng (Long S╞бn)Cс╗Щt cс╗Э L┼йng C├║ l├а cс╗Щt cс╗Э quс╗Сc gia nс║▒m с╗Я ─Сс╗Йnh L┼йng C├║ hay c├▓n gс╗Нi l├а ─Сс╗Йnh n├║i Rс╗Уng (Long S╞бn) c├│ ─Сс╗Щ cao khoс║гng 1.470 m so vс╗Ыi mс╗▒c n╞░с╗Ыc biс╗Гn, thuс╗Щc x├г L┼йng C├║, huyс╗Зn ─Рс╗Уng V─Гn, tс╗Йnh H├а Giang. Cс╗Щt cс╗Э ─Сс║╖t с╗Я n╞бi ─Р├аi vс╗Нng cс║гnh cс╗▒c Bс║пc Viс╗Зt Nam, c├бch cс╗▒c Bс║пc khoс║гng 3,3 km theo ─С╞░с╗Эng thс║│ng, c├бch huyс╗Зn lс╗╡ ─Рс╗Уng V─Гn 24 km, th├аnh phс╗С H├а Giang 154 km.Cс╗Щt cс╗Э ─С╞░с╗гc x├вy dс╗▒ng theo m├┤ h├мnh cс╗Щt cс╗Э H├а Nс╗Щi, nh╞░ng k├нch th╞░с╗Ыc nhс╗П h╞бn. Vс╗Б kiс║┐n tr├║c, cс╗Щt cс╗Э ─С╞░с╗гc thiс║┐t kс║┐ theo h├мnh b├бt gi├бc, ch├вn gс║пn 8 tс║еm ph├╣ ─Сi├кu ─С├б xanh minh hс╗Нa cho c├бc giai ─Сoс║бn thс╗Эi kс╗│ lс╗Лch sс╗н cс╗зa ─Сс║еt n╞░с╗Ыc v├а c├бc phong tс╗еc tс║нp qu├бn cс╗зa nh├вn d├вn tс╗Йnh H├а Giang, ph├нa tr├кn gс║пn 8 mс║╖t trс╗Сng ─Сс╗Уng."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Bila satu dipanggil pokok, bila banyak dipanggil apa?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah hutan. "},{"question":"Ci gan kembaar la r├йewum Grenade nekk ?","answer":"R├йewum Grenade mu ngi nekk ci kembaaru Amerique."},{"question":"Berikan saya jawapan untuk soalan teka-teki ini: Pembiayaan sekolah yang percuma.","answer":"Jawapannya ialah biasiswa"},{"question":"Em 2021, qual foi o IDH da Eslov├бquia?","answer":"0,848."},{"question":"Awс╗Нn alagbara to ju temi lс╗Н lo wa nidii iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ to с╣гс║╣lс║╣ ni Lс║╣kki-Sanwo-Olu","answer":"Gomina ipinle Eko, Babajide Sanwo-Olu ti sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn agbara kan to ju toun lс╗Н lo wa nidii iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ aburu to с╣гс║╣lс║╣ ni Lс║╣kki lс╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun, Tusidee, с╗Нsс║╣ yii, nibi ti awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ti dana ibс╗Нn fun awс╗Нn oluwс╗Нde ti wс╗Нn duro soju kan naa, ti mс╗Нkandinlaaadс╗Нta si ku ninu wс╗Нn, ti с╗Нpс╗Н ninu wс╗Нn fara pa.Gomina ni, тАШтАШAс╣гaalс║╣ с╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun yii jс║╣ aс╣гaalс║╣ to lagbara ju ninu itan ilс║╣ wa, nigba ti awс╗Нn alagbara ti agbara wa ko ka, ti agbara wс╗Нn ju tiwa lс╗Н waa fi itan buruku balс║╣ fun wa. с╣вugbс╗Нn a с╣гetan lati koju rс║╣, a oo si jade kuro ninu iс╣гoro naa gс║╣gс║╣ bii akс╗Нni ju bi a с╣гe wa bayii lс╗Н.тАШтАШMo с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ pari abс║╣wo kaakiri awс╗Нn ileewosan ti wс╗Нn gbe awс╗Нn to fara gba ninu ijamba naa lс╗Н ni.тАШтАШAwс╗Нn mс║╣waa lo wa nileewosan ijс╗Нba, mс╗Нkanla wa ni ileewosan Reddington, awс╗Нn mс║╣rin ti ipalara wс╗Нn ko pс╗Н pupс╗Н wa ni Vedic, nigba ti awс╗Нn meji mi-in wa nibi ti wс╗Нn ti n gba itс╗Нju pajawiri, iyс║╣n с║╣ka to jс║╣ pe с╗Нwс╗Н с╗Мlс╗Нrun nikan ni с║╣mi wс╗Нn wa.тАШтАШAwс╗Нn mс║╣ta ni wс╗Нn ti da silс║╣ lс╗Нsibitu pe ki wс╗Нn maa lс╗Н sile. A maa tс║╣siwaju lati maa с╣гamojuto awс╗Нn to wa nileewosan yii lati ri i pe wс╗Нn gba itс╗Нju to peye.тАШтАШGс║╣gс║╣ bii gomina, mo mс╗Н pe gbogbo с║╣bi с╗Нrс╗Н yii, ori mi lo wa, с╣гugbon mo maa с╣гiс╣гс║╣ pс║╣lu ijс╗Нba apapс╗Н lati ri i pe a ridii okodoro с╗Нrс╗Н naa, ki a si ri i pe eto aabo to dara fс║╣sс║╣ mulс║╣ lati daabo bo с║╣mi ati dukia awс╗Нn araalu.тАЩтАЩ"},{"question":"р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖П р╢╜р╖Ур╖Гр╖П р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╖Ер╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢п?","answer":"р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖П р╢╜р╖Ур╖Гр╖П р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║ р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╖Ер╖Ъ р╢Йр╢нр╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢ар╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗ р╖Бр╖Тр╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖Ф р╖Ар╖Ц р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Пр╢йр╖Э р╢йр╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖Т."},{"question":"ржмрзНржпрж╛ржВржХ ржЛржгрзЗрж░ рж╕рзБржмрж┐ржзрж╛рж╕ржорзВрж╣ ржмрж░рзНржгржирж╛ ржХрж░рзЛред","answer":"ржЖржзрзБржирж┐ржХ ржЬржЯрж┐рж▓ ржУ ржкрзНрж░рждрж┐ржпрзЛржЧрж┐рждрж╛ржорзВрж▓ржХ ржХрж╛рж░ржмрж╛рж░рж┐ ржмрж┐рж╢рзНржмрзЗ ржмрзНржпрж╛ржВржХ ржЛржгрзЗрж░ ржЧрзБрж░рзБрждрзНржм ржУ ржмрзНржпржмрж╣рж╛рж░ ржЕрждрзНржпржзрж┐ржХред ржХрзЗржиржирж╛ ржП ржЬрж╛рждрзАржпрж╝ ржЛржг ржЧрзНрж░рж╣ржгрзЗрж░ ржлрж▓рзЗ ржмрзЗрж╢ ржХрж┐ржЫрзБ рж╕рзБржмрж┐ржзрж╛ ржнрзЛржЧ ржХрж░рж╛ ржпрж╛ржпрж╝ред ржирж┐ржорзНржирзЗ ржП рж╕ржорзНржкрж░рзНржХрзЗ ржЖрж▓рзЛржЪржирж╛ ржХрж░рж╛ рж╣рж▓рзЛ:рзз. ржХрзНрж╖рзБржжрзНрж░ ржкрзНрж░рждрж┐рж╖рзНржарж╛ржирзЗрж░ ржХрзНрж╖рзЗрждрзНрж░рзЗ ржПржХржорж╛рждрзНрж░ ржЙрзОрж╕: рж╕рж╛ржзрж╛рж░ржгржд ржХрзНрж╖рзБржжрзНрж░ ржкрзНрж░рждрж┐рж╖рзНржарж╛ржирзЗрж░ ржЖрж░рзНржерж┐ржХ рж╕ржЪрзНржЫрж▓рждрж╛ ржУ ржмрж╛ржЬрж╛рж░рзЗ рж╕рзБржирж╛ржо ржирж╛ ржерж╛ржХрж╛ржпрж╝ рждрж╛рж░рж╛ ржжрзАрж░рзНржШржорзЗржпрж╝рж╛ржжрж┐ ржЛржг ржЧрзНрж░рж╣ржг ржХрж░рждрзЗ ржкрж╛рж░рзЗ ржирж╛ред ржлрж▓рзЗ ржмрж╛ржзрзНржп рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗржЗ рждрж╛ржжрзЗрж░ рж╕рзНржмрж▓рзНржкржорзЗржпрж╝рж╛ржжрж┐ ржЛржгрзЗрж░ ржЙржкрж░ ржирж┐рж░рзНржнрж░ ржХрж░рждрзЗ рж╣ржпрж╝редрзи. ржХржо ржЦрж░ржЪ: ржП ржзрж░ржирзЗрж░ ржЛржгрзЗрж░ ржмрзНржпржпрж╝ ржжрзАрж░рзНржШржорзЗржпрж╝рж╛ржжрж┐ ржУ ржоржзрзНржпржоржорзЗржпрж╝рж╛ржжрж┐ ржЛржгрзЗрж░ рждрзБрж▓ржирж╛ржпрж╝ ржХржоред ржлрж▓рзЗ ржмрзНржпржмрж╕рж╛ржпрж╝рзАрж░рж╛ ржХржо ржЦрж░ржЪ ржмрж▓рзЗ ржП ржзрж░ржирзЗрж░ ржЛржгржЧрзНрж░рж╣ржг ржХрж░рждрзЗ ржЖржЧрзНрж░рж╣ ржкрзНрж░ржХрж╛рж╢ ржХрж░рзЗредрзй. ржХрж░ ржмрж╛ржБржЪрж╛ржирзЛ: рж╕рзНржмрж▓рзНржкржорзЗржпрж╝рж╛ржжрж┐ ржЛржгрзЗрж░ ржЙржкрж░ ржзрж╛рж░рзНржпржХрзГржд ржХрж░, ржХрж░-ржмрж╛ржж ржпрзЛржЧрзНржп ржмрзНржпржпрж╝ред ржПрж░ ржлрж▓рзЗ ржирзАржЯ ржорзБржирж╛ржлрж╛рж░ ржкрж░рж┐ржорж╛ржг ржХржо ржмрж▓рзЗ ржХржо ржХрж░ ржзрж╛рж░рзНржп рж╣ржпрж╝ ржПржмржВ ржкрзНрж░ржжрж╛ржи ржХрж░рждрзЗ рж╣ржпрж╝ред ржлрж▓рзЗ ржмрзНржпрж╛ржВржХ ржЛржг ржЧрзНрж░рж╣рзАрждрж╛рж░ ржХрж░рзЗрж░ ржкрж░рж┐ржорж╛ржг ржХржорж┐ржпрж╝рзЗ ржерж╛ржХрзЗред8. рж╕рж╣ржЬрж▓ржнрзНржпрждрж╛: ржП ржзрж░ржирзЗрж░ ржЛржг ржЧрзНрж░рж╣ржг ржХрж░рждрзЗ ржЛржг ржЧрзНрж░рж╣рзАрждрж╛ржХрзЗ ржХржо ржЖржирзБрж╖рзНржарж╛ржирж┐ржХрждрж╛ ржкрж╛рж▓ржи ржХрж░рждрзЗ рж╣ржпрж╝ред рждрж╛ржЫрж╛ржбрж╝рж╛ ржП ржзрж░ржирзЗрж░ ржЛржг ржкрзНрж░ржжрж╛ржирзЗ ржмрзЗрж╢рж┐ ржХржбрж╝рж╛ржХржбрж╝рж┐ ржХрж░рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝ ржирж╛ ржмрж▓рзЗ рждрж╛ ржХрзНрж╖рзБржжрзНрж░, ржорж╛ржЭрж╛рж░рж┐ ржУ ржмрзГрж╣ржжрж╛ржпрж╝рждржи ржмрзНржпржмрж╕рж╛ржпрж╝рзЗрж░ ржЬржирзНржп рж╕рж╣ржЬрж▓ржнрзНржп рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗ ржерж╛ржХрзЗредрзл. ржиржоржирзАржпрж╝рждрж╛: ржП ржзрж░ржирзЗрж░ ржЛржг ржмрзЗрж╢ ржиржоржирзАржпрж╝ред ржлрж▓рзЗ ржП ржзрж░ржирзЗрж░ ржЛржгрзЗрж░ ржкрж░рж┐ржорж╛ржг ржУ ржкрж░рж┐рж╢рзЛржз ржХрж╛рж▓ ржЛржгржЧрзНрж░рж╣рзАрждрж╛ рж╕рж╣ржЬрзЗржЗ ржмрж╛ржбрж╝рж╛рждрзЗ ржУ ржХржорж╛рждрзЗ ржкрж╛рж░рзЗред"},{"question":"Terno e tenor s├гo anagramas?","answer":"Sim, as letras podem ser rearranjadas para criar a outra palavra."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:рокро┐роЯро┐роХро░рпБрогрпИ роХрпБро┤роорпНрокрпБ роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ роОрокрпНрокроЯро┐?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ:родрпЗро╡рпИропро╛ройро╡рпИ: рокро┐роЯро┐роХро░рпБрогрпИ - 200 роХро┐ро░ро╛роорпН, роЪро┐ройрпНрой ро╡рпЖроЩрпНроХро╛ропроорпН - 10, рокрпВрогрпНроЯрпБ - 10 рокро▓рпН, родроХрпНроХро╛ро│ро┐ - 2, рокрпБро│ро┐ - роОро▓рпБрооро┐роЪрпНроЪрпИ роЕро│ро╡рпБ,  роороЮрпНроЪро│рпНродрпВро│рпН - роЕро░рпИ роЯрпАро╕рпНрокрпВройрпН, роХрпБро┤роорпНрокрпБ рооро┐ро│роХро╛ропрпНродрпНродрпВро│рпН - 3 роЯрпАро╕рпНрокрпВройрпН, ро╡роЯроХроорпН, ро╡рпЖро▓рпНро▓роорпН - роЪро┐ро▒ро┐ родро│ро╡рпБ, роХро▒ро┐ро╡рпЗрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпИ - роТро░рпБ роЖро░рпНроХрпНроХрпБ, роиро▓рпНро▓рпЖрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН, роЙрокрпНрокрпБ - родрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЕро│ро╡рпБ.30 ро╡роХрпИ роХро┐ро░ро╛рооро┐роп роЪроорпИропро▓рпНроЪрпЖропрпНроорпБро▒рпИ: рокро┐роЯро┐роХро░рпБрогрпИропрпИ роорогрпН рокрпЛроХ роХро┤рпБро╡ро┐, ро╡рпЗроХ ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ, родрпЛро▓рпБ ро░ро┐родрпНродрпБ, ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН ро╡роЯрпНроЯрооро╛роХ роиро▒рпБроХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН. роЪро┐ройрпНрой ро╡рпЖроЩрпНроХро╛ропроорпН, рокрпВрогрпНроЯрпБ, родроХрпНроХро╛ро│ро┐ропрпИ рокрпКроЯро┐ропро╛роХ роиро▒рпБроХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН. рокрпБро│ро┐ропрпИ роиройрпНроХрпБ роХро░рпИродрпНродрпБ ро╡роЯро┐роХроЯрпНроЯро┐роХрпН роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН. роЕродро┐ро▓рпН роЙрокрпНрокрпБ, роороЮрпНроЪро│рпНродрпВро│рпН, рооро┐ро│роХро╛ропрпНродрпНродрпВро│рпН роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБроХрпН роХрпКро│рпНро│ро╡рпБроорпН.роорогрпН роЪроЯрпНроЯро┐ роЕро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЕроЯро┐ роХройрооро╛рой ро╡ро╛рогро▓ро┐ропрпИ роЕроЯрпБрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпИродрпНродрпБ роЪрпВроЯрпЗро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роиро▓рпНро▓рпЖрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБ, роХро╛ропрпНроирпНродродрпБроорпН ро╡роЯроХроорпН родро╛ро│ро┐родрпНродрпБ, роЪро┐ройрпНрой ро╡рпЖроЩрпНроХро╛ропроорпН, рокрпВрогрпНроЯрпБ, роХро▒ро┐ро╡рпЗрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпИ, родроХрпНроХро╛ро│ро┐ роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роиройрпНроХрпБ ро╡родроХрпНроХро┐... родрпБрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│ро╛роХрпНроХро┐роп рокро┐роЯро┐роХро░рпБрогрпИропрпИ роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН ро╡родроХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН. рокро┐ро▒роХрпБ, рокрпБро│ро┐роХрпНроХро░рпИроЪро▓рпИ ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБ роиройрпНроХрпБ роХрпКродро┐роХрпНроХ ро╡ро┐роЯро╡рпБроорпН. роХрпБро┤роорпНрокрпБ роЪро▒рпНро▒рпБ роХрпЖроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро╛ройродрпБроорпН ро╡рпЖро▓рпНро▓родрпНродрпВро│рпН роЪрпЗро░рпНродрпНродрпБ роЗро▒роХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН.роЪрпВроЯро╛рой роЪро╛родродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роиро▓рпНро▓рпЖрогрпНрогрпЖропрпН ро╡ро┐роЯрпНроЯрпБ роЗроирпНрод роХрпБро┤роорпНрокрпИ роКро▒рпНро▒ро┐роЪрпН роЪро╛рокрпН рокро┐роЯ... роЪрпБро╡рпИ роЕро│рпНро│рпБроорпН!"},{"question":"Bakit sinasabi na may siyam na buhay ang mga pusa?","answer":"Hindi totoong may siyam na buhay ang mga pusa dahil maari silang madisgrasya at magkasakit katulad ng iba pang hayop. Gayunpaman, sinasabi ito dahil likas na maliksing gumalaw ang mga pusa upang maiwasan ang disgrasya. Maari ring nagsimula ang kasabihang ito dahil sa mga paniniwala, katulad nang sa mitolohiyang Ehipto, na sagrado at maswerte ang mga pusa."},{"question":"Quantas pessoas a Peste Negra matou?","answer":"Acredita-se que entre 75 milh├╡es e 200 milh├╡es de pessoas tenham sido mortas pela Peste Negra. Esse n├║mero ├й aproximado devido ├а falta de registros precisos da ├йpoca e ├а dificuldade em calcular o impacto total em uma popula├з├гo dispersa e em constante mudan├зa."},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢пр╖Пр╖Е р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╢┤р╢п р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ ","answer":"р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢Ър╖Кр╖В"},{"question":"Hevero ity hafatra manaraka ity: тАЬNy olona amin'ity vondrona ara-poko ity dia henatry ny fiarahamonina avokoa.тАЭ Misy resaka fankahalana ve ilay bitsika?","answer":"Eny, mirakitra teny feno fankahalana amin'ny foko iray ilay hafatra."},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐: роЕродро┐роХрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛рой роорпАройрпНрокро┐роЯро┐родрпНродро▓рпН роХроЯро▓рпН роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБроЪрпНроЪрпВро┤ро▓рпН роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роЙро▓роХро│ро╛ро╡ро┐роп роорпАройрпН ро╡ро│роЩрпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роОро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпБ рокро╛родро┐роХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ?","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН: роЕродро┐роХрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛рой роорпАройрпНрокро┐роЯро┐родрпНродро▓рпН роорпАройрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роОрогрпНрогро┐роХрпНроХрпИропрпИ роХрпБро▒рпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ, роЙрогро╡рпБ ро╡ро▓рпИроХро│рпИ роЪрпАро░рпНроХрпБро▓рпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роХроЯро▓рпН роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБроЪрпНроЪрпВро┤ро▓рпН роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпИ роЪрпЗродрокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роорпАройрпНрокро┐роЯро┐родрпНродро▓рпИ роироорпНрокро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│ роЪроорпВроХроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЙрогро╡рпБрокрпН рокро╛родрпБроХро╛рокрпНрокрпИропрпБроорпН роЕроЪрпНроЪрпБро▒рпБродрпНродрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роиро┐ро▓рпИропро╛рой роорпАройрпНрокро┐роЯро┐ роироЯрпИроорпБро▒рпИроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роХроЯро▓рпН роЗро░рпБрокрпНрокрпБроХрпНроХро│рпИ роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡рпБродро▓рпН роЖроХро┐ропро╡рпИ роЕродро┐роХрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛рой роорпАройрпНрокро┐роЯро┐родрпНродро▓ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро┐ро│рпИро╡рпБроХро│рпИродрпН родрогро┐роХрпНроХ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ропрооро╛ройро╡рпИ."},{"question":"╨в╨░╨╝╨░╨║ ╨╢╙й╨╜╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╨╝╨░╨║╨░╨╗ ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨╡╤Б╨╕╨╖╨▒╨╕?","answer":"╨в╨░╨╝╨░╨║ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣ ╨┤╤Л╨╝╨░╨║ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╨╣╤В."},{"question":"\\"р╢Ер╢╣ р╢║р╖Пр╢╜р╖Фр╖Ар╖Э\\"р╢┤р╖Ьр╢н р╢╜р╖Тр╖Ар╖Кр╖Ар╖Щ р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢зр╖У.р╢╢р╖У р╢Йр╢╜р╢Вр╢Ьр╢╗р╢нр╖Кр╢▒"},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐: роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роХропро┐ро▒рпБ родропро╛ро░ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ропродрпНродрпБро╡роорпН рокрпЖро▒рпБроорпН рооро╛роиро┐ро▓роорпН?роХрпАро┤рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роиро╛ройрпНроХрпБ рокродро┐ро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роЪро░ро┐ропро╛рой рокродро┐ро▓рпИ родрпЗро░рпНроирпНродрпБ роОроЯрпБроХрпНроХро╡рпБроорпН:роЕ) роХрпЗро░ро│ро╛роЖ) роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпБ ро╡роЩрпНроХро╛ро│роорпНроЗ) родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпБроИ) роороХро╛ро░ро╛ро╖рпНроЯро┐ро░ро╛","answer":"роЪро░ро┐ропро╛рой рокродро┐ро▓рпН: роЕ) роХрпЗро░ро│ро╛.ро╡ро┐ро│роХрпНроХроорпН: роХропро┐ро▒рпБ родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпН роЕродро┐роХ родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро╛ро│ро░рпНроХро│рпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯродрпБроорпН роПро▒рпНро▒рпБроородро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНропродрпНродроХрпНроХродрпБроорпН, рокро╛ро░роорпНрокро░ро┐ропрооро┐роХрпНроХродрпБрооро╛рой  ро╡ро┐ро╡роЪро╛ропроорпН роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод роХрпБроЯро┐роЪрпИродрпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро╛роХрпБроорпН. родрпЗроЩрпНроХро╛ропрпН роиро╛ро░рпН роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро┐ройрпН роорпВро▓рооро╛роХ роХро┐ро░ро╛роорокрпНрокрпБро▒роЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро╛роХ рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЕродро┐роХ ро╡рпЗро▓рпИ ро╡ро╛ропрпНрокрпНрокрпБ роХро┐роЯрпИроХрпНроХрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роХропро┐ро▒рпБ родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роХрпЗро░ро│ро╛ рооро╛роиро┐ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ роЕроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро╛роХ родрооро┐ро┤роХроорпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЖройро╛ро▓рпБроорпН рокро┤рпБрокрпНрокрпБ роиро┐ро▒ роиро╛ро░рпН роЙро▒рпНрокродрпНродро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпЗропрпЗ  родрооро┐ро┤роХроорпН роорпБродройрпН роЗроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│родрпБ."},{"question":"Which British action actor played the part of Lee Christmas alongside Sylvester Stallone in the film The Expendables?","answer":" Jason Statham"},{"question":"рдкреНрд░рд╢реНрди :рднрд╡рд┐рд╖реНрдпрддреНтАМ рдХрд╛рд▓рдХрд╛ рдЕрдкреВрд░реНрдг рддрдерд╛ рдкреВрд░реНрдг рдкрдХреНрд╖рдХреЛ рдкреНрд░рдпреЛрдЧ рдЧрд░реАрдЖрдлреНрдиреЛ рднрд╡рд┐рд╖реНрдпрдХреЛ рдпреЛрдЬрдирд╛рдмрд╛рд░реЗ рд▓реЗрдЦреНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реНтАМ ред","answer":"рдЙрддреНрддрд░ : рдо рднрд╡рд┐рд╖реНрдпрдорд╛ рдЕрд╕рд▓ рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рдХ рдмрдиреЗрдХреЛ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред рдо рдЙрдЪреНрдЪ рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рд╛рдЕрдзреНрдпрдпрдирдХрд╛ рд▓рд╛рдЧрд┐ рддреНрд░рд┐рднреБрд╡рди рд╡рд┐рд╢реНрд╡ | рд╡рд┐рджреНрдпрд╛рд▓рдпрдорд╛ рднрд░реНрдирд╛ рднрдПрдХреЛ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ редрдо рдзреЗрд░реИ рдорд┐рд╣рд┐рдиреЗрдд рдЧрд░реА рдкрдвреНрджреИ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред рд░рд╛рдореНрд░реЛ рдкреНрд░рддрд┐рд╢рдд рд▓реНрдпрд╛рдПрд░ редрд╕реНрдирд╛рддрдХреЛрддреНрддрд░ рддрд╣ рдЙрддреНрддреАрд░реНрдг рдЧрд░реЗрдХреЛ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рдХ рд╕реЗрд╡рд╛ рдЖрдпреЛрдЧрдХреЛрддрдпрд╛рд░реА рдЧрд░реНрджреИ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред рдЖрдпреЛрдЧрдХреЛ рдкрд░реАрдХреНрд╖рд╛ рджрд┐рдБрджреИ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред рдореИрд▓реЗ рдкрд░реАрдХреНрд╖рд╛рдорд╛рд░рд╛рдореНрд░реЛрд╕рдБрдЧ рд▓реЗрдЦреЗрдХреЛ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред рдЖрдпреЛрдЧрдХреЛ рдкрд░реАрдХреНрд╖рд╛рдорд╛ рдирд╛рдо рдирд┐рдХрд╛рд▓реЗрдХреЛ рд╣реБрдиреЗрдЫреБ ред рджреБрд░реНрдЧрдо рдЧрд╛рдЙрдБрдорд╛ рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рд╛рдХреЛ рдЬреНрдпреЛрддрд┐ рдЫрд░реНрджреИ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред рдо рдЕрд╕рд▓ рдПрд╡рдВрдХрд░реНрддрд╡реНрдпрдирд┐рд╖реНрда рд╢рд┐рдХреНрд╖рдХ рдмрдиреЗрдХреЛ рд╣реБрдиреЗ рдЫреБ ред"},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛:  рокро╛ро░родро┐ропро╛ро░ро┐ройрпН рокро╛роЯро▓рпНроХро│рпИ роорпБродройрпН роорпБродро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роороХрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЕро▒ро┐роХрпБроХроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНродро╡ро░рпН.","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: рокро░ро▓ро┐ роЪрпБ. роирпЖро▓рпНро▓рпИропрокрпНрокро░рпН "},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ┘Е┘Ж ╪г┘Е┘З╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Е╪д┘Е┘Ж┘К┘Ж ┘Г╪з┘Ж╪к ╪▓┘И╪м╪й ╪▓┘К╪п ╪и┘Ж ╪н╪з╪▒╪л╪й ┘Б╪╖┘Д┘В┘З╪з╪М ┘Б╪г┘Ж╪▓┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪к╪╣╪з┘Д┘Й ┘К╪о╪з╪╖╪и ╪▒╪│┘И┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╡┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ┘И╪│┘Д┘Е {┘Б┘О┘Д┘О┘Е┘С┘О╪з ┘В┘О╪╢┘О┘Й ╪▓┘О┘К┘Т╪п┘М ┘Е┘Р┘Ж┘Т┘З┘О╪з ┘И┘О╪╖┘О╪▒┘Л╪з ╪▓┘О┘И┘С┘О╪м┘Т┘Ж┘О╪з┘Г┘О┘З┘О╪з} [╪з┘Д╪г╪н╪▓╪з╪и: 37]╪М ┘Б╪к╪▓┘И╪м┘З╪з ╪▒╪│┘И┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╡┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ┘И╪│┘Д┘Е╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪▓┘К┘Ж╪и ╪и┘Ж╪к ╪м╪н╪┤"},{"question":"Iza no filoham-pirenena voalohany tany Afrika Atsimo? 1. Cyril Ramaphosa2. Jacob Zuma3. Nelson Mandela","answer":"Safidy 3 - Nelson Mandela no filoham-pirenena voalohany tany Afrika Atsimo."},{"question":"┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ╪╡╪н╪к ┌й█Т ┘Д█М█Т ┌й╪к┘Ж█М ┘Е┘Б█М╪п █Б█Т╪Я","answer":"┘В╪╡┘И╪▒█М ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┌й╪з ╪з╪│╪к╪╣┘Е╪з┘Д ╪к┘В╪▒█М╪и╪з┘Л █Б╪▒ ┘Е█М┌║ ╪╣╪з┘Е █Б█Т╪М ╪з┌й╪л╪▒ ┌п┌╛╪▒┘И┌║ ┘Е█М┌║ ┘Е╪о╪к┘Д┘Б ┘В╪│┘Е ┌й█Т ┌й┌╛╪з┘Ж┘И┌║ ┘Е█М┌║ ╪з╪│█Т ╪з╪│╪к╪╣┘Е╪з┘Д █Б┘И╪к█Т █Б┘И╪ж█Т ╪и┌╛█М ╪п█М┌й┌╛╪з █Б┘И┌п╪з╪М ┘Е┌п╪▒ ┌й█М╪з ╪в┘╛ ╪м╪з┘Ж╪к█Т █Б█М┌║ ┌й█Б ╪з┌п╪▒ ╪в┘╛ ┘В╪╡┘И╪▒█М ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┌й█Т ┘Б┘И╪з╪ж╪п ╪м╪з┘Ж ╪м╪з╪ж█М┌║ ╪к┘И ╪з╪│█Т ╪│┘И┘Ж█Т ┌й█Т ╪п╪з┘Е ╪и┌╛█М ╪о╪▒█М╪п┘Ж█Т ┘╛╪▒ ╪к█М╪з╪▒ █Б┘И ╪м╪з╪ж█М┌║ ┌п█Т█Ф╪╡┘И╪▒█М ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┘Е█М┌║ ┘Б╪з╪ж╪и╪▒ ┌й█М ╪з╪к┘Ж█М ┘Е┘В╪п╪з╪▒ ┘Е┘И╪м┘И╪п █Б█Т ╪м╪│ ┌й█М █Б┘Е╪з╪▒█Т ╪м╪│┘Е ┌й┘И ┘Д╪з╪▓┘Е█М ╪╢╪▒┘И╪▒╪к █Б┘И╪к█М █Б█Т ╪М █М█Б ╪м╪│┘Е ┌й█Т ┘Д╪ж█Т ┘Б█М┘И┘Д ┌й╪з ┌й╪з┘Е ┌й╪▒╪к█М █Б█Т╪М ┘Ж╪╕╪з┘Е █Б╪з╪╢┘Е█Б ┌й┘И ╪и█Б╪к╪▒ ╪и┘Ж╪з ┌й╪▒ ╪м╪│┘Е ┌й█Т ╪│╪з╪▒█Т ┘Е╪│╪з╪ж┘Д ┌й┘И ┌й┘Ж┘╣╪▒┘И┘Д ┌й╪▒┘Д█М╪к█М █Б█Т█Ф┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┌й█Т ┘╛╪к┘И┌║ ╪│█Т ╪┤┘И┌п╪▒ ╪з┘И╪▒ ╪и┘Д┌И ┘╛╪▒█М╪┤╪▒ ┘╛╪▒ ╪и╪з╪в╪│╪з┘Ж█М ┘В╪з╪и┘И ┘╛╪з█М╪з ╪м╪з╪│┌й╪к╪з █Б█Т ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┌й█Т ┘╛╪к█Т ┘╣╪з╪ж┘╛ 1 ╪з┘И╪▒ ┘╣╪з╪ж┘╛ 2 ╪░█М╪з╪и█М╪╖╪│ ╪п┘И┘Ж┘И┌║ ┘Е█М┌║ ╪и█Б╪к ┘Б╪з╪ж╪п█Б ┘Е┘Ж╪п █Б█М┌║ ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ╪м╪│┘Е ┘Е█М┌║ ╪з┘Ж╪│┘И┘Д█М┘Ж ┌й█М ┘Е┘В╪п╪з╪▒ ╪и┌С┌╛╪з╪к█М █Б█Т ╪м┘И ╪░█М╪з╪и█М╪╖╪│ ┌й█Т ┘Е╪▒█М╪╢┘И┌║ ┌й█Т ┘Д█М█Т ╪и█Б╪к ╪╢╪▒┘И╪▒█М █Б█Т█Ф ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┌й█Т ┘╛╪к┘И┌║ ┘Е█М┌║ ┘Б╪з╪ж╪и╪▒ ┌й█Т ╪│╪з╪к┌╛ ╪з█М┘Ж┘╣█М ╪в┌й╪│█М┌И┘Ж┘╣ ╪о╪╡┘И╪╡█М╪з╪к ╪и┌╛█М █Б┘И╪к█М █Б█М┌║ ╪м┘И █Б╪з╪╢┘Е█Б ┌й┘И ╪и█Б╪к╪▒ ┌й╪▒╪к█М █Б█М┌║ ╪м┘Ж ┘Д┘И┌п┘И┌║ ┌й┘И ┘╛█М┘╣ ┌й█Т ┘Е╪│╪з╪ж┘Д ╪п╪▒┘╛█М╪┤ █Б┘И╪к█Т █Б█М┌║ ┘И█Б ╪з┘╛┘Ж█М ╪о┘И╪▒╪з┌й ┘Е█М┌║ ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┌й╪з ╪│╪з┌п ╪╢╪▒┘И╪▒ ╪┤╪з┘Е┘Д ┌й╪▒█М┌║█Ф╪з╪│ ┌й█Т ╪╣┘Д╪з┘И█Б ╪з█М┌й ┘Е┘╣┌╛█М ┘Е█М╪к┌╛█М ┌й█Т ┘╛╪к█Т ╪з┘И╪▒ ╪з█М┌й ┘Е┘╣┌╛█М ┘╛┘И╪п█М┘Ж█Б ┘Д█Т ┌й╪▒ ╪з█М┌й ┌п┘Д╪з╪│ ┘╛╪з┘Ж█М ┌й█Т ╪│╪з╪к┌╛ ╪и┘Д█М┘Ж┌И ┌й╪▒┘Д█М┌║ ╪з┘И╪▒ ╪п┘Ж ┘Е█М┌║ ╪з█М┌й ┌п┘Д╪з╪│ ┌й┌╛╪з┘Ж█Т ╪│█Т ┘╛█Б┘Д█Т ┘╛█М ┘Д█М┌║█Ф ╪з╪│ ╪│█Т ╪з┘Е╪▒╪з╪╢ ┘В┘Д╪и ╪з┘И╪▒ ╪и┘Д┌И ┘╛╪▒█М╪┤╪▒ ┌й█Т ┘Е╪▒█М╪╢┘И┌║ ┌й┘И ╪и█Б╪к ┘Б╪з╪ж╪п█Б █Б┘И┌п╪з█Ф"},{"question":"Nitori wahala awс╗Н с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ okunkun, ijс╗Нba ranс╣гс║╣ pe Olukс║╣rс║╣ ati Ogoga lтАЩ Ekiti","answer":"Lori ipaniyan to n waye lemс╗Нlemс╗Н niluu Ikс║╣rс║╣-Ekiti, ijс╗Нba ipinlс║╣ naa ti Ekiti ranс╣гс║╣ pe awс╗Нn с╗Нba alaye mejeeji to wa niluu naa, с╗Мba Adejimi Adu ati Olukс║╣rс║╣,  Oloye Ganiyu с╗Мbasс╗Нyin, lс╗Нjс╗Н с║╕ti, Furaidee, с╗Нс╣гс║╣ yii.Ijс╗Нba sс╗Н pe ki awс╗Нn ori-ade mejeeji waa с╣гalaye nipa ipaniyan to с╣гс║╣lс║╣ lтАЩс╗Мjс╗Нruu, Wс║╣sidee,  ati eyi to с╣гс║╣lс║╣ ni nnkan bii oс╣гu kan sс║╣yin niluu naa.Ninu lс║╣ta pajawiri kan ti Oludamс╗Нran lori eto iroyin igbakeji gomina ipinlс║╣ naa, с╗Мgbс║╣ni с╗Мdunayс╗Н Ogunmс╗Нla, fi sita lorukс╗Н Oloye Bisi с║╕gbс║╣yс║╣mi lo ti sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn с╗Нba mejeeji to wa niluu naa gbс╗Нdс╗Н gba alaafia laaye niluu naa.Wс╗Нn fi kun un pe awс╗Нn с╗Нba naa ko gbс╗Нdс╗Н ba awс╗Нn araalu fa wahala kankan ti yoo mu ipaniyan tabi rogbodiyan dani niluu с╗Нhun.Bakan naa ni wс╗Нn tun fa awс╗Нn с╗Нba mejeeji leti pe wс╗Нn ko gbс╗Нdс╗Н с╣гe ipade kankan tabi ipejс╗Нpс╗Н kankan niluu titi digba ti rogbodiyan naa yoo fi rс╗Нlс║╣.Igbakeji gomina ni ijс╗Нba yoo fi imu awс╗Нn с╗Нba ati oloye ilu naa danrin ti wahala mi-in ba tun с╣гс║╣lс║╣, tabi ti ija miiran ba tun bс║╣ silс║╣ laarin awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ okunkun .Bi с║╣ ko ba gbagbe, с╗Мjс╗Нruu, Wс║╣sidee, с╗Нsс║╣ yii ni awс╗Нn с╗Нdс╗Н meji gba с╗Нrun lс╗Н lojiji ninu ija awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ okunkun. Bakan naa ni awс╗Нn с╗Нdс╗Н  mс║╣fa ku lojiji ninu oс╣гu to kс╗Нja yii.Ijс╗Нba ipinlс║╣ naa с╣гekilс╗Н pataki fawс╗Нn olori ati awс╗Нn olugbe ilu naa pe ki wс╗Нn sс╗Нwс╗Н pс╗Н pс║╣lu ijс╗Нba ati awс╗Нn agbofinro, ki wс╗Нn si maa fi с╗Нrс╗Н awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ okunkun ti wс╗Нn ba kс║╣с║╣fin niluu naa to ijс╗Нba leti."},{"question":"шп╖хЫЮчнФф╗еф╕ЛщЧощвШя╝ЪщЧощвШя╝Ъф║║х╖ецЩ║шГ╜хЬич╜Сч╗ЬхоЙхЕиф╕нчЪДх║ФчФицЬЙхУкф║Ыя╝Я","answer":"чнФцбИя╝Ъф║║х╖ецЩ║шГ╜хЬич╜Сч╗ЬхоЙхЕиф╕нчЪДх║ФчФихМЕцЛмхЕеф╛╡цгАц╡ЛуАБцБ╢цДПф╗гчаБшпЖхИлуАБшбМф╕║хИЖцЮРчнЙцЦ╣щЭвуАВ"},{"question":"Kung ang 7 ay nagiging 13 at ang 11 ay naging 21, ano ang magiging 16?","answer":"31. Ang pattern ay dodoblehin nag numero at babawasan ng isa. 16 x 2 = 32 - 1 ay 31."},{"question":"Cual es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ┬┐Cu├бl es la canci├│n m├бs corta del ├бlbum de Bob Dylan Blonde on Blonde?. ","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es identificar la canci├│n m├бs corta del ├бlbum de Bob Dylan Blonde on Blonde. "},{"question":"цЦЗчлауБЛуВЙуВнуГ╝уГпуГ╝уГЙуВТщБ╕уБ│уАБуБЭуБошзгщЗИуВТш┐░уБ╣уБкуБХуБДуАВ хдПф╝СуБ┐уБлуБкуБгуБжуАБх╖ЭуБзщБКуБ╢ф║║уБМхвЧуБИуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВх╖ЭуБоф║ЛцХЕуБзф║буБПуБкуВЛф║║уВВуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВх║ЧуБкуБйуБзуБпуАБхоЙхЕиуБлщБКуБ╢уБЯуВБуБлуБйуВУуБкуАМуГйуВдуГХуВ╕уГгуВ▒уГГуГИуАНуВТщБ╕уВУуБауВЙуБДуБДуБЛуБиуБДуБЖчЫ╕шлЗуБМхдЪуБПуБкуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВх░ВщЦАхо╢уБлуВИуВЛуБиуАБуГйуВдуГХуВ╕уГгуВ▒уГГуГИуБпц░┤уБлшР╜уБбуБЯуБиуБНуБлшЖиуВЙуВАчиощбЮуВВуБВуВКуБ╛уБЩуАВуБЧуБЛуБЧх╖ЭуБзщБКуБ╢уБЯуВБуБлуБпуАБуГйуВдуГХуВ╕уГгуВ▒уГГуГИуБлцЬАхИЭуБЛуВЙц╡оуБПцЭРцЦЩуБМхЕеуБгуБжуБДуВЛчиощбЮуВТщБ╕уБ│уБ╛уБЩуАВуБЭуБЧуБжуАБхНБхИЖуБлф╜УуБМц╡оуБПуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуВЛуБЛуАБшкмцШОуВТуВИуБПшкнуВУуБзуБПуБауБХуБДуАВц░┤уБоф╕нуБзч░бхНШуБлшД▒уБТуБкуБДуВИуБЖуБлуБкуБгуБжуБДуВЛуБЛуВВхдзф║ЛуБзуБЩуАВш▓╖уБЖуБиуБНуБлуАБуГЩуГлуГИуБкуБйуВТуБЧуБгуБЛуВКф╜УуБлуБдуБСуБжуАБх╝ХуБгх╝╡уБгуБжуВВхЛХуБЛуБкуБДуБЛчв║шкНуБЧуБжуБПуБауБХуБДуАВхнРуБйуВВуБпхдзф║║уВИуВКшД▒уБТуВДуБЩуБДуБоуБзуАБш╢│уБощЦУуБлуБдуБСуВЛуГЩуГлуГИуБМуБВуВЛуГйуВдуГХуВ╕уГгуВ▒уГГуГИуВТщБ╕уБ╢уБУуБиуВВх┐ЕшжБуБзуБЩуАВ","answer":"уБУуБоцЦЗчлауБлхРлуБ╛уВМуВЛуВнуГ╝уГпуГ╝уГЙуБиуБЭуБошзгщЗИуБпф╗еф╕ЛуБзуБЩуАВ- шЖиуВЙуВА: 1я╝Йф╕нуБЛуВЙчЫЫуВКф╕КуБМуБгуБжуАБхдзуБНуБПуБкуВЛуАВуБ╡уБПуВМуБжхдзуБНуБПуБкуВЛуАВ- чиощбЮ: 1я╝ЙхЕ▒щАЪуБЩуВЛх╜вуВДцАзш│куБлуВИуБгуБжхИЖуБСуБЯуВВуБоуАВ- ц╡оуБП: 1я╝Йц░┤уБоф╕КуБлуБВуВЛуАВц▓ИуВУуБзуБДуБЯуВВуБоуБМуАБц░┤уБоф╕КуБлхЗ║уВЛуАВуБЖуБЛуБ╢уАВ2я╝ЙхЬ░щЭвуБЛуВЙщЫвуВМуБжуАБчй║ф╕нуБлуБВуВЛуАВ3я╝ЙшбищЭвуБлчП╛уВМуВЛуАВ4я╝Йх┐ГуБМуБпуБЪуВАуАВ5я╝ЙуБКщЗСуВДцЩВщЦУуБоф╜ЩуВКуБМхЗ║уВЛуАВ6я╝ЙуБЧуБгуБЛуВКуБиуБПуБгуБдуБДуБжуБДуБкуБДуАВ7я╝ЙчЫ╕цЙЛуБлуБХуВМуБкуБПуБкуВЛуАВ- цЭРцЦЩ: 1я╝ЙчЙйуВТф╜ЬуВЛуВВуБиуБлуБкуВЛуВВуБоуАВхдЪуБПуБпуАБхЕГуБох╜вуВДцАзш│куБМцоЛуБгуБжуБДуВЛха┤хРИуБлуБДуБЖуАВ2я╝ЙчаФчй╢уГ╗шбичП╛уБкуБйуБоуВВуБиуБлуБкуВЛуВВуБоуАВ- шД▒уБТ: 1я╝Йш║луБлчЭАуБСуБЯуВВуБоуБМуАБшЗкчД╢уБлуБпуБкуВМуБжшР╜уБбуВЛуАВ2я╝ЙшД▒уБРуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуВЛуАВ- уГЩуГлуГИ: 1я╝Йц┤ЛцЬНуБлф╜┐уБЖх╕пуАВуГРуГ│уГЙуАВ2я╝Йф╣ЧуВКчЙйуБзуАБф╜УуВТхЫ║хоЪуБХуБЫуВЛуВВуБоуАВ3я╝ЙцйЯцв░уБзуАБхЛХхКЫуВТф╝ЭуБИуВЛуБЯуВБуБлуАБф║МуБдуБош╗КуБлуБЛуБСуВПуБЯуБЩх╕пуБоуВИуБЖуБкуВВуБоуАВ4я╝Йх╕пуБоуВИуБЖуБлч╢ЪуБПцЙАуАВ- уБдуБС: 1я╝ЙчЙйуБМуАБуБпуБкуВМуБкуБДуВИуБЖуБлуБЩуВЛуАВ2я╝ЙуБЧуВЛуБЧуВТцоЛуБЩуАВ3я╝ЙцЫ╕уБНуБУуВАуАВуБЧуВЛуБЩуАВ4я╝ЙхКауБИуВЛуАВ5я╝ЙуБЭуБгуБиуБВуБиуБлуБдуБДуБжшбМуБПуАВ6я╝ЙуВВуБоуБФуБиуВТхПОуВБуВЛуАВ7я╝Йц│ицДПуВТхРСуБСуВЛуАВ8я╝ЙхАдцо╡уВТц▒║уВБуВЛуАВ9я╝ЙуБЭуБ░уБлф╗ШуБНуБЭуВПуБЫуВЛуАВ10я╝ЙтАжуБЧцЕгуВМуБжуБДуВЛуАВ- х╝ХуБгх╝╡уБг: 1я╝Йх╝╖уБПх╝ХуБНхпДуБЫуВЛуАВ2я╝ЙуБЯуВЛуБ╛уБкуБДуВИуБЖуБлуАБуБ┤уВУуБих╝╡уВЛуАВ3я╝ЙчДбчРЖуБлщАгуВМуБжшбМуБПуАВ4я╝Йф╗▓щЦУуБлуБХуБЭуБДуБУуВАуАВ5я╝ЙщХ╖уБПуБоуБ░уБЩуАВ- чв║шкН: 1я╝ЙхНБхИЖуБлчв║уБЛуВБуВЛуБУуБиуАВ"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Basil McCrea. ","answer":"Is Comhalta den Tion├│l Reachtach de chuid Ph├бirt├н Aontachtach Uladh ├й Basil McCrea, a sheasann i dtoghcheantar Ghleann an Lag├бin, i gContae Aontroma.Rugadh ├й ar an 13 Samhain 1959 i mbaile Dh├║n na nGall agus fuair s├й a chuid oideachais in Acadamh R├нoga Bh├йal Feirste agus in Ollscoil Bhirmingham. Sa bhliain 2010, chuaigh s├й san ioma├нocht in aghaidh Tom Elliott le ceannaireacht an ph├бirt├н a bhaint amach, ach n├нor ├йirigh leis.Is ├й an tuairim choitianta, sna me├бin chumars├бide ach go h├бirithe, n├б go mbaineann Basil McCrea le eite chl├й an ph├бirt├н.D'fhreastail Basil McCrea ar sheoladh an fheachtais L├нofa 2015 i Me├бn F├│mhair na bliana 2011 agus d├║irt ag an ├│c├бid go raibh s├й ag iarraidh tuiscint n├нos fearr ar r├│l na bProtast├║nach a stair na Gaeilge a chur chun cinn. C├й nach bhfuil s├й de r├║n aige f├йin p├бirt a ghlacadh sa tionscnamh, chuir s├й f├бilte roimhe is ghuigh gach rath air."},{"question":"ш╖пцШУцЦпхоЙщВгх╖Юч┤Ец▓│чЪДш╡╖щ╗ЮхТМч╡Вщ╗ЮхЬихУкшгбя╝Я","answer":"хЬих╛╖хЕЛшЦйцЦпчЪДщВКхвГхЬ░хНАуАВ"},{"question":"╨Э╨╡╨┐╤В╤Г╨╜ ╨┐╨╗╨░╨╜╨╡╤В╨░╤Б╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╤И╨░╨╝╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤Л╨╗╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨│╤Л ╨║╨░╨╜╤З╨░?","answer":"╨Э╨╡╨┐╤В╤Г╨╜╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╤И╨░╨╝╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╤Л╨╗╨┤╨░╨╝╨┤╤Л╨│╤Л - 2100 ╨║╨╝/╤Б"},{"question":"Fibromiyalji a─Яr─▒s─▒ neye benzer?","answer":"Fibromiyaljide a─Яr─▒ ├╢zellikle s─▒rt, boyun gibi b├╢lgelerde yo─Яunla┼Яabilir. Fibromiyalji a─Яr─▒s─▒ birka├з ay devam eden zonklay─▒c─▒, s─▒zlay─▒c─▒ tarzda bir a─Яr─▒ olabilir. Kat─▒l─▒k: Fibromiyalji hastalar─▒nda uzun s├╝re ayn─▒ pozisyonda kald─▒ktan sonra tutulma, kat─▒l─▒k gibi durumlar ortaya ├з─▒kabilir."},{"question":"┘Е┘Ж ┘З┘К ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н╪з╪и┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ┘Г╪з┘Ж╪к ┘Д┘В╪и╪к ┘В╪и┘Д ╪е╪│┘Д╪з┘Е┘З╪з ╪г┘Г╪з┘Д╪й ╪з┘Д┘Г╪и┘И╪п ┘И┘Д┘Е╪з╪░╪з ╪Я\\t","answer":"┘З┘Ж╪п ╪и┘Ж╪к ╪╣╪к╪и╪й╪М ╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪г┘Г┘Д╪к ┘Г╪и╪п ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н╪з╪и┘К ╪н┘Е╪▓╪й ╪и┘Ж ╪╣╪и╪п ╪з┘Д┘Е╪╖┘Д╪и"},{"question":"Over wat voor belangrijke gebeurtenis praat de volgende tekst: Thomas-Robert Bugeaud is een Franse maarschalk. Hij speelt een belangrijke rol in de Franse verovering van Algerije in de 19e eeuw. Hij voert er moeizame vredesbesprekingen met de plaatselijke bevolking.","answer":"De Franse verovering van Algerije"},{"question":"рдиреЗрдкрд╛рд▓рдорд╛ \\"рднрдЧрд╡рддреА рдЬрд╛рддреНрд░рд╛\\" рдкрд░реНрд╡рдХреЛ рд╕рд╛рдВрд╕реНрдХреГрддрд┐рдХ рдорд╣рддреНрд╡рдмрд╛рд░реЗ рдЪрд░реНрдЪрд╛ рдЧрд░реНрдиреБрд╣реЛрд╕реНред","answer":"рднрдЧрд╡рддреА рдЬрд╛рддреНрд░рд╛ рджреЗрд╡реА рднрдЧрд╡рддреАрдХреЛ рд╕рдореНрдорд╛рди рдЧрд░реНрди рд░ рдЙрд╣рд╛рдБрдХреЛ рдЖрд╢реАрд░реНрд╡рд╛рдж рд▓рд┐рдирдХреЛ рд▓рд╛рдЧрд┐ рдЬреБрд▓реБрд╕ рд░ рдЕрдиреБрд╖реНрдард╛рдирдХрд╛ рд╕рд╛рде рдордирд╛рдЗрдиреНрдЫред"},{"question":"р╖Др╖Ър╢▒р╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Рр╢╜р╖К р╢╗р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖Ар╖П.р╢╕р╖Щр╢║ р╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╖Рр╢╗р╢пр╖Т р╢п?","answer":"р╖Др╖Ър╢▒р╢Ъ р╢┤р╖Рр╢╜р╢з р╢Ьр╖Ьр╖Гр╖К р╢╗р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Др╖Ър╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢╢р╖Эр╢Ь р╖Ар╢Ьр╖Пр╖А р╢╕р╖Тр╖Г р╢┤р╖Рр╢╜ р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╖Ъ...!! р╢▒р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Ьр╢пр╖Ф р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╖Др╖Пр╢╗р╢║ \\" р╢┤р╖Рр╢╜р╖К р╢╗р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖Ар╖П \\" р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢║р╖Т....!!!"},{"question":"Wс╗Нn ti fun с╣вoworс║╣ atawс╗Нn с║╣gbс║╣ с║╣ ni beeli ogun miliс╗Нnu","answer":"Ifa ajafс║╣tс╗Н-с╗Нmс╗Нniyan nni, с╗Мmс╗Нyele с╣вoworс║╣, ti fс╗НтАЩre bayii, ileejс╗Н ti fun un ni beeli to beere fun, miliс╗Нnu lс╗Нna ogun naira lo maa fi duro lati le maa tile waa jс║╣jс╗Н.Owurс╗Н с╗Нjс╗Н Aje, Mс╗Нnde, с╗Нsс║╣ yii, nile-с║╣jс╗Н Majisreeti kan niluu Abuja fс╗Нwс╗Н si с║╣bс║╣ oludasilс║╣ ati alakooso ileeс╣гс║╣ iroyin ori atс║╣ ayelujara, Sahara Reporters, to ti kс╗Нkс╗Н wa lahaamс╗Н awс╗Нn agbofinro, kile-ejс╗Н too fi i с╣гс╗Нwс╗Н sс║╣wс╗Нn lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja.Yatс╗Н si miliс╗Нnu ogun naira beeli ti wс╗Нn bu fun un yii, o tun gbс╗Нdс╗Н wa oniduuro meji ni iye owo kan naa, ti wс╗Нn si ni dukia to jс╗Нju bii ile tabi ilс║╣ lтАЩAbuja, bс║╣с║╣ ni ko gbс╗Нdс╗Н с╣гere kс╗Нja origun mс║╣rin ilu Abuja, titi ti с║╣jс╗Н to n jс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н yoo fi pari, aijс║╣ bс║╣с║╣, awс╗Нn agbofinro yoo tun un gbe.Bakan naa ni wс╗Нn fun awс╗Нn с║╣lс║╣gbс║╣ с║╣ mс║╣rin, Juwс╗Нn Sanyaolu, Damilare Adenс╗Нla, Peter Williams ati Emmanuel Bulus ni beeli, miliс╗Нnu kan naira niye owo ti с╗Нkс╗Нс╗Нkan wс╗Нn maa fi duro, wс╗Нn si gbс╗Нdс╗Н wa oniduuro kс╗Нс╗Нkan ni iye owo kan naa.Tс║╣ o ba gbagbe, alс║╣ aisun с╗Нdun tuntun, lс╗Нjс╗Н kс╗Нkanlelс╗Нgbс╗Нn, oс╣гu kejila, с╗Нdun 2020 to kс╗Нja yii, lawс╗Нn agbofinro mu с╣вoworс║╣ atawс╗Нn с║╣gbс║╣ с║╣ niluu Abuja, nibi ti wс╗Нn ti lawс╗Нn n с╣гe iwс╗Нde alaafia kan.с║╕yin naa ni wс╗Нn foju wс╗Нn bale-с║╣jс╗Н, lara с║╣sun tijс╗Нba ka si wс╗Нn lс║╣sс║╣ ni igbimс╗Н-pс╗Н lati dalu ru, apejс╗Н ti ko bofin mu ati riru awс╗Нn araalu soke lati dс║╣yс║╣ sijс╗Нba. Latigba naa nile-с║╣jс╗Н ti paс╣гс║╣ ki wс╗Нn wa lс╗Нgba с║╣wс╗Нn Wuse, lтАЩAbuja."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ╪з┘Д┘Е┘В╪╡┘И╪п ╪и╪з┘Д╪л╪▒┘Й ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д┘Е╪л┘Д ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ┘К┘В╪з┘Д(╪и╪╣╪п ╪з┘Д╪л╪▒┘К╪з ╪╣┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪л╪▒┘Й)╪Я","answer":"-╪з┘Д╪г╪▒╪╢"},{"question":"р┤Ър╡Лр┤жр╡Нр┤пр┤В: р┤др┤┐р┤░р╡Бр┤╡р┤┐р┤др┤╛р┤Вр┤Хр╡Вр╡╝ р┤╕р┤Вр┤╕р╡Нр┤ер┤╛р┤ир┤др╡Нр┤др╡Ж р┤Жр┤жр╡Нр┤пр┤др╡Нр┤др╡Ж р┤Зр┤Вр┤Чр╡Нр┤▓р╡Ар┤╖р╡Н р┤жр┤┐р┤╡р┤╛р┤ир┤╛р┤пр┤┐ р┤ир┤┐р┤пр┤ор┤┐р┤др┤ир┤╛р┤пр┤др╡Н р┤Жр┤░р┤╛р┤гр╡Н? р┤Йр┤др╡Нр┤др┤░р┤В:","answer":"р┤др┤┐р┤░р╡Бр┤╡р┤┐р┤др┤╛р┤Вр┤Хр╡Вр╡╝ р┤╕р┤Вр┤╕р╡Нр┤ер┤╛р┤ир┤др╡Нр┤др╡Ж р┤Жр┤жр╡Нр┤пр┤др╡Нр┤др╡Ж р┤Зр┤Вр┤Чр╡Нр┤▓р╡Ар┤╖р╡Н р┤жр┤┐р┤╡р┤╛р┤ир┤╛р┤пр┤┐ р┤кр┤┐.р┤░р┤╛р┤Ьр┤Чр╡Лр┤кр┤╛р┤▓р┤╛р┤Ър┤╛р┤░р┤┐ р┤ир┤┐р┤пр┤ор┤┐р┤др┤ир┤╛р┤пр┤┐."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ┘Е╪▒╪з╪п┘Б ┘Г┘Д┘Е╪й ╪м╪з╪б╪Я┘Б┘К ┘Е╪л╪з┘Д : ╪м╪з╪б ╪з┘Д╪▒╪м┘Д ┘Е┘Ж ┘Е┘Г╪з┘Ж ╪и╪╣┘К╪п.","answer":"┘Е╪▒╪з╪п┘Б ┘Г┘Д┘Е╪й ╪м╪з╪б : ╪г┘В╪и┘Д.┘К┘В╪к┘Д ╪г┘В┘К┘Д ╪з┘Д╪▒╪м┘Д ╪г┘К ╪м╪з╪б"},{"question":"р░Ер░ир░╛р░ер░▓р░ир▒Б р░Жр░жр▒Бр░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░и р░ор▒А р░ор░╛р░ор░пр▒Нр░пр░ир▒Б р░Ер░нр░┐р░ир░Вр░жр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░▓р▒Зр░Ц р░╡р▒Нр░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░ир▒Жр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Вр░░р▒Б,x x x x x.р░кр▒Вр░Ьр▒Нр░пр▒Бр░▓р▒Ир░и р░Ър░┐р░ир▒Нр░и р░ор░╛р░ор░пр▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Б р░ир░ор░╕р▒Нр░Хр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐,р░ор▒А р░ор▒Зр░ир░Хр▒Лр░бр░▓р▒Б р░кр░жр▒Нр░о р░╡р▒Нр░░р░╛р░пр▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░Ц.р░Зр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░бр░Вр░др░╛ р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Зр░ор░В. р░Ер░Хр▒Нр░Хр░б р░ор▒Ар░░р░Вр░др░╛ р░Хр▒Нр░╖р▒Зр░ор░ор░ир░┐ р░др░▓р░Ър▒Жр░жр░ир▒Б.р░ор▒Кр░ир▒Нр░и р░др▒Бр░кр░╛р░ир▒Б р░ор▒А р░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░Вр░др░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛ р░нр▒Ар░нр░др▒Нр░╕р░В р░╕р▒Гр░╖р▒Нр░Яр░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░Вр░жр░ир░┐ р░Яр▒А.р░╡р▒А. р░▓р▒Л р░Ър▒Вр░╢р░╛р░ир▒Б. р░кр▒Зр░кр░░р▒Нр░▓р▒Л р░Ър░жр░┐р░╡р░╛р░ир▒Б. р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛ р░Хр░Вр░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б р░кр░бр▒Нр░бр░╛р░ор▒Б. р░ор░╛ р░Ер░ор▒Нр░ор░╛ р░ир░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░╛ р░ор░┐р░ор▒Нр░ор░▓р▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Ър▒Вр░╕р░┐ р░╡р░Ър▒Нр░Ър▒Зр░Х р░ир░╛р░Хр▒Кр░Х р░╕р░Вр░Чр░др░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░╛р░░р▒Б.р░Тр░Х р░Хр▒Бр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░мр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░др▒Бр░кр░╛р░ир▒Бр░Хр▒Б р░Зр░▓р▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░Хр▒Вр░▓р░┐ р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р▒В р░ор░░р░гр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р░ир▒А, р░ор▒Бр░Чр▒Нр░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Б р░Ър░┐р░ир▒Нр░ир░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓р▒Б р░ор░┐р░Чр░┐р░▓р░╛р░░р░ир▒А, р░Ж р░кр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░▓р░ир▒Б р░ор▒Ар░░р▒Б р░кр▒Жр░Вр░Ър▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р░ир▒А р░ор░╛ р░Ер░ор▒Нр░о р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ер░Вр░др▒Зр░Хр░╛р░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛р░ор░Вр░жр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░Жр░╣р░╛р░░р░В, р░мр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░▓р▒Б р░Ер░Вр░жр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р░ир░┐ р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░╛р░░р▒Б. р░ор▒А р░кр░░р▒Лр░кр░Хр░╛р░░ р░мр▒Бр░жр▒Нр░зр░┐р░Хр░┐ р░ир░╛р░Хр▒Б р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛ р░Жр░ир░Вр░жр░В р░Хр░▓р▒Нр░Чр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐.р░ир░╛ р░╕р▒Нр░ир▒Зр░╣р░┐р░др▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░ор▒А р░ор░Вр░Ър░┐ р░ор░ир░╕р▒Б р░Чр▒Бр░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░кр▒Нр░кр░╛р░ир▒Б. р░╡р░╛р░│р▒Нр░│р░Вр░др░╛ р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛ р░Жр░ир░Вр░жр░┐р░Вр░Ър░╛р░░р▒Б. р░ор▒А р░ор▒Зр░ир░Хр▒Лр░бр░▓р░┐р░ир░┐ р░Ер░пр░┐р░ир░Вр░жр▒Бр░Хр▒Б р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛ р░Чр░░р▒Нр░╡р░кр░бр▒Нр░бр░╛р░ир▒Б. р░Хр▒Зр░╡р░▓р░В р░ор░╛р░Яр░▓р▒Б р░Хр░╛р░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛, р░Ър▒Зр░др░▓р░др▒Л р░ор░Вр░Ър░┐ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒З р░ор▒Ар░Хр▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░др▒Бр░▓р▒Жр░др▒Нр░др░┐ р░ир░ор░╕р▒Нр░Хр░░р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░ир▒Б, р░Ер░нр░┐р░ир░Вр░жр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░ир▒Б. р░Ер░др▒Нр░др░пр▒Нр░пр░Хр▒Б р░ир░╛ р░ир░ор░╕р▒Нр░Хр░╛р░░р░╛р░▓р▒Б.р░Зр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б,р░ор▒А р░ор▒Зр░ир░Хр▒Лр░бр░▓р▒Б,р░╡р░┐. р░кр░жр▒Нр░о.р░Ър░┐р░░р▒Бр░ир░╛р░ор░╛ :р░Ор░╕р▒Н. р░ир░░р░╕р░┐р░Вр░╣р░╛р░░р░╛р░╡р▒Бр░Чр░╛р░░р▒Б,р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░Чр▒Б р░Йр░кр░╛р░зр▒Нр░пр░╛р░пр▒Бр░▓р▒Б,р░мр░╛р░▓р░┐р░Хр▒Лр░ир▒Нр░ир░д р░кр░╛р░ар░╢р░╛р░▓,р░ир░░р░╕р░░р░╛р░╡р▒Бр░кр▒Зр░Я, р░Чр▒Бр░Вр░Яр▒Вр░░р▒Б р░Ьр░┐р░▓р▒Нр░▓р░╛."},{"question":"Tori bi wс╗Нn с╣гe n ji awс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н gbe, с║╣gbс║╣ olukс╗Н lawс╗Нn maa ti ileewe pa","answer":"Pс║╣lu bi iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ jiji awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Нleewe ati olukс╗Н gbe lapa Oke-с╗Мya orileede yii с╣гe di lemс╗Нlemс╗Н, с║╣gbс║╣ awс╗Нn olukс╗Н Naijiria (Nigeria Union of Teachers), ati с║╣gbс║╣ awс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н (National Association of Nigerian Students), ti sс╗Н pe awс╗Нn maa tilс║╣kun awс╗Нn ileewe pa jake-jado orileede yii ni. Ki i с╣гe apa ariwa nikan o, tori ko si aabo to peye fawс╗Нn olukс╗Н ati akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н kaakiri mс╗Н bayii.Oru mс╗Нju с╗Нjс╗Н с║╕ti, Furaidee yii, lawс╗Нn agbebс╗Нn kan tun lс╗Нс╗Н ji awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Нс╗Нlewe akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н-binrin bii с╗Нс╗Нdunrun (300) ko nigba ti wс╗Нn с╣гi n sun lс╗Нwс╗Н, ti wс╗Нn si с╣гe bс║╣с║╣ ko wс╗Нn wс╗Нgbo lс╗Н.Nigba to n ba akс╗Нroyin wa sс╗Нrс╗Н lori aago nipa iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ yii, Dokita Mike Ene, to jс║╣ akс╗Н╠Аw├й apapс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ awс╗Нn olukс╗Н n├нlс║╣╠А wa, sс╗Н pe o ti han gbangba bayii pe niс╣гe lawс╗Нn kan fс║╣ diidi fawс╗Н aago itс║╣siwaju eto-с║╣kс╗Н lorileede yii sс║╣yin, tabi ki wс╗Нn tiс║╣ doju с║╣ de paapaa.тАЬAwс╗Нn iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ ijinigbe to n waye lс╗Нtun-un losi maa mu kawс╗Нn eeyan kaaarс║╣ с╗Нkan nipa eto с║╣kс╗Н, o si maa le awс╗Нn kan sa nileewe, wс╗Нn aa di alaabс╗Н с║╣kс╗Н, wс╗Нn o ni i fс║╣ lati tс║╣siwaju mс╗Н. Awс╗Нn to ba si n tiraka lс╗Н naa, inu ibс║╣rubojo ni wс╗Нn maa wa. Bawo leeyan с╣гe le kawe kiwee naa wс╗Нri nibi to ti n wo fс║╣tofс║╣to pс║╣lu ipaya boya awс╗Нn ajinigbe le waa ya bo wс╗Нn?тАЬA ti ri i pe awс╗Нn ileewe to jс║╣ kidaa с╗Нkunrin tabi obinrin ni wс╗Нn yan laayo lati maa с╣гe akс╗Нlu si bayii, lati mu kawс╗Нn majeс╣гin wс╗Нnyс║╣n ni irс║╣wс║╣si с╗Нkan nipa с║╣kс╗Н wс╗Нn, wahala tawс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н ti wс╗Нn ji ni Kagara la с╣гi n ba yi lс╗Нwс╗Н ti eleyii fi tun с╣гс║╣lс║╣. Bс╗Нrс╗Н с╣гe ri yii, ko sigba ta o ni ti awс╗Нn ileewe pa patapata, tori ko si aabo fawс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н ati olukс╗Н.A ti ni kijс╗Нba с╣гe fс║╣nsi sawс╗Нn ileewe ijс╗Нba gbogbo ki eto aabo ati aago idagiri si wa ni sс║╣pс║╣, с╣гugbс╗Нn wс╗Нn o ti i с╣гe bс║╣с║╣. A maa с╣гepade lori с╗Нrс╗Н yii,тАЭ bс║╣с║╣ ni akс╗Нwe apapс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ naa wi.с╗Мgbс║╣ni с╗Мlawale Samuс║╣l to jс║╣ oluс╣гekokaari ni Guusu/Iwс╗Н-Oorun с║╣gbс║╣ awс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н, NANS, ni tiс║╣ sс╗Н pe saka lo daju bayii pe ijс╗Нba ti kuna patapata lati pese aabo fun с║╣mi ati dukia awa с╗Нmс╗Н orileede yii.тАЬAwa akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н o nigbс║╣kс║╣le kan mс╗Н ninu ijс╗Нba yii, ijс╗Нba naa ko sapa to, wс╗Нn o si с╣гe ohun to yс║╣ lati dawс╗Н eto aabo to dс║╣nu kс╗Нlс║╣ yii duro. Awс╗Нn olori с║╣gbс║╣ awс╗Нn akс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н, NANS maa с╣гepade pajawiri lori с╗Нrс╗Н yii, a maa bс║╣rс║╣ iwс╗Нde kaakiri awс╗Нn ileewe, a si maa ri i pe a tilс║╣kun awс╗Нn ileewe pa, tori a o le jс║╣ kijс╗Нba sс╗Н с║╣mi awс╗Нn ewe ati с╗Нdс╗Н di nnkan iс╣гere lasan bii eyi.тАЭ"},{"question":"ржПржЗ ржЕржирзБржЪрзНржЫрзЗржжрзЗрж░ ржЬржирзНржп ржПржХржЯрж┐ ржзрж╛рж░рж╛ржмрж╛рж╣рж┐ржХрждрж╛ рж▓рж┐ржЦрзБржи :ржП ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛ржЯрж┐ ржЖрж░ржм ржЙржкржжрзНржмрзАржкрзЗрж░ ржмрж┐рж▓рзБржкрзНржд рж╣рж╛рж╢рзЗржорзА рж╣рзЗржЬрж╛ржЬ рж░рж╛ржЬрждржирзНрждрзНрж░рзЗрж░ ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛ ржПржмржВ ржЖрж░ржм рж╕ржорж╛ржЬрждрж╛ржирзНрждрзНрж░рж┐ржХ ржмрж╛'ржЖрж╕ ржкрж╛рж░рзНржЯрж┐рж░ ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛рж░ ржЕржирзБрж░рзВржк (рждржмрзЗ ржПрж░рж╛ рзи:рзй ржЕржирзБржкрж╛рждрзЗрж░ ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛ ржмрзНржпржмрж╣рж╛рж░ ржХрж░рзЗ; ржЖрж░ ржлрж┐рж▓рж┐рж╕рзНрждрж┐ржи рзз:рзи ржЕржирзБржкрж╛рждрзЗрж░ ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛ ржмрзНржпржмрж╣рж╛рж░ ржХрж░рзЗ)ред ржЗрж░рж╛ржХ ржУ ржЬрж░рзНржбрж╛ржи ржпрзЗ рж╕рзНржмрж▓рзНржкрж╕рзНржерж╛ржпрж╝рзА ржЖрж░ржм ржлрзЗржбрж╛рж░рзЗрж╢ржи ржЧржаржи ржХрж░рзЗржЫрж┐рж▓ рждрж╛рж░ ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛ржУ ржЕржирзЗржХржЯрж╛ ржПржХржЗ рж░ржХржо (рждржмрзЗ ржПрждрзЗ ржмрзНржпржмрж╣рзГржд рж▓рж╛рж▓ рждрзНрж░рж┐ржнрзБржЬржЯрж┐ рж╕ржоржмрж╛рж╣рзБ рждрзНрж░рж┐ржнрзБржЬ ржЫрж┐рж▓)ред ржПржЫрж╛ржбрж╝рж╛, ржЙрждрзНрждрж░ рж╕рж╛рж╣рж╛рж░рж╛ ржУ ржЬрж░рзНржбрж╛ржирзЗрж░ ржЬрж╛рждрзАржпрж╝ ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛рж░ рж╕рж╛ржерзЗржУ ржлрж┐рж▓рж┐рж╕рзНрждрж┐ржирзА ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛ржЯрж┐рж░ ржмрзЗрж╢ ржорж┐рж▓ рж░ржпрж╝рзЗржЫрзЗред ржПрж░ ржХрж╛рж░ржг рж╣рж▓рзЛ: ржПржЗ рж╕ржмржЧрзБрж▓рзЛ ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛рж░ ржиржХрж╢рж╛ржЗ ржЙрж╕ржорж╛ржирзАржпрж╝ рж╕рж╛ржорзНрж░рж╛ржЬрзНржпрзЗрж░ ржмрж┐рж░рзБржжрзНржзрзЗ","answer":"ржЖрж░ржм ржмрж┐ржжрзНрж░рзЛрж╣рзЗ ржмрзНржпржмрж╣рзГржд ржкрждрж╛ржХрж╛рж░ ржиржХрж╢рж╛рж░ ржЕржирзБржХрж░ржгрзЗ рждрзИрж░рж┐ ржХрж░рж╛ рж╣ржпрж╝рзЗржЫрзЗред"},{"question":"р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖Ур╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ \\"р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖К р╢Ър╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ъ\\" р╢Ур╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╢Тр╖Ар╖Пр╢║р╖Ъ р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕ р╢╕р╢н р╢┤р╢пр╢▒р╢╕р╖Кр╖А р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ь р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖Ур╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢Ьр╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖К р╢Ър╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ъ р╢Ур╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╢Тр╖Ар╖Пр╢║р╖Ъ р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕ р╢╕р╢н р╢┤р╢пр╢▒р╢╕р╖Кр╖А р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢пр╖Т р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ь р╢Ър╖Е р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ.1. 1843 р╢┤р╖Фр╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖П р╢║р╖Пр╢╕: р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕ р╖Гр╖Пр╢┤р╖Ър╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖А р╢Ър╖Фр╢йр╖П р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢нр╢╗, р╢Ер╖Ер╖Ф, р╖Ар╖Рр╢╜р╖Т р╖Гр╖Д р╢Ьр╢╜р╖К р╖Ар╖Тр╢╕р╖Эр╢ар╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕ р╢╕р╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢Вр╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Тр╢н р╖Ар╖Тр╢║. р╢╖р╖Цр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ър╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╖П  р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╢Ьр╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ър╢│р╖Ф р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢Ър╢╕р╖Кр╖Ар╢╜ р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╜р╢Ър╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╖Др╖Рр╢╗, р╖Гр╖Рр╢╜р╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖У р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╕р╖Рр╢н.2. 1963-64 р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕: р╢╕р╖Щр╢║ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖Ур╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Пр╢╜р╢нр╢╕ р╖Др╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖Пр╖Бр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖У р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ср╢Ър╢Ър╖Т. р╢Ср╢║ р╢Эр╖Эр╖Вр╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╖У р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К, р╢╜р╖Пр╖Ар╖П р╢Ьр╢╜р╖Пр╢║р╖Пр╢╕ р╖Гр╖Д р╢пр╖Рр╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Кр╢н р╢┤р╢║р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ьр╢Ър╖Кр╢╜р╖Рр╖Гр╖Кр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Кр╢╗р╖Ар╖Пр╖Др╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢нр╢╗, р╢Зр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╢╕р╖Ър╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Фр╢Ьр╢н р╢┤р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢Ьр╢╜р╢║р╢▒р╖К 1,100-1,500 р╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Тр╢║ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖Д. р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Гр╖Ф р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╖Вр╖Пр╢┤р╢нр╢▒р╢║ р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Ц р╖Гр╖Ур╢нр╢╜ р╢╜р╖Пр╖Др╖Пр╢╗р╖К р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢нр╖Тр╢╗р╖Ър╢Ъ р╢┤р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢Ьр╢╜р╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К 200 р╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Тр╢║ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖Д. р╢╕р╖Рр╢║р╖Т р╢╕р╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╢▒ р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢╕ р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ър╖Фр╢йр╖П р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╖Гр╢╗р╢Ър╢з р╢Жр╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢нр╖Фр╢▒р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕ р╢Лр╖Вр╖Кр╢лр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║ р╢╕р╢н р╢Ьр╖Эр╢╜р╖Ур╢║ р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╢╕р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ър╖Е р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ USAT Liberty р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢вр╢▒р╢┤р╢п р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ар╖Пр╖Др╢▒ р╢▒р╖Юр╢Ър╖Пр╖А р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢┤р╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖Тр╢║.3. 2017-2019 р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К: р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜ р╖Гр╖Ур╢╕р╖Пр╖А р╖Гр╖Рр╢╜р╢Ър╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢╖р╖Ц р╢Ър╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢▒ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╜р╢Ър╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢нр╢╗, р╢┤р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢Ьр╢╜р╢║р╢▒р╖К 122,500 р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╢╕р╢л р╢Йр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Тр╢║. р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢╕р╖Кр╖Ар╢╜р╢з р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╢╕р╖Рр╢Ьр╖Кр╢╕р╖Рр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Фр╖Ер╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Ц р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ер╖Ер╖Ф р╖Ар╢╜р╖Пр╢Ър╖Фр╖Ер╖Ф р╢╕р╖Ур╢зр╢╗р╖К 9,144р╢Ър╖К р╢Лр╖Гр╢з р╖Ер╢Яр╖П р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╢║р╢з р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Пр╢║р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╢┤р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢Ьр╢╜р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢нр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╗р╢лр╖Пр╢Ьр╢нр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢нр╖Рр╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢зр╢нр╖К, Ngurah Rai р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢нр╖Ьр╢зр╖Фр╢┤р╖Е р╖Ар╖Гр╖П р╢пр╖Рр╢╕р╖Ур╢╕р╢зр╢нр╖К, р╢вр╖Пр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗ р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢йр╖Пр╢╜ р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢зр╢нр╖К р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Тр╢║. 2018 р╖Гр╖Д 2019 р╖Др╖Т р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╢║р╢з р╢╢р╖Пр╢░р╖П р╢Ър╖Е р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ер╖Ар╢з р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢вр╖Пр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢╢р╢╜р╢┤р╖Ср╖Ар╖Ър╢║. р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ."},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐: рооро┐ройрпНройрогрпБроХрпН роХро┤ро┐ро╡рпБроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЕродройрпН роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБроЪрпН роЪрпВро┤ро▓рпН рокро╛родро┐рокрпНрокрпИ роиро╛роорпН роОро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒рпБ родрпАро░рпНроХрпНроХро▓ро╛роорпН?","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН: рооро┐ройрпН-роХро┤ро┐ро╡рпБроХро│рпИ роиро┐ро░рпНро╡роХро┐родрпНродро▓рпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ роЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рпБроЪрпНроЪрпВро┤ро▓ро┐ро▓рпН роироЪрпНроЪрпБрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроХро│рпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро┐роЯрпБро╡родрпИродрпН родроЯрпБроХрпНроХ рооро┐ройрпНройрогрпБ роЪро╛родройроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН рокрпКро▒рпБрокрпНрокро╛рой роЕроХро▒рпНро▒ро▓рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рооро▒рпБроЪрпБро┤ро▒рпНроЪро┐ роЖроХро┐ропро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпИ роЙро│рпНро│роЯроХрпНроХро┐ропродрпБ. рооро┐ройрпН-роХро┤ро┐ро╡рпБ рооро▒рпБроЪрпБро┤ро▒рпНроЪро┐ родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпИ роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБродро▓рпН, роиро┐ро▓рпИропро╛рой ро╡роЯро┐ро╡роорпИрокрпНрокрпБ роорпВро▓роорпН рооро┐ройрпНройрогрпБ роХро┤ро┐ро╡рпБроХро│рпИ роХрпБро▒рпИродрпНродро▓рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рооро┐ройрпНройрогрпБ родропро╛ро░ро┐рокрпНрокрпБ роЖропрпБроЯрпНроХро╛ро▓роорпН роирпАроЯрпНроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпИ роорпЗроорпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБродро▓рпН роЖроХро┐ропро╡рпИ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп роЙродрпНродро┐роХро│рпН."},{"question":" р╖Ар╢▒р╢║р╖Ъ р╢╗р╢вр╖Ф р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Др╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢▒ р╖Гр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║р╖Пр╢п?","answer":"р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢║р╖П  р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э  р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╖Др╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ \\"р╖Ар╢▒р╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ р╢╗р╢вр╖Ф\\" р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢╕р╖Пр╢нр╖Шр╢Ър╖Пр╖А р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢з р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ър╖Ър╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢Ъ р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢нр╖Ър╢вр╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢н р╢┤р╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╢╕ р╖Гр╖Д р╖Бр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║, р╢░р╖Ыр╢╗р╖Кр╢║р╢║ р╖Гр╖Д р╢▒р╖Пр╢║р╢Ър╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║ р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╖Гр╢Вр╢вр╖Пр╢▒р╢▒р╖Ур╢║ р╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢л р╢╕р╢н р╢┤р╢пр╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Рр╢╜р╖Ср╖Ар╢╜ р╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╢║ р╢▒р╖Ьр╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖Кр╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П  р╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢лр╢Ър╖Т. р╢Тр╖Ар╖П  р╢╢р╖Др╖Фр╢╜р╖А р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ер╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢нр╢лр╢╢р╖Тр╢╕р╖К, р╖Гр╖Рр╖Ар╖Пр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Д р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Шр╢н р╖Ар╢▒р╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗р╖Ар╢╜ р╖Гр╖Д р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢╗р╖К р╖Ар╢▒р╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ р╢║."},{"question":"H├гy ─Сс║╖t mс╗Щt ti├кu ─Сс╗Б ph├╣ hс╗гp vс╗Ыi ─Сoс║бn v─Гn sau: Tr╞░с╗Ыc khi b╞░с╗Ыc v├аo trс║нn th╞░ h├╣ng tс╗Сi nay, CLB H├а Nс╗Щi (17 ─Сiс╗Гm) ─Сang dс║лn ─Сс║зu bс║гng, h╞бn 1 ─Сiс╗Гm so vс╗Ыi ─Сс╗Щi xс║┐p ngay ph├нa sau l├а SLNA. N├│i c├бch kh├бc, mс╗Щt kс║┐t quс║г h├▓a c┼йng vс║лn gi├║p CLB H├а Nс╗Щi giс╗п vс╗Л tr├н ─Сс╗Йnh bс║гng. Tr├кn l├╜ thuyс║┐t, khi ch╞бi tr├кn s├вn H├аng ─Рс║лy, SLNA c┼йng kh├┤ng d├бm vс╗Щi ─Сс║йy cao ─Сс╗Щi h├мnh, m├а cс╗С gс║пng ch╞бi chс║пc chс║пn b├кn phс║зn s├вn nh├а, chс╗Э c╞б hс╗Щi tс╗л nhс╗пng ─С╞░с╗Эng phс║гn c├┤ng vс╗Ыi khс║г n─Гng c├аn l╞░с╗Ыt cс╗зa bс╗Щ ─С├┤i ngoс║бi binh Oseni - Olaha. Vс║еn ─Сс╗Б cс╗зa CLB H├а Nс╗Щi l├а cс║зn ph├бt huy tс╗Сi ─Сa khс║г n─Гng kiс╗Гm so├бt b├│ng, chс╗Э ─Сс╗Сi thс╗з sс╗Сt ruс╗Щt v├а khi ─С├│ nhс╗пng khoс║гng trс╗Сng sс║╜ mс╗Я ra. Diс╗Еn biс║┐n tr├кn s├вn cho thс║еy CLB H├а Nс╗Щi ─С├г nhс║нp cuс╗Щc ─Сс║зy chс╗з ─Сс╗Щng nh╞░ng bс║еt ngс╗Э lс║бi tс╗Ыi tс╗л ph├║t thс╗й 4. Trong mс╗Щt t├мnh huс╗Сng ─С╞░с╗гc h╞░с╗Яng phс║бt g├│c b├кn c├бnh tr├бi, Phan V─Гn ─Рс╗йc chuyс╗Бn v├аo v├▓ng cс║еm cho Olaha bс║нt cao ─С├бnh ─Сс║зu hiс╗Гm h├│c mс╗Я tс╗╖ sс╗С. B├аn thс║пng ─Сс║зy bс║еt ngс╗Э cс╗зa Olaha d╞░с╗Эng nh╞░ ─С├г khiс║┐n nhс╗пng t├нnh to├бn cс╗зa CLB H├а Nс╗Щi kh├┤ng ─Сi ─С├║ng h╞░с╗Ыng. V├а khi kh├┤ng c├│ HLV tr╞░с╗Яng ng╞░с╗Эi H├аn Quс╗Сc Chun Jae-ho tr├кn b─Гng ghс║┐ huс║еn luyс╗Зn v├м bс╗Л nhiс╗Еm Covid-19, CLB H├а Nс╗Щi ─С├г tс╗П ra n├│ng vс╗Щi trong nhс╗пng t├мnh huс╗Сng l├кn b├│ng. ─Рс╗Щi tr╞░с╗Яng V─Гn Quyс║┐t vс║лn thс╗Г hiс╗Зn ─С╞░с╗гc ─Сс╗Щ ─Сiс╗Бm t─йnh v├а kinh nghiс╗Зm trong nhс╗пng pha ─Сiс╗Бu tiс║┐t b├│ng nh╞░ng c├бc ─Сс╗Уng ─Сс╗Щi cс╗зa anh tr├кn h├аng c├┤ng nh╞░ Siladi, Tuс║еn Hс║гi, Xu├вn T├║ th├м kh├┤ng c├│ ─С╞░с╗гc ─Сiс╗Бu ─С├│. Trong khoс║гng 9 ph├║t thс╗л 21 ─Сс║┐n 29, V─Гn Quyс║┐t ─С├г 3 lс║зn ─С╞░a ra nhс╗пng ─С╞░с╗Эng kiс║┐n tс║бo rс║еt tс╗Сt nh╞░ng hoс║╖c Xu├вn T├║ ─С├б vс╗Нt x├а trong t╞░ thс║┐ ─Сс╗Сi mс║╖t thс╗з m├┤n V─Гn Ho├аng trong v├▓ng cс║еm; hoс║╖c Tuс║еn Hс║гi xс╗н l├╜ b╞░с╗Ыc 1 kh├┤ng tс╗Сt, ─Сс╗Г lс╗б mс║еt c╞б hс╗Щi c├│ thс╗Г dс╗йt ─Сiс╗Гm. T├мnh huс╗Сng c├▓n lс║бi ph├║t 29, V─Гn Hс║нu ─С├бnh ─Сс║зu vс╗Нt x├а cс║нn th├аnh tс╗л ─С╞░с╗Эng chuyс╗Бn b├кn c├бnh phс║гi cс╗зa V─Гn Quyс║┐t. Trong 45 ph├║t ─Сс║зu ti├кn, ngoс║бi binh Siladi thi ─Сс║еu kh├б mс╗Э nhс║бt. Pha b├│ng ─С├б ch├║ ├╜ duy nhс║еt cс╗зa Siladi l├а nс╗Ч lс╗▒c c├б nh├вn ─Сi b├│ng, dс╗йt ─Сiс╗Гm ngay s├бt v├▓ng cс║еm ph├║t 42 th├м lс║бi bс╗Л hс║нu vс╗З SLNA ─С├г ch╞бi l─Гn xс║г chс║╖n b├│ng, cс╗йu thua cho ─Сс╗Щi kh├бch. B├кn kia chiс║┐n tuyс║┐n, sau khi c├│ b├аn dс║лn tr╞░с╗Ыc, SLNA c├аng c├│ ─Сiс╗Бu kiс╗Зn thс╗Г hiс╗Зn r├╡ lс╗Сi ch╞бi ph├▓ng ngс╗▒-phс║гn c├┤ng v├а mс╗Щt c├║ s├║t nhanh ─Сс║зy bс║еt ngс╗Э с╗Я cс╗▒ ly khoс║гng 30m cс╗зa Oseni giс╗пa hiс╗Зp 1 ─С├г khiс║┐n thс╗з m├┤n Tс║еn Tr╞░с╗Эng giс║нt m├мnh kh├┤ng thс╗Г bс║пt d├нnh b├│ng. Sau giс╗Э nghс╗Й, ban huс║еn luyс╗Зn CLB H├а Nс╗Щi ─С├г ─С╞░a ngoс║бi binh ng╞░с╗Эi Croatia Tonci Mujan v├аo s├вn thс║┐ chс╗Ч Xu├вn T├║ ─Сс╗Г t─Гng c╞░с╗Эng sс╗йc mс║бnh tс║еn c├┤ng. V├а khi Tonci Mujan ch╞░a kс╗Лp ph├бt huy khс║г n─Гng th├м ngoс║бi binh Olaha b├кn ph├нa SLNA ─С├г l├аm \\"gi├║p\\". Trong mс╗Щt pha b├│ng rс║еt v├┤ hс║бi с╗Я giс╗пa s├вn ph├║t 49, tr╞░с╗Ыc khi bс║нt cao tranh b├│ng, b├аn tay cс╗зa Olaha lс║бi ─С╞░a ra c├│ chс╗з ├╜ tr├║ng mс║╖t ─Рс║нu V─Гn To├аn (sс╗С 8 - CLB H├а Nс╗Щi) ngay с╗Я g├│c quan s├бt thuс║нn lс╗гi cс╗зa trс╗Нng t├аi ch├нnh Nguyс╗Еn Mс║бnh Hс║гi. V├а trс╗Нng t├аi ─С├г lс║нp tс╗йc r├║t thс║╗ ─Сс╗П truс║еt quyс╗Бn thi ─Сс║еu cс╗зa ch├вn s├║t chс╗з lс╗▒c b├кn ph├нa SLNA. Mс╗Щt quyс║┐t ─Сс╗Лnh m├а c├бc cс║зu thс╗з v├а rс║еt ─С├┤ng C─РV SLNA c├│ mс║╖t tr├кn s├вn H├аng ─Рс║лy c├│ thс╗Г cho l├а nс║╖ng tay nh╞░ng Olaha c├│ lс║╜ chс╗Й biс║┐t tс╗▒ tr├бch m├мnh. \\"Vс║нn ─Сen Olaha\\" ch╞░a qua, SLNA lс║бi phс║гi nhс║нn th├кm mс╗Щt \\"─С├▓n\\" cho├бng v├бng ph├║t 51. Tс╗л pha tс║бt b├│ng \\"kh├│ chс╗Лu\\" b├кn c├бnh tr├бi cс╗зa V─Гn Hс║нu, Th├бi B├б Sang (sс╗С 86-SLNA) trong nс╗Ч lс╗▒c cс║гn ph├б ─С├г ─Сс╗Г b├│ng chс║бm tay trong v├▓ng cс║еm v├а ─Сс╗Щi kh├бch ─С├г phс║гi nhс║нn phс║бt ─Сс╗Бn. Tс╗л chс║еm 11m, Siladi ─С├г ─С├бnh bс║бi thс╗з m├┤n V─Гn Ho├аng, gс╗б h├▓a 1-1 cho CLB H├а Nс╗Щi. Ch╞бi thiс║┐u ng╞░с╗Эi nh╞░ng trong khoс║гng thс╗Эi gian sau ─С├│, SLNA mс╗Ыi l├а ─Сс╗Щi tс║бo ra nhiс╗Бu c╞б hс╗Щi khiс║┐n c├бc C─РV H├а Nс╗Щi \\"th├│t tim\\". Ph├║t 60, Phan V─Гn ─Рс╗йc solo, dс╗йt ─Сiс╗Гm t├бo bс║бo ngo├аi v├▓ng cс║еm khiс║┐n thс╗з m├┤n Tс║еn Tr╞░с╗Эng phс║гi bay ng╞░с╗Эi cс╗йu thua. Ngay trong t├мnh huс╗Сng phс║бt g├│c sau ─С├│, SLNA lс║бi tс║бo ra mс╗Щt c╞б hс╗Щi nguy hiс╗Гm khi Xu├вn Mс║бnh ─С├бnh ─Сс║зu l├аm thс╗з m├┤n Tс║еn Tr╞░с╗Эng b├│ tay nh╞░ng trung vс╗З Th├аnh Chung ─С├г ─Сс╗Нc t├мnh huс╗Сng cс╗▒c hay, bс╗Нc l├│t cс╗йu thua ngay tr├кn vс║бch v├┤i. Khi s├│ng gi├│ ─С├г qua, ─Сiс╗Бu g├м phс║гi ─Сс║┐n c┼йng ─С├г ─Сс║┐n с╗Я ph├║t 76. ─Р├║ng 1 ph├║t sau khi V─Гn Quyс║┐t dс╗йt ─Сiс╗Гm ─С╞░a b├│ng tr├║ng cс╗Щt dс╗Нc hс╗Пng ─Гn, CLB H├а Nс╗Щi ─С├г c├│ pha phс╗Сi hс╗гp rс║еt hiс╗Зn ─Сс║бi. Th├аnh Chung bс║нt cao ─С├бnh ─Сс║зu chuyс╗Бn b├│ng cho Tonci ─Сс╗Г ngoс║бi binh n├аy \\"l├аm t╞░с╗Эng\\" ng╞░с╗гc lс║бi cho ch├нnh Th├аnh Chung s├║t b├│ng n├вng tс╗╖ sс╗С l├кn 2-1. Khoс║гng thс╗Эi gian 15 ph├║t cuс╗Сi trс║нn, SLNA lс╗▒c bс║еt t├▓ng t├вm trong viс╗Зc t├мm c├бch tiс║┐p cс║нn khung th├аnh thс╗з m├┤n Tс║еn Tr╞░с╗Эng, chс║еp nhс║нn trс║пng tay rс╗Эi s├вn H├аng ─Рс║лy. Vс╗Ыi cuс╗Щc lс╗Щi ng╞░с╗гc d├▓ng th├аnh c├┤ng thс║пng chung cuс╗Щc 2-1, CLB H├а Nс╗Щi (20 ─Сiс╗Гm) ─С├г cс╗зng cс╗С chс║пc ng├┤i ─Сс║зu bс║гng, h╞бn nh├│m 3 ─Сс╗Щi xс║┐p sau 4 ─Сiс╗Гm gс╗Уm SLNA, HAGL, SHB.─Р├а Nс║╡ng.","answer":"Kс║┐t quс║г v├▓ng 10 V.League 2022: Thс║╗ ─Сс╗П, phс║бt ─Сс╗Бn khiс║┐n SLNA trс║пng tay tr╞░с╗Ыc CLB H├а Nс╗Щi"},{"question":"╪з┘Г┘Е┘Д ╪з┘Д╪м┘Е┘Д╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К╪й: ┘И╪н╪│╪и ╪к┘В╪▒┘К╪▒ \\"╪з┘Д╪м┘Б╪з┘Б ╪и╪з┘Д╪г╪▒┘В╪з┘Е\\" ╪з┘Д╪╡╪з╪п╪▒ ╪╣┘Ж ╪з╪к┘Б╪з┘В┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪г┘Е┘Е ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к╪н╪п╪й ┘Д┘Е┘Г╪з┘Б╪н╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪╡╪н╪▒ ╪╣╪з┘Е 2022╪М ┘Б╪е┘Ж ╪к┘Г┘Д┘Б╪й ╪к┘Д┘Б ╪з┘Д┘Е╪н╪з╪╡┘К┘Д ┘И╪з┘Д╪╣┘И╪з┘В╪и ╪з┘Д╪з┘В╪к╪╡╪з╪п┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪г╪о╪▒┘Й ┘Д┘Д╪м┘Б╪з┘Б ┘К┘Е┘Г┘Ж ╪г┘Ж ╪к┘Г┘И┘Ж ╪г╪╣┘Д┘Й 5 ┘Е╪▒╪з╪к ┘Е┘Е╪з ┘З┘К ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ╪з┘Д┘К┘И┘Е╪М ╪е╪░╪з ┘И╪╡┘Д","answer":"╪з┘Д╪з╪н╪к╪▒╪з╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪╣╪з┘Д┘Е┘К ╪е┘Д┘Й 3 ╪п╪▒╪м╪з╪к ┘Е╪ж┘И┘К╪й ╪и╪н┘Д┘И┘Д ╪╣╪з┘Е 2100 ┘Г┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ┘Е╪к┘И┘В╪╣."},{"question":"уВ╣уГЪуВдуГ│уБощЧШчЙЫуБзуАБуГЮуВ┐уГЙуГ╝уГлуБМуВжуВ╖уВТшкШуБЖуБоуБлф╜┐уБЖуАБцгТуБлх╖╗уБДуБЯш╡дуБДх╕ГуВТф╜ХуБиуБДуБЖуБзуБЧуВЗуБЖя╝Я","answer":"уГауГмуВ┐"},{"question":"р░ор░╛р░Яр░др▒Ар░░р▒Б р░Ер░Вр░Яр▒З р░Пр░ор░┐р░Яр▒Л р░╡р░┐р░╡р░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░ор░╛р░Яр░др▒Ар░░р▒Б р░Ер░Вр░Яр▒З р░ор░ир░В р░ор░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░бр▒З р░╡р░┐р░зр░╛р░ир░В. р░Ор░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░бр▒В р░╕р▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░┐р░др░Вр░Чр░╛, р░ор▒Гр░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░Чр░╛, р░Ър░┐р░░р▒Бр░ир░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Бр░др▒Л р░ор░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░бр▒З р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐р░ир░┐ р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡р░ор░Вр░жр░┐ р░Зр░╖р▒Нр░Яр░кр░бр░др░╛р░░р▒Б. р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐р░Хр░┐ р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡ р░╕р▒Нр░ир▒Зр░╣р░┐р░др▒Б р░▓р▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Ор░кр▒Нр░кр▒Бр░бр▒В р░Ър░┐р░░р░╛р░Хр▒Б р░кр░бр▒Бр░др▒В, р░кр░░р▒Бр░╖р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░ор░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░бр▒З р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐р░др▒Л р░Ор░╡р░░р▒В р░Хр░▓р░╡р░░р▒Б р░╡р░╛р░░р░┐р░др▒Л р░жр▒Вр░░р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░░р▒Б. р░ор░╛р░ир░╡ р░╕р░Вр░мр░Вр░зр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Нр░ир▒А р░ор░ир░В р░ор░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░бр▒З р░╡р░┐р░зр░╛р░ир░В р░кр▒Ир░ир▒З р░Жр░зр░╛р░░р░кр░бр░┐ р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐.р░╕р▒Бр░жр▒Ар░░р▒Нр░Шр░Хр░╛р░▓р░Вр░Чр░╛ р░ор░ир░┐р░╖р░┐ р░╕р░Вр░Шр░Ьр▒Ар░╡р░┐р░Чр░╛ р░ор░ир▒Бр░Чр░б р░╕р░╛р░Чр░┐р░Вр░Ър░Яр░В р░╡р▒Жр░ир▒Бр░Х р░Чр░▓ р░Ер░ир▒Зр░Х р░Ер░Вр░╢р░╛р░▓р░▓р▒Л р░ор░╛р░Яр░др▒Ар░░р▒Б р░Ър░╛р░▓р░╛ р░мр░▓р░ор▒Ир░и р░Ер░Вр░╢р░В. р░кр▒Нр░░р░др░┐ р░нр░╛р░╖р░Хр▒В р░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░др▒Нр░пр▒Зр░Х р░▓р░Хр▒Нр░╖р░гр░╛р░▓р▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░ир▒Бр░бр░┐р░Хр░╛р░░р░╛р░▓р▒Б. р░Ьр░╛р░др▒Ар░пр░╛р░▓р▒Б, р░╕р░╛р░ор▒Жр░др░▓р▒Б р░╡р░Вр░Яр░┐р░╡р░┐ р░Жр░пр░╛ р░нр░╛р░╖р░▓ р░Ер░╕р▒Нр░др░┐р░др▒Нр░╡р░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░др░┐р░╖р▒Нр░ар░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░пр░┐. р░Зр░╡р░┐ р░нр░╛р░╖р░╛ р░╕р▒Мр░Вр░жр░░р▒Нр░пр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Зр░ир▒Бр░ор░бр░┐р░Вр░к р░Ър▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░пр░┐. р░И р░╡р░┐р░╖р░пр░Вр░▓р▒Л р░ор░и р░ор░╛р░др▒Гр░нр░╛р░╖ р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░Чр▒Б р░Зр░др░░ р░нр░╛р░░р░др▒Ар░п р░нр░╛р░╖р░▓ р░Хр░Вр░Яр▒З р░Зр░Вр░Хр░╛ р░Хр▒Кр░Вр░д р░╡р░┐р░╢р░┐р░╖р▒Нр░Яр░Вр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐.р░╕р░ор░╛р░Ър░╛р░░р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░Ър▒Зр░░р░╡р▒Зр░п р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░ор░╛р░ир░╡ р░╕р░Вр░мр░Вр░зр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░ор▒Жр░░р▒Бр░Чр▒Бр░кр░░р▒Бр░Ър▒Бр░Хр▒Лр░╡р░Яр░╛р░ир░┐р░Хр░┐ р░нр░╛р░╖р░▓р▒Л р░ор░ир░В р░Ер░ир▒Зр░Х р░кр░жр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░Ер░▓р░╡р▒Лр░Хр░Чр░╛ р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░╡р▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░В. р░Ер░╡р░┐ р░ор░и р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╣р░╛р░░р░Вр░▓р▒Л р░Хр░▓р░┐р░╕р░┐р░кр▒Лр░пр░┐ р░╡р▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░И р░кр░жр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░ор░и р░╕р░╛р░ор░╛р░Ьр░┐р░Х тАУ р░╕р░╛р░Вр░╕р▒Нр░Хр▒Гр░др░┐р░Х, р░Ър░╛р░░р░┐р░др▒Нр░░р░Х, р░Жр░░р▒Нр░ер░┐р░Х р░Ер░Вр░╢р░╛р░▓р░др▒Л р░ор▒Бр░бр░┐р░кр░бр░┐ р░╡р▒Бр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░╡р▒Ар░Яр░┐р░ир░┐ р░кр▒Нр░░р░пр▒Лр░Чр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒В р░ор░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░бр▒Б р░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░кр▒Бр░бр▒Б р░ор░и р░ор░╛р░Яр░др▒Ар░░р▒Б р░Ор░Яр▒Бр░╡р░Вр░Яр░┐р░жр▒Л р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐."},{"question":"Qual ├й o signo do zod├нaco associado a pessoas nascidas entre 23 de julho e 22 de agosto?","answer":"O signo do zod├нaco associado a pessoas nascidas entre 23 de julho e 22 de agosto ├й Le├гo."},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ╪в╪о╪▒ ╪з┘Е╪▒╪г╪й ╪к╪▓┘И╪м┘З╪з ╪▒╪│┘И┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╡┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ┘И╪│┘Д┘Е╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ┘Е┘К┘Е┘И┘Ж╪й ╪и┘Ж╪к ╪з┘Д╪н╪з╪▒╪л"},{"question":"Dhaqanka Soomalida?","answer":"Dhaqanka Soomalida?Sheekooyinka Wiilwaal oo ay soomaalidu isu weriyaan waxaa kamid ah mar ayodayaal beeshiisa ah inta u yimaadeen isaga oo hurda ay ka xishoodeen inaykiciyaan, markii ay xaaskii Wiilwaal ka codsadeen inay u kiciso, inta dul istaagtayayay haraati ku kicisey. Xushmadda ay dumarku ku lahaayeen dhaqanka reerguuraaga soomaaliyeed, waxay ahayd mid muuqata xilli walba oo ay beeluhu kusugnaayeen. Arrintaasina waxaa laga garan karaa sida Raage Ugaas looga xaalmariyey xaaskiisii mar uu gabey wax uga sheegay. Raage, gabaygaas wuxuu kutilmaamayay falal uu quursadey oo uu gabadha ku arkey. Raage wuxuu yiri :-тАЬNaa soow Xaliimaay Xadiyo xaalna kama raacdid,Naa soow dabkuba waa xurmee xaabo lama saaro,Naa soow ardaagaan xunka ah waana lama xaaqo,Naa soow xalid laguma dayo xeeradiyo dhiisha,Allahayoow xaraaraa anfaci xaleyto la┬┤ isiiyeyтАжтАЭAflagaaddada uu gabaygaas gaystey ayaa Raage waxaa lagu xukumay inuu gabadha siiyo kala bar magteedii oo dhan 50 halaad. Waxaa kale oo jirtey sheeko dhacdey mar Saahid Qamaan gabar uu jeclaa oo Mullaaxo la oran jiray uu nin xoolo badan leh ka qaaday. Qoyskii Saahid ayaa waxay u dooreen gabadhii qoyskooda ugu qurux badnayd si uu u illaawo Mullaaxo. Habeenkii markii gabadhii loo guri geeyay ayay gabadhii waxay istiri si uu ninku u illaawo gabadhuu jeclaa bal wax kasta oo uu uga samri karo u samee. Waxay ku dadaashay inay wax kasta oo uu jeclaysan karo horgeyso. Hufnaan sariireed, haybad dhago nugayl, haasaawe dabacsan, hooh gacanqabow, iyo heeh walaale waxaan ahayn kuma holliso. Gaarinnimo, gacalnimo,bilic gaammurtay, iyo xaal gobeed ayay gundhig uga dhigtay jeceylkeeda aangaamurin. Habeenkii danbe ayay iyada oo isleh ninku gabadhii hore ha illaawomaskaxdiisana kasaar, ayay waxay usoo dhigtay haruub si wanaagsan loo culayoo caano xoor lihi afkaa ka hayaan, waxayna soo raacisay luqmad ama oodkacay haweeney jari taqaan si wanaagsan ugu soo farayaraysatay, laguna soodaray neef yar oo xilli gu'ah jooga subaggiis, markaas ayay ku tiri, \\" Baashe balisku day xoogaagaan luqmadda ah, raallina ka noqo intaad caanaha lisiddoodasugaysay \\".  Dabadeed, inta dacalka maradeeda kusii jiidday ayay ku tiri, iskanadaa hammiga iyo walaaca aad la foorartid. Odaygii Saahid ahaa, afka ma saarinwixii cunto lasoo hordhigay. Markii ay tiri, \\" Saahid walaale maxaad cunnada uqaadan waydey, miyaad xanuunsan tahay?\\" Saahid wuxuu ku taamaygabaygaan, ay tixihiisa ka mid ahaayeen:-тАЬтАжHaruub laban ah caanaha hoyaad halab karuurkeeda,Hilibka cusub haydaari iyo sogob la hoogaanshay,Habka fudud halkaan yeel ku oran hagar la'aantaada,Habkaad igu baayici kabahaad howda kaga yeerin,Haween baad tahee adiga oon hadin kobtaan joogo,Waa habbi la'aan dhuunigaad hoo ileedahaye,Hindisaha Mullaaxaa qalbigu haabo leeyahaye,Haasaawahaan qaybsannaa magac habeenkiiye,Adoon i hubsan soortaad halligi haysku hanaq goyne,Haraggayga uun baad arkiye kuuma soo hoyaneтАЭ.Gabaygu wuu dheeraa laakiin gabadhii waxay la gam'i waydey habeenkaasereyga ah тАЬHindisaha Mullaaxaa qalbigu haabo leeyahaye, Haraggayga uun baadarkiye kuuma soo hoyaneтАЭ. Waxay ogaatay in Saahid xabbad ku dhuftay, maxaayeelay waxay u qaadan waydey jacaylkii ay islahayd bal abuur oo wiilku yuusunku baabi'in jacaylkii laga qaaday, waxay kaloo istiri ninku waa qoyskaa oo ficilo ayaa ku khasabtay inay u hoyato, waxayse la kulantay dhacdadaas foosha xuniyo inuu ku caayo cunto siintii iyo raaligelintii ay ku wanaajinaysay. Habeenkaasayay goor madoow ka guuraysay, tolkii markay maqleenna sida gabadha loogalay, waxaa Saahid lagu xukumay oo laga qaaday magteedii illeen wuu dilaye."},{"question":"шп╖ф╗Лч╗Нф╕ЛцФпф╗ШхоЭ","answer":"цФпф╗ШхоЭцШпф╕нхЫ╜цЬАхдзчЪДчммф╕ЙцЦ╣чз╗хКихТМхЬич║┐цФпф╗Шх╣│хП░я╝МчФ▒щШ┐щЗМх╖┤х╖┤щЫЖхЫвф║О2004х╣┤хЬиф╕нхЫ╜цЭнх╖ЮхИЫчлЛя╝МцЬАхИЭцШпф╜Ьф╕║щШ┐щЗМх╖┤х╖┤щЫЖхЫвцЧЧф╕Лц╖ШхоЭч╜СчЪДхЬич║┐цФпф╗ШцЬНхКбх╣│хП░уАВцФпф╗ШхоЭцПРф╛Ыф║Жф╕АчзНх┐лщАЯуАБцЦ╣ф╛┐уАБхоЙхЕичЪДцФпф╗ШцЦ╣х╝Пя╝МчФицИ╖хПпф╗еф╜┐чФицФпф╗ШхоЭш┐ЫшбМхЬич║┐ш┤нчЙйуАБш╜мш┤жуАБч╝┤ш┤╣уАБцКХш╡ДчнЙхРДчзНф║дцШУуАВхРМцЧ╢я╝МцФпф╗ШхоЭф╣Яф╕║хХЖхо╢цПРф╛Ыф║Жф╕АчзНцФ╢цм╛чЪДцЦ╣х╝Пя╝МхПпф╗ех╕охКйхХЖхо╢цПРщлШф║дцШУцХИчОЗя╝МщЩНф╜Ош┐РшРецИРцЬмуАВщЩдф║ЖхЯ║чбАчЪДцФпф╗ШхКЯшГ╜я╝МцФпф╗ШхоЭш┐ШцОихЗ║ф║Жф╕Ач│╗хИЧчЪДщЗСшЮНцЬНхКбя╝МхжВф╜ЩщвЭхоЭуАБшЪВшЪБшК▒хСЧуАБшЪВшЪБхАЯхСЧчнЙя╝Мф╕║чФицИ╖цПРф╛Ыф║Жф╛┐цН╖чЪДчРЖш┤вхТМф┐бш┤╖цЬНхКбуАВцФпф╗ШхоЭчЪДхоЙхЕицАзх╛ЧхИ░ф║Жх╣┐ц│ЫшодхПпя╝МхоГщЗЗчФиф║ЖхдЪщЗНхКахпЖцКАцЬпхТМхоЮхРНхИ╢шодшпБя╝МцЬЙцХИщШ▓цнвф║Жцм║шпИхТМчЫЧчкГшбМф╕║уАВщЪПчЭАчз╗хКиф║ТшБФч╜СчЪДхПСх▒Хя╝МцФпф╗ШхоЭх╖▓ч╗ПцИРф╕║ф╕нхЫ╜ф║║чФЯц┤╗ф╕нф╕НхПпцИЦч╝║чЪДф╕АщГихИЖя╝МцЧашо║цШпхЬич║┐ф╕Кш┐ШцШпч║┐ф╕Ля╝МцФпф╗ШхоЭщГ╜хЬихРДчзНхЬ║цЩпф╕нхПСцМечЭАщЗНшжБчЪДф╜ЬчФиуАВ"},{"question":"misy firy ny karazana sekoly ary inona avy izy ireo?","answer":"misy karazany telo ny sekoly: ny sekolim-panjakana, ny sekolim-pinoana, ary ny sekoly tsy miankina"},{"question":"ри╕ри╛ри▓ 2010 тАЩриЪ риЖриИ тАШри╣ри╛риКри╕рилрйБрй▒ри▓тАЩ рижрйА ри╕рйЮри▓ридри╛ ридрйЛриВ римри╛риЕриж ри╕ри╛риЬри┐риж рйЩри╛рии риЙри╕ рижри╛ ри╕рйАриХрйБриЕри▓ тАШри╣ри╛риКри╕рилрйБрй▒ри▓-2тАЩ ри▓рйИ риХрйЗ риЖриП ри╣рии рикри░ риЗри╕ рйЮри┐ри▓рио рижрйА рйЩри╛ри╕рйАриЕрид риЗри╣ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЗри╕ рижрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риХри┐ри░рижри╛ри░ риири╡рйЗриВ ри╣рииред риХри╣ри╛ригрйА ри╡рйА риири╡рйАриВ ри╣рйИред рижрйЛри╡ри╛риВ рйЮри┐ри▓риори╛риВ тАЩриЪ ри╕риори╛рииридри╛ риЗри╣ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ ри╕ри╛ри░рйАриЖриВ риШриЯриири╛ри╡ри╛риВ риЗрй▒риХ тАШри╣ри╛риКри╕тАЩ ринри╛ри╡ риШри░ рижрйЗ риЕрй░рижри░ ри╣рйА ри╡ри╛рикри░рижрйАриЖриВ ри╣рииред риЗри╕ рйЮри┐ри▓рио тАЩриЪ рикри╣ри┐ри▓рйА ри╡ри╛ри░ ри╕ри╛риЬри┐риж рйЩри╛рии риирйЗ ри╣ри┐рй░рижрйА ри╕ри┐риирйЗриори╛ рижрйЗ ридри┐рй░рии риори╣ри╛риВри░риерйАриЖриВ ри░ри┐ри╢рйА риХрикрйВри░, ри░ригризрйАри░ риХрикрйВри░ риЕридрйЗ риори┐риерйБрии риЪрй▒риХри░ри╡ри░ридрйА риирйВрй░ ри╣ри┐рй▒ри╕ри╛ римригри╛риЗриЖ ри╣рйИред риЗри╕ рижрйЗ риири╛ри▓ риЖри╕ри┐рии риирйЗ ри╡рйА риЗри╕ рйЮри┐ри▓рио тАЩриЪ риРриВриЯри░рйА риХрйАридрйА ри╣рйИред ри╕ри╛риЬри┐риж рижри╛ риХри╣ри┐ригри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЙри╣ римриЪрикрии ридрйЛриВ риори┐риерйБрии рижрйЗ рикрйНри░ри╢рй░ри╕риХ ри░ри╣рйЗ ри╣рии ридрйЗ риЙри╕ риирйЗ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйА ри╣ри░ рйЮри┐ри▓рио рижрйЗриЦрйА ри╣рйИред римриЪрикрии тАЩриЪ риорйИриВ риЙриирйНри╣ри╛риВ рижрйА риириХри▓ риХри░ри┐риЖ риХри░рижри╛ ри╕рйАред ри╕ри╛риЬри┐риж рижри╛ риХри╣ри┐ригри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риорйИриВ рикри░ри┐ри╡ри╛ри░риХ рйЮри┐ри▓рио римригри╛риЙриг ри╡ри╛ри▓рйЗ риири┐ри░рижрйЗри╢риХ рижрйЗ ри░рйВрик тАЩриЪ тАШримрйНри░ри╛риВрибтАЩ римриг риЪрйБрй▒риХри┐риЖ ри╣ри╛риВ ридрйЗ риЗри╕ риирйВрй░ риХрижрйЗ римрижри▓ригри╛ риири╣рйАриВ риЪри╛ри╣рйБрй░рижри╛редрйЮри┐ри▓рио тАШри╣ри╛риКри╕рилрйБрй▒ри▓ -2тАЩ риЗрй▒риХ рижри░риЬрии рибри░риЯрйА ри▓рйЛриХри╛риВ рижрйЗ риХри╛ри░риири╛риори┐риЖриВ рижрйА рижри╛ри╕ридри╛рии ри╣рйИред риЗри╣ риХри╣ри╛ригрйА риЪри╛ри░ рикри┐ридри╛, риЪри╛ри░ ризрйАриЖриВ ридрйЗ ри╣рйЛриг ри╡ри╛ри▓рйЗ риЪри╛ри░ риЬри╡ри╛риИриЖриВ рижрйБриЖри▓рйЗ риШрйБрй░риорижрйА ри╣рйИред ри╣ри░рйЗриХ рикри┐ридри╛ риЪри╛ри╣рйБрй░рижри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЙри╕ рижрйА ризрйА рижри╛ ри╡ри┐риЖри╣ рижрйБриирйАриЖриВ рижрйЗ ри╕рин ридрйЛриВ риЕриорйАри░ риЗриири╕ри╛рии риири╛ри▓ ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗ ридрйЗ ри╣ри░ ризрйА рижрйА ри╡рйА риЗри╣рйА риЗрй▒риЫри╛ ри╣рйИред риЗри╕ рйЮри┐ри▓рио тАЩриЪ риЪри╛ри░рйЗ риЬри╡ри╛риИ риЗри╣рйА рижри┐риЦри╛риЙриг рижрйА риХрйЛри╢ри┐ри╢ риХри░ ри░ри╣рйЗ ри╣рии риХри┐ риЙри╣ ри╕рин ридрйЛриВ риЕриорйАри░ риЬри╡ри╛риИ ри╣рииред риЗри╕ ри╕рин риХри╛ри░рии ри╣ри╛ри╕ри░ри╕ риШриЯриири╛ри╡ри╛риВ ри╡ри╛рикри░рижрйАриЖриВ ри╣рииред риорйЫрйЗрижри╛ри░ риЧрй▒ри▓ риЗри╣ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риЗрй▒риХ-рижрйВриЬрйЗ рижрйЗ рйЩри┐ри▓ри╛рйЮ риири╛ ри╣рйЛ риХрйЗ риЗрй▒риХ риШри░ тАЩриЪ риЗрй▒риХ риЫрй▒рид ри╣рйЗриа ри░ри╣ри┐ риХрйЗ риЗрй▒риХ-рижрйВриЬрйЗ риирйВрй░ риори╛рид рижрйЗриг римри╛ри░рйЗ ри╕рйЛриЪрижрйЗ ри╣рииредтАШри╣ри╛риКри╕рилрйБрй▒ри▓-2тАЩ рижрйА риЗрй▒риХ рйЩри╛ри╕рйАриЕрид ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЕриори┐ридри╛рин римрй▒риЪрии ридрйЗ ри╡ри┐риирйЛриж риЦрй░риири╛ рижрйА ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риЗри╕ рйЮри┐ри▓рио тАЩриЪ риЕриХри╢рйИ риХрйБриори╛ри░ ридрйЗ риЬри╛рй▒рии риЕримри░ри╛ри╣ри┐рио рижрйЗ риЖрикри╕ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪ ри▓рйЬрии рижрйЗ рижрйНри░ри┐ри╢ ри╣рииред риЗри╕ ри╡рй▒рибрйЗ римриЬриЯ рижрйА рйЮри┐ри▓рио рижрйЗ риири┐ри░риори╛ридри╛ ри╕ри╛риЬри┐риж риири╛рибри┐риЖрибри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ рижри╛ риХри╣ри┐ригри╛ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ ри╡рй▒рибрйЗ рикрй▒ризри░ рижрйА ри╡рй▒рибрйЗ римриЬриЯ ри╡ри╛ри▓рйА ридрйЗ риРриирйЗ риХри▓ри╛риХри╛ри░ри╛риВ ри╡ри╛ри▓рйА рйЮри┐ри▓рио риЕрй▒риЬ рижрйЗ рйЫриори╛риирйЗ тАЩриЪ римригри╛риЙригри╛ ри╕рйМриЦри╛ риири╣рйАриВредриЗри╕ рйЮри┐ри▓рио тАЩриЪ ри░ри┐ри╢рйА риХрикрйВри░, ри░ригризрйАри░ риХрикрйВри░, риори┐риерйБрии риЪрй▒риХри░ри╡ри░ридрйА, ри░ригриЬрйАрид, римрйЛриории риИри░ри╛риирйА, риЕриХри╢рйИ риХрйБриори╛ри░, риЬри╛рй▒рии риЕримри░ри╛ри╣ри┐рио, ри░ри┐ридрйЗри╢ рижрйЗри╢риорйБрй▒риЦ, ри╢рйНри░рйЗриЖри╕ ридри▓рикрйЬрйЗ, риЖри╕ри┐рии, риЬрйИриХри▓ри┐рии рилри░риири╛риВрибрйЗрйЫ, ри╢ри╣ри┐риЬри╛рии рикрижриори╕рйА, риЬри╛риирйА ри▓рйАри╡ри░, риЪрй░риХрйА рикри╛риВрибрйЗ, ри╡ри┐ри░рйЗриВрижри░ ри╕риХри╕рйИриири╛ риЖрижри┐ риХри▓ри╛риХри╛ри░ риХрй░рио риХри░ ри░ри╣рйЗ ри╣рииредриЗри╣ рйЮри┐ри▓рио ри╕ри┐риирйЗриори╛ риШри░ри╛риВ рижри╛ ри╢ри┐рй░риЧри╛ри░ римриг риЪрйБрй▒риХрйА ри╣рйИ риЕридрйЗ риХри╛риорйЗрибрйА риири╛ри▓ ринри░рикрйВри░ риЗри╕ рйЮри┐ри▓рио риирйВрй░  рижри░ри╢риХри╛риВ ри╡рй▒ри▓рйЛриВ риЪрй░риЧри╛ ри╣рйБри▓ри╛ри░ри╛ риори┐ри▓ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйИредрикрйНри░ри╢риириГ рйЮри┐ри▓рио  тАШри╣ри╛риКри╕рилрйБрй▒ри▓-2тАЩ риХри┐ри╕ рикрйНри░риХри╛ри░ рижрйА ри╣рйИ?","answer":"риЙрй▒ридри░риГ рйЮри┐ри▓рио  тАШри╣ри╛риКри╕рилрйБрй▒ри▓-2тАЩ  риХри╛риорйЗрибрйА риири╛ри▓ ринри░рикрйВри░ ри╣рйИред"},{"question":"р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢Ър╢нр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╢╗р╢║р╢з р╖Гр╖Фр╢пр╖Фр╖Гр╖Ф р╢╕р╖Пр╢нр╖Шр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒. р╢Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ьр╢╕р╢Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖П р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢нр╢╕р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Пр╢п р╖Гр╢╕р╢Я р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╢Ър╖К р╢║р╖Пр╢╕р╢з р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П. р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Щр╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖П р╢зр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╢з р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з, р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╢Ър╖Ф р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢▒р╖Рр╢Ьр╖У, р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╢Ър╖К р╢║р╢▒ р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╢Ър╖Ф р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢з р╢╕р╖Фр╢л р╢Ьр╖Рр╖Гр╖Фр╢лр╖П.\\"р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║р╖Т р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╢║р╖Т р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒ р╢╕р╖Эр╢йр╢║р╖Э р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖Кр╢п ? р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖П р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢Лр╢й р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Фр╖А р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒ р╢Ср╖Др╖Щр╢Ър╢зр╢п р╢╢р╖Фр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╢Ъ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ.\\" р╢║р╖Рр╢║р╖Т р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П р╢Фр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Кр╢╕р╢з р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖П. р╢Йр╢нр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒ р╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╢▒р╖П р╢Ър╢╜ р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖П, р╢нр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╖Пр╖А р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖П р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢Лр╢йр╢з р╢▒р╢Вр╖Ар╖П р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒ р╢║р╖Пр╢╕р╢з р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П. р╢Йр╢нр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Фр╖Др╖Ьр╢╕ р╢нр╖А р╢зр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Щр╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖П р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Ер╖П. р╢║р╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗р╢╕р╢Ьр╢пр╖У р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Ьр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢╕р╖Фр╢л р╢Ьр╖Рр╖Гр╖Фр╢лр╖П. р╢Ср╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Г р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Щр╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖П р╢пр╖Щр╖Г р╢╢р╢╜р╖П \\"р╢Ер╢▒р╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Щр╢╕р╢нр╖К р╢Ър╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╖Рр╢╜р╖Т р╖Ер╢╕р╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖К. р╖Ар╖Рр╢йр╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢Ьр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢пр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щ р╢▒р╖С. р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖П р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖П р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╢Ър╢▒р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Ар╖П.р╖Ер╢╕р╢║р╖П р╖Др╖Ьр╢│р╢з р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╢Ьр╖Щ р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢Лр╢й р╢║р╢▒р╖Ар╖П\\" р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Щр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П. р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖П р╢зр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╢Ьр╖Ьр╖Гр╖К р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╖П р╖А р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖П р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖П, р╢Фр╖Др╖Ф р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖П р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢Лр╢й р╢▒р╖Рр╢Ь р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П. р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Щр╢╕ р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢зр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Ер╖П. р╢▒р╖Рр╖Ар╢нр╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Щр╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Пр╢з р╢┤р╖Пр╢╗р╖Ъ р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╖Др╢╕р╖Ф р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П. \\"р╢Ер╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ер╢п р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╖Ъ р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢╜р╖П р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Др╖Рр╢зр╖Т. р╢нр╢╕р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╖Ер╢╕р╢║р╖П р╢┤р╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Ар╖П.р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖П р╖Др╖Ьр╢│р╖Др╖Рр╢зр╖Т р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╢Ьр╖Щ р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢Лр╢й р╢║р╢▒р╖Ар╖П. р╖Ер╢╕р╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢Жр╢пр╢╗р╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╖Гр╖Ф\\" р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢╢р╢▒р╖Тр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ср╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Г р╢п р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖П. р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢Ър╢нр╖Пр╖А р╢Зр╖Гр╖Ц р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢пр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Пр╢п р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢Лр╢й р╢▒р╢Вр╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢пр╖Фр╢╗ р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П. р╢нр╖А р╢пр╖Фр╢╗ р╢║р╢▒р╢Ър╖Ьр╢з р╢Жр╢║р╖Щр╢╕р╢нр╖К р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢Ьр╢╜р╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Фр╢лр╢Ьр╖Рр╖Гр╖Фр╢лр╖П. \\"р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Щр╢╕р╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╖Гр╖Ф.!! р╢Ер╢╗ р╢Ер╖Др╖Тр╢Вр╖Гр╢Ъ р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╖Ъ р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║р╖Т р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╢║р╖Т р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢╕ р╢║р╢▒ р╢Ер╢┤р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖А. р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖А р╢з р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╢нр╢╗р╢╕р╖К р╢Ер╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Ф р╢Зр╢пр╖Кр╢п ? р╖Др╖Тр╢нр╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╢┤р╖Фр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖С.\\" р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖П. р╢Ер╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢╕р╖Ър╢пр╖У, р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢нр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢║р╖Т р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╢║р╖Т р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖П р╢з р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖П р╢Ър╢╗р╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П.р╢╕р╢Ьр╢пр╖У р╖Др╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╖Щр╢▒ р╖Др╖Рр╢╕р╖Эр╢╕ р╢╕р╖Ъ р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╖Др╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╖Ар╖Фр╢лр╖П. р╖Др╖Рр╢╕р╖Эр╢╕ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒ р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖Тр╖Др╢з р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢╕ р╢нр╢╕р╢║р╖Т р╢╕р╖Щр╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╖Ар╖Рр╢й р╖Гр╖Тр╢пр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ. ","answer":"р╢┤р╖Тр╢║р╖П, р╢┤р╖Фр╢нр╖П р╖Гр╖Д р╢╢р╖Цр╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒"},{"question":"H├гy viс║┐t tiс║┐p nс╗Щi dung cho ─Сoс║бn v─Гn sau: Nhс╗пng chiс║┐c si├кu xe, xe si├кu sang h├аng chс╗еc tс╗╖ ─Сс╗Уng lu├┤n l├а niс╗Бm ao ╞░с╗Ыc cс╗зa nhiс╗Бu ng╞░с╗Эi. Tuy nhi├кn, viс╗Зc sс╗Я hс╗пu mс╗Щt chiс║┐c xe nh╞░ vс║нy kh├┤ng chс╗Й l├а mua vс╗Б v├а sс╗н dс╗еng m├а c├▓n li├кn quan ─Сс║┐n h├аng loс║бt c├бc vс║еn ─Сс╗Б kh├бc ─Сс╗з ─Сс╗Г khiс║┐n chс╗з nh├вn tс╗л cс║гm thс║еy \\"s╞░с╗Ыng run ng╞░с╗Эi\\" mс╗Чi khi cс║зm l├бi trс╗Я n├кn lo ├вu. Hс║б tс║зng, mс║нt ─Сс╗Щ giao th├┤ng Tuy hс║б tс║зng giao th├┤ng c├│ thс╗Г n├│i l├а kh├┤ng c├▓n kh├│ kh─Гn ─Сс╗Г nhс╗пng chiс║┐c si├кu xe gс║зm thс║еp di chuyс╗Гn nh╞░ hс╗Уi mс╗Ыi ─С╞░с╗гc ─С╞░a vс╗Б Viс╗Зt Nam. Tuy nhi├кn, vс║лn c├▓n ─С├│ nhiс╗Бu kh├│ kh─Гn ─Сс╗Г nhс╗пng chiс║┐c xe n├аy c├│ thс╗Г ─Сi thoс║гi m├бi. Chс║еt l╞░с╗гng ─С╞░с╗Эng kh├┤ng tс╗Сt mang ─Сс║┐n cс║гm gi├бc kh├┤ng thoс║гi m├бi khi sс╗н dс╗еng xe, ─Сс╗Уng thс╗Эi khiс║┐n c├бc chi tiс║┐t c╞б kh├н, ─Сiс╗Зn tс╗н с╗Я hс╗З thс╗Сng treo hoс║бt ─Сс╗Щng nhiс╗Бu h╞бn. Mс║╖t kh├бc, mс║нt ─Сс╗Щ giao th├┤ng ─С├┤ng ─С├║c tс║бi c├бc th├аnh phс╗С lс╗Ыn (n╞бi tс║нp trung hс║зu hс║┐t xe ─Сс║пt tiс╗Бn tс║бi n╞░с╗Ыc ta) c┼йng l├а mс╗Щt vс║еn ─Сс╗Б m├а c├бc chс╗з xe phс║гi bс║нn t├вm. ─Рiс╗Бu n├аy khiс║┐n chс╗з sс╗Я hс╗пu trс╗Я n├кn e d├и mс╗Чi khi xuс╗Сng phс╗С do lo ngс║бi va quс║╣t. Chс║еt l╞░с╗гng nhi├кn liс╗Зu Tс║бi Viс╗Зt Nam, loс║бi nhi├кn liс╗Зu cao cс║еp nhс║еt hiс╗Зn tс║бi l├а x─Гng RON 97, mс╗Щt loс║бi nhi├кn liс╗Зu ph├╣ hс╗гp vс╗Ыi nhс╗пng chiс║┐c si├кu xe, xe sang ─Сс║пt tiс╗Бn. Tuy nhi├кn, loс║бi nhi├кn liс╗Зu n├аy vс║лn ch╞░a ─С╞░с╗гc phс╗Х biс║┐n v├а ─Сa sс╗С vс║лn phс║гi d├╣ng x─Гng RON 95. Vс╗Ыi nhс╗пng chс╗з nh├вn kс╗╣ t├нnh, RON 95 vс║лn ch╞░a ph├╣ hс╗гp v├а c├│ thс╗Г sс║╜ g├вy h╞░ hс╗Пng vс╗Б sau cho xe cс╗зa hс╗Н. ─Рс╗Г khс║пc phс╗еc, nhс╗пng ng╞░с╗Эi n├аy th╞░с╗Эng sс╗н dс╗еng phс╗е gia t─Гng octane cho x─Гng. C╞б sс╗Я bс║гo d╞░с╗бng Si├кu xe, xe sang ─Сс║пt tiс╗Бn tс║бi Viс╗Зt Nam ─Сa phс║зn ─С╞░с╗гc ─С╞░с╗гc vс╗Б bс╗Яi c├бc ─С╞бn vс╗Л nhс║нp khс║йu t╞░ nh├вn chс╗й kh├┤ng phс║гi l├а c├бc ─С╞бn vс╗Л ph├вn phс╗Сi с╗зy quyс╗Бn v├а thс║нm ch├н l├а c├│ mс║╖t tr╞░с╗Ыc khi ─Сс║бi l├╜ ─С╞░с╗гc mс╗Я tс║бi Viс╗Зt Nam. ─Рiс╗Бu n├аy khiс║┐n cho c├бc chс╗з xe phс║гi sс╗н dс╗еng dс╗Лch vс╗е bс║гo d╞░с╗бng, bс║гo tr├м tс║бi c├бc gara b├кn ngo├аi thay v├м gс╗нi chiс║┐c xe cho nhс╗пng chuy├кn gia ─С╞░с╗гc ─С├аo tс║бo bс╗Яi h├гng. Mс║╖c d├╣ c├бc h├гng xe sang, si├кu xe phс╗Х biс║┐n ─С├г ─Сс╗Бu c├│","answer":"mс║╖t tс║бi n╞░с╗Ыc ta, phс║зn nhiс╗Бu chс╗з xe vс║лn sс╗н dс╗еng c├бc dс╗Лch vс╗е ─Сс║┐n tс╗л gara b├кn ngo├аi. Sс╗Я d─й c├│ t├мnh trс║бng n├аy l├а do c├бc gara ngo├аi ─С├г qu├б quen vс╗Ыi chс╗з nh├вn xe, gi├б cс║г hс╗гp l├╜ h╞бn so vс╗Ыi chi ph├н m├а chс╗з nh├вn phс║гi bс╗П ra khi v├аo h├гng. B├кn cс║бnh ─С├│, nhс╗пng chiс║┐c xe mua kh├┤ng ch├нnh h├гng phс║гi buс╗Щc mua th├кm g├│i dс╗Лch vс╗е mс╗Ыi c├│ thс╗Г ─С╞░с╗гc c├бc chuy├кn gia ch├нnh h├гng ch─Гm s├│c. Bс║гo hiс╗Гm Cuс╗Сi c├╣ng, l├а nhс╗пng chiс║┐c xe trс╗Л gi├б ngang nhс╗пng c─Гn biс╗Зt thс╗▒, biс╗Зt phс╗з nh╞░ng nhс╗пng chiс║┐c xe n├аy th╞░с╗Эng ├нt khi n├аo ─С╞░с╗гc mua bс║гo hiс╗Гm. Vс║еn ─Сс╗Б ─Сс║┐n tс╗л viс╗Зc gi├б bс║гo hiс╗Гm hai chiс╗Бu cho ch├║ng kh├б \\"ch├бt\\", khoс║гng 1,5% gi├б trс╗Л xe khiс║┐n nhс╗пng g├│i bс║гo hiс╗Гm mс╗Чi n─Гm c├│ thс╗Г l├кn ─Сс║┐n h├аng tr─Гm triс╗Зu ─Сс╗Уng. ─Рс╗Уng thс╗Эi, khi xс║гy ra sс╗▒ cс╗С, c├бc c├┤ng ty bс║гo hiс╗Гm th╞░с╗Эng giс║гi quyс║┐t chс║нm chс║бp c┼йng l├а l├╜ do khiс║┐n c├бc chс╗з xe kh├┤ng muс╗Сn mua bс║гo hiс╗Гm. Mс║╖t kh├бc, nhс╗пng chiс║┐c si├кu xe ─Сс║пt tiс╗Бn th╞░с╗Эng chс╗Й ─С╞░с╗гc cho xuс╗Сng phс╗С v├аi lс║зn mс╗Чi th├бng, tс╗л ─С├│ c┼йng giс║гm thiс╗Гu khс║г n─Гng xс║гy ra sс╗▒ cс╗С cс╗зa ch├║ng trong mс╗Щt n─Гm./. https://vov.vn/o-to-xe-may/o-to/so-huu-sieu-xe-chuc-ty-tuong-suong-ma-khong-he-suong-post960078.vov Trang Th├┤ng tin ─Сiс╗Зn tс╗н Docbao.vn C├┤ng ty Cс╗Х phс║зn Quang Minh Viс╗Зt Nam Giс║еy ph├йp thiс║┐t lс║нp Trang th├┤ng tin ─Сiс╗Зn tс╗н tс╗Хng hс╗гp tr├кn Internet sс╗С 2372/GP-STTTT cс║еp ng├аy 29/8/2014. S─РT: 024. 666.40816 ─Рс╗Лa chс╗Й: P604, Tс║зng 6, T├▓a nh├а Golden Field, Khu ─С├┤ thс╗Л mс╗Ыi Mс╗╣ ─Р├мnh 1, ph╞░с╗Эng Cс║зu Diс╗Еn, quс║нn Nam Tс╗л Li├кm, H├а Nс╗Щi Chс╗Лu tr├бch nhiс╗Зm nс╗Щi dung: ─Рiс╗Бu Thс╗Л B├нch; ─РT: 0903.263.198; Email: docbao@kib.vn ─Рс╗Нc b├бo trс╗▒c tuyс║┐n hiс╗Зn tс║бi chс╗Й sс╗н dс╗еng t├кn miс╗Бn duy nhс║еt l├а docbao.vn; ─Сс╗Щc giс║г l╞░u ├╜ tr├бnh nhс║зm lс║лn. Ch├нnh s├бch bс║гo mс║нt RSS"},{"question":"ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп рк╕рлНрк╡ркдркВркдрлНрк░ркдрк╛ ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ рк╡рк┐рк╖рлЗ ркорк╛рк╣рк┐ркдрлА ркЖрккрлЛ.","answer":"ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп рк╕рлНрк╡ркдркВркдрлНрк░ркдрк╛ ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ ркП ркнрк╛рк░ркдркорк╛ркВ ркмрлНрк░рк┐ркЯрлАрк╢ рк╢рк╛рк╕ркиркирлЛ ркЕркВркд рк▓рк╛рк╡рк╡рк╛ркирк╛ ркЕркВркдрк┐рко ркЙркжрлНркжрлЗрк╢ рк╕рк╛ркерлЗ ркЪрк▓рк╛рк╡рк╡рк╛ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлЗрк▓рлА ркРркдрк┐рк╣рк╛рк╕рк┐ркХ рк▓ркбркдркирлА ркШркЯркирк╛ркУркирлА рк╢рлНрк░рлЗркгрлА рк╣ркдрлА. ркЖ ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ рлзрлорллрлн ркерлА рлзрлпрлкрлн рк╕рлБркзрлА ркЪрк╛рк▓рлА рк╣ркдрлА. ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп рк╕рлНрк╡ркдркВркдрлНрк░ркдрк╛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗркирлА рккрк╣рлЗрк▓рлА рк░рк╛рк╖рлНркЯрлНрк░рк╡рк╛ркжрлА ркХрлНрк░рк╛ркВркдрк┐ркХрк╛рк░рлА ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ ркмркВркЧрк╛рк│ркорк╛ркВ рк╢рк░рлВ ркеркИ.  ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░ ркмрк╛ркж ркЕркЧрлНрк░ркгрлА ркорк╡рк╛рк│ ркирлЗркдрк╛ркУ рк╕рк╛ркерлЗ ркирк╡рлА рк░ркЪрк╛ркпрлЗрк▓рлА ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп рк░рк╛рк╖рлНркЯрлНрк░рлАркп ркХрлЛркВркЧрлНрк░рлЗрк╕ ркеркХрлА ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп рк╕ркиркжрлА рк╕рлЗрк╡рк╛ркирлА (рк╕рк┐рк╡рк┐рк▓ рк╕рк░рлНрк╡рк┐рк╕) рккрк░рлАркХрлНрк╖рк╛ркУ ркЖрккрк╡рк╛ркирк╛ ркорлВрк│ркнрлВркд ркЕркзрк┐ркХрк╛рк░ркирлА ркЕркирлЗ ркжрлЗрк╢рк╡рк╛рк╕рлА ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ рк╡ркзрлБ ркЕркзрк┐ркХрк╛рк░рлЛркирлА (ркорлБркЦрлНркпркдрлНрк╡рлЗ ркЖрк░рлНркерк┐ркХ) ркорк╛ркВркЧркгрлА ркХрк░ркдрлА ркЪрк│рк╡рк│рлЛ ркжрлНрк╡рк╛рк░рк╛ рк╕рлНрк╡ркдркВркдрлНрк░ркдрк╛ркирлА ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ркирк╛ ркорлВрк│ рк╡ркзрлБ ркКркВркбрк╛ ркЙркдрк░рлНркпрк╛. рлирлж ркорлА рк╕ркжрлАркирк╛ рккрлНрк░рк╛рк░ркВркнрк┐ркХ ркХрк╛рк│ркорк╛ркВ рк▓рк╛рк▓ ркмрк╛рк▓ рккрк╛рк▓ (ркдрлНрк░рк┐ркирлЗркдрк╛) , ркЕрк░ркмрк┐ркВркжрлЛ ркШрлЛрк╖ ркЕркирлЗ рк╡рлА.ркУ. ркЪрк┐ркжркорлНркмрк░рко рккрк┐рк▓рлНрк▓рк╛ркИ ркЬрлЗрк╡рк╛ ркирлЗркдрк╛ркУркирк╛ ркорк╛рк░рлНркЧркжрк░рлНрк╢рки рк╣рлЗркарк│ ркЖ ркЪрк│рк╛рк╡рк│рлЗ рк╡рлНркпрк╛рккркХ рк░рк╛ркЬркХрлАркп рк╕рлНрк╡рк░рлВркк ркзрк╛рк░ркг ркХрк░рлНркпрлБркВ ркЕркирлЗ ркдрлЗ рк╕рлНрк╡рк░рк╛ркЬрлНркпркирлА ркорк╛ркВркЧркгрлА ркдрк░ркл рк╡рк│рлА. рлзрлпрлирлж ркирк╛ ркжрк╛ркпркХрк╛ркерлА рк╕рлНрк╡рк░рк╛ркЬрлНркпркирлА рк▓ркбркдркирк╛ ркЫрлЗрк▓рлНрк▓рк╛ ркдркмркХрлНркХрк╛ркорк╛ркВ ркХрлЛркВркЧрлНрк░рлЗрк╕рлЗ ркорк╣рк╛ркдрлНркорк╛ ркЧрк╛ркВркзрлАркирк╛ ркЕрк╣рк┐ркВрк╕рк╛, рк╕рк╡рк┐ркиркп ркХрк╛ркирлВрки ркнркВркЧ ркЕркирлЗ ркЕркирлНркп ркПрк╡рк╛ ркШркгрк╛ ркЕркирлНркп ркЕркнрк┐ркпрк╛ркирлЛ ркЕрккркирк╛рк╡рлНркпрк╛ рк╣ркдрк╛. рк╕рлБркнрк╛рк╖ркЪркВркжрлНрк░ ркмрлЛркЭ, ркнркЧркдрк╕рк┐ркВрк╣, ркнркЧркд рк╕рк┐ркВрк╣, рк╕рлВрк░рлНркп рк╕рлЗрки ркЬрлЗрк╡рк╛ рк░рк╛рк╖рлНркЯрлНрк░рк╡рк╛ркжрлА ркХрлНрк░ркВркдрк┐ркХрк╛рк░рлАркУркП рк╕рлНрк╡-рк╢рк╛рк╕рки ркорлЗрк│рк╡рк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ рк╕рк╢рк╕рлНркдрлНрк░ ркХрлНрк░рк╛ркВркдрк┐ркирлЛ ркЙрккркжрлЗрк╢ ркЖрккрлНркпрлЛ рк╣ркдрлЛ. рк░рк╡рлАркирлНркжрлНрк░ркирк╛рке ркЯрк╛ркЧрлЛрк░, рк╕рлБркмрлНрк░ркоркгрлНркпрк╛ ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлА, ркмркВркХрк┐ркоркЪркВркжрлНрк░ ркЪркЯрлНркЯрлЛрккрк╛ркзрлНркпрк╛ркп ркЕркирлЗ ркХрк╛ркЭрлА ркиркЭрк░рлВрк▓ ркИрк╕рлНрк▓рк╛рко ркЬрлЗрк╡рк╛ ркХрк╡рк┐ркУ ркЕркирлЗ рк▓рлЗркЦркХрлЛ рк░рк╛ркЬркХрлАркп ркЬрк╛ркЧрлГркдрк┐ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗркирк╛ рк╕рк╛ркзрки ркдрк░рлАркХрлЗ рк╕рк╛рк╣рк┐ркдрлНркп, ркХрк╛рк╡рлНркп ркЕркирлЗ ркнрк╛рк╖ркгркирлЛ ркЙрккркпрлЛркЧ ркХрк░ркдрк╛ рк╣ркдрк╛. рк╕рк░рлЛркЬрк┐ркирлА ркирк╛ркпркбрлБ, рккрлНрк░рлАркдрлАрк▓ркдрк╛ рк╡рк╛ркбрлНркбрлЗркжрк░, ркмрлЗркЧрко рк░рлЛркХрлЗркпрк╛ ркЬрлЗрк╡рлА ркирк╛рк░рлАрк╡рк╛ркжрлА ркирлЗркдрк╛ркУркП ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп ркорк╣рк┐рк▓рк╛ркУркирлА ркорлБркХрлНркдрк┐ ркЕркирлЗ рк░рк╛рк╖рлНркЯрлНрк░рлАркп рк░рк╛ркЬркХрк╛рк░ркгркорк╛ркВ ркдрлЗркоркирлА ркнрк╛ркЧрлАркжрк╛рк░рлАркирлЗ рккрлНрк░рлЛркдрлНрк╕рк╛рк╣рки ркЖрккрлНркпрлБркВ. ркмрлА.ркЖрк░. ркЖркВркмрлЗркбркХрк░рлЗ рк╡ркзрлБ рк╕рлНрк╡рк░рк╛ркЬрлНркпркирлА ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ркорк╛ркВ ркнрк╛рк░ркдрлАркп рк╕ркорк╛ркЬркирк╛ рк╡ркВркЪрк┐ркд рк╡рк░рлНркЧркирк╛ ркорлБркжрлНркжрк╛ркирлЗ рк╡ркгрлА рк▓рлАркзрлЛ.  ркмрлАркЬрк╛ рк╡рк┐рк╢рлНрк╡ркпрлБркжрлНркзркирк╛ ркжрк░ркорлНркпрк╛рки ркЬрк╛рккрк╛ркиркирлА ркоркжркжркерлА рк╕рлБркнрк╛рк╖ркЪркВркжрлНрк░ ркмрлЛркЭркирлА ркЖркЧрлЗрк╡рк╛ркирлА рк╣рлЗркарк│ркирлА ркнрк╛рк░ркдркирлА рк░рк╛рк╖рлНркЯрлНрк░рлАркп рк╕рлИркирлНркпркирлА ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ ркЕркирлЗ ркХрлЛркВркЧрлНрк░рлЗрк╕ркирлА ркЖркЧрлЗрк╡рк╛ркирлА рк╣рлЗркарк│ркирк╛ ркнрк╛рк░ркд ркЫрлЛркбрлЛ ркЖркВркжрлЛрк▓рки ркП ркЖ ркЪрк│рк╡рк│ркирлЛ ркЪрк░ркоркХрк╛рк│ рк╣ркдрлЛ. "},{"question":"Mi ake nufi da \\"light\\" da Hausa? \\t\\t","answer":"Tana nufin \\"wuta\\"\\t\\t\\t\\t"},{"question":"рдпрджрд┐ рд░рд╛рд╖реНрдЯреНрд░рдкрддрд┐ рдХрд╛ рдкрдж рдЦрд╛рд▓реА рд╣реЛ, рддреЛ рдЙрд╕реЗ рдХрд┐рддрдиреА рдЕрд╡рдзрд┐ рдХреЗ рдЕрдиреНрджрд░ рднрд░рдирд╛ рдЖрд╡рд╢реНрдпрдХ рд╣реЛрддрд╛ рд╣реИ ?","answer":"рд░рд╛рд╖реНрдЯреНрд░рдкрддрд┐ рдХрд╛ рдкрдж рдпрджрд┐ рдЦрд╝рд╛рд▓реА рд╣реЛ, рддреЛ рдЙрд╕реЗ рем рдорд╣реАрдиреЗ рдореЗрдВ рднрд░рдирд╛ рдЖрд╡рд╢реНрдпрдХ рд╣реЛрддрд╛ рд╣реИред"},{"question":"Kedu mgbe emere steeti Adamawa?","answer":"E mere ya na 27 с╗Мgс╗Нс╗Нst 1991"},{"question":"K├н ni ├аpс║╣с║╣rс║╣ с╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А t├н a fi ├аf├▓mс╗Н╠Б ├мb├й├иr├и с╣гс║╣╠Аd├б?","answer":"├Аpс║╣с║╣rс║╣ kan ni 'Awakс╗Н╠А'."},{"question":"ркоркирлЗ ркоркирлАрк╖ рк╡ркШрк╛рк╕рк┐ркпрк╛ ркПркХ рккрлНрк░рлЗрк░ркХ рк╡ркХрлНркдрк╛ рк╡рк┐рк╢рлЗ ркХрк╣рлЛ.","answer":"ркоркирлАрк╖ рк╡ркШрк╛рк╕рк┐ркпрк╛ ркПркХ ркЬрлАрк╡рки ркХрлЛркЪ ркЕркирлЗ рккрлНрк░рлЗрк░ркХ рк╡ркХрлНркдрк╛ ркЫрлЗ ркЬрлЗ рк╡рлНркпркХрлНркдрк┐ркЧркд рккрк░рк┐рк╡рк░рлНркдрки рккрк░ ркзрлНркпрк╛рки ркХрлЗркирлНркжрлНрк░рк┐ркд ркХрк░рк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркЬрк╛ркгрлАркдрк╛ ркЫрлЗ. ркдрлЗ 'ркорк╛ркирк╕ рк▓рк╛ркИркл ркХрлЛркЪ' рк╕ркВрк╕рлНркерк╛ркирк╛ рк╕рлНркерк╛рккркХ ркЫрлЗ, ркЬрлЗ рк╡рлНркпркХрлНркдрк┐ркЧркд рк╡рк┐ркХрк╛рк╕ ркЕркирлЗ рк╕рлНрк╡-рк╢рлЛркз рккрк░ ркХрлЛркЪрк┐ркВркЧ рккрлНрк░рлЛркЧрлНрк░рк╛ркорлНрк╕, рк╡рк░рлНркХрк╢рлЛркк ркЕркирлЗ рк╕рлЗркорк┐ркирк╛рк░ ркУрклрк░ ркХрк░рлЗ ркЫрлЗ."},{"question":"Inona no tena loharanon'ny entona mampidi-doza avy amin'ny fiara?1-karb├┤nina (CO)2-gazy karbonika (CO2)3-Metana (CH4)","answer":"Valiny: 2Ny gazy karbonika (CO2) dia zava-doza ho an'ny fomba fiainan'ny olombelona."},{"question":"Sidee ayaa loo maareyn karaa walwalka oo maxaan sameyn karaa anigu?","answer":"Waxa caadi ah in la rabo in la baxsado marka uu walwalku kuu yimaado. In waxa xun la iska dhowro ayaa ah mid biniaadamku sameeyo. Laakiin walwalku iskama tago kalliya iyadoo la iska ilaalinaayo uun, waxa dhacda taas mid liddi ku ah. Hab wanaagsan oo la iskaga ilaaliyo walwalku waa iyadoo la ogolaado kaas, xaalada laga helo oo aan la isku deyin inaan laga baxsan. Haddii aad awoodi karto ayaa inta badan walwalku dhakhso iskaga tagaa, iyadoo marka danbe ay ka sii dhib yaraan karto in la maareeyo.Waxa caawisa in qof lagala hadlo sida aad dareemeyso. In laga hadalo ayaa inta badan ay talaabada ugu horeysa ee lagaga roonaanaayo. Waxaad sidoo kale ka baran kartaa wax badan oo ku saabsan walwalka adigoo akhriya waxyaalaja ku sabsan walwalka iyo sida loo daaweyn karo.Istareeska iyo walwalkaayaa inta badan wada socda. Haddii aad isku daydo inaad cunto, seexato oo aad sameyso waxyaalaha aad jeceshahay, ayuu sii badanayaa iska caabinta aad yeelaneyso istareeska iyo walwalka. Qeyb kale oo muhiim ah waa in maya la odhan karro oo la xadeeyo waxyaala aah awoodi karo."},{"question":"2015 роЯро┐роЪроорпНрокро░ро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роОроирпНрод ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡ройроорпН ро░ро╛роХрпНроХрпЖроЯрпНроЯрпИ рокрпВрооро┐роХрпНроХрпБ роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡роирпНродродрпБ?","answer":"роиро╛роЪро╛ роОройрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡родрпБ роРроХрпНроХро┐роп роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЖропрпНро╡рпБ роЕроорпИрокрпНрокро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗродрпБ роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЖропрпНро╡рпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡ро╛ройрпВро░рпНродро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпН, ро╡ро┐рогрпНрогрпВро░рпНродро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпН роЖро░ро╛ропроЪрпНроЪро┐роХро│ро┐ройрпН роХроЯрпНроЯрпБрокрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роиро┐ро░рпНро╡ро╛роХ роЕроорпИрокрпНрокро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗродрпБ 1958 роЬрпВро▓рпИ 29 роЕройрпНро▒рпБ родрпЗроЪро┐роп ро╡ро╛ройрпВро░рпНродро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐роЪрпН роЪроЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роХрпАро┤рпН роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. роЗродрпБ роЗродро▒рпНроХрпБ роорпБройрпН ро╡ро╛ройрпВро░рпНродро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпН роЖро░ро╛ропроЪрпНроЪро┐роХро│рпБроХрпНроХро╛роХ роЗро░рпБроирпНрод, родрпЗроЪро┐роп ро╡ро╛ройрпВро░рпНродро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпН роЖро▓рпЛроЪройрпИ роЪрпЖропро▒рпНроХрпБро┤рпБро╡рпИроХрпН ( роиро╛роХро╛) роХро▓рпИродрпНродрпБ роЕродройрпН ро╡роЯро┐ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. роЗродройрпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╡ро░ро╡рпБ роЪрпЖро▓ро╡рпБ, 2012 роЗро▓рпН 17.8 рокро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро┐ропройрпН роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХ роЯро╛ро▓ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЖроХрпБроорпН.родрпБро▒рпИ роорпЗро▓рпЛроЯрпНроЯроорпН:роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБ: роЬрпВро▓рпИ 29,1958 ; 64 роЖрогрпНроЯрпБроХро│рпН роорпБройрпНройро░рпНроорпБройрпНрокро┐ро░рпБроирпНрод роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБ: роиро╛роЪро╛ (1915тАУ1958)роЖроЯ,роЪро┐ роОро▓рпНро▓рпИ: роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХ роЕро░роЪрпБродро▓рпИроорпИропроХроорпН: ро╡ро╛ро╖ро┐роЩрпНроЯройрпН,роЯро┐.роЪро┐.рокрогро┐ропро╛роЯрпНроХро│рпН: 18,800 рокрпЗро░рпНроЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роиро┐родро┐ :17.8 рокро┐ро▓рпНро▓ро┐ропройрпН роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХ роЯро╛ро▓ро░рпНроХро│рпНроЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБ родро▓рпИроорпИроХро│рпН: роЪро╛ро░рпНро▓ро╕рпН рокрпЛро▓рпНроЯройрпН, роиро┐ро░рпНро╡ро╛роХро┐. ро▓рпЛро░рпА роХро╛ро░рпНро╡рпЖро░рпН, родрпБрогрпИ роиро┐ро░рпНро╡ро╛роХро┐ро╡ро▓рпИродрпНродро│роорпН: nasa govрокро┐рокрпНро░ро╡ро░ро┐ 2006- ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЖропрпНро╡рпБ, роЕро▒ро┐ро╡ро┐ропро▓рпН роЖро░ро╛ропрпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡ро╛ройрпВро░рпНродро┐ропро┐ропро▓рпН роЖро░ро╛ропрпНроЪро┐роХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роОродро┐ро░рпНроХро╛ро▓родрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро╛рой роорпБройрпНройрпЛроЯро┐ропро╛роХ роЗро░рпБродрпНродро▓рпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ роиро╛роЪро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН родро╛ро░роХ роороирпНродро┐ро░рооро╛роХро╡рпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЪрпЖрокрпНроЯроорпНрокро░рпН 14, 2011 роЕройрпНро▒рпБ, рокрпБродро┐роп ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роПро╡рпБродрпН родрпКроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ройрпН ро╡роЯро┐ро╡роорпИрокрпНрокрпИродрпН родрпЗро░рпНроирпНродрпЖроЯрпБродрпНродрпБро│рпНро│родро╛роХ роЕро▒ро┐ро╡ро┐родрпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЗродройрпН роорпВро▓роорпН роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХ ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ ро╡рпАро░рпНро░рпНроХро│рпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЗродрпБро╡ро░рпИ роЪрпЖро▓рпНро▓ро╡ро┐ропро▓ро╛род родрпКро▓рпИро╡рпБроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпЖро▓рпНро▓ро╛роорпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро▓ро╡ро┐ропро▓рпБроорпН роОройро╡рпБроорпН, роОродро┐ро░рпНроХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рооройро┐родро░рпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНро▓рпБроорпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЖропрпНро╡рпБроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокрпБродрпБрокрпЖро░рпБроорпН родрпКроЯроХрпНроХрооро╛роХ роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпЖройро╡рпБроорпН роиро╛роЪро╛ роЕро▒ро┐ро╡ро┐родрпНродрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ.роЕроХрпНроЯрпЛрокро░рпН 1 1958 роЕройрпНро▒рпБ роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокроЯродрпН родрпКроЯроЩрпНроХро┐роп роЗро╡рпНро╡роорпИрокрпНрокрпБ, роЕройрпНро▒ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпНроХро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЖропрпНро╡рпБроХро│рпИроЪрпН роЪрпЖропрпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро▒родрпБ. роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро╛роХ роЕрокрпНрокро▓рпНро▓рпЛ родро┐роЯрпНроЯроорпН, ро╡ро┐рогрпНрогро╛ропрпНро╡роХроорпН роОройрпБроорпН ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роиро┐ро▓рпИропроорпН, ро╡ро┐рогрпНрогрпЛроЯродрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпИроЪрпН роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. родро▒рпНрокрпЛродрпБ роЕройрпИродрпНродрпБро▓роХ ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роиро┐ро▓рпИропродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХрпБ рокро▓ро╡ро┐родроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЖродро░ро╡ро│ро┐родрпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роУро░ро┐ропро╛ройрпН рокро▓рпНроирпЛроХрпНроХ роХрпБро┤рпБ ро╡ро╛роХройроорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡рогро┐роХро░рпАродро┐ропро┐ро▓ро╛рой роХрпБро┤рпБ роорпЗроорпНрокро╛роЯрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпИ роорпБройрпНройрпЖроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроЪрпН роЪрпЖропрпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН роЖро│ро▒рпНро▒ ро╡ро┐рогрпНрокропрог роПро╡рпБродро▓рпНроХро│рпН роЕройрпИродрпНродрпИропрпБроорпН роЗродрпБро╡рпЗ роХрогрпНроХро╛рогро┐роХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рокрпБро╡ро┐ роЕро╡родро╛ройро┐рокрпНрокрпБродрпН родрпКроХрпБродро┐ роорпВро▓роорпН рокрпБро╡ро┐ропрпИ роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН рокрпБро░ро┐роирпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро│рпБродро▓рпН, роЕро▒ро┐ро╡ро┐ропро▓рпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯ роЗропроХрпНроХрпБроиро░роХродрпНродро┐ройрпН рокро░ро┐родро┐ропро┐ропро▒рпНрокро┐ропро▓рпН роЖро░ро╛ропрпНроЪрпНроЪро┐родрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН роХрпАро┤рпН рокро░ро┐родро┐ропро┐ропро▒рпНрокро┐ропро▓рпН роЖропрпНро╡рпБроХро│рпИ роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпКро│рпНро│рпБродро▓рпН, роЪрпВро░ро┐ропроХрпН роХрпБроЯрпБроорпНрокродрпНродро┐ро▓рпБро│рпНро│ роТро╡рпНро╡рпКро░рпБ роЙро▒рпБрокрпНрокрпБроХрпНроХро│рпИрокрпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропрпБроорпН роЖро│ро▒рпНро▒ ро╡ро┐рогрпНрогрпБро▓ро╡ро┐роХро│рпН роЕройрпБрокрпНрокро┐ роЖро░ро╛ропрпНроирпНродро▒ро┐родро▓рпН, рокрпЖро░рпБ ро╡рпЖроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпБроХрпН роХрпЛроЯрпНрокро╛роЯрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ ро╡ро╛ройро┐ропро▒рпНрокро┐ропро▓рпН роХрпЛроЯрпНрокро╛роЯрпБроХро│рпИ роЖро░ро╛ропрпНро╡родрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ рокрогро┐роХро│рпИ роиро╛роЪро╛ роЪрпЖропрпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН роЗро╡рпНро╡роорпИрокрпНрокрпБ роХрогрпНроЯро▒ро┐ропрпБроорпН родро░ро╡рпБродрпНродрпКроХрпБрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпИрокрпН рокро▓роиро╛роЯрпБроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЕроорпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпЛроЯрпБроорпН рокроЩрпНроХрпАроЯрпБроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ. ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐родрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│рпН родро╡ро┐ро░ роЗро░ро╛рогрпБро╡ ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЖропрпНро╡рпБроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роЗро╡рпНро╡роорпИрокрпНрокрпБ роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпКро│рпНро│рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роЗроирпНрод роиро╛роЪро╛ ро╡ро┐рогрпНро╡рпЖро│ро┐ роЖро░ро╛ропрпНроЪро┐роХрпНроХрпБро░ро┐роп роиро┐родро┐ роТродрпБроХрпНроХрпАроЯрпНроЯрпИ роЕроорпЖро░ро┐роХрпН роЕро░роЪрпЗ роЕро│ро┐родрпНродрпБ ро╡ро░рпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.роиро╛роЪро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН рокро┐ро░родро┐роиро┐родро┐ропро╛роХ родро▓рпИроорпИ ро╡ро┐роЮрпНроЮро╛ройро┐ рокро┐ро░родро┐рокро▓ро┐рокрпНрокро╛ро░рпН.роиро╛роЪро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роиро┐родро┐роиро┐ро▓рпИ роЕро▒ро┐роХрпНроХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН родрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЖро▓рпЛроЪройрпИроХро│рпН ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХрпБродро▓рпН, роорпВро▓рпЛрокро╛роп роЗро▓роХрпНроХрпБроХро│рпИ роиро┐ро░рпНрогропро┐родрпНродро▓рпН, роиро╛роЪро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роироЯрокрпНрокрпБродрпНродро┐роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЙро│рпНро│роЯроХрпНроХродрпНродрпИ роирпЖро▒ро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБродро▓рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокро╛роЯрпБроХро│рпБроХрпНроХро╛роХро╡рпЗ родро▓рпИроорпИ ро╡ро┐роЮрпНроЮро╛ройро┐ роОройрпНро▒ роиро┐ро▓рпИ роиро╛роЪро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЙро░рпБро╡ро╛роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯродрпБ. роорпВро▓рпЛрокро╛роп роорпБропро▒рпНроЪро┐роХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роХро│рпН роорпИропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роиро╛роЪро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН рокро┐ро░родро┐роиро┐родро┐ропро╛роХ родро▓рпИроорпИ ро╡ро┐роЮрпНроЮро╛ройро┐ роирпЖро░рпБроХрпНроХрооро╛роХрокрпН рокрогро┐рокрпБро░ро┐ро╡ро╛ро░рпН. роЗро╡рпИроороЯрпНроЯрпБрооро┐ройрпНро▒ро┐ роЖро▓рпЛроЪройрпИроХрпНроХрпБро┤рпБ, ро╡рпЖро│ро┐рокрпНрокрпБро▒ роЪроорпВроХродрпН родрпКроЯро░рпНрокрпБ роЖроХро┐ропро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро▓рпБроорпН роЗро╡ро░рпН роорпБроХрпНроХро┐роп рокроЩрпНроХрпБ ро╡роХро┐рокрпНрокро╛ро░рпН. роорпБроХроорпИропро┐ройрпН роЕро▒ро┐ро╡ро┐ропро▓рпН роирпЛроХрпНроХроЩрпНроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро┐ро▒ роХрпВроЯрпНроЯро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐ роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡ройроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роЪро╛родройрпИроХро│рпН, родрпКро┤ро┐ро▒рпНроЪро╛ро▓рпИ, роХро▓рпНро╡ро┐, роПройрпИроп роЕро░роЪро╛роЩрпНроХ роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡ройроЩрпНроХро│рпН, роЪро░рпНро╡родрпЗроЪ роЪроорпВроХроорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокрпКродрпБроороХрпНроХро│рпН роЖроХро┐ропрпЛро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роиро╛роЪро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН рокро┐ро░родро┐роиро┐родро┐ропро╛роХ родро▓рпИроорпИ ро╡ро┐роЮрпНроЮро╛ройро┐ рокро┐ро░родро┐рокро▓ро┐рокрпНрокро╛ро░рпН."},{"question":"┬┐De qu├й est├б hecha la seda artificial?","answer":"A diferencia de la seda natural, que se fabrica a partir de los capullos de los gusanos de seda, la seda artificial se produce tratando qu├нmicamente e hilando fibras naturales como pulpa de madera, bamb├║ o algod├│n. El tejido resultante es muy similar a la seda en cuanto a aspecto y tacto, pero a un coste mucho menor. La seda artificial es tambi├йn m├бs vers├бtil que la seda real y puede te├▒irse en una amplia gama de colores. Tambi├йn es m├бs transpirable y absorbente que la seda aut├йntica. Sin embargo, es m├бs propensa a arrugarse y encogerse, y puede no durar tanto como la seda aut├йntica."},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐:роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпБ  роХрпБро▒ро┐родрпНродрпБ роХроЯрпНроЯрпБро░рпИ ро╡ро░рпИроХ:","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН:       роорпКро┤ро┐роХро│ро┐ро▓рпН рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН рокро┤роорпИропро╛ройродрпБ роОрой рокрпЛро▒рпНро▒рокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН родрооро┐ро┤рпН роорпКро┤ро┐ропро╛ройродрпБ рокро▓рпНро▓ро╛ропро┐ро░роорпН ро╡ро░рпБроЯ роХро╛ро▓ роЗро▓роХрпНроХрог, роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯ роЕроорпИроирпНродродро╛роХро╡рпЗ роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ.  родрооро┐ро┤рпН роорпКро┤ро┐ропро┐ройрпБроЯрпИроп роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпБ роОройрпНрокродрпБ рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН роирпАрогрпНроЯ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродрпБроХрпНроХрпБро░ро┐ропродро╛роХро╡рпЗ роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роЗродро┐ро▓рпН роорпБродройрпНроорпИропро╛рой роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐роп ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпБроХрпН роХро╛ро▓рооро╛роХро╡рпЗ роЗроирпНрод роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓роорпН родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ.роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокрпБ роЪроЯрпНроЯроХроорпН:роорпБройрпНройрпБро░рпИроЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпНроЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпНроЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роХрпВро▒рпБроорпН роЕро▒роХрпНроХро░рпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро│рпНроЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН родрпЖройрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ропро▓рпНроорпБроЯро┐ро╡рпБро░рпИроорпБройрпНройрпБро░рпИ:       роОроорпНроорпБроЯрпИроп родро╛ропрпНроорпКро┤ро┐ропро╛рой родрооро┐ро┤ро┐ро▓рпН родрпЛройрпНро▒ро┐роп роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН рокро┤роорпИропро╛ройро╡рпИропрпБроорпН роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН роиро┐ро▒рпИроирпНродро╡рпИропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБрокро╡рпИ роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родрпЛройрпНро▒ро┐роп роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЖроХрпБроорпН. роЗроирпНрод роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓роорпН роорпВройрпНро▒рпБ ро╡роХрпИропро╛рой роХро╛ро▓рокрпНрокроХрпБродро┐роХро│ро╛роХ роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ. роЗроХрпНроХро╛ро▓рокрпН рокроХрпБродро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЕроХродрпНродро┐ройрпИ рокрпБро▒родрпНродро┐ройрпИ роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод рокродро┐ройрпЖрогрпН роорпЗро▓рпН роХрогроХрпНроХрпБ роирпВро▓рпНроХро│рпН роОро┤рпБроирпНродрой роЗро╡рпИ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро╛ро▓рпН роЕро┤ро┐ропро╛роЪрпН роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБроЯрпИро╡рпИропро╛роХ родро┐роХро┤рпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓ рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН:       роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН ропро╛ро╡рпБроорпН рокрпБроХро┤рпНрокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройро╛ро▓рпЗ роЗропро▒рпНро▒рокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│рой. роЕроХрпНроХро╛ро▓рокрпН рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ рооройрпНройро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройро╛ро▓рпН роЖродро░ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБ ро╡роирпНродро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро╛ро╡ро░рпН. роЗро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒ро╛роХ роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▒роирпНрод роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпИ роЗропро▒рпНро▒ро┐роп рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпБро│рпН роТро│ро╡рпИропро╛ро░рпН, рокро░рогро░рпН, роХрогро┐ропройрпН рокрпВроЩрпНроХрпБройрпНро▒ройрпН, роироХрпНроХрпАро░ро░рпН, роХрокро┐ро▓ро░рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒рпЛро░рпИ роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯро▓ро╛роорпН.роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродрпБ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН:роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роОро┤рпБроирпНрод роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНро│рпИ роОроЯрпНроЯрпБродрпНродрпКроХрпИ, рокродрпНродрпБрокрпНрокро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ роОрой ро╡роХрпИрокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ роЙро│рпНро│ройро░рпН. роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпН роЕроЯро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЕроХродрпНродро┐рогрпИ рокрпБро▒родрпНродро┐рогрпИ роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роОрой ро╡рпЗро▒рпБрокроЯрпБродрпНродрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЗроЩрпНроХрпБ роЕроХроорпН роОройрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡родрпБ рокрпКродрпБро╡ро╛роХ роХро╛родро▓рпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐роп роЪрпЖропрпНродро┐роХро│рпИ роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯрпБро╡родро╛роХрпБроорпН. рокрпБро▒роорпН роОройрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡родрпБ роХрпКроЯрпИ, ро╡рпАро░роорпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпИ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБро╡родро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ.роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роХрпВро▒рпБроорпН роЕро▒роХрпНроХро░рпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН:роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓роорпН роОройрпНрокродрпБ рокрпКродрпБро╡ро╛роХро╡рпЗ роЕроХроорпН, рокрпБро▒роорпН роЪро╛ро░рпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН родрпЛро▒рпНро▒ роХро╛ро▓рооро╛роХрпБроорпН.роЕродро╛ро╡родрпБ роЗроЩрпНроХрпБ рокрпБро▒роорпН роОройрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡родрпБ рооройрпНройро░рпНроХро│рпБроЯрпИроп рокрпЛро░рпНроТро┤рпБроХрпНроХроорпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропро╛роХрпБроорпН. рооройрпНройро░рпНроХро│рпН роОродро┐ро░рпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роорпАродрпБ рокроЯрпИропрпЖроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роЕроирпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИ роХрпИрокрпНрокро▒рпНро▒ро╡рпБроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНродройро░рпН. роЗродройро╛ро▓рпН роЕроЩрпНроХрпБ роиро┐ро▒рпИроп роЙропро┐ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪрпЗродроЩрпНроХро│рпН, рокрпКро░рпБроЯрпНроЪрпЗродроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЗроЯроорпНрокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой.  роЗро╡рпНро╡ро╛ро▒ро╛рой роЪрпЖропро▓рпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роороХрпНроХро│рпИ роорпАроЯрпНроЯро┐ роиро▓рпНро╡ро┤ро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроорпН ро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпЗропрпЗ рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН роЕро▒роХрпНроХро░рпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро│рпН роиро┐ро▒рпИроирпНрод роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНропрпБро│рпНроХро│рпИропрпБроорпН роОро┤рпБрод роЖро░роорпНрокро┐родрпНродройро░рпН.  роЕроирпНрод ро╡роХрпИропро┐ро▓рпН тАЬропро╛родрпБроорпН роорпВро░рпЗ ропро╛ро╡ро░рпБроорпН роХрпЗро│ро┐ро░рпНтАж..тАЭ роОройрпНро▒ рокрпБроХро┤рпНрокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ рокро╛роЯро▓рпН ро╡ро░ро┐роХро│ро┐ройрпН роКроЯро╛роХ рооройро┐родройрпБроХрпНроХрпБ родрпЗро╡рпИропро╛рой роЕро▒роЩрпНроХро│рпН роЕройрпИродрпНродрпИропрпБроорпН рокрпЛродро┐родрпНродрпБро│рпНро│роорпИропрпИ роХро╛рог роорпБроЯро┐ропрпБроорпН.роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН родрпЖройрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ропро▓рпН:родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роОрой ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ропро▓рпН, ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпБ, роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроорпН роОройрпНрокрой роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ роОройрпНрокродройрпИ роЙро▓роХ роЕро░роЩрпНроХро│ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роХро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ропрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ роОройрпНро▒ро╛ро▓рпН роЕродрпБ роЪроЩрпНроХ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН родро╛ройрпН роОройрпНрокродро┐ро▓рпН рооро┐роХрпИ роЗро▓рпНро▓рпИ. рокрогрпНроЯрпИродрпН родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпНроХро│родрпБ рокрпЛро░рпН, ро╡рпАро░роорпН, роХрпКроЯрпИ, роХро╛родро▓рпН рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпИ рооро┐роХро╡рпБроорпН роЕро┤роХро╛рой роорпБро▒рпИропро┐ро▓рпН роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБро╡ройро╡ро╛роХ роЗроирпНрод роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродрпБ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роорпЗро▓рпБроорпН роЕро▒родрпНродрпЛроЯрпБ роЗрогрпИроирпНрод родрооро┐ро┤ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ропро▓рпИ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроХрпНроХро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роЕродро╛ро╡родрпБ рокро┐ро▒ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБ родро╛ройроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНроп ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН, роЙро▒ро╡ро┐ройро░рпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЙродро╡ро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНроп ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН, роПрооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ роХрпВроЯро╛родрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпИроХрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯро▓ро╛роорпН.роорпБроЯро┐ро╡рпБро░рпИ:роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓роорпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропрпБроорпН роЪроЩрпНроХроХро╛ро▓родрпНродрпБ рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпН роХро╡ро┐роиропроорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЖро▒рпНро▒ро▓рпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропрпБроорпН роОроороХрпНроХрпБ роОроЯрпБродрпНродрпБроЪрпН роЪрпКро▓рпНро╡родро╛роХро╡рпЗ роЗроирпНрод роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роЕроорпИропрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой. роОроорпНроорпБроЯрпИроп роорпБройрпНройрпЛро░рпНроХро│родрпБ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ропро▓рпИ родро▒рпНроХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤роХрпНроХрпВроЯро┐роп роЗро│роорпН роЪроорпВроХродрпНродро┐ройро░рпБроорпН роХро▒рпНро▒рпБ роЕро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБ роХрпКро│рпНро╡родро▒рпНроХро╛рой роУро░рпН роЕроЯро┐рокрпНрокроЯрпИропро╛роХро╡рпЗ роЗроирпНрод роЪроЩрпНроХ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродрпБ роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропроЩрпНроХро│рпН роХро╛рогрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой роОройрпНрокродрпБ роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯродрпНродроХрпНроХ ро╡ро┐роЯропрооро╛роХрпБроорпН."},{"question":"\\"р╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╢╕р╢╜р╖К р╖Гр╖Фр╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Фр╢л\\" р╢Ьр╖Ур╢нр╢║ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Кр╢л р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒. ","answer":"р╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╢╕р╢╜р╖К р╖Гр╖Фр╢┤р╖Тр╢┤р╖Фр╢лр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╢╗р╢нр╖Пр╖Ар╢║ р╢Йр╖Др╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢лр╖Др╢п р╢╕р╢мр╢╜р╢з р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢пр╖Э р╢Жр╖Ар╖Пр╖Др╢п р╢пр╖Фр╢Ъ р╢Ьр╖Пр╖Ар╖П р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢пр╖Э р╢Жр╖Ар╖Пр╢╕р╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╖Щр╢нр╖Т р╖Гр╖Тр╢╣ р╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╢╗р╖Рр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒р╢╕р╢╜ р╖Гр╖Тр╢│ р╢╢р╖Тр╢│ р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢Ьр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖Др╢п р╢пр╖Фр╢Ъ р╢Ьр╖Пр╖Ар╖П р╢Ър╖Ар╖Фр╢пр╖Э р╢Жр╖Ар╖Пр╖Др╖Г р╢Ер╢Вр╢Ьр╢▒р╖Пр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ър╖Гр╢│ р╢пр╖Тр╢║ р╢╕р╖Рр╢п р╢Ър╖Тр╢╕р╖Тр╢пр╖Ур╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Т р╖Гр╖Тр╖Др╖Тр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ъ р╢╕р╖П р╢╗р╢│р╖Ар╖Пр╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Тр╢пр╖Э р╢╢р╖Рр╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Ър╢▒р╖Ур╢╜ р╢Ър╖Рр╢╜р╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢Ьр╢╜р╖П р╖Др╖Рр╢╜р╖Щр╢▒р╢Йр╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Тр╢╜р╖К р╢╕р╖Тр╢лр╖Т р╢пр╖Ср╖Г р╖Ар╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╢Ьр╖Щ р╢пр╖Эр╢нр╢з р╢▒р╖Ср╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢▒р╖Фр╢╣р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Тр╢пр╖Э р╢╢р╖Рр╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Ър╖Др╖Тр╢╗р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Рр╢╜р╖Ар╖Фр╢л р╖Др╖Рр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ср╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢│р╖Фр╢╗р╢з р╢Ьр╖Фр╢╜р╖Т р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢░р╖Ф р╢╢р╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╢з р╖Др╖Пр╢пр╖Ф р╢пр╖Тр╢пр╖У р╖Др╖Тр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╢║р╖Пр╢╕р╖Ър╢▒р╖Щр╢нр╖Ф р╢Ър╢│р╖Фр╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╖Ьр╢│ р╢Ър╖Е р╢Тр╢Ер╢нр╖Ур╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Др╖Ур╢▒ р╢┤р╖Рр╢╜р╢зр╢╕р╖П р╢Ър╖Рр╢│р╖Ар╖П р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢з р╢▒р╖Фр╢╣р╢Зр╢║р╖Тр╢пр╖Э р╢Жр╖Ар╖Ър╢Йр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Щр╢╗р╖Ър╢╗р╖Пр╢нр╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢л р╢╗р╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢╕р╢╜р╢╜р╖Гр╖Ър╢Ър╢╗р╢╗р╢Вр╢вр╖Тр╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Фр╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢▒р╖К "},{"question":"Sheeg xilligii uu Madaxweynaha ahaa C/qaasim Salaad Xasan?","answer":" Wuxuu ahaa intii  u dhaxeysay 27/08/2000 тАУ 14/10/2004."},{"question":"Ngizw' imvunge yeminyezane,Izwakal' ezinkwazini zoMhlathuze,Iqongel' ezintabeni zoNgoye,Ingikhumbuz' amaqhawe namaqhawekaziAdl' umhlanganiso kwaNgqondebanzi,Evath' iminyezane yobuhlakaniAhlahl' indlela yakwaLwaziEhanjwa ngokuzinikela zikhuthali.Ngizw' imvunge yeminyezane,Izwakal' osebeni loMngeni,Naphakath' ezizibeni zoMngeniOkubhukud' amaqhawe namaqhawekazi,Evunul' izidlodlo zenhlonipho,Avunul' ezegwalagwala zekhethelo,Kwahlokom' umhlaba ngenhlokomo,Kwenanel' imvelo ngemvunge.Ngizw' imvunge yeminyezane,Ngavul' izindlebe zakhongozelaUnqambothi lobuzwilili baphakade,Ngaqanul' amaqaphelo ngasingaIzimangaliso zemikhiqizo yakwaNgqondebanzi:Zihlinzek' ubuntu nobunye,Zahlinzek' ubuqotho nesineke,Zahlinzek' inhlonipho nenkuthalo.1. Chaza ngokukhethwa kwala magama alandelayo asenkondlweni ukuthiawuthinta kanjani umoya wenkondlo. Umhlanganiso, Iminyezane. ","answer":"Umoya wokutusa. Uma sebenqobile (umhlanganiso) bafunda bagogodabagqoka amajazi emfundo(iminyezane). "},{"question":"T├нnh c├бc biс╗Гu thс╗йc sau mс╗Щt c├бch hс╗гp l├н:a) (тАУ 16) . (тАУ 7) . 5; b) 11. (тАУ 12) + 11. (тАУ 18);c) 87. (тАУ 19) тАУ 37 . (тАУ 19); d) 41 . 81 .(тАУ 451). 0.","answer":"a) (тАУ 16) . (тАУ 7) . 5 = [(тАУ 16) . 5] . (тАУ 7)          (t├нnh chс║еt giao ho├бn v├а kс║┐t hс╗гp)= [тАУ (16 . 5)] . (тАУ 7) = (тАУ 80) . (тАУ 7)= 80 . 7 = 560. b) 11 . (тАУ 12) + 11 . (тАУ 18) = 11 . [(тАУ 12) + (тАУ 18)]     (t├нnh chс║еt ph├вn phс╗Сi cс╗зa ph├йp nh├вn ─Сс╗Сi vс╗Ыi ph├йp cс╗Щng)= 11 . [тАУ (12 + 18)] = 11 . (тАУ 30) = тАУ (11 . 30) = тАУ 330.  c) 87 . (тАУ 19) тАУ 37 . (тАУ 19) = (тАУ 19) . (87 тАУ 37)          (t├нnh chс║еt ph├вn phс╗Сi cс╗зa ph├йp nh├вn ─Сс╗Сi vс╗Ыi ph├йp trс╗л)= (тАУ 19) . 50 = тАУ (19 . 50) = тАУ 950. d) 41 . 81 . (тАУ 451) . 0 = 0.         (t├нnh chс║еt ph├йp nh├вn mс╗Щt sс╗С vс╗Ыi 0) Hoс║╖c ch├║ng ta c├│ thс╗Г l├аm lс║зn l╞░с╗гt tс╗лng b╞░с╗Ыc nh╞░ sau: 41 . 81 . (тАУ 451) . 0 = 41 . 81 . [(тАУ 451) . 0]     (t├нnh chс║еt kс║┐t hс╗гp)= 41 . 81 . 0           (t├нnh chс║еt ph├йp nh├вn mс╗Щt sс╗С vс╗Ыi 0)= 41 . (81 . 0)         (t├нnh chс║еt kс║┐t hс╗гp)= 41 . 0 = 0.           (t├нnh chс║еt ph├йp nh├вn mс╗Щt sс╗С vс╗Ыi 0)"},{"question":"Motorlu Ta┼Я─▒tlar Vergisi hangi bankalar al─▒yor?","answer":"Motorlu Ta┼Я─▒tlar Vergisi ├╢demenizi Halkbank Mobil, ─░nternet ┼Юubesi, Halkbank Dialog ve ATM'lerimizden h─▒zl─▒ ve zaman kaybetmeden hesab─▒n─▒zdan veya kredi kart─▒n─▒zdan kolayca ger├зekle┼Яtirebilirsiniz."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air diminum rasa duri, nasi dimakan rasa sekam\\"?","answer":"Dikatakan bkn orang yang dalam kesusahan (dukacita) sehingga tidak sedap makan dan minum"},{"question":"┘В┘Е ╪и╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ┘Е╪з ┘З┘К ┘Г┘Д┘Е╪й ╪з╪│╪к╪▒╪з╪н╪й ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д┘Д╪║╪й ╪з┘Д╪│┘И┘К╪п┘К╪й ╪Я ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡ ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К: ╪▒╪║┘Е ╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Г┘Д┘Е╪й ╪к╪╣┘Ж┘К ┘Б┘К ╪н╪п ╪░╪з╪к┘З╪з \\"╪г╪о╪░ ╪з╪│╪к╪▒╪з╪н╪й ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪╣┘Е┘Д\\" ┘Б┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪║╪з┘Д╪и ┘К╪┤╪п╪п ╪░┘Д┘Г ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ┘Г┘Д┘Е╪й fikapaus (┘И┘В┘Б┘З ╪з┘Д┘Б┘К┘Г┘З ╪г┘И fikarast (\\"╪з╪│╪к╪▒╪з╪н╪й ╪з┘Д┘Б┘К┘Г┘З\\") ┘Е╪╣ ┘И┘В┘Б┘З ╪з┘Д┘Б┘К┘Г┘З ┘И╪з╪│╪к╪▒╪з╪н╪й ╪з┘Д┘Б┘К┘Г┘З ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д╪к┘И╪з┘Д┘К ┘Г╪з┘Д┘Е╪▒╪з╪п┘Б╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘В╪▒┘К╪и╪й..","answer":"╪н╪│┘Ж╪з┘Л ╪и╪е╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪╡ ╪з┘Д╪│╪з╪и┘В ╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й ┘З┘К fikarast."},{"question":"Skriv en forts├дttning p├е den h├дr paragrafen - P├е seniorniv├е slog Talbot igenom n├дr han blev bronsmedalj├╢r sin specialdistans 200 meter vid EM 2012","answer":"i Helsingfors, besegrad endast av den nederl├дndska duon Martina och van Luijk. Samma ├еr sprang han tredjestr├дckan i det brittiska korta stafettlaget som v├дxlade bort sig i f├╢rs├╢ken i Londonolympiaden. I EM 2014 i Z├╝rich n├еdde Talbot semifinal p├е 200 meter och l├╢pte sistastr├дckan i det brittiska guldlaget p├е 4 x 100 meter. I Samv├дldesspelen 2014 i Glasgow blev Talbot sjua i 200 metersfinalen och d├дrmed b├дste europ├й. I stafetten var Talbot slutman f├╢r det engelska laget som slutade tv├еa bakom Jamaica. P├е slutstr├дckan fick Talbot ge sig f├╢r Usain Bolt men h├╢ll Trinidads Richard Thompson bakom sig."},{"question":"\\"Ny tabataba tsy tapaka amin'ny fananganana akaikin'ny tranoko dia mahatonga ahy ho adala, ka tsy azo atao ny mifantoka.\\" inona ny fihetseham-pon' io fanambarana io ?","answer":"Ny andian-teny dia miteraka fahasosorana sy fahasarotana vokatry ny tabataba fananganana mitohy, mitarika fihetseham-po ratsy noho ny fiantraikany manelingelina ny fahafahan'ny mpandahateny mifantoka."},{"question":"р╢пр╖У р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ыр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╢з р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Ар╢▒ р╢┤р╖Цр╢╗р╖Кр╢л р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ыр╖КтАНр╢║р╖П р╢╕р╖Пр╢╜р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╢╜р╖Фр╢╕ р╢║р╖Фр╢Ьр╢╜ р╖Гр╖Ьр╢║р╖П р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Щр╖Гр╖Ър╢п?","answer":"def find_pairs(lst, sum_value):    pairs = [(x, y) for x in lst for y in lst if x + y == sum_value]    return pairsnumbers = [1, 2, 3, 4, 5]print(find_pairs(numbers, 5))  # Output: [(1, 4), (2, 3), (3, 2), (4, 1)]"},{"question":"Toonta faaidada laga helo maxey tahay?","answer":"TOONTA WA DAAWO LAHUBO MISANA INBADAN O NAGA MID AH MOOGYIHIINToonta inta ugu badan badan waxa loo isticmaala in lagu udgooneeyo dhadhana loogu yeelo cuntooyin aad u farabadan. dhinaca kale toontu waxay leedahay faaтАЩidooyin caafimaad oo cajaaтАЩib ah.Toontu waxay inta ugu badan ka kooban tahay maado loo yaqaano Allicin taasi oo la dagaalanta bacteriyada, virus-ka, funguska iyo sidoo kalena jidhka sunta ka saarta.Toonta waxay kaloo ka mid tahay geedo daaweedyada ay cilmibaarayaashu isku waafaqeen waxtarkeeda caafimaadkeeda.Maqaalkan waxaan kuugu sheegi doonaa 8 faaтАЩido oo toontu u leedahay caafimaadka. 1. WAXAY HORMARISAA CFMDKA WADNAHA:Toontu waxay si aad ah ugu fiican tahay caafimaadka wadnaha, waxay caawimaad ka geysataa inay horumariso wareegga dhiigga waxay hoos u dhigtaa kalastaroolka, waxaanay ka hortagtaa cudurrada wadnaha ku dhaca, sidoo kale waxay ka hortagtaa in halbowlayaasha wadnaha ee dhiigga haba ay cidhiidhi noqdaan taasi oo ah waxa ugu badan ee sababa wadne istaagga.2. WAXAY KANTOROOSHA DHIIGKARKA:Cilmi Baadhis ayaa waxay caddeysay in toontu ay hoos u dhigto dhiig karka, dadka dhiig karka qabaa waa inay maalin walba cunaan jab yar oo toon qeydhiin ah iyagoo calooshoodu madhan tahay.3. WAXAY SARRE UQAADA DIFAACA JIRKA:Toonta waxaa aad ugu badan fiitamiinada ay ka mid yihiin Fiitamiin C, B6 iyo macdanaha sillium iyo magnesium kuwaasi oo si aad ah sare ugu qaada difaaca jidhka.4.WAXAY DAWEYSA QUFACA IYO HERGEBKA:Toontu waxay si weyn u daweysaa qufaca iyo durayga sidoo kale waxay sidoo kale waxay faaтАЩiido weyn u leedahay daweynta xiiqda (asthma) iyo burukiitada.5. WAXAY LADAGAALANTA ELERJIGA:Toonta Waxaa ku jira maadooyin la dagaalama fayraaska iyo inflamation-ka kuwaasoo jidhka ka caawiya inuu la dagaalamo noocyada kala duwan ee elerjiga ama xasaasiyadda.6. WAXAY DAWEYSAA ILKO XANUUNKA:Toontu waxay sidoo kale aad hoos ugu dhigtaa ilko xanuunka maadaama ay ku jiraan maadooyin la dagaalama bakteeriyada. Si iligga ku xanuunaya si dhakhso ah xanuunka uga joojiso burburi jab yar oo toon ah islamarkaana dul dhig iligga ku xanuunaya.7.WAXAY CAWISAA DHEFSHIIDKA:Toontu nidaamisaa shaqada caloosha si ay sare ugu qaado dheefshiidka iyo burburinta cuntada toontu waxay sidoo kale beerka ku caawisaa inuu jidhka kasii daayo sunta, iyadoo sidoo kalena beerka ka ilaalisa inay waxyeello soo gaadho.8. WAXAY KAHORTAGTA KANSARKA:Toontu waxay caawimo ka geysataa ka hortagga kansarka siiba kansarka ku dhaca hab-dhiska dheefshiidka iyo sambabada. Dadka taariikh ahaan qoysaskooda uu kansarku ku lugleeyahay waxaa lagula taliyaa inay si joogto u cunaan toonta si ay hoos u dhigaan khatarta ay ugu jiraan noocyo badan oo kansar ah. ALLAHA INNAGA HAYO DHAMMAANTEEN."},{"question":"р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ър╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢▒р╖Пр╢╕р╖Тр╢Ър╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Тр╢╗ р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Ьр╢╕р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╢▒ р╢╗р╢зр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖Т. р╢Т р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╢з р╢Фр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢Жр╖Др╖Пр╢╗ р╖Гр╖Д р╢нр╢лр╢╢р╖Тр╢╕р╖К р╖Гр╖Ьр╢║р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢║р╢╕р╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢зр╖П р╢Ьр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╖Т. р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕р╢лр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢з р╢Ср╢Ъ р╢нр╖Рр╢▒р╢Ъ р╢╗р╖Рр╢│р╖У р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Г р╢╕р╖Фр╢╜р╖К р╖Бр╖Тр╖Вр╖Кр╢зр╖Пр╢ар╖Пр╢╗р╖Ар╢╜р╢з р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Тр╢║."},{"question":"uAYa uyambhambhazela","answer":"Aya is beating his chest."},{"question":"Bana herhangi bir ┼Яairden bir ┼Яiir yaz.","answer":"Sana gitme demeyece─Яim.├Ь┼Я├╝yorsun ceketimi al.G├╝n├╝n en g├╝zel saatleri bunlar.Yan─▒mda kal.Sana gitme demeyece─Яim.Gene de sen bilirsin.Yalanlar istiyorsan yalanlar s├╢yleyeyim,─░ncinirsin.Sana gitme demeyece─Яim,Ama gitme, Lavinia.Ad─▒n─▒ gizleyece─ЯimSen de bilme, Lavinia.├Цzdemir Asaf - Lavinia"},{"question":"Inona ny anaran'ny \\" Idlewild Airport \\" amin'izao ? ","answer":"Niova ho \\" John F. Kennedy International Airport \\" ny Idlewild Airport amin'izao. "},{"question":"рокро╛ро░родро┐ропро╛ро░рпН роЪродрпНро░рокродро┐ роЪро┐ро╡ро╛роЬро┐ропрпИрокрпНрокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ рокро╛роЯро┐роп рокро╛роЯро▓рпИ роОро┤рпБродрпБроХ.","answer":"роЬропроЬроп рокро╡ро╛ройро┐! роЬропроЬроп рокро╛ро░родроорпН!роЬропроЬроп рооро╛родро╛! роЬропроЬроп родрпБро░рпНроХрпНроХро╛!ро╡роирпНродрпЗ рооро╛родро░роорпН! ро╡роирпНродрпЗ рооро╛родро░роорпН!роЪрпЗройрпИродрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпНроХро╛ро│рпН! роЪро┐ро▒роирпНрод роороирпНродро┐ро░ро┐роХро╛ро│рпН!ропро╛ройрпИродрпН родро▓рпИро╡ро░рпБроорпН роЕро░рпБроирпНродро┐ро▒ро▓рпН ро╡рпАро░ро░рпНроХро╛ро│рпН!роЕродро┐ро░род рооройро░рпНроХро╛ро│рпН! родрпБро░роХродрпН родродро┐рокро░рпНроХро╛ро│рпНроОродро┐ро░ро┐роХро│рпН родрпБрогрпБроХрпНроХрпБро▒ роЗроЯро┐родрпНродро┐роЯрпБ рокродро╛родро┐роХро╛ро│рпН!ро╡рпЗро▓рпЖро▒ро┐ рокроЯрпИроХро╛ро│рпН! роЪрпВро▓рпЖро▒ро┐ рооро▒ро╡ро░рпНроХро╛ро│рпН!роХро╛ро▓ ройрпБро░рпБроХрпНроХрпНроХрпКро│рпБроорпН роХрогрпИродрпБро░роирпН родро┐роЯрпБро╡рпАро░рпН.рооро▒рпНро▒рпБрооро╛ ропро┐ро░ро╡ро┐родроорпН рокро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН родроорпНроорпИроЪрпНроЪрпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐роЯрпБроирпН родро┐ро▒ройрпБроЯрпИродрпН родрпАро░ро░родрпН родро┐ройроЩрпНроХро╛ро│рпН!ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпН ро╡ро╛ро┤ро┐роп! ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпН ро╡ро╛ро┤ро┐роп!родрпЗро╡ро┐роирпБроирпН родроороХрпНроХрпЖро▓ро╛роорпН родро┐ро░рпБро╡ро░рпБро│рпН рокрпБро░ро┐роХ!рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН родроорпНрокрпБро▓рпИ роиро╛ро▒рпНро▒роорпЗ ропро▒ро┐ропро╛роЖро▒рпНро▒ро▓рпНроХрпКрогрпН роЯро┐ро░рпБроирпНродродро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроХро┤рпН роиро╛роЯрпБ!ро╡рпЗродроирпВро▓рпН рокро┤ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐родрпНродро┐роЪрпИ рооро┐ро▓рпЗроЪрпНроЪро░рпНрокро╛родроорпБроорпН рокрпКро▒рпБрокрпНрокро│рпЛ рокро╛ро░род родрпЗро╡ро┐?ро╡рпАро░ро░рпБроорпН роЕро╡ро░ро┐роЪрпИ ро╡ро┐ро░ро┐родрпНродро┐роЯрпБ рокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпБроорпНрокро╛ро░рпЖро▓ро╛роорпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроХро┤рпН рокро░рокрпНрокро┐роп роиро╛роЯрпБ!родро░рпНроороорпЗ роЙро░рпБро╡рооро╛родрпН родро┤рпИродрпНрод рокрпЗ ро░ро░роЪро░рпБроорпНроиро┐ро░рпНрооро▓ роорпБройро┐ро╡ро░рпБроорпН роиро┐ро▒роирпНрод роиройрпН ройро╛роЯрпБ!ро╡рпАро░ро░рпИрокрпН рокрпЖро▒ро╛род роорпЗройрпНроорпИроирпАро░рпН роороЩрпНроХрпИропрпИроКро░ро╡ро░рпН рооро▓роЯро┐ропрпЖройрпН ро▒рпБро░рпИродрпНродро┐роЯрпБ роиро╛роЯрпБ!рокро╛ро░родрокрпН рокрпВрооро┐ рокро┤роорпНрокрпЖро░рпБроорпН рокрпВрооро┐;роирпАро░родройрпН рокрпБродро▓рпНро╡ро░рпН, роЗроирпН роиро┐ройрпИро╡роХро▒рпН ро▒ро╛родрпАро░рпН!рокро╛ро░род роиро╛роЯрпБ рокро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпЖро▓ро╛роорпН родро┐ро▓роХроорпН;роирпАро░родройрпН рокрпБродро▓рпНро╡ро░рпН, роЗроирпН роиро┐ройрпИро╡роХро▒рпН ро▒ро╛родрпАро░рпН!ро╡ро╛ройроХ роорпБроЯрпНроЯрпБроорпН роЗрооропрооро╛ро▓рпН ро╡ро░рпИропрпБроорпНроПройрпИроп родро┐роЪрпИроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродро┐ро░рпИроХрпН роХроЯро▓рпБроорпНроХро╛родрпНродро┐роЯрпБ роиро╛роЯрпБ! роХроЩрпНроХрпИропрпБроорпН роЪро┐роирпНродрпБро╡рпБроорпНродрпВродрпНродро┐ро░рпИ ропроорпБройрпИропрпБроорпН роЪрпБройрпИроХро│рпБроорпН рокрпБройро▓рпНроХро│рпБроорпНроЗройрпНройро░рпБроорпН рокрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпНроХро│рпБроорпН роЗрогрпИропро┐ро▓ро╛ ро╡ро│роЩрпНроХро│рпБроорпНроЙройрпНройрод рооро▓рпИроХро│рпБроорпН роТро│ро┐ро░рпНродро░рпБ роиро╛роЯрпБ!рокрпИроирпНроиро┐ро▒рокрпН рокро┤ройроорпН рокроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓ро╛ родро│ро┐роХрпНроХроорпИроирпНроиро┐ро▒ роорпБроХро┐ро▓рпНроХро│рпН ро╡ро┤роЩрпНроХрпБроорпН рокрпКройрпНройро╛роЯрпБ!родрпЗро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐роЯроорпН, родро┐ро▒ро▓рпБропро░рпН роорпБройро┐ро╡ро░рпНроЖро╡ро▓рпЛ роЯроЯрпИропрпБроорпН роЕро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроХро┤рпН роиро╛роЯрпБ!роКройроорпКройрпНро▒ро▒ро┐ропро╛ роЮро╛ройроорпЖропрпН рокрпВрооро┐,ро╡ро╛ройро╡ро░рпН ро╡ро┐ро┤рпИропрпБроорпН рооро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐ропро╛ро░рпН родрпЗропроорпН!рокро╛ро░род роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐роЪрпИ рокроХро░ропро╛ройрпН ро╡ро▓рпНро▓ройрпЛ?роирпАро░родройрпН рокрпБродро▓рпНро╡ро░рпН роиро┐ройрпИро╡роХро▒рпН ро▒ро╛родрпАро░рпН!родро╛ропрпНродрпНродро┐ро░рпБ роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИродрпН родро▒рпБроХрогрпН рооро┐ро▓рпЗроЪрпНроЪро░рпНрокрпЗропрпНродрпНродроХрпИ роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпЛ ро░рпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпБроорпН ро╡ройрпНроорпИропрпБроорпНроЮро╛ройроорпБроорпН роЕро▒ро┐ропро╛ роиро╡рпИрокрпБро░ро┐ рокроХрпИро╡ро░рпНро╡ро╛ройроХроорпН роЕроЯроХрпНроХ ро╡роирпНродро┐роЯрпБроорпН роЕро░роХрпНроХро░рпН рокрпЛро▓рпНроЗроирпНроиро╛ро│рпН рокроЯрпИ роХрпКрогро░рпНроирпНродрпБ роЗройрпНройро▓рпНроЪрпЖропрпН роХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН!роЖро▓ропроорпН роЕро┤ро┐родрпНродро▓рпБроорпН роЕро░рпБрооро▒рпИ рокро┤ро┐родрпНродро▓рпБроорпНрокро╛ро▓ро░рпИ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБродрпНродро░рпИрокрпН рокроЪрпБроХрпНроХро│рпИ роТро┤ро┐родрпНродро▓рпБроорпНрооро╛родро░рпНроХро▒рпН рокро┤ро┐родрпНродро▓рпБроорпН рооро▒рпИро╡ро░рпН ро╡рпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроПродроорпЗ роЪрпВро┤рпНро╡родрпБроорпН роЗропро▒рпНро▒ро┐роиро┐ро▒рпН роХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН!роЪро╛родрпНродро┐ро░родрпН родрпКроХрпБродроЩрпНропрпИродрпН родро╛ро┤рпНродрпНродрпБро╡рпИроХрпН роХроЩрпНройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпНроХрпЛродрпНродроЩрпНро░ роороЩрпНроХрпИропро░рпН роХрпБро▓роЩрпНроХрпЖроЯрпБроХрпН роХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпНроОрогрпНрогро┐ро▓ родрпБрогрпИро╡ро░рпНроХро╛ро│рпН! роОроороХрпНроХро┐ро╡ро░рпН роЪрпЖропрпБроирпНродрпБропро░рпНроХрогрпНрогро┐ропроорпН рооро▒рпБродрпНродройро░, роЖрогрпНроорпИропрпБроЩрпН роХроЯро┐роирпНродройро░рпН,рокрпКро░рпБро│ро┐ройрпИроЪрпН роЪро┐родрпИродрпНродройро░рпН, рооро░рпБро│ро┐ройрпИ ро╡ро┐родрпИродрпНродройро░рпНродро┐рогрпНроорпИропрпИ ропро┤ро┐родрпНродрпБрокрпН рокрпЖрогрпНроорпИропро┐роЩрпН роХро│ро┐родрпНродройро░рпН,рокро╛ро░родрокрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпНрокрпЖропро░рпН рокро┤ро┐рокрпНрокрпЖроп ро░ро╛роХрпНроХро┐ройро░рпН,роЪрпВро░ро░рпНродроорпН роороХрпНроХро│рпИродрпН родрпКро┤рпБроорпНрокро░ро╛ропрпНрокрпН рокрпБро░ро┐роирпНродройро░рпН,ро╡рпАро░ро┐ропроорпН роЕро┤ро┐роирпНродрпБ роорпЗройрпНроорпИропрпБроорпН роТро┤ро┐роирпНродрпБ роироорпНроЖро░ро┐ропро░рпН рокрпБро▓рпИропро░рпБроХрпН роХроЯро┐роорпИроХ ро│ро╛ропро┐ройро░рпН.рооро▒рпНро▒ро┐родрпИрокрпН рокрпКро▒рпБродрпНродрпБ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡родрпЛ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐роХрпКро│рпН рокрпБро▓рпИропро░рпНродро╛ро│рпН ро╡рпАро┤рпНроирпНродрпБроХрпКро▓рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпАро░рпН?роорпКроХрпНроХрпБроХро│рпНродро╛ройрпН родрпЛройрпНро▒ро┐ роорпБроЯро┐ро╡родрпБ рокрпЛро▓роороХрпНроХро│ро╛ропрпНрокрпН рокро┐ро▒роирпНродрпЛро░рпН роороЯро┐ро╡родрпБ родро┐рогрпНрогроорпН.родро╛ропрпНродрпНродро┐ро░рпБ роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИродрпН родроХро░рпНродрпНродро┐роЯрпБ рооро┐ро▓рпЗроЪрпНроЪро░рпИрооро╛ропрпНродрпНродро┐роЯ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокро╛ройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпБроорпЛро░рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпБроХрпКро▓рпН?рооро╛ройроорпЖройрпН ро▒ро┐ро▓ро╛родрпБ рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН родрпКро┤рпБроорпНрокро╛ропрпНроИройроорпБро▒рпН ро▒ро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХ роОро╡ройрпНроХрпКро▓рпЛ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпБро╡ройрпН?родро╛ропрпНрокро┐ро▒ройрпН роХрпИрокрпНрокроЯроЪрпН роЪроХро┐рокрпНрокро╡ ройро╛роХро┐роиро╛ропрпЖрой ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡рпЛройрпН роирооро░ро┐ро▓рпНроЗроЩрпН роХрпБро│ройрпЛ?рокро┐роЪрпНроЪрпИро╡ро╛ро┤рпН ро╡рпБроХроирпНродрпБ рокро┐ро▒ро░рпБроЯрпИроп ропро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ро▓рпНроЕроЪрпНроЪроорпБро▒рпН ро▒ро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокрпЛройрпН роЖро░ро┐роп ройро▓рпНро▓ройрпН,рокрпБройрпНрокрпБро▓ро╛ро▓рпН ропро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИропрпИрокрпН рокрпЛро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропрпЗ родро╛ропрпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБроЕройрпНрокро┐ро▓ро╛ родро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокрпЛройрпН роЖро░ро┐роп ройро▓рпНро▓ройрпН.рооро╛роЯрпНроЪро┐родрпАро░рпН рооро┐ро▓рпЗроЪрпНроЪро░рпН рооройрокрпНрокроЯро┐ ропро╛ро│рпБроорпНроЖроЯрпНроЪро┐ропро┐ ро▓роЯроЩрпНроХрпБро╡рпЛройрпН роЖро░ро┐роп ройро▓рпНро▓ройрпН.роЖро░ро┐ропродрпН родройрпНроорпИ роЕро▒рпНро▒ро┐роЯрпБроЮрпН роЪро┐ро▒ро┐ропро░рпНропро╛ро░ро┐ро╡рогрпН роЙро│ро░ро╡ро░рпН ропро╛рогрпНроЯрпЗройрпБроорпН роТро┤ро┐роХ!рокроЯрпИроорпБроХродрпНродрпБ роЗро▒роирпНродрпБ рокродроорпНрокрпЖро▒ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокро╛роХрпНроХроЯрпИрокроЯрпБ рооро╛роХрпНроХро│рпЖройрпН роХрогрпНроорпБройро┐ро▓рпН ро▓ро╛родрпАро░рпН!роЪрпЛродро░ро░рпН родроорпНроорпИродрпН родрпБро░рпЛроХро┐роХро│рпН роЕро┤ро┐рокрпНрокрооро╛родро░ро░рпН роиро▓родрпНродро┐ройрпН роороХро┐ро┤рпНрокро╡ройрпН роороХро┐ро┤рпНроХ,роиро╛роЯрпЖро▓ро╛роорпН рокро┐ро▒ро░рпНро╡роЪроорпН роирогрпНрогрпБродро▓рпН роиро┐ройрпИропро╛ройрпНро╡рпАроЯрпБроЪрпЖройрпН ро▒рпКро│ро┐роХрпНроХ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпБро╡рпЛройрпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроХ!родрпЗроЪроорпЗ роиро▓ро┐ро╡рпКроЯрпБ родрпЗропрпНроирпНродро┐роЯ роороХрпНроХро│ро┐ройрпНрокро╛роЪроорпЗ рокрпЖро░ро┐родрпЖройрокрпН рокро╛ро░рпНрокрпНрокро╡ройрпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНроХ!роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБро│ро╛ро░рпН рокроЪро┐ропро┐ройро╛ро▓рпН роиро▓ро┐роирпНродро┐роЯродрпН родройрпНро╡ропро┐ро▒рпБроКроЯрпНроЯрпБродро▓рпН рокрпЖро░роЩрпНродрпЖрой роЙрогрпНрогрпБро╡рпЛройрпН роЪрпЖро▓рпНроХ!роЖрогрпБро░рпБроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯ рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроорпН роЕро▓ро┐роХро│рпБроорпНро╡рпАрогро┐ро▓рпНроЗроЩрпН роХро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпЖройрпИ ро╡рпЖро▒рпБродрпНродро┐роЯро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпЗройрпН.роЖро░ро┐ропро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН! роЖрогрпНроХро│рпНроЗроЩрпНроХрпБ роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!ро╡рпАро░ро┐ропроорпН рооро┐роХрпБроирпНрод роорпЗройрпНроорпИропрпЛро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!рооро╛ройроорпЗ рокрпЖро░ро┐родрпЖрой роородро┐рокрпНрокро╡ро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!роИройроорпЗ рокрпКро▒ро╛род роЗропро▓рпНрокро┐ройро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!родро╛ропрпНроиро╛роЯрпН роЯройрпНрокрпБро▒рпБ родройрпИропро░рпН роЗроЩрпНроХрпБ роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!рооро╛ропрпНроиро╛роЯрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропро┐ройрпН рооро╛ропрпНрокро╡ро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!рокрпБро▓рпИропро░рпНродроорпН родрпКро┤рпБроорпНрокрпИрокрпН рокрпКро▒рпБроХрпНроХро┐ро▓ро╛ро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!роХро▓рпИропро▒рпБ рооро┐ро▓рпЗроЪрпНроЪро░рпИроХрпН роХроЯро┐рокро╡ро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!роКро░ро╡ро░рпН родрпБропро░ро┐ро▓рпНроирпЖроЮрпН роЪрпБро░рпБроХрпБро╡рпАро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!роЪрпЛро░ роирпЖроЮрпНроЪроЩрпНро▓ро╛родрпН родрпВропро╡ро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!родрпЗро╡ро┐родро╛ро│рпН рокрогро┐ропрпБроирпН родрпАро░ро░рпН роЗроЩрпНроХрпБ роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!рокро╛ро╡ро┐ропро░рпН роХрпБро░рпБродро┐ропрпИрокрпН рокро░рпБроХрпБро╡ро╛ро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!роЙроЯро▓ро┐ройрпИрокрпН рокрпЛро▒рпНро▒ро╛ роЙродрпНродрооро░рпН роЗро░рпБрооро┐ройрпН!роХроЯро▓рпНроороЯрпБрокрпН рокро┐ройрпБроорпНрооройроорпН роХро▓роЩрпНроХро▓ро░рпН роЙродро╡рпБрооро┐ройрпН!ро╡роорпНрооро┐ройрпЛ родрпБрогрпИро╡рпАро░рпН? рооро░рпБроЯрпНроЪро┐роХрпКро│рпН ро│ро╛родрпАро░рпН!роироорпНрооро┐ройрпЛ ро░ро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро▓рпИ роиро╛ро┤ро┐роХрпИрокрпН рокрпКро┤рпБродрпЖройрпБроорпНрокрпБро▓рпНро▓ро┐роп рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН рокрпКро▒рпБроХрпНроХро╡ро▓рпН ро▓ро╛ро░рпНроХрпКро▓рпН?роорпЖро▓рпНро▓ро┐роп родро┐ро░рпБро╡роЯро┐ ро╡рпАро▒рпБроЯрпИродрпН родрпЗро╡ро┐ропро┐ройрпНроЗройрпНройро░рпБро│рпН роироороХрпНроХрпЛро░рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБрогрпИ ропро╛роХрпБроорпНрокройрпНройро░рпБроорпН рокрпБроХро┤рпБроЯрпИрокрпН рокро╛ро░рпНродрпНродройрпБроорпН роХрогрпНрогройрпБроорпНро╡рпАрооройрпБроорпН родрпБро░рпЛрогройрпБроорпН ро╡рпАроЯрпНроЯрпБрооройрпН ро▒ро╛ройрпБроорпНро░ро╛рооройрпБроорпН ро╡рпЗро▒рпБро│ роЗро░рпБроирпНродро┐ро▒ро▓рпН ро╡рпАро░ро░рпБроорпНроиро▒рпНро▒рпБрогрпИ рокрпБро░ро┐ро╡ро░рпН; ро╡ро╛ройроХ, роиро╛роЯрпБро▒рпБроорпН!ро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропрпЗ ропройрпНро▒ро┐ ро╡рпЗро▒рпЖродрпБроорпН рокрпЖро▒рпБроХро┐ро▓рпЗроорпН!рокро▒рпНро▒ро▒рпБ роорпБройро┐ро╡ро░рпБроорпН роЖроЪро┐роХро│рпН рокроХро░рпНро╡ро░рпНроЪрпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройро┐ рооро┐ро┤рпЗроЪрпНроЪро░рпИродрпН родрпАро░рпНродрпНродро┐роЯ ро╡роорпНроорпАройрпН!роИроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро╛ро▒рпН роЪро┐ро░роЩрпНроХро│рпИ ро╡рпАроЯрпНроЯро┐роЯ роОро┤рпБрооро┐ройрпН!роирпАроЯрпНроЯро┐роп ро╡рпЗро▓рпНроХро│рпИ роирпЗро░ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роОро▒ро┐рооро┐ройрпН!ро╡ро╛ро│рпБроЯрпИ роорпБройрпИропро┐ройрпБроорпН ро╡ропроирпНродро┐роХро┤рпН роЪрпВро▓ро┐ройрпБроорпН,роЖро│рпБроЯрпИроХрпН роХро╛ро▓рпНроХ ро│роЯро┐ропро┐ройрпБроирпН родрпЗро░рпНроХро│ро┐ройрпНроЙро░рпБро│рпИропро┐ ройро┐роЯрпИропро┐ройрпБроорпН рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН родро▓рпИроХро│рпНроЙро░рпБро│рпИропро┐ро▒рпН роХрогрпНроЯрпБроирпЖроЮрпН роЪрпБро╡рокрпНрокрпБро▒ ро╡роорпНрооро┐ройрпН!роироорпНроЗродроорпН, рокрпЖро░рпБро╡ро│роорпН роиро▓ро┐роирпНродро┐роЯ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроорпН(ро╡ройрпНрооро┐ропрпИ) ро╡рпЗро░ро▒родрпН родрпКро▓рпИродрпНродрокро┐ройрпН ройройрпНро▒рпЛроЖрогрпЖройрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпБро╡рпЛроорпН, роЕройрпНро▒ро┐роиро╛роорпН роЗро▒рокрпНрокро┐ройрпБроорпНро╡ро╛ройрпБро▒рпБ родрпЗро╡ро░рпН роорогро┐ропрпБро▓ роХроЯрпИро╡рпЛроорпН,ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНро╡роорпЗро▒рпН рокро╛ро░род ро╡ро╛ройрпНрокрпБроХро┤рпНродрпН родрпЗро╡ро┐ропрпИродрпНродро╛ро┤рпНро╡ро┐ройро┐ройрпН ро▒рпБропро░рпНродрпНродро┐роп родроЯроорпНрокрпБроХро┤рпН рокрпЖро▒рпБро╡рпЛроорпН!рокрпЛро░рпЖройро┐ро▓рпН роЗродрпБрокрпЛро░рпН, рокрпБрогрпНрогро┐ропродрпН родро┐ро░рпБрокрпНрокрпЛро░рпН!рокро╛ро░ро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН роЗродрпБрокрпЛро▒рпН рокро╛ро░рпНродрпНродро┐роЯро▒рпН роХрпЖро│ро┐родрпЛ?роЖроЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпИроХрпН роХрпКройрпНро▒рпБ ро╡рпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐роХро│рпН роЗропро▒рпНро▒ро┐ро╡рпАроЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпИрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпБро╡ро╛ройрпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпБро╡ро╛ро░рпН роЪро┐ро▓ро░рпЗроирпЖроЮрпНроЪроХроХрпН роХрпБро░рпБродро┐ропрпИ роиро┐ро▓родрпНродро┐роЯрпИ ро╡роЯро┐родрпНродрпБро╡роЮрпНроЪроХ рооро┤ро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН рооро╛роороХроорпН рокрпБро░ро┐ро╡роорпНропро╛роорпНро╡рпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐ропро┐ро▓рпНроЗродрпБрокрпЛро▓рпН ро╡рпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐ропрпКройрпН ро▒ро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпИ!родро╡родрпНродро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН роЗродрпБрокрпЛро▓рпН родро╡роорпНрокро┐ро▒ро┐ родро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпИ!роорпБройрпНройрпИропрпЛро░рпН рокро╛ро░рпНродрпНродройрпН роорпБройрпИродрпНродро┐роЪрпИ роиро┐ройрпНро▒рпБродройрпНройрпЖродро┐ро░рпН роиро┐ройрпНро▒ родро│родрпНродро┐ройрпИ роирпЛроХрпНроХро┐роЯрооро╛родрпБро▓ро░рпН роЪрпЛродро░ро░рпН роорпИродрпНродрпБройро░рпН родро╛родрпИропро░рпНроХро╛родро▓ро┐ройрпН роирогрпНрокро░рпН роХро▓рпИродро░рпБ роХрпБро░ро╡ро░рпЖройрпНро▒рпБроЗройрпНройро╡ро░рпН роЗро░рпБродрпНродро▓рпНроХрогрпНроЯрпБ, роЗродропроорпНроирпКроирпН родрпЛройро╛ропрпНродрпНродройрпНройро░рпБроирпН родрпЖропрпНро╡ро┐роХроЪрпН роЪро╛ро░родро┐ роорпБройрпНройро░рпНроРропройрпЗ! роЗро╡ро░рпНроорпА родроорпНрокрпИропрпЛ родрпКроЯрпБрокрпНрокрпЗройрпН?ро╡рпИропроХродрпН родро░роЪрпБроорпН ро╡ро╛ройроХ роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐ропрпБроорпНрокрпЛропро┐ройрпБроорпН роЗро╡ро░рпНродроорпИрокрпН рокрпЛро░ро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН ро╡рпАро┤рпНродрпНродрпЗройрпН.роорпЖропрпНропро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН роироЯрпБроХрпНроХроорпН роорпЗро╡рпБроХро┐ройрпН ро▒родрпБро╡ро╛ро▓,fроХрпИропро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпБроорпН роХро┤ройрпНро▒рпБро╡рпАро┤рпН роХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ.ро╡ро╛ропрпБро▓ро░рпН роХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ; рооройроорпН рокродрпИроХрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒родрпБ,роУропрпНро╡рпБро▒рпБроЩрпН роХро╛ро▓рпНроХро│, роЙро▓рпИроирпНродродрпБ роЪро┐ро░роороорпБроорпН,ро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропрпИ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпЗройрпН, роорпЗройрпНроорпИропрпИ ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпЗройрпНроЪрпБро▒рпНро▒рооро┐роЩрпН роХро▒рпБродрпНродрпБроЪрпН роЪрпБроХроорпНрокрпЖро▒ро▓рпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпЗройрпН,роОройрпИропро┐ро╡ро░рпН роХрпКро▓рпНро▓ро┐ройрпБроорпН роЗро╡ро░рпИропро╛ройрпН родрпАрогрпНроЯрпЗройрпН,роЪро┐ройрпИропро▒рпБродрпН родро┐роЯрпНроЯрокро┐ройрпН роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпЛ роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐?роОройрокрпНрокро▓ роХрпВро▒ро┐ропро╡рпН ро╡ро┐роирпНродро┐ро░ройрпН рокрпБродро▓рпНро╡ройрпНроХройрокрпНрокроЯрпИ ро╡ро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпИроХрпН роХро│родрпНродро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН роОро▒ро┐роирпНродрпБроЪрпЛро░рпНро╡рпЛроЯрпБ ро╡рпАро┤рпНроирпНродройройрпН, роЪрпБро░рпБродро┐ропро┐ройрпН роорпБроЯро┐ро╡ро╛ропрпНродрпНродрпЗро░рпНро╡ропро┐ройрпН роиро┐ройрпНро▒роироорпН родрпЖропрпНро╡ро┐роХрокрпН рокрпЖро░рпБрооро╛ройрпНро╡ро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпЖро▒ро┐роирпН родро┐ро░рпБроирпНрод ро╡рпАро░ройрпИ роирпЛроХрпНроХро┐рокрпБро▓рпНро▓ро┐роп роЕро▒ро┐ро╡рпКроЯрпБ рокрпБро▓роорпНрокрпБроХро┐ройрпН ро▒ройрпИропро╛ро▓рпНроЕро▒родрпНродро┐ройрпИрокрпН рокро┐ро░ро┐роирпНрод роЪрпБропрпЛродройро╛ родро┐ропро░рпИроЪрпНроЪрпЖро▒рпБродрпНродро┐ройро┐ рооро╛ропрпНрокрпНрокродрпБ родрпАроорпИропрпЖройрпН роХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ропрпН,роЙрогрпНроорпИропрпИ роЕро▒ро┐ропро╛ропрпН роЙро▒ро╡рпИропрпЗ роХро░рпБродро┐рокрпНрокрпЖрогрпНроорпИроХрпКрогрпН роЯрпЗродрпЛ рокро┐родро▒рпНро▒ро┐роиро┐ро▒рпН роХро┐ройрпНро▒ро╛ропрпНро╡роЮрпНроЪроХро░рпН, родрпАропро░рпН, рооройро┐родро░рпИ ро╡ро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡рпЛро░рпН,роирпЖроЮрпНроЪроХродрпН родро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроЯрпИ роирпАроЪро░рпНроХро│рпН; роЗройрпНройрпЛро░рпНродроорпНроорпКроЯрпБ рокро┐ро▒роирпНрод роЪроХрпЛродро░ро░ро╛ропро┐ройрпБроорпНро╡рпЖроорпНроорпИропрпЛ роЯрпКро▒рпБродрпНродро▓рпН ро╡рпАро░ро░рпНродроЮрпН роЪрпЖропро▓ро╛роорпН.роЖро░ро┐роп роирпАродро┐роирпА роЕро▒ро┐роХро┐ро▓рпИ рокрпЛро▓рпБроорпН!рокрпВро░ро┐ропро░рпН рокрпЛро▓рпНрооройроорпН рокрпБро┤рпБроЩрпНроХрпБро▒ ро▓ро╛ропро┐ройрпИроЕро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроХро┤рпН родрпЗропрпНрокрпНрокродрпБроорпН роЕройро╛ро░ро┐ропродрпН родроХрпИродрпНродрпБроорпНрокрпЖро░рпБроорпНрокродродрпН родроЯрпИропрпБрооро╛роорпН рокрпЖрогрпНроорпИропрпЖроЩрпН роХрпЖропрпНродро┐ройрпИ?рокрпЗроЯро┐роорпИ ропроХро▒рпНро▒рпБ! роиро┐ройрпН рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпИ рооро▒роирпНродро┐роЯрпЗро▓рпН!роИроЯро┐ро▓ро╛рокрпН рокрпБроХро┤ро┐ройро╛ропрпН! роОро┤рпБроХро╡рпЛ роОро┤рпБроХ! роОройрпНро▒рпБроорпЖропрпНроЮрпН роЮро╛ройроорпНроироорпН роЗро▒рпИропро╡ро░рпН роХрпВро▒роХрпНроХрпБройрпНро▒рпЖройрпБроорпН ро╡ропро┐ро░роХрпН роХрпКро▒рпНро▒ро╡ро╛ройрпН рокрпБропродрпНродрпЛройрпНроЕро▒роорпЗ рокрпЖро░ро┐родрпЖрой роЕро▒ро┐роирпНродро┐роЯрпБ рооройродрпНродройро╛ропрпНрооро▒роорпЗ роЙро░рпБро╡рпБроЯрпИ рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН родроорпНроорпИроЪрпНроЪрпБро▒рпНро▒роорпБроорпН роирпЛроХрпНроХро╛ройрпН родрпЛро┤роорпИ роородро┐ропро╛ройрпНрокро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН родроорпИропрпЖро▓ро╛роорпН рокро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроХро┐ро░рпИ ропро╛роХрпНроХро┐ройройрпН.ро╡ро┐роЪропройройрпН ро▒ро┐ро░рпБроирпНрод ро╡ро┐ропройрпНрокрпБроХро┤рпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпНроЗроЪрпИропрпБроиро▒рпН ро▒ро╡родрпНродро╛ро▓рпН роЗройрпНро▒рпБро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроирпН родро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпНроЖро░ро┐роп ро╡рпАро░ро░рпНроХро╛ро│рпН! роЕро╡ро░рпБроЯрпИ рооро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро▓ро░рпН,родрпЗро░ро┐ро▓рпНроЗроирпН роиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройро░рпН, роЪрпЖро▒ро┐ро╡рпБроЯрпИ роЙро▒ро╡ро┐ройро░рпН,роироорпНроорпИропро┐ройрпН ро▒рпЖродро┐ро░рпНроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роиропройро┐ро▓ро╛рокрпН рокрпБро▓рпНро▓рпЛро░рпН,роЪрпЖроорпНроорпИродрпАро░рпН рооро┐ро▓рпЗроЪрпНроЪро░рпН, родрпЗроЪроорпБроорпН рокро┐ро▒ро┐родро╛роорпНрокро┐ро▒рокрпНрокро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН роЕройрпНройро┐ропро░рпН, рокрпЗроЪрпНроЪро┐ройро┐ро▓рпН роЕройрпНройро┐ропро░рпНроЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокрпБроЯрпИ ропро╛ро░ро┐ропроЪрпН роЪрпАро░рпНроорпИропрпИ роЕро▒ро┐ропро╛ро░рпН."},{"question":"╪з┘Г┘Е┘Д ╪з┘Д╪м┘Е┘Д╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К╪й:┘И┘К╪н╪к┘И┘К ╪з┘Д╪┤╪з┘К ╪з┘Д╪г╪│┘И╪п ┘И╪з┘Д╪г╪о╪╢╪▒ ┘И╪з┘Д┘Е╪з╪к╪┤╪з ┘И╪г┘И┘Д┘И┘Ж╪║ ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Г╪з┘Б┘К┘К┘Ж╪М ┘И┘З┘И ┘Е┘Ж╪и┘З ┘К╪м╪и ╪з┘Д╪н╪п ┘Е┘Ж┘З ╪г╪л┘Ж╪з╪б ╪з┘Д╪н┘Е┘Д. ┘И╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д╪▒╪║┘Е ┘Е┘Ж ╪г┘Ж┘З╪з ╪в┘Е┘Ж╪й ╪и╪┤┘Г┘Д ╪╣╪з┘Е╪М ┘Б╪е┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪│╪з╪б ┘В╪п ┘К╪│╪к┘Б╪п┘Ж ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪к┘В┘Д┘К┘Д ┘Е┘Ж ╪к┘Ж╪з┘И┘Д┘З┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘К┘И┘Е┘К ┘Д╪г┘Ж┘И╪з╪╣ ╪з┘Д╪┤╪з┘К╪М","answer":"╪з┘Д╪к┘К ╪к╪н╪к┘И┘К ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Г╪з┘Б┘К┘К┘Ж ╪г╪л┘Ж╪з╪б ╪з┘Д╪н┘Е┘Д╪М ╪и╪н┘К╪л ┘Д╪з ┘К╪к╪м╪з┘И╪▓ ╪з┘Д┘Е╪г╪о┘И╪░ ╪з┘Д┘К┘И┘Е┘К 200 ┘Е┘Д┘К╪║╪▒╪з┘Е."},{"question":"Responde la siguiente pregunta :┬┐D├│nde estudi├│ la universidad David Schwimmer?","answer":"La respuesta es en la universidad del Noroeste. "},{"question":"┘Д╪п┘К ┘З╪░╪з ╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д ╪г┘К┘Ж ┘К┘И╪м╪п ╪п┘Е╪з╪║ ╪з┘Д╪е┘Ж╪│╪з┘Ж ╪Я ╪М ╪г╪м╪и ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ╪и╪╖╪▒┘К┘В╪й ┘Е╪и╪│╪╖╪й.","answer":"╪н╪│┘Ж╪з┘Л. ╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й ┘З┘К ┘Б┘К ╪м┘Е╪м┘Е╪к┘З."},{"question":"ф╕║ф╗еф╕ЛчЪДхОЯцЦЗч╗ЩшпСцЦЗя╝ЪшЛ╗хЭЪхПмшзБя╝ИщлШц│░я╝Йя╝МцВжф╣Ля╝МщЧоф╗еф╕║ц▓╗ф╣ЛцЬмуАВхп╣цЫ░я╝ЪтАЬц▓╗цЬмхЬих╛Чф║║я╝Мх╛ЧхЕехЬихобф╕╛я╝Мхобф╕╛хЬица╕чЬЯя╝МцЬкцЬЙхоШх╛ЧхЕ╢ф║║шАМхЫ╜хо╢ф╕Нц▓╗шАЕф╣ЯуАВтАЭхЭЪцЫ░я╝ЪтАЬхПпш░Уш╛ЮчоАшАМчРЖхНЪчЯгуАВтАЭ","answer":"чмжхЭЪхПмшзБщлШц│░я╝Мх╛ИхЦЬцмвф╗Ця╝МхРСф╗Цшп╖цХЩц▓╗хЫ╜чЪДца╣цЬмхКЮц│ХуАВщлШц│░хЫЮчнФшп┤я╝ЪтАЬц▓╗хЫ╜чЪДца╣цЬмхКЮц│ХхЬиф║Ох╛Чф║║цЙНя╝Мх╛Чф║║цЙНхЬиф║ОцЕОщЗНцОишНРя╝МцЕОщЗНцОишНРхЬиф║ОшАГхпЯш┐Щф║║чЪДчЬЯхоЮцГЕхЖ╡уАВцпПф╕кхоШф╜Нх╛ЧхИ░хРИщАВф║║щАЙя╝МхЫ╜хо╢хН┤ц▓╗чРЖх╛Чф╕Нхе╜чЪДцГЕхЖ╡я╝МцШпф╕Нф╝ЪцЬЙчЪДуАВтАЭшЛ╗хЭЪя╝ИхРмхРОя╝Йшп┤я╝ЪтАЬшп┤чЪДчЬЯцШпшиАшпНчоАчХешАМщБУчРЖц╖▒х╣┐хХКуАВтАЭ"},{"question":"C├й h├й Richard Brinsley Sheridan/ ","answer":"Dr├бmad├│ir as Baile ├Бtha Cliath ab ea Richard Brinsley Sheridan (a rugadh ar 30 Deireadh F├│mhair 1751 -a d'├йag 7 I├║il 1816), agus ├║in├йir na hamharclainne Drury Lane i Londain ├│ 1776 go dt├н 1811.Ba den fh├нorfhuil ├й╦Р a athair, Tom├бis, aisteoir, agus a sheanathair, an Dr Thomas Sheridan (1687тАУ1738), m├║inteoir c├бili├║il agus cara m├│r Swift. Fuir s├й post san amharclann Drury Lane, ├бit a raibh Ble├б Cliathach eile - an tean├│r Michael Kelly ag obiar.Is l├йir freisin gurbh fhear m├│r grinn ├й Sheridan. O├нche ar fh├бg Michael Kelly a theach faoi Sheridan agus beirt cairde leis, d'├│l siad c├║ig bhuid├йal p├│irt, dh├б bhuid├йal f├нona Maid├йarach agus buid├йal branda, agus bh├н Sheridan chomh tinn sin ina dhiaidh nach bhf├йadadh s├й ├йir├н go dt├н a seacht a chlog tr├бthn├│na an lae d├бr gcionn."},{"question":"ро╡ро┐ройро╛ : роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роорпБродройрпН роорпБродро▓ро╛роХ ро╡ро╛ройрпКро▓ро┐ роТро▓ро┐рокро░рокрпНрокрпБ родрпБро╡роЩрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ..............","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: 1927"},{"question":"In┼Яaatta en ├зok hangi ├зimento kullan─▒l─▒r?","answer":"Bununla beraber, en yayg─▒n kullan─▒lan ├зimentolar genellikle OPC ve PPC'dir. OPC yani a├з─▒l─▒m─▒ s─▒radan Portland ├зimentosu olan bu ├зimento t├╝r├╝ t├╝m genel beton yap─▒lar i├зin uygun olan ve en yayg─▒n ┼Яekilde kullan─▒lan ├зimento t├╝r├╝d├╝r."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ┘З┘И ╪з┘Д┘Б┘К╪к╪з┘Е┘К┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Е╪│╪ж┘И┘Д ╪╣┘Ж ╪к┘В┘И┘К╪й ┘Ж╪╕╪▒ ╪з┘Д╪е┘Ж╪│╪з┘Ж ╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й : ┘Б┘К╪к╪з┘Е┘К┘Ж ╪г."},{"question":"├Аwс╗Нn ├аd├║gb├▓ ├мl├║ Il├йс╣г├а","answer":"1. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мk├│t├м ├Мtum├▓: ├Мb├н y├м├н ni ├аwon omo ogun ├Мj├иs├а gb├а l├й ├аwon ├▓t├б won ni ├мgb├а ogun ni ├иy├н, ├иka ├иde l├│ f├а ├б t├н ├│ fi j├й ├Мk├│t├м.2. ├Аd├║gbo: B├нl├бd├╣ ├Мtum├▓: Or├║ko ow├б ket├аl├б t├│ j├и ni Il├йs├а ni B├нl├бd├╣ Ar├иre, ├мr├бnt├н r├и ni won fi so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ni or├║ko r├и. N├мgb├а t├н ├▓ ti d├й or├н oy├и, ├│ w├б gbaj├║m├▓ d├йbi p├й f├н ├аwon ├и├иy├аn ba n lo si ├аd├║gb├▓ yen, d├нgb├▓ ki won so pe ├аwon n lo si ├▓gb├│n w├│n ├б ni ├аwon n lo s├н il├й B├нl├бd├╣ b├н w├│n se so ├│ ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н di B├нl├бd├╣ n├мy├н3. ├Аd├║gbo: Ota p├иt├й ├Мtum├▓: ibi t├н ├аwon jagunjagun ├Мj├иs├а pelu ├аwon omo Ogun ├Иk├мt├м ti p├аd├й n├н ├мgb├а Ogun ni ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н tor├н p├й ota ├мb├│n p├▓ ni il├и ibi y├м├н l├йy├мn Ogun y├м├н ni won se so o n├н ota p├иt├й.4. ├Аd├║gbo: Omi Asor├▓ ├Мtum├▓: Omi kan w├а ni ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н t├н won ┼Д p├и ni asor├▓ tori omi y├м├н ni won se so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ni omi-asor├▓.5. ├Аd├║gbo: Orink├╣nr├аn ├Мtum├▓: ├Аwon ├иn├мy├аn gb├а p├й igb├│ t├н ├│ w├а ni ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ni ├мgb├а ├аtij├│ ni ├аwon ab├аm├м l├│p├▓l├│p├▓ eni t├│ s├м m├║ ki won gb├а p├й ├▓r├аn ni y├│├▓ ri, Or├мn-ken-├▓r├аn (├иd├и ├Мj├иs├а) O r├мn kan ├▓r├аn.6. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мd├н ├аy├аn ├Мtum├▓: Igi ├а├аy├аn kan w├а n├н agb├иgb├и y├м├н tele ├иy├н l├│ f├а├б t├н won fi so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н n├н ├мd├н ├аy├аn.7. ├Аd├║gbo: Ita-Balogun ├Мtum├▓: ├Аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ni il├й Obal├│gun Ilesa w├а n├н ├аk├│k├▓ ti won so or├║ko ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н (├Мta-Obalogun).8. ├Аd├║gbo: M├╣r├│k├▓ ├Мtum├▓: Ibi y├м├н koj├б ibi t├н ├мr├│k├▓ kan w├а d├н├и, ├иy├н l├│ f├а ├б ti won fi so pe o-mu-iroko (├иd├и ├Мj├иs├а) ├мtum├▓-mu-iroko nip ├й ├│ koj├б ├мr├│k├▓ m├╣r├│k├▓.9. ├Аd├║gbo: Isar├и ├Мtum├▓: Ibi t├н ├аwon Ha├║s├б ┼Д gb├й t├н won s├н ti n ta oj├а, ├аlej├▓ ni ar├и n├н ├иd├и ├Мj├иs├а10. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мd├бs├а ├Мtum├▓: ├Аwon t├н won ├│n d├б ara won s├а s├н ├▓n├а kan ni ├мtum├▓ ├мd├бs├а, ├аwon kan k├║r├▓ ni ├а├бr├нn ├мgboro, w├│n s├м lo da ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н s├нl├и ni won ba so o ni ├Мd├бs├а.11. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тk├и-Padre ├Мtum├▓: (P├б├аd├м) Ibi y├м├н ni ├аwon ├Тy├мnb├│ ├мjo R├бt├│l├нk├м t├н a gb├а p├й won mu ├мgb├аgb├│ w├б ┼Д gb├й n├нgb├а yen ni ├▓k├и-P├б├аd├м.12. ├Аd├║gbo: Ar├бgan ├Мtum├▓: Eni t├н ├│ k├│k├│ d├б ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н s├нl├и b├нn├║ k├║r├▓ l├б├аrin ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn lo d├б d├║r├│ s├нb├и ni, ├иy├н ni awon ├иn├мy├аn f├м so ib├и n├н ar├бgan tor├н p├й, w├│n gb├а p├й ├мw├а eni t├н ├│ k├│k├│ d├й ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н k├▓ jot i ├иn├мy├аn t├│ k├╣ l├▓ f├а├б to fi w├б d├б ├аd├║gb├▓ tir├и s├нl├и.13. ├Аd├║gbo: B├бm├║so ├Мtum├▓: ├Тt├и l├│ gb├й ├аwon t├│ k├│k├│ de adugbo y├м├н d├й ib├и tor├н p├й w├│n ┼Д gb├иr├▓ l├бti yan ol├│y├и l├б├аrin ara won, Ow├б gb├│ ├иy├н l├│ b├б l├й won k├║r├▓ ni ibi t├н won ti w├б t├йl├и.14. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мl├│r├▓ ├Мtum├▓: ├Аwon t├н ├│ k├│k├│ d├й ad├║gb├▓ y├м├н j├и ├│l├▓w├│ p├а├бp├а├б ├аwon t├н ├│ k├│k├│ j├бde to se awo ni ├иy├мn odi t├н won fi w├б n k├│l├й s├н il├й.15. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тk├и ├иs├│ ├Мtum├▓: ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ni won ti m├бa n ta aso ├аwon oyinbo nigba t├н ├аwon k├▓r├б├а k├│k├│ gb├й aso t├нt├а d├й Ilesa, ├мd├н niyi ti won fi n p├и ├й ni ├Тk├и-eso.16. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мs├▓n├а ├Мtum├▓: Ibi t├н ├аwon t├│ ma n se is├й on├а p├▓ j├╣ s├н l├бy├й ├аtij├│, ├мt├аn so f├║n wa p├й ib├и ni won ti m├бa n hun ├▓p├б ├аse ├аti ├мl├иk├и ow├б, t├н ├аwon ├мy├аw├│ r├и ├аti ├аwon ol├│y├и.17. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мgand├▓ ├Мtum├▓: ├Мgi ├мgand├▓ kan n├б├а l├│ w├а n├н ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н l├бy├й ├аtij├│.18. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тk├и-Ay├▓ ├Мtum├▓: ├Аwon d├йs├мn kiny├│ l├│ so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ni ├▓k├и ay├▓ n├нgb\`at├н won k├│ il├й ├мj├│s├мn ati ibi ├мsoj├н ├аti l├й isun won s├нb├и.19. ├Аd├║gbo: Omo-Ofe (Omife) ├Мtum├▓: ├Мt├аn so p├й ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ├аwon omo ogun ti n├нl├бti gb├йra lati sigun lo sibi ti won ti f├й jagun. B├й├и n├б├а ni won s├м gb├│d├▓ w├б j├бb├▓ ti won si pin en├мati er├║ t├н w├│n k├│ b├▓ l├│j├║ ogun.20. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мl├бj├й ├Мtum├▓: ├мbi t├н ar├б ├мgboro ti m├б a ┼Д w├б p├аd├й ├аwon ar├б oko l├бti ra oj├а l├│w├│ won ├иy├н l├│ f├а ├б t├н w├│n fi so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н n├н ├Мl├бj├й.21. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тk├и ├Мr├▓ ├Мtum├▓: Or├║ko igi kan t├│ w├а l├бd├╣gb├│├▓ y├м├н t├йl├и ni w├│n fi so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н22. ├Аd├║gbo: Od├▓ ├Мr├▓ ├Мtum├▓: Ibi t├н ├│ b├│ s├н aop├б ├мs├аl├и n├н ad├║gb├▓ ├▓k├и ├мr├▓ ni od├▓ ├мr├▓23. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мj├▓f├м ├Мtum├▓: ib├н y├м├н ni w├│n ti m├бa n aso of├м n├нgb├а t├н ├│ k├│k├│ d├й Il├йs├а.24. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мk├▓y├н ├Мtum├▓: ├Аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н j├и ├мbi titun t├н ├▓p├▓lop├▓ ├аwon t├н ├│ fi j├бde n├нl├╣├║ tip├й tip├й ┼Д gb├й ├▓p├▓lop├▓ won lo ti ├Иk├│ w├б k├│l├й s├нle, oj├║ t├м w├▓n fi wo ├мk├▓y├н Estate lтАЩEkoo ni won fi mu ├аd├║gb├▓ n├б├а.25. ├Аd├║gbo: En├║ Odi ├Мtum├▓: Ib├н y├м├н ni ├мl├║ par├н si l├бtij├│ s├╣gb├│n ├мl├║ ti fe s├йy├мn si i ju ib├н y├м├н lo26. ├Аd├║gbo: Ad├йt├н ├Мtum├▓: Ibi t├н ├аwon ├Мb├▓kun d├║r├│ d├н n├нgb├а t├н og├║n par├н ti won w├б l├бti d├║p├й l├│w├│ Ow├б ti o r├аn w├│n l├│w├│ l├бti segun ├▓t├б w├▓n (A-de-eti-ow├б) ├А d├й t├▓s├н il├й Ow├б Ad├иt├н Ow├б.27. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мj├▓k├а ├Мtum├▓: ├Аwon ar├б ├Тw├▓ l├│ so ad├║gb├▓ y├м├н l├│r├║ko y├м├н, ├аgb├аdo ni won m├бa n t├а n├нb├и t├йl├и b├│y├б ├аgb├аdo t├н won m├бa n d├аp├и n├н ok├а l├│ fa or├║ko y├м├н.28. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мm├аd├нn ├Мtum├▓: N├н ├мgb├а ├аtij├│ ├аwon ├мy├б ├аgb├а m├б a n se ├аd├нn n├нb├н y├м├н (├Щm├аd├нn)29. ├Аd├║gbo: Tem├мdire ├Мm├аd├нn ├Мtum├▓: ├аd├║gb├▓ titun t├│ j├бde lara ├Мm├аd├нn n├мy├н30. ├Аd├║gbo: Omo Ol├║p├и ├Мtum├▓: ├Тr├нk├м ├и├иy├аn t├н ├│ k├│k├│ k├│l├й s├н ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ni won fi pe ib├н y├м├н.31. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тk├иs├а ├Мtum├▓: ├Мk├▓k├▓ ni ├аwon├мj├иs├а m├бa ┼Д d├а ├б p├и n├н ├мs├а. ├Аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н s├м ni w├│n ti m├бa ┼Д n├б oy├а ├мk├▓k├▓ sa├бj├║ k├н il├йs├а t├│ di il├й-├мs├а.32. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мs├▓k├╣n ├Мtum├▓: ├Мs├▓ ok├╣n l├│ di ├мsok├╣n y├м├н, ib├и ni ├аwon ├аgb├и ├аti el├йmu ti m├бa ┼Д w├б ok├╣n l├бti fid i er├╣ t├аb├н ├▓pe-emu won n├н ├мgb├а l├б├йl├б├й.33. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мd├н Ose ├Мtum├▓: Igi os├и ┼Дl├б kan l├│ w├а n├н ├мb├н y├м├н ni ├мgb├а l├б├йl├б├й t├н ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn m├бa ┼Д d├║r├│ ta oj├а m├н ab├й r├и.34. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мd├н ├Тg├║n ├Мtum├▓: ├Мb├н y├м├н ni w├│n ti m├бa ┼Д bo ├▓g├║n ow├б n├н ├мgb├а ├аtij├│, w├│n s├м m├бa ┼Д pa aj├б ├▓g├║n s├н ib├й y├м├н t├нt├н di on├н.35. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мta Akogun ├Мtum├▓: Ib├н y├м├н ni ├аwon ol├│gun m├бa ┼Д d├║r├│ s├н de ├аwon ├▓t├б n├н ├мgb├а l├б├йl├б├й, ├мd├н n├мy├н t├н w├│n fi ┼Д p├и ├й n├н ├мta akogun.36. ├Аd├║gbo: Ad├йt├н ├Мtum├▓: ├Аg├йk├║r├нn f├║n тАЬA d├й et├н ow├бтАЭ m├н ├иy├н, ib├и ni ├аwon ar├б ├мb├▓kun d├║r├│ s├й n├нgb├а t├н ogun par├н t├н w├│n f├й w├б d├║p├й l├│w├│ ow├б-omo-Aj├нb├│gun t├│ r├аn w├│n l├│w├│ l├бti s├йgun ├аwon ├Мl├аr├й.37. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мb├аl├б ├Мtum├▓: ├Тr├║ko akoni kan t├│ w├б l├бti ├мb├▓kun s├╣gb├│n t├│ wol├и l├б├аrin ├мl├йs├а ├аti ├мb├▓kun n├нgb├а t├н ├│ gb├│ p├й ogun ti pa ├мy├аw├│ ├аti omo ├▓un mi ├мb├▓kun.38. ├Аd├║gbo: Er├йg├║r├мn ├Мtum├▓: Or├н eg├║r├╣ l├│ di Er├йg├║r├╣, ├мl├и t├│ le l├│ w├а n├н ib├н y├м├н t├йl├и ├аwon omod├й s├м m├бa ┼Д ser├й n├нb├и.39. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мs├▓n├а ├Мtum├▓: Ibi t├н ├аwon t├│ m├б a ┼Д se is├й on├а p├▓ j├╣ s├н l├бy├й ├аtij├│ ├мt├аn so f├║n wa p├й ib├и ni w├│n ti m├бa ┼Д hun ├▓p├б ┼Дl├иk├и ow├б, t├н ├аwon Ol├│y├и r├и ├аti ti ├аwon ├мy├аw├│ r├и.40. ├Аd├║gbo: Araromi ├Мtum├▓: Or├║ko ├мgb├аl├│d├й n├н ├иy├н, Ar├бgan ni or├║ko ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н t├йl├и w├│n s├иs├и y├нi pad├а s├й Ar├бr├▓m├н ni41. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мtinsin ├Мtum├▓: ├Мgi Isis ┼Дl├б kan l├│ w├а n├н ib├н y├м├н t├йl├и t├н ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn m├бa ┼Д ta ay├▓ n├н idi r├и ├иy├н l├│ di ├мt├а-isin l├│n├м├н (├Мhnsin).42. ├Аd├║gbo: B├│l├│rund├║r├▓ ├Мtum├▓: Or├║ko tuntun ni or├║ko ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н n├нtor├н p├й ├аwon t├│ k├│k├│ d├й ib├и k├▓ t├иt├и k├│l├й kan ara won, w├│n gb├а p├й ├аwon b├б ol├│run d├║r├▓.43. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мgb├аy├и ├Мtum├▓: N├н ├мgb├а ogun, Ib├н y├м├н ni ├аwon Ol├│gun ├мj├иs├а gb├а l├бti s├б ├аs├бl├а f├║n ├иm├н won. тАЬIbi t├н a gb├а t├н a fi y├итАЭni ├аp├иj├б r├и.44. ├Аd├║gbo: Er├йj├а ├Мtum├▓: Or├н oj├а ni w├│n g├й k├║r├║ s├н Er├йj├а, ib├н y├м├н l├│ j├й b├нi or├нta f├║n gbogbo ├аwon ├мl├║ k├йk├и├иk├й ib├и s├м ni w├│n ti m├бa ┼Д p├аd├й l├бti ta oj├а won.45. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мk├▓y├н ├Мtum├▓: ├Аd├║gb├▓ tuntun ni ├иy├н, ├аwon t├│ s├м f├║n un n├н or├║ko y├м├н y├б a l├▓ l├бti ├мl├║ ├Иk├│ ni.46. ├Аd├║gbo: Omi-Oko ├Мtum├▓: ├Аd├║gb├▓ t├н omi t├н ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn m├бa ┼Д pon n├н ay├й ├аtij├│, omo y├м├н w├а n├н ├мt├▓s├н ibi t├н w├│n m├бa ┼Д d├б oko s├н, ├иy├н ni w├│n fi m├бa ┼Д p├и ├й n├н omi-oko.47. ├Аd├║gbo: Enu-Odi ├Мtum├▓: Ib├н y├м├н ni il├йs├а d├й n├н ├аk├│k├▓ y├м├н, ├иy├н l├│ f├а ├б t├н w├│n fi ┼Д pe ib├н y├м├н n├н Enu-Odi.48. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мr├│y├и ├Мtum├▓: ├Мr├│y├и y├м├н k├▓ j├мn├а s├н ├мgb├аy├и, ib├и ni ├аwon t├│ s├б f├║n ├иm├н won n├н ├мgb├а ogun ti k├│k├│ d├║r├│.49. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мl├│r├▓ ├Мtum├▓: ├Аwon t├н ├│ k├│k├│ d├│ ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н j├й ol├│w├│, p├а├бp├а├б w├│n j├й ├▓kan l├бra ├аwon t├│ k├│k├│ j├бde lo s├▓w├▓ n├н ├▓k├и oya t├н w├│n w├б ┼Д k├│l├й s├нl├й.50. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тl├│mil├бgb├аl├б ├Мtum├▓: ├Аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н k├▓ j├мn├а s├н omi kan t├н ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn m├бa ┼Д mu, ├иy├н l├│ j├й k├н ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn m├бa pe ├аwon t├│ ┼Д gb├й ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н n├н ├▓l├│mil├бgb├аl├б.51. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тgb├│n ├Аgb├иde ├Мtum├▓: ├Аgb├иde kan w├а n├н ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н n├н ├аk├│k├▓ t├н w├│n f├║n un n├н or├║ko y├м├н, omo ├Иf├▓n al├а├аy├и ni ├аgb├иde y├м├н.52. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тk├и-j├мgb├а ├Мtum├▓: ├Тr├║ko Babal├бwo kan ni J├мgb├а, ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н l├│ s├м m├бa ┼Д gb├й t├н ├│ ti ┼Д se is├й owo r├и. ├мd├н n├мy├н t├н w├│n fi ┼Д pe ├аd├║gb├▓ n├б├а n├н ├▓k├и-j├мgb├а.53. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тk├и-omi-ir├║ ├Мtum├▓: ├Тmi kan w├а n├н ib├н y├м├н t├н w├│n ti m├бa ┼Д fo ir├║ n├н ay├й ├аtij├│, ├мgb├а t├н ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn t├й├иr├и sin ├н k├│l├й omi ir├║.54. ├Аd├║gbo: Omi-Al├бd├мe ├Мtum├▓: Oko kan w├а n├н ib├н y├м├н n├н ├мgb├а ├аtij├│ t├н w├│n ti m├бa ┼Д sin adie (poultry) omi kan s├м w├а n├н ├мt├▓s├н oko y├м├н, ├иy├н l├│ m├║ k├н won m├бa pe omi y├м├н n├н omi al├бd├мe ├иy├н t├│ di oтАЩruko ├аd├║gb├▓ n├б├а l├│n├м├н.55. ├Аd├║gbo: Ol├│runs├▓go ├Мtum├▓: ├Аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н ti w├а l├бti ├мgb├а l├б├йl├б├й s├╣gb├│n ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn k├▓ t├иt├и w├б ko il├й s├н ib├и, n├нgb├а t├н ├│ s├м y├б ├а├аrin ├мgb├а d├н├и ni ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn k├│ ├▓p├▓lop├▓ il├й s├н ib├и, ├иy├н l├│ m├║ k├н won p├и ├й n├н Ol├│runs├▓go.56. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мj├бmo ├Мtum├▓: Ib├н y├м├н ni ├аwon ├аgb├и t├│ b├б ┼Д b├▓ l├бti oko ti m├бa ┼Д j├б im├▓ ├▓pe l├бti di er├╣ won ib├и l├│ di ├Мj├бm├▓ n├нgb├а t├н il├й b├иr├и si n├н de ib├и.57. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Тg├║d├╣ ├Мtum├▓: Or├║ko ak├нkanj├║ kan ni ├мgb├а ogun ├▓g├иd├и╟╣gb├й ni ├иy├н, n├н ├мr├бnt├н r├и ni w├│n se so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н n├н ├▓g├║d├╣.58. ├Аd├║gbo: ├Мf├▓f├нn ├Мtum├▓: ├Тmi kan w├а n├н ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н t├йl├и t├н ├аwon ├иn├мy├аn ti m├бa ┼Д do n╟╣kan, tor├н omi y├м├н ni w├│n se so ├аd├║gb├▓ y├м├н n├н ├Мfof├нn.59. ├Аd├║gbo: Omi-Eran ├Мtum├▓: Ibi t├н ├аwon al├бpat├а ti m├бa ┼Д pa eran won f├║n t├нt├а ni w├│n so di omi-eran.60. ├Аd├║gbo: Im├аd├нn ├Мtum├▓: Ibi t├н ├аwon ├мy├б ├аgb├а ti m├бa ┼Д se ├аd├нn n├н ├мgb├а ├аtij├│ ni w├│n ┼Д p├и n├н Um├аd├нn n├н ├иka ├иd├и ├мj├иs├а, ├иy├н l├│ s├м di Im├аd├нn l├│n├м├н."},{"question":"Jox ma been waxi wolof.","answer":"Nopp pejj la, waaye kenn du ca w├йkk gafaka."},{"question":"ф║║ф╜УхЕ╖цЬЙшзгцпТф╜ЬчФичЪДхЖЕшДПцШп","answer":"ф║║ф╜УхЕ╖цЬЙшзгцпТф╜ЬчФичЪДхЖЕшДПцШп"},{"question":"роо. роЪро┐роЩрпНроХро╛ро░ро╡рпЗро▓ро░рпН роорпЗро▒рпНроХрпЛро│рпН роТройрпНро▒рпИ родро░ро╡рпБроорпН.","answer":"рокрпБро▓ро┐ропрпБроорпН рокроЪрпБро╡рпБроорпН роТро░рпБ родрпБро▒рпИропро┐ро▓рпН роирпАро░рпН роЕро░рпБроирпНродро┐ройро╛ро▓рпБроорпН роЕро░рпБроирпНродрпБроорпН. роЖройро╛ро▓рпН, роорпБродро▓ро╛ро│ро┐ропрпБроорпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓ро╛ро│ро┐ропрпБроорпН роЪро░ро┐роЪроородрпНродрпБро╡рооро╛роХ родроЩрпНроХро│рпН родрпЗроЪрокрпН рокрпКро░рпБро│рпНроХро│рпИ, роХро╛роирпНродро┐ропро╛ро░ро┐ройрпН роЪрпБропро░ро╛роЬрпНроЬро┐ропродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЕройрпБрокро╡ро┐рокрпНрокро╛ро░рпНроХро│рпНроО ройрпНрокродрпБ рокроХро▒рпНроХройро╡рпЗ."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'gajah sama gajah berjuang, pelanduk mati di tengah-tengah'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud jika pemimpin (kuasa besar) bergaduh (berperang), rakyat (negara kecil) juga yang susah. Contoh ayat: Pemimpin-pemimpin harus mengetepikan kepentingan peribadi masing-masing kerana jikalau mereka bersengketa, orang-orang bawahan juga yang akan menderita, seperti kata pepatah gajah sama gajah berjuang, pelanduk mati di tengah-tengah."},{"question":"р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢║р╖Фр╢╗р╖Эр╢┤р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢║р╖Фр╢╗р╖Эр╢┤р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ер╢║р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢з р╢пр╢Ър╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢Жр╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖П р╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╖Ар╖Др╖Пр╢╗ р╖Ар╢▒ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢пр╖Ф р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╖Ар╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Др╖Тр╢н р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢┤р╖Ар╖Фр╢╜р╢Ър╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢┤р╖Ар╖Фр╢╜ р╢╜р╖Эр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Гр╖Кр╢н р╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖А р╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╢║р╖П р╢Ер╢нр╢╗р╖Тр╢▒р╖К 50% р╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ыр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Пр╢нр╖Ш (р╖Др╖Э р╢┤р╖Тр╢нр╖Ш) р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Эр╢вр╢▒р╢║ р╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╖Т. р╢╕р╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢Лр╢┤ р╢┤р╖Ар╖Фр╢╜р╖К р╖Др╖П р╢Кр╢з р╢Ер╢║р╢нр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╢╕р╖Щр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢║. 1. р╢Зр╢╜р╖Кр╢╢р╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф - р╢Зр╢╜р╖Кр╢╢р╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А2. р╢Жр╢╕р╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф - р╢Жр╢╕р╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А3. р╢╢р╖Эр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Э-р╖Гр╖Кр╢╜р╖Рр╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╖К3.1. р╢╢р╖Эр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╖К - р╢╜р╖Рр╢зр╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╜р╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А3.2 р╖Гр╖Кр╢╜р╖Рр╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╖К - р╢┤р╖Эр╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢н р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А (р╢┤р╖Эр╢╜р╖Тр╖Бр╖К), р╢ар╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Кр╢╜р╖Эр╖Ар╖Рр╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Гр╖Кр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╢╗р╖Кр╢╢р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ьр╢Тр╖Вр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╢р╢╜р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ър╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╕р╖Рр╖Гр╖Тр╢йр╖Эр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╢р╖Щр╢╜р╢╗р╖Фр╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢║р╖Фр╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╗р╖Фр╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А4. р╢Ър╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╢зр╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П - р╢Ер╢║р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Вр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Ьр╢зр╖Тр╖Вр╖К р╢Ьр╖Ър╢╜р╖Тр╢Ър╖К, р╢Ър╖Эр╢▒р╖Тр╖Вр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Ар╖Щр╢╜р╖Кр╖Бр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А5. р╢Йр╢нр╖Пр╢╜р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П - р╢╜р╢нр╖Тр╢▒р╖К5.1 р╢╗р╖Эр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П (р╢╜р╢нр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╖Ар╢║ р╖Ар╖У р╢Кр╢з р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Гр╖К р╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢лр╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢н) - р╢╗р╖Ьр╢╕р╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢Вр╖Б р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢┤р╖Шр╢нр╖Фр╢Ьр╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Кр╢┤р╖Пр╢др╖Кр╢д р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Йр╢нр╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢йр╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А6. р╢вр╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Фр╢Ъ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П - р╢Ер╢║р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢н р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢йр╖Ър╢▒р╖Тр╖Вр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢йр╖Тр╖Вр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢║р╖Тр╢йр╖Тр╖Вр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╜р╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ър╖Гр╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Зр╖Жр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╕р╢н р╢вр╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Ьр╢зр╖Кр╖Гр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А7. р╖Др╖Щр╢╜р╖Щр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П - р╢зр╖Кр╖Гр╢Ър╖Эр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢Ъ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А8. р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф- р╢Йр╢╗р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П -8.1 р╢▒р╖Фр╢╗р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П - р╢Ър╢╕р╖Кр╢Ър╢зр╖П-р╖Ар╖Пр╢╗р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Ер╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Фр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А8.2 р╢Йр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф-р╢Жр╢╗р╖Кр╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П - р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢н р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢┤р╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Др╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Фр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Пр╢▒р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А (р╖Др╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Т,р╢Лр╢╗р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф), р╢┤р╢Вр╢вр╖Пр╢╢р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Ър╖Вр╖Кр╢╕р╖Ур╢╗р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Ьр╖Фр╢вр╢╗р╖Пр╢зр╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╗р╖Пр╢вр╖Гр╖Кр╢нр╖Пр╢▒р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╗р╖Ьр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Зр╖Гр╖Ср╢╕р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╢р╖Щр╢Вр╢Ьр╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Фр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Ър╖Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ър╖Пр╢▒р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╕р╢╗р╖Пр╢нр╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢▒р╖Ър╢┤р╖Пр╢╜р╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╖Др╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А8.3 р╢Йр╢╗р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ур╢║ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П - р╢Фр╖Гр╖Ър╢зр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢┤р╖Бр╖Кр╢зр╖Э р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢┤р╢╗р╖Кр╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢зр╢вр╖Тр╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢╢р╢╜р╖Эр╢ар╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А, р╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╖Кр╢пр╖Тр╖Вр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖А"},{"question":"╪з┘К╪┤ ┘Е╪╣┘Ж┘Й ╪з┘Д╪м┘Е┘Д╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪з┘Д┘К╪й \\"┘З╪░┘З ╪з┘Д╪з┘Г┘Д┘З ╪┤╪н┘К┘Б┘З\\" ╪и╪з┘Д┘Б╪╡╪н┘Й.","answer":"╪┤╪н┘Б┘З: ╪┤┘З┘К┘З ( ┘З╪░┘З ╪з┘Д╪з┘Г┘Д┘З ╪┤╪н┘К┘Б┘З) ┘З╪░┘З ╪з┘Д╪з┘Г┘Д┘З ╪┤┘З┘К┘З."},{"question":"Odpowiedz na pytanie. Jakie s─Е typowe polskie potrawy wigilijne?","answer":"Typowe potrawy wigilijne to barszcz z uszkami, zupa grzybowa, kapusta z grochem, pierogi z kapust─Е i grzybami, karp sma┼╝ony, kutia. Kutia to potrawa wschodnich region├│w Polski, przygotowywana z gotowanej pszenicy, kt├│r─Е wcze┼Ыniej obt┼Вukiwano w st─Щpach, z dodatkiem miodu i maku. Zar├│wno mak, jak i mi├│d to produkty zajmuj─Еce specjalne miejsce w wigilijnym menu. Mak znany ze swej mocy usypiania m├│g┼В by─З pomocny w drodze w za┼Ыwiaty lub by─З pocz─Щstunkiem dla tych, kt├│rzy stamt─Еd przychodz─Е na ziemi─Щ. Mi├│d to produkt od pszcz├│┼В, powszechnie w kulturze uwa┼╝anych za ┼Ыwi─Щte, by┼В darem ofiarnym dla dusz zmar┼Вych. Wigilia nie mog┼Вa si─Щ te┼╝ oby─З bez suszonych grzyb├│w. Ich znaczenie wynika┼Вo z faktu, ┼╝e ros┼Вy w lasach czyli przestrzeni nieoswojonej przez ludzi, a wi─Щc nale┼╝a┼Вy bardziej do przestrzeni za┼Ыwiat├│w i dlatego mia┼Вy niezwyk┼В─Е moc. Ryba na wiejski st├│┼В trafi┼Вa do┼Ы─З p├│┼║no, wcze┼Ыniej тАЮkr├│lowa┼ВaтАЭ na dworach."},{"question":"Tamin' ny oviana no nanjakan'i Radama II  teto Madagasikara ? ","answer":"1861-1863 no nanjakan'i Radama II teto Madagasikara "},{"question":"р╢Зр╢╕р╢╗р╖Тр╢Ър╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢вр╢▒р╖Кр╢п р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢╜ р╢Ьр╢лр╢▒","answer":"538"},{"question":"╪е╪░╪з ╪г╪н╪п ┘В┘Д┘Г ┘Г┘Б┘И ╪е┘К╪┤ ╪к╪▒╪п╪Я","answer":"┘Г┘Б┘И┘Г ╪з┘Д╪╖┘К╪и"},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐ :роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЗро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роорпБродро▓рпН роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ ропро╛ро░рпН?","answer":"ро╡ро┐роЯрпИ: ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роГрокро░ро┐ропро╛роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐ :ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роГрокро░ро┐ропро╛ - ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИ ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпБ: роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роорпБродро▓рпН рокрпЖрогрпН роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роГрокро░ро┐ропро╛ рокро╡ро▓рпН, роЖроХро╕рпНроЯрпН 23, 1943 роЗро▓рпН рокро┐ро▒роирпНродро╛ро░рпН, роЕро╡ро░родрпБ роЕро┤роХрпБрокрпН рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐роХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЕро╡ро░родрпБ роЕро▒рпНрокрпБродрооро╛рой ро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐роХрпНроХро╛роХ роХрпКрогрпНроЯро╛роЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯ роТро░рпБ роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯродрпНродроХрпНроХ роирокро░рпН. 1966 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН, роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ рокроЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒ роорпБродро▓рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро░рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роорпБродро▓рпН рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡ро░рпН роОройрпНро▒ ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпИрокрпН рокроЯрпИродрпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЗродрпБ родроЯрпИроХро│рпИродрпН родроХро░рпНродрпНродродрпБ роороЯрпНроЯрпБрооро▓рпНро▓ро╛рооро▓рпН, роЙро▓роХро│ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роТро░рпБ роЙродрпНро╡рпЗроХрооро╛рой роЕро│ро╡рпБроХрпЛро▓рпИропрпБроорпН роиро┐ро▒рпБро╡ро┐ропродрпБ.роЖро░роорпНрокроХро╛ро▓ ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЪро╡ро╛ро▓рпНроХро│рпНрокро┐ро▒роирпНрод родрпЗродро┐: роЖроХро╕рпНроЯрпН 23, 1943рокро┐ро▒роирпНрод роЗроЯроорпН: роорпБроорпНрокрпИ, роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роГрокро░ро┐ропро╛ роорпБроорпНрокрпИропро┐ро▓рпН роТро░рпБ роироЯрпБродрпНродро░ ро╡ро░рпНроХрпНроХ роХрпЛро╡ро╛ роХродрпНродрпЛро▓ро┐роХрпНроХ роХрпБроЯрпБроорпНрокродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рокро┐ро▒роирпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЕро╡ро│рпБроЯрпИроп рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒рпЛро░рпН, роЬро╛ройрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЕройрпНроЯрпЛройрпЖроЯрпН, роХроЯро┐рой роЙро┤рпИрокрпНрокрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роЙро▒рпБродро┐рокрпНрокро╛роЯрпБ роЖроХро┐ропро╡ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ройрпН роородро┐рокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпИ роЕро╡ро│рпБроХрпНроХрпБро│рпН ро╡ро┐родрпИродрпНродройро░рпН. родройродрпБ роЙропро░родрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХро╛роХ роХро┐рогрпНроЯро▓рпН роЪрпЖропрпНропрокрпНрокроЯрпБро╡родрпБ рокрпЛройрпНро▒ роЪро╡ро╛ро▓рпНроХро│рпИ роОродро┐ро░рпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯ рокрпЛродро┐ро▓рпБроорпН, ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ родройродрпБ роЙропро░рооро╛рой рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роТро▓рпНро▓ро┐ропро╛рой роЪроЯрпНроЯроХродрпНродрпИ ро╡ро┐ро│рпИропро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ро▓рпН, роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро╛роХ ро╣ро╛роХрпНроХро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▒роирпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХ рокропройрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ройро╛ро░рпН, роЕроЩрпНроХрпБ роЕро╡ро░рпН родройродрпБ ро╣ро╛роЯрпНро░ро┐роХрпН роироЯро┐рокрпНрокро┐ро▒рпНроХро╛роХ роЕроЩрпНроХрпАроХро╛ро░роорпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН.рооро▒рпНро▒ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ропрооро╛рой роХроЯрпНроЯрпБро░рпИроХро│рпНроЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роорпБродро▓рпН рокрпЖрогрпНроХро│рпН роЙро▓роХро┐ро▓рпЗропрпЗ роорпБродро▓рпНроЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роорпБродро▓рпН рокрпЖрогрпН ро╡ро┐рооро╛ройро┐, роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роорпБродро▓рпН рокрпЖрогрпН ро░ропро┐ро▓рпН роУроЯрпНроЯрпБройро░рпНрооро╛роЯро▓ро┐роЩрпН родрпКро┤ро┐ро▓рпНрооро┐ро╕рпН рокроорпНрокро╛ропрпН роХро┐ро░рпАроЯродрпНродрпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒рокрпЛродрпБ ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ роХро┐ро░рпАроЯродрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХро╛рой рокропрогроорпН родрпКроЯроЩрпНроХро┐ропродрпБ. роЕро╡ро░родрпБ ро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐ 1966 роЗро▓рпН роИро╡рпНро╕рпН ро╡рпАроХрпНро▓ро┐ рооро┐ро╕рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЕро╡ро░рпН рокроЩрпНроХрпЗро▒рпНрокродро▒рпНроХрпБ ро╡ро┤ро┐ ро╡роХрпБродрпНродродрпБ, роЕроЩрпНроХрпБ роЕро╡ро░рпН ро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропро╛ро│ро░ро╛роХ роЙро░рпБро╡рпЖроЯрпБродрпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЗроирпНрод ро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐, 1966 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡рпИрокрпН рокро┐ро░родро┐роиро┐родро┐родрпНродрпБро╡рокрпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐, роЪро░рпНро╡родрпЗроЪ роЕро░роЩрпНроХро┐ро▓рпН роЕро╡ро░рпИродрпН родрпВрогрпНроЯро┐ропродрпБ.роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ 1966рооро┐ро╕рпН ро╡рпЗро░рпНро▓рпНроЯрпН 1966 рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро┐ройрпН рокрпЛродрпБ, ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роГрокро░ро┐ропро╛, 'рокрпЖро╕рпНроЯрпН роЗройрпН роирпАроЪрпНроЪро▓рпБроЯрпИ' рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН 'рокрпЖро╕рпНроЯрпН роЗройрпН роИро╡ро┐ройро┐роЩрпНро╡рпЗро░рпН' роЖроХро┐роп родрпБрогрпИ родро▓рпИрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒родройрпН роорпВро▓роорпН роорпБродрпНродро┐ро░рпИ рокродро┐родрпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЕро╡ро░родрпБ роХро░рпБрогрпИ, рокрпБродрпНродро┐роЪро╛ро▓ро┐родрпНродройроорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН роХрогрпНроХро╡ро░рпН роЕро┤роХрпБ роЖроХро┐ропро╡рпИ роироЯрпБро╡ро░рпНроХро│рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро╛ро░рпНро╡рпИропро╛ро│ро░рпНроХро│ро┐роЯрпИропрпЗ роирпАроЯро┐родрпНрод родро╛роХрпНроХродрпНродрпИ роПро▒рпНрокроЯрпБродрпНродро┐ропродрпБ. роТро░рпБ ро╡ро░ро▓ро╛ро▒рпНро▒рпБ родро░рпБрогродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН, ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роГрокро░ро┐ропро╛ роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ропро╛роХ роорпБроЯро┐роЪрпВроЯрпНроЯрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯро╛ро░рпН, роЗроирпНрод роородро┐рокрпНрокрпБрооро┐роХрпНроХ рокроЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒ роорпБродро▓рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро░рпН роОройрпНро▒ рокрпЖро░рпБроорпИропрпИрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН.  роироЯрпНроЪродрпНродро┐ро░роорпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡роорпН роЗроЯрпИропрпЗ роТро░рпБ родрпЗро░рпНро╡рпБроЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ роОройрпНро▒ ро╡рпЖро▒рпНро▒ро┐роХро░рооро╛рой роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐роХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокро┐ро▒роХрпБ, ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роГрокро░ро┐ропро╛ роТро░рпБ роорпБроХрпНроХро┐ропрооро╛рой роорпБроЯро┐ро╡рпИ роОродро┐ро░рпНроХрпКрогрпНроЯро╛ро░рпН. рооро╛роЯро▓ро┐роЩрпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роироЯро┐рокрпНрокродро▒рпНроХрпБ роПро░ро╛ро│рооро╛рой ро▓ро╛рокроХро░рооро╛рой ро╡ро╛ропрпНрокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпИрокрпН рокрпЖро▒рпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН, роЖройро╛ро▓рпН роЕро╡ро░рпН ро╡рпЗро▒рпБ рокро╛родрпИропрпИродрпН родрпЗро░рпНроирпНродрпЖроЯрпБродрпНродро╛ро░рпН. рокрпКро┤рпБродрпБрокрпЛроХрпНроХро┐ро▓рпН роТро░рпБ роХро╡ро░рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ропро╛рой ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроХрпНроХрпИропрпИродрпН родрпКроЯро░рпНро╡родро▒рпНроХрпБрокрпН рокродро┐ро▓ро╛роХ, роЕро╡ро░рпН рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡родрпНродро┐ройрпН роорпАродро╛рой родройродрпБ роЖро░рпНро╡родрпНродро┐ро▒рпНроХрпБ роЙро▒рпБродро┐ропро│ро┐родрпНродро╛ро░рпН. ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ роХро┐ро░ро╛рогрпНроЯрпН рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡роХрпН роХро▓рпНро▓рпВро░ро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЗро░рпНроирпНродро╛ро░рпН & роЪро░рпН роЬрпЗ.роЬрпЗ. рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡рооройрпИроХро│рпН роХрпБро┤рпБ, роЕроЩрпНроХрпБ роЕро╡ро░рпН родройродрпБ роОроорпН.рокро┐.рокро┐.роОро╕рпН. рокроЯрпНроЯроорпН.рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡родрпН родрпБро▒рпИропро┐ро▓рпН роЪро┐ро▒роирпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐ро│роЩрпНроХрпБро╡родрпИродрпН родрпКроЯро░рпНроирпНродрпБ, роЗроЩрпНроХро┐ро▓ро╛роирпНродро┐ройрпН ро▓рогрпНроЯройро┐ро▓рпН роЙро│рпНро│ роХро┐роЩрпНро╕рпН роХро▓рпНро▓рпВро░ро┐ рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡рооройрпИропро┐ро▓рпН ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ рокроЯро┐рокрпНрокрпИродрпН родрпКроЯро░рпНроирпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЕро╡ро░родрпБ роХро▓рпНро╡ро┐роХрпНроХро╛рой роЕро╡ро░родрпБ роЕро░рпНрокрпНрокрогро┐рокрпНрокрпБ роЕроЪрпИроХрпНроХ роорпБроЯро┐ропро╛родродрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН 1971 роЗро▓рпН, роЕро╡ро░рпН родройродрпБ ро╡ро┤ро┐роХро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ропро╛рой роЯро╛роХрпНроЯро░рпН. роЯрпЗро╡ро┐роЯрпН рокро╡ро▓рпИ, роЙроЯрпНроЪрпБро░рокрпНрокро┐ропро▓рпН роиро┐рокрпБрогро░рпИ роорогроирпНродро╛ро░рпН. роЗроирпНрод роЬрпЛроЯро┐ рокро┐ройрпНройро░рпН роЕропро░рпНро▓ро╛роирпНродро┐ройрпН роЯрокрпНро│ро┐ройрпБроХрпНроХрпБ роХрпБроЯро┐рокрпЖропро░рпНроирпНродродрпБ, роЕроЩрпНроХрпБ ро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ родройродрпБ рооро░рпБродрпНродрпБро╡рокрпН рокропро┐ро▒рпНроЪро┐ропрпИродрпН родрпКроЯроЩрпНроХро┐ройро╛ро░рпН, рооро┐ро╕рпН ро╡рпЗро░рпНро▓рпНроЯрпН роХро┐ро░рпАроЯродрпНродрпИ ро╡рпЖро▓рпНро╡родро▒рпНроХро╛рой роЕро╡ро░родрпБ роЕро░рпНрокрпНрокрогро┐рокрпНрокрпБ роОро╡рпНро╡ро│ро╡рпБ ро╡ро▓ро┐роорпИропро╛ройродрпБ роОройрпНрокродрпИ роиро┐ро░рпВрокро┐родрпНродро╛ро░рпН.рооро░рокрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокроЩрпНроХро│ро┐рокрпНрокрпБроХро│рпНро░рпАроЯрпНроЯро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН роХрпБро▒ро┐рокрпНрокро┐роЯродрпНродроХрпНроХ рокропрогродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН 1998 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ роГрокрпЖрооро┐ройро╛ рооро┐ро╕рпН роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роироЯрпБро╡ро░ро╛роХ рокрогро┐ропро╛ро▒рпНро▒ро┐ропродрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рокро▓ роЪроирпНродро░рпНрокрпНрокроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН рооро┐ро╕рпН ро╡рпЗро░рпНро▓рпНроЯрпН рокрпЛроЯрпНроЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роироЯрпБро╡ро░ро╛роХ родро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокро┐ропродрпБроорпН роЕроЯроЩрпНроХрпБроорпН. рооро┐ро╕рпН ро╡рпЗро░рпНро▓рпНроЯрпН 1976 роироЯрпБро╡ро░рпН роХрпБро┤рпБро╡ро┐ро▓рпН, роЯрпЖрооро┐ро╕рпН ро░рпВроЪрпЛро╕рпБроЯройрпН роЗрогрпИроирпНродрпБ, роЪро┐рогрпНроЯро┐ рокро┐ро░рпЗроХрпНро╕рпНрокро┐ропро░ро┐ройрпН роЙро▓роХ роЕро┤роХро┐ рокроЯрпНроЯродрпНродрпИ ро╡рпЖройрпНро▒ро╛ро░рпН."},{"question":"р░Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐р░и р░нр░╛р░╡р░В р░╡р░Ър▒Нр░Ър▒Зр░▓р░╛р░Чр░╛ р░кр░жр▒Нр░пр░В р░░р░╛р░пр░Вр░бр░┐:р░ир░╛ р░╢р░мр▒Нр░жр░В р░пр▒Кр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░кр▒Нр░░р░др░╛р░кр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░╡р░┐р░ир░Вр░бр░┐. р░ир░╛ р░кр▒Зр░░р▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р░Ьр░╛р░Хр▒Лр░Яр░┐. р░Тр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░Хр▒Лр░Яр░┐ р░Хр░╛р░жр░Вр░бр░┐. р░Хр▒Лр░Яр░╛р░ир▒Бр░Хр▒Лр░Яр▒Нр░▓ р░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░гр▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░ор░╛р░Яр░▓р░ир▒З р░мр░▓р░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐р░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐ р░ир▒Ир░кр▒Бр░гр▒Нр░пр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Хр░▓р░┐р░Чр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛р░ир▒Б.","answer":"р░╡р░┐р░ир▒Бр░бр▒А р░ир░╛ р░╢р░мр▒Нр░жр░зр░╛р░Яр░┐р░ир░╛ р░кр▒Зр░░р▒Б р░кр▒Нр░░р░Ьр░╛р░Хр▒Лр░Яр░┐р░Тр░Хр▒Нр░Х р░Хр▒Лр░Яр░┐ р░Хр░╛р░жр░Вр░бр▒Лр░Хр▒Лр░Яр░┐р░Хр▒Лр░Яр▒Нр░▓ р░кр▒Нр░░р░╛р░гр▒Бр░▓р░Хр▒Бр░ор░╛р░Я р░мр░▓р░Вр░др▒Л р░Жр░╢р░╛р░кр░╛р░Яр░╡р░ор▒Бр░ир▒Б р░Хр░▓р░┐р░Чр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░╛"},{"question":"р░Хр▒Нр░░р░┐р░Вр░жр░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р░╛ р░Ър░жр░┐р░╡р░┐, р░Зр░Ър▒Нр░Ър░┐р░и р░╡р░╛р░Хр▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░╕р░░р▒Ир░ир░╡р▒Л р░Хр░╛р░жр▒Л (тЬУ ) (тЬЧ) р░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Нр░др▒Бр░▓ р░жр▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р░╛ р░Чр▒Бр░░р▒Нр░др░┐р░Вр░Ър░Вр░бр░┐.р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р░┐р░Хр▒А р░Жр░зр░╛р░░р░ор▒Ир░и р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░ир▒Зр░бр▒Б р░Хр░ир▒Б р░ор░░р▒Бр░Чр▒И р░кр▒Лр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░┐. р░Кр░│р▒Нр░▓р░ир▒Б, р░кр░Яр▒Нр░Яр░гр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░нр░╡р░ир░╛р░▓р░др▒Л р░ир░┐р░Вр░кр▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б. р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б р░кр▒Жр░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░ир▒Нр░и р░зр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╕ р░▓р▒Зр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░кр▒Лр░др▒Лр░Вр░жр░┐. р░Ьр░ир░╛р░▓р▒Б р░др░╛р░ор▒Б р░ор▒Кр░Хр▒Нр░Хр░▓р▒Б р░ир░╛р░Яр░┐ р░кр▒Жр░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░ир▒Нр░и р░Жр░▓р▒Лр░Ър░ир░ир▒Б р░ор░░р░┐р░Ър░┐, р░Пр░│р▒Нр░▓ р░др░░р░мр░бр░┐р░Чр░╛ р░╡р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др░░р░┐р░Вр░Ър░┐р░и р░╡р░Яр░╡р▒Гр░Хр▒Нр░╖р░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░Хр▒Вр░бр░╛ р░ир▒Зр░▓ р░Хр▒Вр░▓р▒Бр░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░░р▒Б. р░жр▒Ар░ир░Вр░др░Яр░┐р░Хр▒А р░ор░ир░┐р░╖р░┐ р░Ер░др▒Нр░пр░╛р░╢р▒З р░кр▒Нр░░р░зр░╛р░и р░Хр░╛р░░р░гр░В. р░╕р▒Нр░╡р░╛р░░р▒Нр░ер░Вр░др▒Л р░ор▒Бр░Вр░жр▒Б р░Ър▒Вр░кр▒Б р░▓р▒Зр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░кр▒Нр░░р░Хр▒Гр░др░┐р░ир░Вр░др░╛ р░Ер░Вр░др░░р░┐р░Вр░к р░Ьр▒Зр░╕р▒Нр░др▒В, р░Ер░нр░┐р░╡р▒Гр░жр▒Нр░зр░┐ р░кр▒Зр░░р▒Бр░др▒Л р░Жр░Хр░╛р░╢ р░╣р░░р▒Нр░ор▒Нр░пр░╛р░▓р▒Б р░ир░┐р░░р▒Нр░ор░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░бр▒Б. р░Ер░▓р░╛р░Чр▒З р░░р▒Лр░бр▒Нр░▓р░ир▒Б р░Жр░ир▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░ир░┐ р░Йр░ир▒Нр░и р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╕р░╛р░п р░нр▒Вр░ор▒Бр░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░╡р░┐р░Хр▒Нр░░ р░пр░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░бр▒Б. р░Хр▒Кр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░│р▒Нр░▓р░Хр▒Б р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╕р░╛р░п р░нр▒Вр░ор░┐ р░Хр▒Кр░░р░╡р░бр░┐ р░ор░ир░┐р░╖р░┐ тАШр░Ер░ир▒Нр░ир░ор▒Л р░░р░╛р░ор░Ър░Вр░жр▒Нр░░р░╛тАЩ р░Ер░ир░┐ р░Ер░░р░┐р░Ър░┐ р░Ър░╛р░╡р░Х р░др░кр▒Нр░кр░ир░┐ р░кр░░р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░ер░┐р░др░┐р░ир░┐ р░Ър▒Зр░Ьр▒Зр░др▒Бр░▓р░╛ р░╕р▒Гр░╖р▒Нр░Яр░┐р░Вр░Ър▒Бр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░бр▒Б.р░кр▒Нр░░р░╢р▒Нр░ир░▓р▒Б тАУ р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Бр░▓р▒Б :1. р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р░┐р░Хр▒А р░Жр░зр░╛р░░р░ор▒Ир░ир░╡р░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б. (  )2. р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Жр░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░ир▒Нр░и р░зр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╕ р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р░┐р░▓р▒Л р░кр▒Жр░░р░┐р░Чр░┐ р░кр▒Лр░пр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. (  )3. р░ор░ир░┐р░╖р░┐ р░Ер░др▒Нр░пр░╛р░╢ р░▓р▒Зр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░бр▒Б. (  )4. р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╕р░╛р░п р░нр▒Вр░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░кр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░ор░╛р░░р▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░┐. (  )5. р░Ер░ир▒Нр░ир░В р░жр▒Кр░░р░Хр░ир░┐ р░кр░░р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░ер░┐р░др░┐ р░░р░╛р░мр▒Лр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. (  )","answer":"р░кр▒Нр░░р░╢р▒Нр░ир░▓р▒Б тАУ р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Бр░▓р▒Б :1. р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р░┐р░Хр▒А р░Жр░зр░╛р░░р░ор▒Ир░ир░╡р░┐ р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Б. (  )р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Б:(тЬУ )2. р░Ър▒Жр░Яр▒Нр░▓р░ир▒Б р░кр▒Жр░Вр░Ър░╛р░▓р░ир▒Нр░и р░зр▒Нр░пр░╛р░╕ р░Ер░Вр░жр░░р░┐р░▓р▒Л р░кр▒Жр░░р░┐р░Чр░┐ р░кр▒Лр░пр░┐р░Вр░жр░┐. (  )р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Б:(тЬЧ)3. р░ор░ир░┐р░╖р░┐ р░Ер░др▒Нр░пр░╛р░╢ р░▓р▒Зр░Хр▒Бр░Вр░бр░╛ р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░бр▒Б. (  )р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Б:(тЬЧ)4. р░╡р▒Нр░пр░╡р░╕р░╛р░п р░нр▒Вр░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░кр▒Нр░▓р░╛р░Яр▒Нр░▓р▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░ор░╛р░░р▒Бр░др▒Бр░ир▒Нр░ир░╛р░пр░┐. (  )р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Б:(тЬУ )5. р░Ер░ир▒Нр░ир░В р░жр▒Кр░░р░Хр░ир░┐ р░кр░░р░┐р░╕р▒Нр░ер░┐р░др░┐ р░░р░╛р░мр▒Лр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. (  )р░Ьр░╡р░╛р░мр▒Б:(тЬУ )"},{"question":"Pasakykite did┼╛iausi─Е sal─Е pasaulyje?","answer":"Grenlandijos bendras plotas yra 2,16 milijono kvadratini┼│ kilometr┼│, kur─п did┼╛i─Еj─Е sausumos mas─Щ visi┼бkai u┼╛ima ledas."},{"question":"р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢Ъ р╢Ър╢│р╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ, р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Ър╖Вр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╗р╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Шр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Д р╖Бр╖Ур╢н р╢Нр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢пр╖У р╢Ър╖Щр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖Фр╢з р╢╖р╖Фр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢│р╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢▒р╖Эр╢пр╖Пр╢нр╖Кр╢╕р╢Ъ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╢╕р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢п?","answer":"р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢Ъ р╢Ър╢│р╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╢з р╢┤р╖Рр╢╕р╖Тр╢лр╖Щр╢▒ р╢Ер╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╖Бр╖Ур╢н р╢Нр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢пр╖У р╢Лр╖Гр╢╕ р╢Ър╢│р╖Ф р╢╢р╖Ср╖Ар╖Фр╢╕р╖Кр╖Ар╢╜ р╖Др╖Тр╢╕ р╢╕р╢н р╢╜р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╖Гр╖П р╢║р╖Пр╢╕ р╢Зр╢нр╖Фр╖Ер╖Ф р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╢╗р╖Пр╖Бр╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢╖р╖Фр╢Ър╖Кр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢│р╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║. р╢╕р╖Ур╢з р╢Ер╢╕р╢нр╢╗р╖А, р╢Ър╢│р╖Ф р╢▒р╖Рр╢Ьр╖Ур╢╕, р╢Ър╢│р╖Ф р╢▒р╖Рр╢Ьр╖Ур╢╕, р╢╕р╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╢зр╢▒р╖К р╢╢р╢║р╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢Ър╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╢пр╖Ур╢╕, р╢Ер╖Бр╖Кр╖Ар╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╢пр╖Ур╢╕ р╖Гр╖Д р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╢пр╖Ъ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖П р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Ъ. р╢Зр╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╢║р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢в р╖Бр╖Пр╢╜р╖П р╢Лр╢пр╖Кр╢║р╖Эр╢Ьр╖Тр╢╕р╢нр╖К р╢Ер╢║ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢Ър╢│р╖Фр╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Кр╢╗р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢Ър╢╕р╖К р╖Гр╢Вр╖Ар╖Тр╢░р╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╖Т."},{"question":"O que ├й uma \\"fun├з├гo an├┤nima\\" em Go?","answer":"Uma fun├з├гo an├┤nima ├й uma fun├з├гo sem nome que pode ser definida e usada diretamente em express├╡es ou atribu├нda a vari├бveis."},{"question":"Naa ka'y gipanagot nga problema karon? Unsa ang imong mga buhaton?","answer":"Usa ka labing daku nga challenge karon mao ang pagdumala sa mga isyu sa trabaho, ug akong gipaningkamutan nga makakita og solusyon pinaagi sa komprehensibo nga pag-alam sa sitwasyon."},{"question":"╨в╤Г╤Г╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨║╥п╨╜╨│╙й ╨║╨░╤А╨░╤В╨░ ╨║╤Г╤В╤В╤Г╨║╤В╨╛╨╛ ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡ ╨░╨╗╨░╤Б╤Л╥г╨▒╤Л  ?","answer":"╨б╨╕╨╖╨│╨╡ ╨║╥п╨╗╨║╥п ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨▒╨░╨║╤В╤Л╨╗╤Г╤Г╨╗╤Г╨║╨║╨░ ╤В╨╛╨╗╨│╨╛╨╜ ╤Г╨╗╤Г╤Г ╨║╥п╨╜╨┤╥п ╨║╨░╨░╨╗╨░╨╣╨╝. ╨в╤Г╤Г╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨║╤Г╨╜╤Г╥г╤Г╨╖ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨║╤Г╤В╤В╤Г╨║╤В╨░╨╣╨╝!"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho hafaliana, alahelo, hatezerena, tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity:Fanambarana┬а: ┬л┬аMbola injany tsaroako mangorintsina any amiтАЩny tenako rehetra any, mivaivay any anaty rako any ny akonтАЩny fitiavana nanjary antom-pahavelomako ankehitriny. Lasa anefa ianao, tsy hiverina intsony.┬а┬╗","answer":"Maneho alahelo io fanambarana io. Nandao ny tany ilay olon-tiany."},{"question":"Pergunta: Qual foi o maior projeto de obras p├║blicas na hist├│ria dos EUA? Resposta:","answer":"Big Dig"},{"question":"р╖Гр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖КтАНр╖А р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Т р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢нр╢╕ р╢┤р╖Рр╢зр╖Ар╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖КтАНр╖Вр╖Ур╢╗р╢┤р╖Пр╢║р╖У р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╢▒ р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢ор╖Ур╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢┤р╢пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Фр╢пр╖Ф р╢┤р╖Пр╢з р╢пр╖Тр╢║р╢╗р╢║ р╖Гр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖КтАНр╖А р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Т р╖Ар╖Ъ."},{"question":"Inona no dikan'ny teny hoe \\"plante\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy?","answer":"Ny dikan'ny teny hoe \\"plante\\" amin'ny teny Malagasy dia \\"zava-maniry\\"."},{"question":"Where do you live?","answer":"Currently, I live in Somalia and I want to know the location of the job."},{"question":"Ahitsio ny diso tsipelina ao anatin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity:\\"Ny fitantanana ny ala mahartra dia manampy amin'ny fiarovna ny zavamannaina sy ny ady amin'ny fiovana.\\"","answer":"Ity ilay fanambarana miaraka amin'ny tsipelina efa voahitsy \\"Ny fitantanana ny ala maharitra dia manampy amin'ny fiarovana ny zavamananaina sy ny ady amin'ny fiovana\\""},{"question":"Thс╗Эi gian vс╗лa rс╗Уi t├┤i thс║еy nhiс╗Бu th├┤ng tin rao b├бn giс║гm gi├б ─Сс║еt с╗Я S├│c S╞бn, Ba V├м n├кn c┼йng hс╗Пi mс╗Щt sс╗С m├┤i giс╗Ыi. T├┤i ─С╞░с╗гc mс╗Щt ng╞░с╗Эi giс╗Ыi thiс╗Зu mс╗Щt khu ─Сс║еt tс║зm nh├мn hс╗У с╗Я S├│c S╞бn c├│ diс╗Зn t├нch ─Сс║еt 3.000 m2. Gi├б hai n─Гm tr╞░с╗Ыc khoс║гng 5,5 triс╗Зu ─Сс╗Уng mс╗Чi m2, giс║гm c├▓n 5 triс╗Зu ─Сс╗Уng mс╗Щt m2.M├┤i giс╗Ыi cho biс║┐t ─С├вy l├а khu vс╗▒c chс╗з yс║┐u ─Сс║еt l├вm nghiс╗Зp ch╞░a c├│ sс╗Х ─Сс╗П, mua b├бn c├┤ng chс╗йng vi bс║▒ng. Nhс╗пng giao dс╗Лch quanh khu vс╗▒c n├аy vс║лn ─С╞░с╗гc thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn nh╞░ thс║┐. Nhiс╗Бu nh├а ─Сс║зu t╞░ sau khi mua ─Сс║еt ─С├г x├вy khu nghс╗Й d╞░с╗бng hay homestay, chс╗Э chuyс╗Гn ─Сс╗Хi mс╗еc ─С├нch sс╗н dс╗еng ─Сс║еt.Mong chuy├кn gia t╞░ vс║еn x├вy nh├а tr├кn ─Сс║еt rс╗лng c├│ rс╗зi ro ra sao? Nh├а ─Сс║зu t╞░ cс║зn l╞░u ├╜ nhс╗пng g├м nс║┐u giao dс╗Лch nhс╗пng khu ─Сс║еt nh╞░ tr├кn?","answer":"Biс╗Зt thс╗▒, homestay l├а c├┤ng tr├мnh nh├а с╗Я ri├кng lс║╗ cс╗зa c├бc hс╗Щ gia ─С├мnh, c├б nh├вn. Theo Luс║нt Nh├а с╗Я, ph├бp luс║нt cс║еm h├аnh vi x├вy dс╗▒ng nh├а с╗Я tr├кn c├бc loс║бi ─Сс║еt m├а kh├┤ng phс║гi ─Сс║еt с╗Я. Do ─С├│, viс╗Зc x├вy dс╗▒ng c├бc c├┤ng tr├мnh nh├а с╗Я tr├кn ─Сс║еt rс╗лng, t├╣y tс╗лng tr╞░с╗Эng hс╗гp v├а h├аnh vi cс╗е thс╗Г, c├│ thс╗Г vi phс║бm rс║еt nhiс╗Бu quy ─Сс╗Лnh kh├бc nhau nh╞░ Luс║нt X├вy dс╗▒ng, Luс║нt ─Рс║еt ─Сai hay quy ─Сс╗Лnh ph├бp luс║нt vс╗Б l─йnh vс╗▒c l├вm nghiс╗Зp.Cс╗е thс╗Г, h├аnh vi x├вy dс╗▒ng nh├а с╗Я tr├кn ─Сс║еt rс╗лng ph├▓ng hс╗Щ c├│ thс╗Г bс╗Л xс╗н phс║бt h├аnh ch├нnh tс╗л 3 ─Сс║┐n 250 triс╗Зu ─Сс╗Уng v├м chuyс╗Гn mс╗еc ─С├нch khi ch╞░a c├│ sс╗▒ chс║еp thuс║нn cс╗зa c╞б quan c├│ thс║йm quyс╗Бn, theo Nghс╗Л ─Сс╗Лnh 91/2019. B├кn cс║бnh ─С├│, ng╞░с╗Эi vi phс║бm sс║╜ phс║гi kh├┤i phс╗еc lс║бi t├мnh trс║бng ban ─Сс║зu cс╗зa ─Сс║еt v├а nс╗Щp lс║бi sс╗С lс╗гi bс║еt hс╗гp ph├бp c├│ ─С╞░с╗гc. Ngo├аi ra, x├вy dс╗▒ng nh├а tr├кn ─Сс║еt l├вm nghiс╗Зp sс║╜ kh├┤ng ─С╞░с╗гc c╞б quan c├│ thс║йm quyс╗Бn cс║еp giс║еy ph├йp x├вy dс╗▒ng.C├│ thс╗Г thс║еy, viс╗Зc x├вy dс╗▒ng nh├а tr├кn ─Сс║еt rс╗лng lu├┤n tiс╗Бm с║йn h├аng loс║бt rс╗зi ro. Trong ─С├│, viс╗Зc xс╗н phс║бt vi phс║бm h├аnh ch├нnh giс╗Ыi hс║бn trong hai n─Гm, kс╗Г tс╗л thс╗Эi ─Сiс╗Гm kс║┐t th├║c vi phс║бm th├м biс╗Зn ph├бp khс║пc phс╗еc hс║нu quс║г kh├┤ng bс╗Л giс╗Ыi hс║бn thс╗Эi gian. ─Рiс╗Бu n├аy c├│ ngh─йa l├а bс║бn x├вy nh├а tr├кn ─Сс║еt rс╗лng, bс║еt cс╗й khi n├аo m├а c╞б quan c├│ thс║йm quyс╗Бn ph├бt hiс╗Зn ─Сс╗Бu c├│ quyс╗Бn y├кu cс║зu th├бo dс╗б, kh├┤i phс╗еc t├мnh trс║бng ban ─Сс║зu cс╗зa ─Сс║еt v├а nс╗Щp lс║бi sс╗С lс╗гi bс║еt hс╗гp ph├бp (gс╗Уm viс╗Зc thu lс╗гi tс╗л kinh doanh homestay).Thс╗▒c tс║┐, viс╗Зc xс╗н l├╜ vс╗Ыi c├┤ng tr├мnh vi phс║бm trс║нt tс╗▒ x├вy dс╗▒ng tс║бi S├│c S╞бn v├а mс╗Щt sс╗С ─Сс╗Лa ph╞░╞бng tс║бi H├а Nс╗Щi gс║╖p nhiс╗Бu kh├│ kh─Гn thс╗Эi gian qua, g├│p phс║зn tс║бo t├вm l├╜ nhс╗Эn luс║нt cс╗зa mс╗Щt sс╗С ng╞░с╗Эi. Cс╗Щng th├кm vс╗Ыi t├вm l├╜ ─Сс║зu t╞░, x├вy dс╗▒ng ─Сс╗Г chс╗Э chuyс╗Гn ─Сс╗Хi mс╗еc ─С├нch sс╗н dс╗еng ─Сс║еt dс║лn ─Сс║┐n t├мnh trс║бng vi phс║бm ph├бp luс║нt vс╗Б ─Сс║еt ─Сai, x├вy dс╗▒ng с╗Я khu vс╗▒c n├аy kh├б phс╗Х biс║┐n."},{"question":"р┤Ор┤ир╡Нр┤др┤╛р┤гр╡Н р┤▓р┤╛р╡╝р┤Ьр╡Н р┤╣р┤╛р┤бр╡Нр┤░р╡Лр╡║ р┤Хр╡Кр┤│р╡Ир┤бр╡╝?","answer":"р┤▓р┤╛р╡╝р┤Ьр╡Н р┤╣р┤╛р┤бр╡Нр┤░р╡Лр╡║ р┤Хр╡Кр┤│р╡Ир┤бр╡╝ р┤▓р╡Лр┤Хр┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤▓р╡Ж р┤Пр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р┤╡р╡Бр┤В р┤╡р┤▓р╡Бр┤др╡Бр┤В р┤╢р┤Хр╡Нр┤др┤╡р╡Бр┤ор┤╛р┤п р┤Хр┤гр┤┐р┤Хр┤╛ р┤Жр┤Хр╡Нр┤╕р┤┐р┤▓р┤▒р╡Зр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р┤▒р┤╛р┤гр╡Н, р┤Зр┤др╡Н р┤╕р╡Нр┤╡р┤┐р┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р╡Нр┤╕р╡╝р┤▓р╡╗р┤бр┤┐р┤▓р╡Ж р┤Ьр┤ир╡Ар┤╡р┤пр╡Нр┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Н р┤╕р┤ор╡Ар┤кр┤ор╡Бр┤│р╡Нр┤│ р┤пр╡Вр┤▒р╡Лр┤кр╡Нр┤пр╡╗ р┤Ур╡╝р┤Чр┤ир╡Ир┤╕р╡Зр┤╖р╡╗ р┤лр╡Лр╡╝ р┤ир╡Нр┤пр╡Вр┤Хр╡Нр┤▓р┤┐р┤пр╡╝ р┤▒р┤┐р┤╕р╡╝р┤Ър╡Нр┤Ър╡Н-р╡╜ р┤╕р╡Нр┤ер┤┐р┤др┤┐ р┤Ър╡Жр┤пр╡Нр┤пр╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир╡Б. р┤Зр┤др╡Н р┤Йр┤кр┤Жр┤▒р╡Нр┤▒р╡Лр┤ор┤┐р┤Хр╡Н р┤Хр┤гр┤Щр╡Нр┤Щр┤│р╡Ж р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤Хр┤╛р┤╢р┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Нр┤▒р╡Ж р┤╡р╡Зр┤Чр┤др┤пр┤┐р╡╜ р┤др╡Нр┤╡р┤░р┤┐р┤др┤кр╡Нр┤кр╡Жр┤Яр╡Бр┤др╡Нр┤др╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир╡Б, р┤Хр┤гр┤┐р┤Хр┤╛ р┤нр╡Чр┤др┤┐р┤Хр┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Нр┤▒р╡Ж р┤Ер┤Яр┤┐р┤╕р╡Нр┤ер┤╛р┤и р┤╡р┤╢р┤Щр╡Нр┤Щр┤│р╡Бр┤В р┤жр╡Нр┤░р┤╡р╡Нр┤пр┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Нр┤▒р╡Ж р┤Шр┤Яр┤ир┤пр╡Бр┤В р┤кр┤░р╡Нр┤пр┤╡р╡Зр┤Хр╡Нр┤╖р┤гр┤В р┤Ър╡Жр┤пр╡Нр┤пр╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Бр┤│р╡Нр┤│ р┤кр┤░р╡Ар┤Хр╡Нр┤╖р┤гр┤Щр╡Нр┤Щр╡╛ р┤╕р╡Бр┤Чр┤ор┤ор┤╛р┤Хр╡Нр┤Хр╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир╡Б. р┤╣р┤┐р┤Чр╡Нр┤╕р╡Н р┤мр╡Лр┤╕р╡Лр┤гр┤┐р┤ир╡Ж р┤Хр┤гр╡Нр┤Яр╡Жр┤др╡Нр┤др╡Бр┤ир╡Нр┤ир┤др┤┐р╡╜ р┤Ор╡╜р┤Ор┤Ър╡Нр┤Ър╡Нр┤╕р┤┐ р┤Тр┤░р╡Б р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤зр┤╛р┤и р┤кр┤Щр╡Нр┤Хр╡Н р┤╡р┤╣р┤┐р┤Ър╡Нр┤Ър╡Б, р┤кр╡Нр┤░р┤кр┤Юр╡Нр┤Ър┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Нр┤▒р╡Ж р┤Ер┤Яр┤┐р┤╕р╡Нр┤ер┤╛р┤и р┤Хр┤гр┤Щр╡Нр┤Щр┤│р╡Жр┤пр╡Бр┤В р┤╢р┤Хр╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤Хр┤│р╡Жр┤пр╡Бр┤В р┤Хр╡Бр┤▒р┤┐р┤Ър╡Нр┤Ър╡Бр┤│р╡Нр┤│ р┤ир┤ор╡Нр┤ор╡Бр┤Яр╡Ж р┤Чр╡Нр┤░р┤╛р┤╣р╡Нр┤пр┤др╡Нр┤др┤┐р┤ир╡Н р┤Хр┤╛р┤░р╡Нр┤пр┤ор┤╛р┤п р┤╕р┤Вр┤нр┤╛р┤╡р┤и р┤ир╡╜р┤Хр┤┐."},{"question":"Jox ma p├йeteg waat yi ci k├аddu gii: Bul├йen di y├лdoonte; bul├йen di j├лwante.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci k├аddu gii di \\"Bul├йen di y├лdoonte; bul├йen di j├лwante.\\" ak s├йen i p├йete ├▒oo di:Bul├йen: AUXdi: AUXy├лdoonte: VERB;: PUNCTbul├йen: AUXdi: AUXj├лwante: VERB.: PUNCT"},{"question":"Dorcas с╣гс╗Нl├б Fapson","answer":"Dorcas с╣гс╗Нl├б Fapson jс║╣╠Б ├▓с╣г├иr├йb├мnrin ├аti atс╗Н╠Бk├╣n t├н ├│ gbaj├║mс╗Н╠А f├║n ipa t├│ k├│ n├нn├║ ├иt├▓ kan t├н wс╗Н╠Бn p├и n├н с╣г├║g├а l├│r├н ├мk├аnn├м MTV's. ├Аd├аkс╗Н:Circular reference as тАШSophieтАЩ. Lс╗Н╠Бd├║n 2020, ├│ pad├а s├н ├иt├▓ с╣г├║g├а n├б├а l├│r├н ├мk├аnn├м MTV l├бti sс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А l├│r├н ├аj├аk├бlс║╣╠А ├аr├╣n k├▓r├│n├а pс║╣╠Аl├║ ├аwс╗Нn ├▓с╣г├иr├й t├н wс╗Н╠Бn ┼Д с╣гiс╣гс║╣╠Б pс╗Н╠А k├б├аkiri ilс║╣╠А ad├║l├бwс╗Н╠А ├Бf├нr├нk├аWс╗Н╠Бn b├н Fapson nilui London n├н n╟╣kan b├н с╗Нd├║n 1990s. ├Мy├б rс║╣╠А k├║ n├нgb├а t├│ w├а lс╗Н╠Бmс╗Н с╗Нd├║n mс║╣╠Бr├мnl├б. ├У k├аw├й gboy├и n├нn├║ ├мmс╗Н╠А ├мс╣гe с╗Н╠Аdar├аn (Criminology) l├│r├нlс║╣╠А ├иd├и England. ├У tс║╣╠А s├нw├бj├║ n├нn├║ с║╣╠Аkс╗Н╠Б rс║╣╠А, ├│ s├мn k├аw├й gboy├и n├нn├║ ├мmс╗Н╠А t├н├бt├а n├н New York.├У k├│pa n├нn├║ ├иt├▓ с╣г├║ga abala kс║╣ta n├н ├мk├аnn├м MTV.[1] as тАШSophieтАЩ and she was the presenter of \\"The Juice\\" an interview series for NdaniTV.├У w├а n├нn├║ ├иt├▓ с╣г├║g├а n├н ├мk├аnn├м MTV t├н ├│ ├│ t├║n fi pad├а di akс╗Н╠Бс╣гс║╣╠Бmс╗Нс╣гс║╣╠Б ├мс╣г├иg├╣n t├н wс╗Н╠Бn p├и n├н \\"Sophie\\" n├нn├║ ├иt├▓ m├м├нr├аn t├н w├│n p├и n├н MTV Shuga Alone Together n├нbi t├н wс╗Н╠Бn ti ┼Д sс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А n├нpa ├аj├аk├бlс║╣╠А ├аr├╣n k├▓r├│n├а lс╗Н╠Бd├║n 2020. The series was written by T├║nd├й Al├бd├йс╣гe and broadcast for several nights - its backers include the United Nations. ├Аwс╗Нn ├иt├▓ wс╗Н╠Аny├н w├а n├н N├а├мj├нr├н├а, South Africa, Kenya ├аti C├┤te d'Ivoire, t├н ├мt├аn n├б├а ┼Д tс║╣╠А s├нw├бj├║ l├│r├н ├мt├аk├╣n ay├йluj├бra who include Mohau Cele, Lerato Walaza, Sthandiwe Kgoroge, Uzoamaka Aniunoh, Mamarumo Marokane and Jemima Osunde."},{"question":"Wafika ekhaya wangawuvala umlomo ngendlela uMaNdlovu amtshele ngayo.Baqala ukuba bethuke manje, kwakufanele ukuba basuke ngaso leso sikhathi bayeeMnambithi nabo bayofuna lapho becabanga ukuthi bakhona oyise nonina.Bahamba ubusuku bonke indodakazi yabo ingafuni ngisho ukubakhulumisa.EThekwini uMjwayeli nomkakhe baya kulo muzi lapho uyise wayejwayele ukuyakhona. Bathi bengena nje esangweni, indoda yavulela inja kwakhalwaubumayemaye inja enkulu ibasukela, wayikhuza. Bacela ukukhuluma nayo, yathiabangene.Baba ukungena nje endlini yababuza: 'Nginganisiza ngani?'Kwaphendula uMchunu: 'Besicela ukubuza ukuthi ubaba evalelisa kinina akashongoyini ukuthi uyaphi?''Uthe uya eMnambithi. Nikushiso yini lokho?''Abafowethu ababatholanga esiteshini, bafike sebehlile esitimeleni.''Kanti ubaba wenu ngempela uMchunu naningamnakile nje. UMchunu ubehambangezinto ezinganakekelwe zonke izinsuku ukhona makoti?' 1. Uyavumelana yini nombono wokuthi ukubekezela kuyasiza? Sekelaimpendulo yakho ngokubhekisa kuManyoba.","answer":"Ngiyavumelana ngoba ...тАв Ziningi izinkinga abhekana nazo esakhula, esesebenza nalaphoesenomndeni. Akalilahli nokho ithemba. тАв Nalapho esegugile eselahlwa yizingane zakhe ulokhu ebambeleleethembeni njalo nje futhi ugcina ephumeleleNOMAAngivumelani ngoba ...тАв Wabekezela esebenza kanzima efundisa izingane zakhe ngobaekholelwa ukuthi ziyoba usizo kuye uma esephelelwe ngamandlaokuzisebenzela. тАв Ukubekezela kwakhe akubanga nomphumela othokozisayo ngoba impiloyakhe yaze yashintsha emva kokuba ewine ilotho, okuyintoengahlanganise lutho nokubekezela kwakhe. "},{"question":"рдиреЗрдкрд╛рд▓рдорд╛ рдХрд╛рдЧрдЬреА рдиреЛрдЯ рдХрд╣рд┐рд▓реЗ рджреЗрдЦрд┐ рд╕реБрд░реБ рднрдпреЛ ?","answer":"рдиреЗрдкрд╛рд▓рдорд╛ рдХрд╛рдЧрдЬреА рдиреЛрдЯ рдмрд┐.рд╕. реирежрежреи рдЕрд╕реЛрдЬ режрез рджреЗрдЦрд┐ рд╕реБрд░реБ рднрдпрдХреЛ рдерд┐рдпреЛред"},{"question":"Qual a resposta correta para a pergunta a seguir: Qual ├й o rio mais longo do Brasil?","answer":"A resposta correta ├й Rio Amazonas"},{"question":"р╢┤р╖Др╢н р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢пр╖Пр╖Е р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Фр╢пр╖Кр╢░ р╢┤р╢п р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?р╢Ер╢╢р╖Тр╢║р╖Г","answer":"р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╖Фр╢┤р╖Г"},{"question":"╨Я╨╛╤А╤В╤Г╨│╨░╨╗╨╕╤П╨┤╨░ ╨┤╨╡╨╜-╤Б╨╛╨╛╨╗╤Г╨║╤В╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨│╥п╨╗╨┤╙й╨┐ ╙й╨╜╥п╨│╥п╥п╨╜╥п╨╜ ╤Б╨╕╨╝╨▓╨╛╨╗╤Г ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ╨░╨╣╤В╤Л╨╗╨░╤В?","answer":"╨Ц╥п╨╖╥п╨╝ ╤Б╨░╨▒╨░╨│╤Л - ╨Я╨╛╤А╤В╤Г╨│╨░╨╗╨╕╤П╨┤╨░ ╨┤╨╡╨╜-╤Б╨╛╨╛╨╗╤Г╨║╤В╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨│╥п╨╗╨┤╙й╨┐ ╙й╨╜╥п╨│╥п╥п╨╜╥п╨╜ ╤Б╨╕╨╝╨▓╨╛╨╗╤Г"},{"question":"Qual ├й o processo pelo qual as plantas perdem ├бgua na forma de vapor atrav├йs de pequenos poros em suas folhas?","answer":"Esse processo ├й chamado de transpira├з├гo. A transpira├з├гo ├й uma parte importante do ciclo da ├бgua nas plantas, e ocorre maioritariamente atrav├йs das suas folhas."},{"question":"┬┐Cu├бl es la capital de Nari├▒o Colombia?","answer":"La capital de Nari├▒o Colombia es Pasto"},{"question":"╨Ь╥п╨╜╥п╤И╨║╙й╤А ╨▒╤Г╨╗...","answer":"╨Ш╨╗╨│╨╡╤А╨╕-╨╕╨╗╨│╨╡╤А╨╕ ╨╛╨╜ ╨╢╨╡╤В╨╕ ╨╢╨░╤И╨░╤А ╨╝╥п╨╜╥п╤И╨║╙й╤А ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨▒╨░╨╣╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╥п╨╣╥п╨╜╙й ╨║╨╡╨╗╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨╛╨╜╤Б╨╛ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В ╤В╤Г╤А╨░╤В. ╨н╤А╤В╨╡╥г ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨░╨╣╨▒╨╕╤З╨╡╤Б╨╕ ╤Н╨║╙й╙й ╨╢╨╡╨╗╨╡╨│╨╡ ╨▒╤Н╤Н ╨▒╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨╣╨╗╤Л ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╕╤И╨╡╤В. ╨С╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╨║╙й ╨║╨░╤А╨░╨┐:-╨Ъ╨░╨╣╤А╨░╨╜ ╨░╤Б╤Л╨╗, ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╜╨░ ╤В╨╕╨╣╨▒╨╡╨╣, ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨▒╨╡╤Б ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╜╨░ ╤В╨╕╨╣╨╕╨┐╤Б╨╕╥г,-╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╤Б╥п╨╣╨╗╙й╨╜╙й╤В.╨Р╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╤Б╙й╨╖╥п╨╜ ╤Г╨│╤Г╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╨░╨╣╨│╨░ ╨▒╨░╤А╤Л╨┐:-╥о╨╣╨┤╙й╨│╥п ╨║╨╛╨╜╨╛╨║ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п \\"╨║╨░╨╣╤А╨░╨╜ ╨░╤Б╤Л╨╗, ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╜╨░ ╤В╨╕╨╣╨▒╨╡╨╣, ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨▒╨╡╤Б ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╜╨░ ╤В╨╕╨╣╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐╤Б╤Л╥г\\"-╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨╢╨░╤В╨░╤В,-╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В.╨С╨░╨╗╨░╨│╨░ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨╕╨┐ ╨▒╨░╨╣:╨С╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╤В╨░╨┐╤В╨░╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨│╨╕╨╜,-╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В.╨С╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╤В╨░╨┐╤В╨╛╨╛╨╜╤Г ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨▒╨╡╨╣╨╝╨╕╨╜,-╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░.╨С╨░╨╗╨░╨╝, ╤Г╤И╤Г╨╗ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╤В╨░╨┐╤В╨░╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤А╤Б╨╡╥г, ╨║╤Л╨╖╤Л╨╝╨┤╤Л ╤Б╨░╨│╨░ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╡╨╝╨╕╨╜,-╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В ╨▒╨░╨╣.╨Ю╤И╨╛╨╜╨┤╨╛ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░ ╨╝╨░╨║╤Г╨╗ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐:-╨н╨║╨╕ ╨╢╤Л╨╗ ╤В╤Г╤Г ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨▒╤Н╤Н ╤В╨░╨┐, ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╖ ╥п╨╣ ╤В╨╕╨║╤В╨╕╤А╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨╛╤О╥г╤Г╨╖, ╨░╨╗ ╥п╨╣╨┤╥п╨╜ ╨╕╤З╨╕╨╜╨┤╨╡ ╤Н╤З ╨╜╨╡╤А╤Б╨╡ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨▒╨╛╤Б╤Г╨╜, ╨░╨│╨░ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╨║╨╛╤С╨╝╤Г╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨▒╤Н╤Н╨╜╨╕ ╤Б╨╛╤О╨┐ ╤Н╤В╨╕╨╜ ╨║╨╕╤А╨│╨╕╨╖╨╡╨╝╨╕╨╜,-╨┤╨╡╨╣╤В. ╨С╨░╨╣ ╤Н╨║╨╕ ╨╢╤Л╨╗ ╤В╤Г╤Г ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨▒╤Н╤Н╨╜╨╕ ╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨╡╤В ╨╢╨░╨╜╨░ ╨▒╨╕╤А ╥п╨╣╨┤╥п ╤В╨╕╨║╤В╨╕╤А╨╕╨┐ ╨┤╨░╤П╤А╨┤╨░╨╣╤В, ╥п╨╣╨┤╥п╨╜ ╨╕╤З╨╕╨╜╨╡ ╤Н╤З ╨╜╨╡╤А╤Б╨╡ ╨║╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╤А╨▒╨░╨╣╤В.╨С╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╤Н╤Н╨╜╨╕ ╤Б╨╛╨╣╨┤╤Г╤А╨░╤В, ╨░╨╜╤Л ╨▒╥п╤В╥п╨╜ ╥п╨╣╨│╙й ╨║╨╕╤А╨│╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╕╤А╨╡╤В. ╨С╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╨┤╨░ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╤А╨╕╨┐ ╨▒╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╤И ╨║╨╛╨╡╤В. ╨Р╨╗ ╤З╤Л╨│╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╡╤В╨┐╨╡╨╣ ╤В╤Г╤А╨│╨░╨╜ ╨║╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╥п╨╣╨┤╥п ╨╢╤Л╨╗╤З╤Л╨│╤Л ╨╢╨╛╨║ ╨▒╨╡╨║╨╕╤В╨╡╤В. ╨Ю╤И╨╡╨╜╤В╨╕╨┐ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╨║╨░╨╝╨░╨┐ ╨║╨╛╨╡╤В ╨┤╨░, ╨║╤Н╤Н╨┤╨╡ ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╤Б╤Г╤Г ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨╛╤О╨┐ ╨╢╥п╤А╙й╤В. ╨С╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В ╨▒╤Н╤Н╨╜╨╕╨╜ ╤Н╤В╨╕╨╜ ╨╢╨╡╨┐ ╨▒╥п╤В╥п╨┐, ╤Б╨╡╨╝╨╕╨╖╨╕╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤Б╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨║╨░╨╗╨░╤В. ╨С╨░╨╗╨░: \\"╨С╨░╤Б╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В ╤В╨░╨┐╤В╨╛╨╛╨│╨╛ ╨╛╥г╨╛╨╣ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В\\" ╨┤╨╡╨┐, ╤В╨░╨┐╤В╨░╨╣ ╨▒╨░╤И╤В╨░╨╣╤В. ╨С╨╕╤А ╨░╨╣ ╤В╨░╨┐╤В╨░╨│╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╨░╨╜╤Л ╤В╥п╨╗╨║╥п╨│╙й ╤Б╨░╨╗╤Г╤Г ╥п╤З╥п╨╜ ╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╤З╤Л╨│╨░╤В. ╨С╨╕╤А ╤В╨╛╨┐ ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░ ╨║╤Л╨┤╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐ ╨╢╥п╤А╤Б╙й, ╨▒╨╕╤А ╨║╨░╤А╨░ ╤В╥п╨╗╨║╥п ╤З╤Л╨│╨░ ╨║╨░╤З╨░╤В ╨┤╨░, ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╨║╙й╤А╙й ╤Б╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╤В╨╕╨║╤В╨╡╨┐ ╤В╤Г╤А╤Г╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨░╤В, ╨░╨╗ ╨╢╙й╨╜ ╤В╥п╨╗╨║╥п ╤Н╨╝╨╡╤Б ╨║╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜. ╨С╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п╨╜ ╤В╨╛╨╝╨╛╨│╨╛╤Б╤Г╨╜ ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨░╨╗╨░╤В ╨┤╨░, ╨▒╨╕╤А╨╛╨║ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╙й ╨║╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╤Б╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣ ╤В╨╛╨╝╨╛╨│╨╛╤Б╤Г╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╣╤А╨░ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨│╨╕╨╖╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨╛╨╡╤В. ╨С╨░╨╗╨░ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╨╕╤А╨│╨╡ ╨╢╥п╤А╨│╙й╨╜ ╨║╨╕╤И╨╕╨╗╨╡╤А: \\"╨С╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ╤Б╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В?\\" ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╤В╨░╥г ╨║╨░╨╗╤Л╤И╨░╤В.╨С╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╤В╨╛╨╝╨╛╨│╨╛╤Б╤Г╨╜ ╨┤╨░╨│╤Л ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╤И╤Л╨┐╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐ ╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐, ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╤Б╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣ ╤В╨╛╨╝╨╛╨│╨╛╤Б╤Г╨╜ ╨║╨░╨╣╤А╨░ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨│╨╕╨╖╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨╛╨╡╤В. ╨С╨░╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╤И╤В╨╛╤А╤Г \\"╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╥п╨╜ ╤Н╨╝╨╜╨╡ ╤Б╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨╣╤В, ╨║╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨▒╨╕╨╖╨│╨╡ ╤Л╤А╨░╨░ ╨║╙й╤А╨▒╙й╨╣ ╤В╤Г╤А╨░╤В ╨│╨╛\\" ╨┤╨╡╤И╨╕╨┐ ╨╜╨░╨░╨╗╤Л╤И╨░╤В.╨С╨░╨╗╨░ ╤В╨╛╨╝╨╛╨│╨╛╨╜╤Г ╨░╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╤И╨╕╨╗╤В╨╡╨╣╤В. ╨С╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В ╨║╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╨║╨░╤А╨░╨▒╨░╨╣ ╨░╤Б╨╝╨░╨╜╨│╨░ ╨║╨╡╤В╨╡╤В. ╨Ъ╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛ ╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╥г╨║╤Л ╤Н╨║╨╕ ╨▒╤Г╤В╤Г╨╜ ╨║╙й╤В╙й╤А╥п╨┐ ╨░╤Б╨╝╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л ╤В╨╕╨║╤В╨╡╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨░╤В. ╨С╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В ╙й╤В╙й ╨▒╨╕╨╣╨╕╨║ ╨║╙й╤В╙й╤А╥п╨╗╥п╨┐, ╨║╨░╤А╨░╨░╨╜╤Л ╨║╙й╨╖╨│╙й ╨║╙й╤А╥п╨╜╨▒╙й╨╣ ╥п╨╗╨▒╥п╨╗╨┤╙й╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╡╨╖╨┤╨╡ ╤И╤Г╨║╤И╤Г╤А╤Г╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╤В╨╕╨║ ╤Б╨░╨╣╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨╕╨┐ ╨║╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨▒╨░╤И╤Л╨╜╨░╨╜ ╨╝╤Л╨║╤З╤Л╨╣ ╨║╨░╤А╨╝╨░╨┐ ╨║╙й╨║╨║╙й ╨║╙й╤В╙й╤А╥п╨╗╨┤╥п ╨┤╨░, ╨╢╨╡╤А╨│╨╡ ╤В╨░╤И╤В╨░╨┐ ╨╢╨╕╨▒╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕. ╨Ъ╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А╨┤╤Л ╨░╨╗╤Л╤И╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╜ ╨║╨╕╨╣╨╕╨╜ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╨┤╨╛╤И╤В╨╛╤А╤Г:╨н╨║╨╕ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п╨╜ ╤В╨╛╨╝╨╛╨│╨╛╤Б╤Г╨╜ ╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╥г, ╨▒╨╕╤А╨╛╨║ ╤Б╨░╨╗╨▒╨░╨┤╤Л╥г, ╥п╤З╥п╨╜╤З╥п ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г ╨│╨░╨╜╨░ ╤Б╨░╨╗╨┤╤Л╥г, ╨╝╤Г╨╜╤Г╨╜ ╤Б╨╡╨▒╨╡╨▒╨╕ ╨║╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╨╣?-╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╨┤╨░╨╜ ╤Б╤Г╤А╨░╤И╨░╤В.╨С╨╕╤А╨╕╨╜╤З╨╕ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г ╨░╤Б╤Л╨╗ ╨╝╨╡╨╜╨╡╨╜ ╨░╤Б╤Л╨╗ ╨║╨░╨╜╤В╨╕╨┐ ╨▒╨╡╤В╤В╨╡╤И╨╡╤В ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╨║╨░╨╗╤В╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╤Б╨░╨╗╤Г╤Г╨│╨░ ╨║╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╝ ╨▒╨░╤А╨▒╨░╨┤╤Л. ╨н╨║╨╕╨╜╤З╨╕ ╨╢╨╛╨╗╤Г ╨░╤Б╤Л╨╗╨┤╤Л ╨░╤Б╤Л╨╗ ╨║╨░╨╜╤В╨╕╨┐ ╨║╤Л╤П╤В ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╤Б╨░╨╗╤Г╤Г╨│╨░ ╨║╨╛╨╗╤Г╨╝ ╨▒╨░╤А╨▒╨░╨┤╤Л, ╥п╤З╥п╨╜╤З╥п╤Б╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╤В╨╛╨▒╨╛╨║╨╡╨╗ ╨┤╨╡╨┐ ╤З╤Л╨╝╤Л╤А╨║╨░╨╜╤Л╨┐ ╤В╤Г╤А╤Г╨┐ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╥п╨╝╨┤╥п ╨║╨╛╨╡ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨┤╨╕╨╝, ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п╨╜ ╨░╤Б╨╝╨░╨╜╨│╨░ ╨▒╨╕╨╣╨╕╨║ ╤З╤Л╨║╨║╨░╨╜╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╤Б╨╡╨▒╨╡╨▒╨╕, ╨░╨╗ ╨║╨░╨╜╤З╨░╨╗╤Л╨║ ╨▒╨╕╨╣╨╕╨║ ╨║╙й╤В╙й╤А╥п╨╗╤Б╙й, ╨╛╤И╨╛╨╜╤З╨╛╨╗╤Г╨║ ╤В╨╕╨║╤В╨╡╨╣ ╨▒╨╡╤А╨╕╨┐ ╤В╥п╨╗╨║╥п╨╜╥п╨╜ ╨║╙й╨╖╥п╨╜╙й ╨╢╨░╤И ╤В╨╛╨╗╨╛╤В, ╨║╨░╤З╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨╡ ╨╢╨░╤В╨║╨░╨╜ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В╤В╥п ╨║╙й╤А╨▒╙й╨╣ ╨║╨░╨╗╨░╤В. ╨Р╨║╤З╨╡╨║╨╕╤А ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╨▒╥п╤А╨║╥п╤В ╤Г╤И╤Г╨╗,-╨┤╨╡╨┤╨╕ ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░.╨н╨╗: \\"╨з╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜╨┤╨░ ╨▒╨░╨╣╨┤╤Л╨╜ ╨║╤Л╨╖╤Л ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╨│╨░ ╤Л╨╗╨░╨╣╤Л╨║ ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜\\" ╨┤╨╡╤И╨╕╨┐, ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╨╜╤Л ╥п╨╣╨╗╙й╨╜╨┤╥п╤А╥п╨┐-╨╢╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╤А╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨╛╤О╤И╨║╨░╨╜ ╤Н╨║╨╡╨╜."},{"question":"Qual ├й a capital do Togo?","answer":"Lom├й ├й a capital do Togo e a maior cidade do pa├нs. A cidade e localiza-se na costa do Golfo da Guin├й. Para al├йm de ser a capital administrativa do pa├нs, ├й tamb├йm a mais importante cidade do Togo. Lom├й foi fundada no s├йculo XVIII pelos jejes e tornou-se capital no s├йculo seguinte."},{"question":"р╢Ер╢нр╖Рр╢╣р╖Фр╢╜ р╢Лр╢┤р╖Гр╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ар╢╜р╢з р╢Ер╢║р╢нр╖К р╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Щ р╢▒р╖Рр╖Др╖Р р╢▒р╖Ъ р╢п?","answer":"р╢▒р╖С ....р╢Ер╢н р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Лр╢┤р╖Гр╢╗р╖Кр╢Ьр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Ер╢н+р╢Зр╢╣р╖Фр╢╜р╢Ер╢нр╖К+р╢Е+р╢Зр╢╣р╖Фр╢╜р╢Ер╢нр╖К+[р╢Е]р╢Зр╢╣р╖Фр╢╜р╢Ер╢нр╖Рр╢╣р╖Фр╢╜р╢┤р╖Цр╢╗р╖Кр╖А р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╗ р╢╜р╖Эр╢┤ р╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢░р╖Т "},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'makan bunga'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud mengambil keuntungan daripada wang yang dipinjamkan. Contoh ayat: Ceti itu makan bunga dengan mengenakan kadar faedah 20% daripada jumlah wang yang dipinjam."},{"question":"Lс╗Ыp 6A c├│ 6 tс╗Х hс╗Нc sinh. ─Рс╗Г tс╗Х chс╗йc li├кn hoan cho lс╗Ыp, c├┤ Ng├вn ─С├г mua 42 chiс║┐c b├бnh ngс╗Нt v├а 45 quс║г qu├╜t.C├┤ Ng├вn c├│ thс╗Г chia ─Сс╗Бu sс╗С b├бnh ngс╗Нt cho 6 tс╗Х ─С╞░с╗гc kh├┤ng?C├┤ Ng├вn c├│ thс╗Г chia ─Сс╗Бu sс╗С quс║г qu├╜t cho 6 tс╗Х ─С╞░с╗гc kh├┤ng?","answer":"─Рс╗Г biс║┐t c├┤ Ng├вn c├│ chia ─Сс╗Бu sс╗С b├бnh ngс╗Нt v├а sс╗С quс║г qu├╜t cho 6 tс╗Х hay kh├┤ng th├м ta thс╗▒c hiс╗Зn ph├йp chia.Ta c├│: 42 : 6 = 7 ; 45 : 6 = 7 (d╞░ 3).Khi ─С├│ ta n├│i 42 chia hс║┐t cho 6 v├а 45 kh├┤ng chia hс║┐t cho 6 (qua b├аi hс╗Нc d╞░с╗Ыi n├аy ta sс║╜ t├мm hiс╗Гu k─й h╞бn)Vс║нy c├┤ Ng├вn c├│ thс╗Г chia ─Сс╗Бu sс╗С b├бnh ngс╗Нt cho 6 tс╗Х v├а kh├┤ng thс╗Г chia ─Сс╗Бu sс╗С quс║г qu├╜t cho 6 tс╗Х."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berakit-rakit ke hulu, berenang-renang ke tepian; bersakit-sakit dahulu, bersenang-senang kemudian\\"? Berilah contoh ayat untuknya. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud untuk mendapat kesenangan, biar bersusah payah dahulu. Jikalau mahu menjadi orang yang berjaya, kamu mesti tabah menghadapi segala cabaran dan rintangan seperti kata pepatah berakit-rakit ke hulu, berenang-renang ke tepian; bersakit-sakit dahulu, bersenang-senang kemudian."},{"question":"Ibo ipinlс║╣ Edo ti wс╗Нn ti ka, с╗Мbasс║╣ki lo wс╗Нle nibс║╣ o","answer":"Ninu ibo gomina ti wс╗Нn di ni ipinlс║╣ с║╕do lanaa ode yii, awс╗Нn esi lati ijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ ti wс╗Нn ti ka ni akayanju bayii, Gomina Godwin с╗Мbasс║╣ki lo wс╗Нle julс╗Н. Ijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ mс║╣tala ni esi wс╗Нn ti jade, ninu awс╗Нn mс║╣tala naa, с╗Мbasс║╣ki to n dije lorukс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ APC ti mu mс╗Нkanla, nigba ti с║╣ni to n ba a du ipo naa, Pasitс╗Н Ize-Iyamu ti mu meji pere. Lapapс╗Н, o ti le ni с║╣gbс║╣run lс╗Нna с╗Нgс╗Нta ibo ti с╗Мbaseki fi ju Ize Iyamu lс╗Н. Lati ipinlс║╣ marun-un lo ku t iwon tin reti esi idibo bayii, lс║╣yin naa ni ajс╗Н INEC to n с╣гeto idibo na ayo si kede с║╣ni to ba bori pata ninu wс╗Нn.Bi wс╗Нn ti to esi idibo naa tс║╣ le ara wс╗Нn ree, ati awс╗Нn ijoba ibilс║╣ wс╗Нn:Esan WestAPC 7,189PDP 17,434Oredo LGAAPC 18,365PDP 43,4983. Etsako West LGAAPC 26,140PDP 17,9594. Ovia North EastAPC 9,907PDP 16,9875. Esan South EastAPC 9,237PDP 10,5656. Owan WestAPC 11,193PDP 11,485Owan EastAPC 19,295PDP 14,7628. Egor LGAAPC 10,202PDP 27,6219. UhunmwondeAPC 5,972PDP 10,02210. Ikpoba-Okha LGAAPC тАУ 18,218PDP тАУ 41,03011. Esan Central LGAPC 6,719PDP 10,6941 Esan North East LGAPC тАУ 6,556PDP тАУ 13, 57913. Igueben LGAPDP тАУ 7,870APC тАУ 5,199"},{"question":"Kedu mgbe agbara с╗еlo Igwe Oliver Nnaji ","answer":"A gbara u╠гlo╠г Igwe Oliver Nnaji nke Ogwu Aniocha Anambra steeti o╠гku╠г n'abalс╗Л iri na isii nke с╗Нnwa No╠гvemba  nke afс╗Н 2021."},{"question":"тАЬф╕ЬщгОхОЛхАТше┐щгОтАЭш┐ЩхПешпЭцШпф╗Аф╣ИцДПцАЭхСвя╝Я","answer":"ш┐ЩхПешпЭхОЯцМЗх░Бх╗║хдзхо╢х║нщЗМхп╣члЛчЪДф╕дцЦ╣,ф╕АцЦ╣хОЛхАТхПжф╕АцЦ╣я╝ЫчО░цпФхЦ╗щЭйхС╜хКЫщЗПхп╣ф║ОхПНхКихК┐хКЫхНахОЛхАТчЪДф╝ШхК┐уАВ"},{"question":"Inona no anaran'ilay fipoahana volkano malaza any Indonezia izay nisy vokany ara-toetr'andro tamin'ny 1815?","answer":" Ny anaran'ilay fipoahana volkano malaza any Indonezia izay nisy fiantraikany ara-toetr'izao tontolo izao tamin'ny 1815 dia ny fipoahan'ny Tendrombohitra Tambora."},{"question":"O dono de um restaurante situado a╠Аs margens de uma rodovia percebeu que, ao colocar uma placa de propaganda de seu restaurante ao longo da rodovia, as vendas aumentaram. Pesquisou junto aos seus clientes e concluiu que a probabilidade de um motorista perceber uma placa de anu╠Бncio e╠Б 1/2 . Com isso, apo╠Бs autorizac╠зa╠Гo do o╠Бrga╠Гo competente, decidiu instalar novas placas com anu╠Бncios de seu restaurante ao longo dessa rodovia, de maneira que a probabilidade de um motorista perceber pelo menos uma das placas instaladas fosse superior a 99/100. A quantidade mi╠Бnima de novas placas de propaganda a serem instaladas e╠Б?a) 99.b) 51.c) 50.d) 6.e) 1.","answer":"d) 6."},{"question":"Umhlaba ungumhlaba ngokuhlabaUwuhloniphe uwukhonze uyakuhloniphaUbazonda kabi abazazi ukuhlakanipha.Lunye kuwo uhamboImpinda ayikho.Sinye kuwo isikhathiSifushane aseneleUbupigogo nobusakabuli buyaqedwaBushazwe yizangqotho nemishazo yomhlabaOmahlalothini abantengenyekayo ntengentengeBawe bhu bahuhuluze okwamahoboshaAbaqhwaklazela phezul' onontandakubukwaBaphendukтАЩizinqibi kugayingane imilomoOsemuva limshwibe shwi limbeke phambiliNgentobeko yobuphansi okwentuthaneUbe phansi nangenzolo ezothile yobuntu.1. Fingqa kafushane okushiwo yimbongi","answer":"Imbongi ithi ukuziqhenya nokuziphakamisa/ukuzithwalakomuntu kugcina kuphelile. Imbongi ithi ukuzikhukhumeza kwenza umuntu agcineejezisiwe ukuze afunde isifundo sokuthi kubalulekileukuzehlisa. Abaziphakamisayo bayathotshiswa bazithole sebebhuquzaphansi."},{"question":"Tunjukkan saya cara-cara menyediakan Bak Kut Teh yang halal dengan daging lembu dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan A: Herba bak kut teh-Dang shenTong DSum (Codonopdidi root)-You zhuYok cook (Solomon sealтАЩs rhizome)-Black dates-GojiWolf Berries-Chuan Xiong (Rhizoma ligustici)-Shu di huang/Lo sok tei (Rehmannia)-Star anise, clove, fennel seeds, peppercornBahan B: Daging lembu, 1 labu bawang putih yang tidak perlu dikupas dan diketuk. halia, cendawan shitake, sos tiram, kicap cair, sedikit kicap pekat, perasaCara memasak:1. Kesemua bahan-bahan dimasukkan sekali ke dalam periuk.2. Masak dengan api perlahan selama 1 jam lebih atau lagi bagus guna pressure cooker.3. Guna pressure cooker tak perlu masak lama. Set je bahagian daging, dalam 30 minit daging sudah empuk dan bahan-bahan herba tadi pun dah meresap ke seluruh daging.4. Sup siap dan boleh dimakan."},{"question":"р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢Жр╢┤р╖Кр╢нр╖Эр╢┤р╢пр╖Ър╖Бр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢Лр╢┤р╢пр╖Щр╖Гр╢п р╖Гр╢╕р╢Ь р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒.","answer":"р╢Ер╢╜р╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╖Фр╢лр╖П р╢╜р╖Пр╢╖ р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢╢р╖Рр╢╗р╖Т р╖Ар╖Цр╢пр╖Ъ р╢нр╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╢╜р╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╢Ър╖Тр╢лр╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢╢р╖Пр╢Ьр╢н р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╢╜р╖Рр╢╢р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢╜р╖Ьр╢Ър╖Фр╢╕ р╢Ер╖Ар╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║р╖Эр╢вр╢▒ р╢▒р╖Ьр╢Ьр╖Щр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Фр╖Ер╖Ф р╖Гр╖Фр╖Ер╖Ф р╢пр╖Ър╖Ар╢╜р╖К р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╢╜р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢н"},{"question":"Iza no tena anaran'ilay mpanao sarimihetsika mampihomehy Roy Chubby Brown ? ","answer":"I Royston Vasey no tena anaran'ilay mpanao sarimihetsika mampihomehy mitondra ny solon'anarana Roy Chubby Brown. "},{"question":"Idayari yami: impelasontoA uSenzoEkugcineni, usuku ebengilufisa seluze lwafika. NguMgqibelo namuhla futhi usuku lwami lokuzalwanjengoba ngineminyaka eyishumi nesithupha. Angilicelanga ikhekhe elibhakwe ekhaya kulokhukodwa abazali bami bangithengele yonke into engibacele yona тАУ angikholwa! Ngiyacabanga ukuthiudadewethu nomfowethu bese bekhathele yimi ngibaxoxela ngokuthi ngifisa lube njani lolu suku.Sekuphele amasonto amaningi ngilungiselela futhi ngicabanga ngalolu suku. Angikholwa ukuthiangilalanga ngicabanga ubumnandi esizoba nabo mina nabangane bami. Bonke abangane bamibangitshelile ukuthi bazofika ekhaya lami ngehora lokuqala. Ngiyathemba ukuthi abangane bamibangithengele izipho ezinhle. Ubani ngempela ongazithandi izipho.B uZandleLolu suku belulude kodwa futhi lube mnandi kakhulu. Abangane bami bangijabulise kakhulungokuzongihalalisela emva kokuphumelela emncintiswaneni wokugijima obungempelasontoedlule. Khona ngangingakholwa nami ukuthi yimi lo osekwazi ukugijima ibanga elide kangaka.Bengingakulindele ukuthi abangane bami bangihalalisele ngokungithelenga izinto eziningi kangaka.Noma ngingeyena umuntu othanda izipho kakhulu kodwa ngiyazi ukuthi uma uthola izipho lokhokukhombisa ukuthi abantu bakukhonzile. Mina kungenze ngaba namahloni kodwa ngabona futhiukuthi abangane bami bangithanda kangakanani. Angazi ukuthi yini engiyenzile ukuba ngifanelweukwenzelwa into enhle kangaka. Ngithole izinto eziningi kakhulu futhi ebengihlale ngifisa ukubanazo kodwa ebengingakabi nawo amandla okuzithengela zona. Ukuba nabangane abafana nalabakungikhumbuza izimfundiso zikamama wami zokuthi kubalulekile ukukhetha abangane abajabulanawe futhi bakweseke.C uMattAbantu abaningi bajwayele ukusho ukuthi abezwani nezingane zakubo. Bayaxabana njalo futhiabalekelelani. Lokhu kubi ngempela. Ngiyawuthanda umndeni wami. Senza izinto ezahlukene.Kwesinye isikhathi udadewethu uthanda ukulalela umculo ekamelweni lakhe kanti mina nomfowethusidlala ibhola. Sivame ukudlala umdlalo wamakhadi noma umdlalo webhodi ngempelasonto futhisiyahleka siphinde sikhale kwezinye izikhathi. Ngithemba ukuthi izingane zami ziyofana nathi. Nomasingefani, siyezwana kakhulu, futhi asithandi ukuxabana. Siyadumala uma oyeda wethu engaphilile.Nginesiqiniseko ukuthi ubaba nomama bayaziqhenya ngathi.D uKhethiweLolu bekuwusuku oluhle kimi. Ubaba wami ungisizile ukuthi sithenge yonke into engiyidingayoukubhaka ikhekhe futhi umama ungithembisile ukuthi uzongisiza uma esebuyile emsebenzini.Yisona sipho engizosipha umngane wami uSamantha. Ukubhaka kuyiyona ndlela engiziphumuzangayo nokuthatha ikhefu emsebenzini wami wesikole. Uthisha wami uthi kumele senze nezinyeizinto ngaphandle komsebenzi wesikole. Ukubhaka kungisize ukuba ngifunde ukuthi ezinye izintokumele zilindwe. Kumele ulandele iresiphi, ukuhlanganisa izithako, ulinde likhukhumale, ukulilindaliphole bese ulihlobisa bese uzwa ubumnandi. Ngiyazi umngane wami uzojabula ngoMsombulukouma esebona ngifika nekhekhe esikoleni.1.  owazimangaza ngokuphumelela kwakhe?","answer":"B"},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa sidda looga hortagi karo  kansarka ku dhaca mindhicirrada?","answer":"Hadii aad ku jirto┬а ama aad nolol maalmeedkaagu ku salaysanyahay qodobada dadka halista ugu jirah aan ku xusnay waxaad u┬а baahantahay in 2тАФ6 bilood inta udhaxaysa hal mar inaad fiirisid mindhiradaada. Sidaad u nooshahay waxay ka hortagi kartaah┬а darajada xanuunku uu kugu dhici karoh┬а tusaale ahaan┬аhadii aad isticmaasho cuntooyin isku dheeli tiran┬а subaxa canjeero ,duhurka khudaar habeenka cuntooyinka galka leh┬а┬аwaxay kaa fogaynaysaa ama aad kaga hortagaysaa darajada xanuunku uu kuugu dhici karoh.Jimicsigu waxa uu ka qayb-qaatah in caafimaadka mindhicirka weyn uu noqdo mid caafimaadkiisu uu aad u sareeyoh┬а ,biyo cabista badan iyo dhaqdhaqaaqa muruqyada ka sareeya mindhicirada waxa ay kor uqaadan in qashin badan laga saaro mindhicirada lagana hortago calool istaag.Miisaankaga ku ilaali┬а miisaan caafimaad qab ah 75kg.SIDEE LOO BAADHAA XANUUNKA.┬аTuunbo ku xidhantahay kamerad ayaa lagu dhaadhiciniyah qofka.Dhiig ayaa baadhitaan lagu samaynayah.DAAWAYN.Daawaynta ugu muhiimsan waa in laga jaraa mindhicirka halka uu kaga dhacay xanuunka kansarka.Daawooyinka kale dhakhaatiirta ayaa ka tashanaysa si xaaladiisa loogu lifaaqo.Hadii aad┬а halis ugu jirto xanuunkan hagaaji oo ka hortag xanuunka.Hadii aad calaamadaha┬а isku aragtay la xidhiidh sida ugu dhakhsiyaha badan┬а dhakhtar."},{"question":"р▓Тр▓Чр▓Яр▓ир│Нр▓ир│Б р▓мр▓┐р▓бр▓┐р▓╕р▓┐: р▓Кр▓Яр▓Хр│Нр▓Хр│Ж р▓Хр│Бр▓│р▓┐р▓др▓╡р▓░р│Б р▓╣р▓ир│Нр▓ир│Жр▓░р▓бр│Б р▓Ьр▓ир▓░р│Б, р▓мр▓бр▓┐р▓╕р│Бр▓╡р▓╡р▓░р│Б р▓Зр▓мр│Нр▓мр▓░р│Б, р▓Тр▓мр│Нр▓мр▓ир│Б р▓Тр▓мр│Нр▓мр▓░р▓┐р▓Чр│Ж р▓мр▓бр▓┐р▓╕р│Бр▓╡р▓╕р│Нр▓Яр▓░р▓▓р│Нр▓▓р▓┐ р▓Зр▓ир│Нр▓ир│Кр▓мр│Нр▓мр▓ир│Б р▓╣р▓ир│Нр▓ир│Жр▓░р▓бр│Б р▓Ьр▓ир▓Хр│Нр▓Хр│В р▓мр▓бр▓┐р▓╕р▓┐р▓░р│Бр▓др│Нр▓др▓╛р▓ир│Ж","answer":"р▓Чр▓бр▓┐р▓пр▓╛р▓░"},{"question":"рдорд░рд╛рдареНрдпрд╛рдВрдЪрд╛ рд╕рд░реНрд╡рд╢реНрд░реЗрд╖реНрда рд╕реЗрдирд╛рдкрддреА рдХреЛрдг рд╣реЛрддрд╛ ?","answer":"рдорд░рд╛рдареНрдпрд╛рдВрдЪрд╛ рд╕рд░реНрд╡рд╢реНрд░реЗрд╖реНрда рд╕реЗрдирд╛рдкрддреА рдмрд╛рдЬреАрд░рд╛рд╡ рдкреЗрд╢рд╡рд╛ рд╣реЛрддрд╛ ."},{"question":"хЬихКацЛ┐хдзя╝МчХ╢чЩ╝чФЯф║дщАЪцДПхдЦцЩВя╝Мф╗Ащ║╝цГЕц│Бф╕Лф╕АхоЪшжБха▒шнжя╝Я","answer":"цРНхд▒ш╢ЕщБО2000 цИЦцЬЙф║║хПЧхВ╖цИЦцн╗ф║б"},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana :  тАЬMankahala legioma maitso izy ireo.тАЭ sy \\"Tsy tian'izy ireo mihitsy ny legioma maitso.\\"Mifanindran-teny ve ireo ?","answer":"Eny, miresaka momban'ny tsy fitiavana legioma maintso ireo."},{"question":"K├н ni or├║kс╗Н g├│m├нn├а ├аkс╗Н╠Бkс╗Н╠Б n├н ├мp├нnlс║╣╠А Delta?","answer":"Felix Ibru ni."},{"question":"ркЕрк╣рлАркВ ркПркХ \\"рк╕рлМркерлА ркорлЛркЯрлБркВ ркИркирк╛рко\\" ркмрк╛рк│рк╡рк╛рк░рлНркдрк╛ ркирк╛ рк╢рк░рлВркЖркдркирк╛ рклркХрк░рк╛ рк▓ркЦрлЗрк▓рк╛ ркЫрлЗ:\\"ркПркХ рк╡рк░рлБ рк╣ркдрлБркВ. ркПркХ ркжрк┐рк╡рк╕ ркдрлЗ рк╢рк┐ркХрк╛рк░ ркХрк░рлАркирлЗ ркЦрк╛ркдрлБркВ рк╣ркдрлБркВ ркдрлНркпрк╛рк░рлЗ ркЙркдрк╛рк╡рк│ркорк╛ркВ ркдрлЗркирк╛ ркЧрк│рк╛ркорк╛ркВ ркирк╛ркирлБркВ рк╣рк╛ркбркХрлБркВ рклрк╕рк╛ркИ ркЧркпрлБркВ. ркПркгрлЗ рк╣рк╛ркбркХрк╛ркирлЗ ркмрк╣рк╛рк░ ркХрк╛ркврк╡рк╛ ркШркгрлА ркорк╣рлЗркиркд ркХрк░рлА рккркг рк╣рк╛ркбркХрлБркВ ркмрк╣рк╛рк░ ркирлАркХрк│рлНркпрлБркВ ркирк╣рк┐.ркдрлЗркирлЗ ркеркпрлБркВ ркХрлЗ ркЬрлЛ ркЖ рк╣рк╛ркбркХрлБркВ ркирк╣рк┐ ркирлАркХрк│рлЗ ркдрлЛ рк╣рлБркВ ркнрлВркЦ ркЕркирлЗ ркдрк░рк╕ркерлА ркорк░рлА ркЬркИрк╢! ркдрлЗ ркЬркВркЧрк▓ркирк╛ркВ ркмркзрк╛ркВ рккрлНрк░рк╛ркгрлАркирлЗ ркХрк╣рлЗрк╡рк╛ рк▓рк╛ркЧрлНркпрлБркВ, тАШркорк╛рк░рк╛ ркЧрк│рк╛ркорк╛ркВркерлА рк╣рк╛ркбркХрлБркВ ркХрк╛ркврлА ркЖрккрлЛ ркирлЗ?тАЩ рккркг ркмркзрк╛ркВ рккрлНрк░рк╛ркгрлАркУркП ркПркирлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ ркХрлЗ ркирк╛, ркЕркорлЗ ркирк╣рк┐ ркХрк╛ркврлА ркЖрккрлАркП.рк╡рк░рлБркирлЗ ркЧрк│рк╛ркорк╛ркВ ркЦрлВркм ркЬ ркжрлБркГркЦрк╡рк╛ рк▓рк╛ркЧрлНркпрлБркВ. ркдрлЗ ркмрк░рк╛ркбрк╛ рккрк╛ркбркдрлБркВ ркиркжрлА ркХрк┐ркирк╛рк░рлЗ ркЖрк╡рлА рккрк╣рлЛркВркЪрлНркпрлБркВ. ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ ркПркХ ркмркЧрк▓рлЛ ркКркнрлЛ рк╣ркдрлЛ.\\"ркЖ рк╡рк╛рк░рлНркдрк╛ ркирлЗ рккрлБрк░рлА ркХрк░рлЛ.","answer":"рк╡рк░рлБркП ркмркЧрк▓рк╛ркирлЗ ркХрк╣рлНркпрлБркВ,тАШркмркЧрк▓рк╛ркнрк╛ркИ, ркорк╛рк░рк╛ ркЧрк│рк╛ркорк╛ркВ рклрк╕рк╛ркпрлЗрк▓ рк╣рк╛ркбркХрлБркВ ркХрк╛ркврлА ркЖрккрлЛ, рк╣рлБркВ ркдркоркирлЗ ркорлЛркЯрлБркВ ркИркирк╛рко ркЖрккрлАрк╢.тАЩрк╡рк░рлБ рккрлЛркдрк╛ркирлБркВ ркорлЛркВ ркЦрк▓рлНрк▓рлБркВ рк░рк╛ркЦрлАркирлЗ ркмрлЗркарлЛ рк╣ркдрлЛ. ркмркЧрк▓рк╛ркнрк╛ркИркП ркИркирк╛ркоркирлА рк▓рк╛рк▓ркЪрлЗ рк╡рк░рлБркирк╛ ркорлЛркВркорк╛ ркдрлЗркирлА ркЪрк╛ркВркЪ ркирк╛ркЦрлА ркЦрлВркм ркорк╣рлЗркиркд ркХрк░рлАркирлЗ рк╡рк░рлБркирк╛ ркЧрк│рк╛ркорк╛ркВркерлА рк╣рк╛ркбркХрлБркВ ркмрк╣рк╛рк░ ркХрк╛ркврлНркпрлБркВ. рк╡рк░рлБркирлЗ рк░рк╛рк╣ркд ркеркИ.ркмркЧрк▓рлЛ ркХрк╣рлЗ, тАШрк╡рк░рлБркнрк╛ркИ, ркоркирлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлБркВ ркИркирк╛рко ркЖрккрлА ркжрлЛ.тАЩрк╡рк░рлБ ркШрлВрк░ркХрлНркпрлЛ, тАШркЕрк▓рлНркпрк╛ ркмркЧрк▓рк╛! ркдрлБркВ ркИркирк╛ркоркерлА рк╡рк╛ркд ркнрлВрк▓рлА ркЬрк╛. ркорк╛рк░рк╛ ркорлЛркВркорк╛ркВркерлА ркХрлЛркИ ркмркЪрлНркпрлБркВ ркЫрлЗ ркЦрк░рлБркВ? ркдрк╛рк░рлА ркбрлЛркХ ркорк╛рк░рк╛ ркорлЛркорк╛ркВ рк╣ркдрлА ркдрлЛркп рк╣рлБркВ ркдркирлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлАркирлЗ ркЦрк╛ркИ рки ркЧркпрлЛ ркПркЯрк▓рлЗ ркдрк╛рк░рлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлЛ ркЖркнрк╛рк░ ркорк╛ркирк╡рлЛ ркЬрлЛркИркП. ркдрлБркВ ркмркЪрлА ркЧркпрлЛ ркЫрлЗ, ркЖркерлА рк╡ркзрлБ рк╕рк╛рк░рлБркВ ркИркирк╛рко рк╣рлБркВ ркдркирлЗ ркмрлАркЬрлБркВ рк╢рлБркВ ркЖрккрлБркВ, ркмрлЛрк▓?тАЩркмркЧрк▓рлЛ рк╢рлБркВ ркмрлЛрк▓рлЗ? ркорлЛркВ рк╡ркХрк╛рк╕рлАркирлЗ ркмрлЗрк╕рлА рк░рк╣рлНркпрлЛ. рк▓рлБркЪрлНркЪрлБркВ рк╡рк░рлБ ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВркерлА рк╣рк╕ркдрлБркВ рк╣рк╕ркдрлБркВ ркЬркдрлБркВ рк░рк╣рлНркпрлБркВ."},{"question":"Jox ma p├йeteg waat yi ci k├аddu gii: ├Сent (4) i n├йew la'├▒ y├│bbu fa c├╣uruur u D├аlal J├аmm bu G├йejawaay ginnaaw ├▒axtu yi ├аm ci r├йew mi.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci k├аddu gii di \\"├Сent (4) i n├йew la'├▒ y├│bbu fa c├╣uruur u D├аlal J├аmm bu G├йejawaay ginnaaw ├▒axtu yi ├аm ci r├йew mi.\\" ak s├йen i p├йete ├▒oo di:├Сent: NUM(: PUNCT4: NUM): PUNCTi: ADPn├йew: NOUNla: AUX'├▒: PRONy├│bbu: VERBfa: ADVc├╣uruur: NOUNu: ADPD├аlal: NOUNJ├аmm: NOUNbu: PRONG├йejawaay: PROPNginnaaw: ADP├▒axtu: NOUNyi: PRON├аm: ADJci: ADPr├йew: NOUNmi: DET.: PUNCT"},{"question":"╪з┘Д╪│╪д╪з┘Д: ┘Е┘Ж ┘З┘И ╪з┘Д┘Ж╪и┘К ╪з┘Д┘Е┘Д┘В╪и ╪и╪▒┘И╪н ╪з┘Д┘Д┘З╪Я","answer":"╪з┘Д╪е╪м╪з╪и╪й: ╪╣┘К╪│┘Й ╪╣┘Д┘К┘З ╪з┘Д╪│┘Д╪з┘Е."},{"question":"Enunciado 1: Imagica y Robot Communications fundaron Imagica Robot Holdings Inc. el 1 de abril de 2004 e Imagica se volvi├│ parte de esta compa├▒├нa.Enunciado 2: El 1 de abril de 2004, Imagica y Robot Communications coestablecieron Imagica Robot Holdings Inc., e Imagica se volvi├│ parte de esta compa├▒├нa.Pregunta: ┬┐El Enunciado 1 expresa el mismo significado al Enunciado 2? Responde S├н o No a la pregunta.","answer":"S├н, el Enunciado 1 tiene el mismo significado al Enunciado 2."},{"question":"р╢пр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Ър╖Ар╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖Кр╢п?","answer":"р╢пр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Ър╖Ар╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢║, р╢пр╖Ър╖Ар╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╖Бр╖Пр╢Ыр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╖Гр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╢┤р╖Рр╖Др╖Рр╢пр╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╢Ер╖Ар╢╢р╖Эр╢░р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╢╢р╖П р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢пр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕ р╢Лр╢┤р╢║р╖Эр╢Ьр╖У р╢Ър╢╗ р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Т. р╖Гр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╢Ър╢╗р╖П р╢╜р╢Яр╖П р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П р╢пр╢╗р╢▒ р╢Лр╢нр╖Кр╖Гр╖Др╢║р╢з р╢пр╖Ър╖Ар╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢║ р╖Др╖П р╢пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢▒р╢║ р╢║р╢▒ р╢пр╖Щр╢Ър╢╕ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢п, р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Др╖Ьр╢нр╖К р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╢╕р╢║ р╢Ср╖Ер╖Тр╢пр╢╗р╖Ар╖Кр╖А р╢нр╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╢╕ р╢┤р╖Рр╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢п р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Пр╢п р╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖У. р╢пр╖Ър╖Ар╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╖Ар╖Пр╢пр╖У р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ър╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╖Ар╢╜р╢з р╢пр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢▒р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕р╢║ р╢Ър╖Щр╢нр╢╗р╢╕р╖К р╢┤р╖Фр╖Ер╖Фр╢╜р╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢║р╖Ьр╢пр╖П р╢Ьр╢н р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Фр╢п р╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│р╖А р╢╗р╢зр╖Ар╢╜р╖К р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢░ р╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢нр╖Тр╢╢р╖Ъ. р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗р╖Ф р╢┤р╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ср╢╕ р╢Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢лр╖Ф р╢пр╖Щр╢Ъ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ъ р╖Гр╢╕р╢Я р╢Ър╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢╕ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢╢р╖Ар╢║р╖Т. р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖КтАНр╢║р╢╕р╢║ р╢Ср╖Ер╖Тр╢пр╢╗р╖Ар╖Кр╖А р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П р╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╖Рр╢╗р╢пр╖Тр╖А р╖Ар╢зр╖Др╖П р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢▒р╢║ р╖Др╖П р╢нр╢╗р╖Кр╢Ър╢║ р╢Ер╖Ар╖Бр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╢╢р╖А р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗р╖Ф р╢┤р╖Ар╖Гр╢нр╖Т. р╢нр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗р╖Ф р╢пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢▒р╖Ар╖Пр╢пр╢║ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║р╖Эр╢вр╢лр╖Ар╢нр╖К р╢╕р╖Щр╖Ар╢╜р╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢▒р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢Ср╢║ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢┤р╖Цр╢╗р╖Кр╢лр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╗р╢│р╖П р╢▒р╖Ьр╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╢┤р╖Ар╖Гр╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╕р╢░р╖КтАНр╢║р╖Гр╖Кр╢о р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ар╖Ър╖Бр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ьр╢▒р╖Тр╢нр╖Т. р╢пр╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╖Бр╢лр╖Тр╢Ъ р╢пр╖Ър╖Ар╢░р╢╗р╖Кр╢╕р╢║ р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╖Рр╢╗р╢пр╖Т р╢Жр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢║р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╖Э р╖Ар╖Рр╢╗р╢пр╖Т р╢Жр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢║р╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╢Ър╖Е р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢╕р╖Щр╖Ар╢╜р╢╕р╢Ър╖Т. р╢Ср╢║ р╢ар╖Ър╢нр╢▒р╖Пр╖А р╖Др╖П р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕р╖Фр╢Ыр╢нр╖Пр╖Ар╢║ р╢┤р╖Тр╖Ер╖Тр╢╢р╢│ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Бр╖Кр╢лр╢║р╢Ър╖Т: р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Пр╢пр╢▒р╢╜р╢п р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖К р╢╕р╢▒р╖П р╖Ар╖Тр╖Бр╖Кр╖Ар╖Пр╖Гр╢║ р╢нр╢╢р╖П р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Пр╢╗р╖Кр╢Ь р╖Гр╖Д р╖Гр╖Тр╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╢нр╖Ър╢╗р╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Ер╢┤ р╢Лр╢нр╖Кр╖Гр╖Д р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К, р╢Ер╢┤ р╢╢р╢╜р╖Пр╢┤р╖Ьр╢╗р╖Ьр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ф р╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Ф р╢Зр╢н. р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖Тр╖Гр╖П р╢╢р╖Пр╢╢р╖Щр╢╜р╖К р╢Ър╖Фр╖Ер╖Фр╢лр╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Тр╢з р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Щр╢н р╖Ер╢Яр╖П р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╖А р╢Фр╢┤р╖Кр╢┤р╖Ф р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Лр╢нр╖Кр╖Гр╖Д р╢Ър╢╗р╢║р╖Т. р╢▒р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ър╢╕р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Др╢▒р╖Кр╖Гр╖Ър╖А р╖Др╢│р╖Фр╢▒р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕р╖Ъ р╢Жр╖Бр╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Щр╖Ер╢╣р╖У р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢▒р╢╕р╖К, р╢Ер╢┤р╖Т р╢Ер╢┤р╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╕р╢▒р╖Г р╖Ар╢йр╖Пр╢нр╖К р╖Др╖Ьр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╢Ър╢╗р╢╕р╖Ф."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"belum tuarang panjang, buah sengkuang sebesar betis\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud khabar angin yang dilebih-lebihkan."},{"question":"Qeex koox? ","answer":"Koox waa dad badan oo meel iskugu imaaday."},{"question":"родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роорпБроХрпНроХроЯро▓рпН роЪроЩрпНроХрооро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЗроЯроорпН  роОродрпБ?","answer":"родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роорпБроХрпНроХроЯро▓рпН роЪроЩрпНроХрооро┐роХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЗроЯроорпН  роХройрпНройро┐ропро╛роХрпБрооро╛ро░ро┐. роХройрпНройро┐ропро╛роХрпБрооро░ро┐ рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН родрооро┐ро┤рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯро┐ройрпН роорпБрокрпНрокродрпНродро┐ роОроЯрпНроЯрпБ рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроЩрпНроХро│ро┐ро▓рпН роТройрпНро▒ро╛роХрпБроорпН. роЗроирпНродро┐ропро╛ро╡ро┐ройрпН родрпЖройрпНроХрпЛроЯро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБро│рпНро│ роЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИроироХро░роорпН роиро╛роХро░рпНроХрпЛро╡ро┐ро▓рпН роЖроХрпБроорпН. роЗроирпНрод рооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯроорпН 1,672 роЪ.роХро┐.роорпА. рокро░рокрпНрокро│ро╡рпИроХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ. роЗроорпНрооро╛ро╡роЯрпНроЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родрооро┐ро┤рпН рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН рооро▓рпИропро╛ро│ роорпКро┤ро┐роХро│рпН рокрпЗроЪрокрпНрокроЯрпБроХро┐ройрпНро▒рой."},{"question":"* ┘Е╪з ╪╣╪п╪п ╪г╪м┘Ж╪н╪й ╪з┘Д╪и╪▒╪║┘И╪л╪Я","answer":"┘Д╪з ┘К┘И╪м╪п ╪г╪м┘Ж╪н╪й ╪и┘Д ┘К┘Е╪┤┘К ┘В┘Б╪▓╪з┘Л."},{"question":"\\"Nahazo fanomezana tsy fantatra anarana teo am-baravarako aho nandritra ny fialantsasatra:\\"Inona no mety ho fiafaran'ny tantara teo aloha?A. Fihetseham-po avy amin'ny mpankafy miafina ilay fanomezana.B. Fifangaroana fanaterana ilay izy, ary natao ho an'ny jiosy ilay fanomezana","answer":"A. no fiafarana azo inoana indrindra."},{"question":"\\"╨Р╨╝╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤З╤Г ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜!\\"- ╨┤╨╡╨│╨╡╨╜ ╤Л╤А ╨║╨╕╨╝╨│╨╡ ╤В╨░╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║?","answer":"╨Ч╨░╤А╤Л╨╗╨▒╨╡╨║ ╨Р╨╢╤Л╨╝╨░╤В╨╛╨▓ ╨│╨╛ ╤В╨░╨░╨╜╨┤╤Л╨║.╨Р╨Ь╨Р╨Э ╨С╨Ю╨Ы╨з╨г, ╨Ъ╨л╨а╨У╨л╨Ч╨б╨в╨Р╨Э!╨Ъ╨░╨│╤Л╨╗╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜ ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜, ╨║╨░╨│╤Л╨╗╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜,╨Ъ╨░╨╣╤А╨░╤В╤В╨░╨╜╤Л╨┐ ╨║╨░╤А╤Г╤Г╥г╨┤╤Г ╨╢╨░╥г╤Л╨╗╨░╨│╤Л╨╜.╨Ъ╨░╨╜╤Л╨╝, ╨╢╨░╨╜╤Л╨╝ ╨┤╨░╤А╤В╤Л╥г╨░ ╤И╤Л╨┐╨░╨░ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛,╨Ъ╨░╨╜╨░╤В╤Л╥г╨┤╤Л ╤Б╤Г╨╜ ╨╝╨░╨│╨░, ╨┤╨░╤А╤Л╨╗╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜.╙и╨╗╨▒╙й ╙й╨╗╨║╙й╨╝, ╨▒╨░╨╗╨░╨┐╨░╨╜ ╨╢╨░╤И ╤З╨░╨│╤Л╥г╨┤╨░,╙и╨╗╙й╨╗╥п ╨▒╨╕╨╖ ╨║╨░╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╤З╨░ ╨░╤А╤В ╨╢╨░╨│╤Л╥г╨┤╨░.╨г╤П╨╗╨░╤И╤В╨░╤А, ╨░╨╖╨┤╨╡╨║╤В╨╡╨┐ ╨║╨░╤А╨╡╨│╨╕╥г╨┤╨╡╨╣,╨г╤А╨┐╨░╨║╤В╨░╤А╨│╨░ ╨╝╨╡╨║╨╡╨╜╨┤╨╕ ╤Б╨░╨║╤В╨░╨│╤Л╨╗╨░.╨Ц╨░╤А╨░ ╤В╨░╤А╤В╨░╤А ╨▒╙й╤А╥п ╨║╙й╨┐ ╨╢╨░╨╜-╨╢╨░╨│╤Л╥г╨┤╨░,╨Ц╥п╨║ ╨▒╨░╤А ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨╡╨╝ ╨╛╨┐╨╛╨╗ ╤В╨╛╨╛ ╨░╨╣ ╨┤╨░╨╗╤Л╥г╨┤╨░.╨н╨╗╨┤╨╕ ╨░╤П, ╨║╨╡╤А╨╡╨╝╨╡╤В ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜╤Л╨╝,╨н╤Б╤Б╨╕╨╖ ╤З╤Л╨║╤В╤Л ╨▒╨╡╨║╤В╨╡╤А╨╕╥г, ╤Е╨░╨╜╨┤╨░╤А╤Л╥г ╨┤╨░╨Ц╥п╤А╙й╨│╥п╥г╨┤╥п ╨╢╨╡╨▒╨╡╨┤╨╡╨╣ ╨║╙й╨╖╙й╨┐ ╙й╤В╤В╥п╨║,╨Ц╥п╨┤╙й╙й ╨║╤Л╨╗╨┤╤Л╨║, ╙й╨╣╨┤╙й-╤Л╨╗╨┤╤Л╨╣ ╨║╙й╨╝╙й╨╗╙й╤В╤В╥п╨║.╨Ь╤Л╤Б╨║╤Л╨╗ ╨║╤Л╨╗╤Л╨┐ ╨┤╤Г╤И╨╝╨░╨╜╨│╨░ ╨▒╤Г╨╗ ╨┤╨╛╨╛╤А╨┤╨╛,╨Ь╤Л╤А╨╖╨░ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤З╤Г╥г, ╨▒╨╕╨╖ ╤Б╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╤З╙й╨│╙й╨╗╙й╤В╤В╥п╨║..╨л╨╜╤В╤Л╨╝╨░╨║╤Б╤Л╨╖ ╨║╥п╤З╤В╙й╤А╨┤╙й╨╜ ╨░╤А╤Л╨┤╤Л╥г╨▒╤Л,╨л╨╣╨╗╨░╨┐ ╤В╤Г╤А╨░╨╝, ╙й╤З╥п╤А╨▒╙й ╨╢╨░╤А╤Л╨│╤Л╥г╨┤╤Л.╨Р╨╗╨░-╨в╨╛╨╛╨╝, ╨▒╨╕╨╖ ╤Б╨╡╨╜╨╕ ╨╢╤Л╤А╨│╨░╤В╨┐╨░╨┤╤Л╨║,╨Р╥г╨║╨░╤П╨▒╤Л╨╖ ╨▒╨╕╨╗╨▒╨╡╤Б╤В╨╡╨╜ ╨║╨░╨┤╤Л╤А╤Л╥г╨┤╤Л.╨Р╨╣╨╗╨░╨╜╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜, ╨Ъ╤Л╤А╨│╤Л╨╖╤Б╤В╨░╨╜, ╨░╨╣╨╗╨░╨╜╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜,╨Р╤Б╨║╨░ - ╤В╨╛╨╛╥г╨┤╤Г ╨║╤Г╤З╨░╨║╤В╨░╨┐ ╨░╨╣╨╝╨░╨╗╨░╨╣╤Л╨╜.╙и╤З╙й ╨║╙й╤А╨▒╙й, ╨║╨░╤А╤В╨░╨┤╨░╨╜ ╙й╤З╙й ╨║╙й╤А╨▒╙й,╨Ъ╨░╤В╨░╤А╤Л╨╜ ╤В╥п╨║ ╨▒╤Г╨╖╨▒╨░╤Б╤Л╨╜ ╤В╨░╨╝╨│╨░╨╗╨░╤А╤Л╥г.╨С╥п╤В╥п╨╜ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Г╨┐ ╨┤╨░╨╣╤Л╨╝╨░ ╤В╤Г╤А╤Г╤Г╥г ╨║╨╡╤А╨╡╨║,╨Р ╨╝╨╡╨╜ ╤Б╨░╨│╨░ ╤Л╤А╤Л╨╝╨┤╤Л ╤Б╤Г╨╜╤Г╤Г╨╝ ╨║╨╡╤А╨╡╨║.╨С╨╕╨╖╨┤╨╕ ╨║╨╡╤З╨╕╤А, ╨Р╤В╨░ ╨╢╤Г╤А╤В, ╨░╨╝╨░╨╜ ╨▒╨╛╨╗╤Б╨╛╥г,╨С╨╕╤А ╨┤╨╛╨╛╤А╨┤╨╛ ╤Б╨╡╨╜ ╨║╥п╤В╨║╙й╨╜ ╨╝╤Г╤Г╨╜ ╨║╨╡╨╗╨╡╤В. "},{"question":"┘Е╪з ┘З┘К ╪╣╪з╪╡┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д╪│┘И┘К╪п╪Я","answer":"╪╣╪з╪╡┘Е╪й ╪з┘Д╪│┘И┘К╪п ┘З┘К ╪│╪к┘И┘Г┘З┘И┘Д┘Е ┘И┘З┘К ╪г┘Г╪и╪▒ ┘Е╪п┘К┘Ж╪й ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪и┘Д╪з╪п."},{"question":"Kayan Aiki yin Sussukar ?","answer":"Turmi da Ta╔Уarya: Su ne muhimman kayan aikin sussuka, ana zuba dukkan abin da ake son casawa a cikin turmi sai kuma a ri╞Щa bugunsa da ta╔Уarya har sai an cire asalin ╞Щwayar daga jikin abin da ba a so.Babbar tabarma: Akan zuba abin da ake casawa a kai. Sannan kuma wasu lokutan akan yi sussukar a kan tabarmar ta hanyar bugu.Masaki: Ana zuba sussukakken abu a ciki.╞Шwarya: Kamar masaki take, sai dai girmanta bai kai na masaki ba. Da ita ake yin shi╞Щa (shi╞Щa ita ce cire ╞Щai╞Щayi ko kwanso daga cikin asalin ╞Щwayar abin da aka sussuka ta hanyar ╔Чaga abin sama ana juyewa a cikin ╞Щwaryar da ke ╞Щasa, idan iska ta ratsa tsakani sai ta kore ╞Щai╞Щayin ya fice daga cikin ╞Щwayar).Faifai: Ana tanka╔Чe sauran abin da bai she╞Щu ba domin a cire abubuwan da ba a so kamar tsakuwa wacce ita bata she╞Щuwa.Sanda: Dogon ita ce ne mai kauri da kuma ╞Щarfi. Da shi ake bugu idan ba a turmi za a yi casar ba."},{"question":"┘Г┘К┘Б┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪к╪│╪м┘К┘Д ┘Д┘Д╪н╪╡┘И┘Д ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪н╪│╪з╪и ╪к┘И┘К╪к╪▒ ╪и╪з╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ╪м┘И╪м┘Д","answer":"1. ╪з╪░┘З╪и ╪е┘Д┘Й ┘Е┘И┘В╪╣ ╪к┘И┘К╪к╪▒ ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д╪е┘Ж╪к╪▒┘Ж╪к2. ╪з┘Ж┘В╪▒ ╪╣┘Д┘Й ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к╪з╪и╪╣╪й ╪и╪е╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ╪м┘И╪м┘Д3. ╪│┘К╪╕┘З╪▒ ┘Д┘Г ┘Е╪▒╪и╪╣ ╪з╪о╪к┘К╪з╪▒ ╪н╪│╪з╪и4. ╪з╪о╪к╪▒ ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к╪з╪и╪╣╪й ╪и╪з╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ╪н╪│╪з╪и ╪м┘И╪м┘Д 5.╪е╪░╪з ┘Д┘Е ┘К╪╕┘З╪▒ ┘Д┘Г ╪з┘Д╪н╪│╪з╪и ╪з┘Д╪░┘К ╪к╪▒╪║╪и ┘Б┘К ╪з╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е┘З ╪з┘Ж┘В╪▒ ┘Б┘И┘В ╪е╪╢╪з┘Б╪й ╪н╪│╪з╪и"},{"question":"O с╣гoju mi koro (Apa Kin-in-ni)","answer":"Olori ilс║╣ wa, с╗Мgagun agba Muhammadu Buhari, lс╗Н si orilс║╣-ede Mali, lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja. Ohun pataki kan naa lo tori с║╣ lс╗Н, o lс╗Нс╗Н ba wс╗Нn pari ija lс╗Нhun-un ni. Ko pada yaayan lс║╣nu pe wс╗Нn ko rija naa pari, koda, abuku ni wс╗Нn sс╗Н pe o kan Buhari nibс║╣, nitori ko si с║╣ni to ka с╗Нrс╗Н rс║╣ si kinni kan laarin awс╗Нn olori ijс╗Нba to ku. с╗Мrс╗Н yii ko le с╣гe ko ma ri bс║╣с║╣, с║╣ni ti yoo ba niyi nita, ile ni yoo ti niyi lс╗Н. с╣вugbс╗Нn Aarс║╣ tiwa nigbagbс╗Н pe ita loun yoo ti maa niyi wa sile nitori bс║╣с║╣, awс╗Нn ohun to ba jс║╣ ti araata ni yoo mura lati ba wс╗Нn da si, ti yoo si fi ina buruku to n jo loriс╣гiiriс╣гii ni ile tirс║╣ silс║╣. Nigba ti Buhari n lс╗Н si Mali yii, o lo ibomu-bс║╣nu lati bo imu ati с║╣nu rс║╣, Naijiria nibi lo si ti gbe kinni naa lс╗Н. Lara ohun ti awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn n gbogun ti arun Korona yii kari aye sс╗Н naa ni pe lati ma jс║╣ ki arun yii gbilс║╣, afi ki gbogbo с║╣ni to ba fс║╣с║╣ jade sita, tabi to ba fс║╣с║╣ gbalejo, tabi ti yoo ba wa laarin eeyan meji mс║╣ta, lo ibomu-bс║╣nu. с╣вugbс╗Нn lati с╗Нjс╗Н ti Buhari ti n jade ni Naijiria, tabi to n ba awс╗Нn eeyan sс╗Нrс╗Н, ko lo kinnni naa ri. Boya lo si mс╗Н pe ohun to n с╣гe yii ni с╗Нpс╗Н awс╗Нn alaс╣гс║╣ ilu n с╣гe, ti с╗Нgс╗Нс╗Нrс╗Н eeyan nilс║╣ Hausa n с╣гe, oun ni wс╗Нn n fara we, nigba ti oun to jс║╣ olori ilu ko с╣гe bс║╣с║╣, kin ni araalu yoo maa с╣гe bс║╣с║╣ si. Iye oku to nikan sun ni ilс║╣ Hausa, agaga ni Kano ati Katsina, wс╗Нn ko с╣гee ka niye tan bayii o. Lojoojumс╗Н, iku ni. Kin ni Buhari ri с╣гe si iru nnkan bayii. Tabi eleyii ko to ohun to n dс║╣ru ba olori ijс╗Нba ni. Awс╗Нn olori ologun to yс║╣ ko ri si iru nnkan bayii, gbogbo wс╗Нn lo ti rс║╣, gbogbo aye lo si n pariwo pe ki Buhari paarс╗Н wс╗Нn, с╣гugbс╗Нn Buhari ko с╣гe bii с║╣ni pe oun gbс╗Н, bo tilс║╣ jс║╣ pe awс╗Нn eeyan naa ko wulo fun Naijiria mс╗Н. Ninu awс╗Нn minisita ati awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn n ba a с╣гejс╗Нba, ija buruku to n lс╗Н laarin wс╗Нn ko с╣гee gbс╗Н, wс╗Нn aa ma с╣гe tanadi ara wс╗Нn debii pe iс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba to yс║╣ ko lс╗Н deede ko ni i lс╗Н deede, ipalara oriс╣гiiriс╣гii lo si n lс╗Н. Buhari to ni oun yoo gbogun ti iwa ibajс║╣, iwa ibajс║╣ to wa ninu ijс╗Нba tirс║╣ funra rс║╣ ju eyi ti a ti n ba bс╗Н latс║╣yin lс╗Н. Awс╗Нn ohun to yс║╣ ki Buhari moju to gbogbo ree nile, awс╗Нn ohun to yс║╣ ki awс╗Нn oludamс╗Нran с║╣ ba a sс╗Н niyi! Tabi kin ni iс╣гс║╣ awс╗Нn to n gba Buhari nimс╗Нran! Bo ba si jс║╣ oun ni ko gbс╗Н amс╗Нran wс╗Нn, ki wс╗Нn fi iс╣гс║╣ rс║╣ silс║╣, ki aye le mс╗Н ibi ti wс╗Нn yoo doju с╗Нrс╗Н wс╗Нn kс╗Н. с║╕ gba a nimс╗Нran tootс╗Н, с║╣ jс║╣ ko mс╗Н pe с║╣ni ti ko ba niyi ninu ile с║╣, ko ni i niyi nita o!Iwa ibajс║╣ inu ijс╗Нba yii le debii pe awс╗Нn с║╣gbe oс╣гelu PDP pe lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja pe ki Buhari kс╗Нwe fi ipo rс║╣ silс║╣, nitori apa rс║╣ ko ka igbogun ti iwa ibajс║╣ yii mс╗Н rara, ati ki awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn n kowo jс║╣ ma wo Naijiria yii mс╗Н gbogbo wa lori. Loootс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ PDP naa ki i с╣гe с║╣ni ti eeyan n ka с╗Нrс╗Н wс╗Нn si, nitori awс╗Нn naa ko kuku san to ba di ibi owo-kikojс║╣, с╣гugbс╗Нn awс╗Нn ohun to с╣гс║╣lс║╣ lasiko yii ko le jс║╣ ki eeyan ko с╗Нrс╗Н wс╗Нn danu patapata. с║╕ jс║╣ ka fi с╗Нrс╗Н Magu ati Malami silс║╣ sс║╣gbс║╣с║╣ kan, с║╣ jс║╣ ka wo ohun to n с╣гс║╣lс║╣ nileeс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba ti wс╗Нn da silс║╣ fun idagbasoke agbegbe Naija-Delta, iyс║╣n NNDC (Niger Delta Development Commission). Awс╗Нn owo ti wс╗Нn ni wс╗Нn ko jс║╣ to foju han, ati awс╗Нn с╗Нrс╗Н aс╣гiwere ti wс╗Нn kс╗Н siwee nipa bi wс╗Нn с╣гe nawo naa jс║╣ ohun ti ko le mu orukс╗Н orilс║╣-ede yii ni iyi kan lс║╣yin odi rara. Lasiko ti Korona mu gbogbo eeyan yii, ti ijс╗Нba с╣гofin pe ki с║╣nikс║╣ni ma jade, ileeс╣гс║╣ yii si kс╗Н с╗Н sinu iwe wс╗Нn pe awс╗Нn fi milс╗Нnu с╗Нtalelс║╣gbс║╣ta o din mс║╣rin naira (N656m) с╣гe idanilс║╣kс╗Нс╗Н fawс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ awс╗Нn. Lasiko Korona! Awс╗Нn oс╣гiс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn ko lс╗Н sibi iс╣гс║╣ o, awс╗Нn kan kan jokoo sibi kan, wс╗Нn si ko owo naa jс║╣, wс╗Нn si gbe e sinu iwe bс║╣с║╣, pс║╣lu igbagbс╗Н pe ko sс║╣ni ti yoo yс║╣ awс╗Нn lс╗Нwс╗Н wo. Awс╗Нn owo ti wс╗Нn с╣гс║╣ si minisita wс╗Нn, Godswill Akpabio, lс╗Нrun ki i с╣гe kekere, o si daju pe с╗Нkunrin naa ti inu PDP waa kowo jс║╣ ninu ijс╗Нba APC yii ni. с║╕ni ti wс╗Нn fi с╣гe olori ileeс╣гс║╣ yii, nigba ti с╗Нrс╗Н da bayii, ti awс╗Нn aс╣гofin ni ko waa rojс╗Н ohun to mс╗Н, o kuku wa sibс║╣ o. с╣вugbс╗Нn ibeere с║╣yс╗Н kan ni wс╗Нn bi i, n lo ba daku pata. Ko si ji saye ti wс╗Нn fi gbe e jade, igba to jade lo ji saye pada. Akpabio ti wс╗Нn pe ko waa rojс╗Н naa dewaju awс╗Нn aс╣гofin, o si sс╗Н с╗Н loju wс╗Нn nibс║╣ pe gbogbo owo ti wс╗Нn n sс╗Нrс╗Н с║╣ pe o sс╗Нnu yii, pupс╗Н wa lс╗Нwс╗Н awс╗Нn aс╣гofin gan-an funra wс╗Нn, nitori awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н ile-igbimс╗Н naa gba iс╣гс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н NNDC ti wс╗Нn ko si с╣гe e, wс╗Нn si ti gbowo с║╣. N lawс╗Нn aс╣гofin ba binu, wс╗Нn ni ko maa lс╗Н. Meloo leeyan waa fс║╣с║╣ ka ninu iwa ibajс║╣ to n lс╗Н nileeс╣гс║╣ kan с╣гoс╣гo. Gbogbo wa la n pariwo pe ijс╗Нba ko ran awс╗Нn ara Naija Delta, nibi ti wс╗Нn ti n wa epo bс║╣ntiroolu ni Naijiria lс╗Нwс╗Н, с╣гugbс╗Нn awс╗Нn aс╣гiri to jade yii n fi han pe awс╗Нn oloс╣гelu Naija Delta gan-an lс╗Нta awс╗Нn eeyan wс╗Нn. с╣вugbс╗Нn Buhari lo yan awс╗Нn araabi yii sipo, с╣гe bi yoo с╣гe waa maa wo wс╗Нn niran ti wс╗Нn yoo ba aye jс║╣, ti wс╗Нn yoo tun ba с╗Нrun jс║╣ ree, ti wс╗Нn yoo si sс╗Н Naijiria di ilu oniyс║╣yс║╣ laarin awс╗Нn orilс║╣-ede aye gbogbo. Ko si ohun to n jс║╣ ki awс╗Нn eeyan yii mura si ole jija ju pe ijс╗Нba wa ki i с╣гe nnkan kan fun wс╗Нn, paapaa ti wс╗Нn ba ti jс║╣ с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu wс╗Нn tabi ti wс╗Нn ba sun mс╗Н Aarс║╣ funra rс║╣. Ohun to n ba gbogbo с║╣ jс║╣ ree o. с║╕ bс║╣ Buahri ko ma с╣гe bii с║╣ni pe oun ko gbс╗Н с╗Нrс╗Н awс╗Нn akowojс║╣ wс╗Нnyi, ko jс║╣ ki wс╗Нn ju wс╗Нn sс║╣wс╗Нn, ki Naijiria le sinmi.Ismail Issa Funtua, с╗Нkan ninu awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn sun mс╗Н Buhari ju lс╗Н ku lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja yii. Bo ti ku laaarс╗Н ni wс╗Нn ti palс║╣ oku с║╣ mс╗Н, koda, wс╗Нn ko rс║╣ ibi ti wс╗Нn sin in si, wс╗Нn kan ko yeepс║╣ le e lori lasan ni. Bс║╣с║╣ ni baba naa lс╗Н. с╣вugbс╗Нn ninu awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn lu с╗Нmс╗Н Naijiria ni jibiti to pс╗Н ju lс╗Н laye yii, с╗Нkan ni Issa Funtua, awс╗Нn ekute ile to n jс║╣un nile ijс╗Нba gbogbo to ba ti jс║╣ ni Naijiria yii ni. с╣вugbс╗Нn laye ijс╗Нba Buhari yii ni Funtua di ikooko, с║╣ran nla lo ku to n gbe; o di kalokalo miwo miwo, o si n ko owo с╗Нmс╗Н Naijiria mi. с╗Мkunrin naa ko ni iс╣гс║╣ gidi kan, loootс╗Н oniroyin ni, с╣гugbс╗Нn lati с╗Нdun 1980 to ti da iwe iroyin Democrat silс║╣, ti iwe naa si ti ku ni bii с╗Нdun marun-un lс║╣yin с║╣, с╗Нkunrin yii ko с╣гiс╣гс║╣ mi-in mс╗Н, ka maa jс║╣ nidii ijс╗Нba to ba jс║╣ nikan lo n с╣гe. Ohun to waa mu ti asiko Buhari yii le ni pe oun nikan ni с╗Нrс║╣ ati ana Buhari ninu awс╗Нn mс║╣ta ti wс╗Нn sun mс╗Н с╗Нn ju lс╗Н. Awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn n ba Buhari с╣гejс╗Нba rс║╣ ree, oun, Maman Daura ati Abba Kyari. Nitori eyi lo с╣гe n fi orukс╗Н Buhari gba oriс╣гiiriс╣гii iс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba. Oun lo sun с╗Нkunrin kan, Emefiele, kс║╣rс║╣kс║╣rс║╣ titi ti Buhari fi fi iyс║╣n с╣гe olori banki apapс╗Н ilс║╣ wa. Lati igba naa ni Funtua ti n gba owo dс╗Нla ni Central Bank, ti yoo ni oun fс║╣с║╣ fi raja kan lati oke-okun, с╣гugbс╗Нn to jс║╣ awс╗Нn Mс╗Нla to n с╣гс║╣wo ni yoo ta a fun, ti yoo si tibс║╣ ri ere rс║╣pс║╣tс║╣ ti awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn nileeс╣гс║╣ nla ko le jс║╣. Funtua gba iс╣гс║╣ с╗Нgbс╗Нn biliс╗Нnu lс╗Нwс╗Н Central Bank, o loun yoo ba wс╗Нn fi kс╗Н aaye igbс╗Нkс╗Н si (Car Park), si ileeс╣гс║╣ wс╗Нn lтАЩAbuja. Bi eeyan ba tilс║╣ fс║╣с║╣ kс╗Н aaye mс╗Нto fun gbogbo aye, owo rс║╣ wa gbс╗Нdс╗Н to bс║╣с║╣! Funtua ati с╗Нkс╗Н с╗Нmс╗Н rс║╣ fi jibiti ra banki Keynote. Bi wс╗Нn с╣гe с╣гe e ni pe с╗Нkс╗Н с╗Нmс╗Н rс║╣ lo wa nileeс╣гс║╣ ijс╗Нba to maa n gba awс╗Нn ileeс╣гс║╣ to ba jс║╣ gbese, tabi ti wс╗Нn fс║╣с║╣ kogba wс╗Нle (AMCON). с╗Мkс╗Н с╗Нmс╗Н rс║╣ yii lo gba banki Keynote lorukс╗Н ileeс╣гс║╣ yii, ti wс╗Нn ni ki awс╗Нn eeyan waa ra a. Funtua lawс╗Нn yoo ra a, bс║╣с║╣ ni Funtua ko lowo lс╗Нwс╗Н. Ni с╗Нkс╗Н с╗Нmс╗Н rс║╣ ba gbowo lati ileeс╣гс║╣ AMCON, o gbe e si banki kan, banki naa ni awс╗Нn ya Funta lowo, ni wс╗Нn ba fi ra banki naa, wс╗Нn waa ni ki banki yii maa san gbese naa pada diс║╣ diс║╣. Bi ileeс╣гс║╣ naa с╣гe di tiwс╗Нn niyс║╣n. Nitori pe o sun mс╗Н Buhari yii, ko sohun to nawс╗Н si ti ko to o lс╗Нwс╗Н. Ni awс╗Нn gomina, awс╗Нn minisita, awс╗Нn oloс╣гelu Naijiria gbogbo ba n wс╗Н lс╗Н sile с║╣ bii pe oun gan-an ni olori ijс╗Нba. с╣вugbс╗Нn o ku lс╗Нс╣гс║╣ to kс╗Нja, o fi aye silс║╣ lai dagbere. Gbogb ohun to fi с╗Нna buruku ko jс╗Н yii, ko duro lati jс║╣ ere с╗Нkankan nibс║╣, nitori с╗Мlс╗Нrun fi han an pe oun ju gbogbo с║╣da aye lс╗Н. Ko si с╗Нna mi-in ti awс╗Нn oloс╣гelu Naijiria fi le kс╗Нgbс╗Нn ju iru eyi lс╗Н. Oloс╣гelu to ba fс║╣с║╣ с╣гoriire, ko fi ti Funtua kс╗Нgbс╗Нn, ko ma wa ile aye mс╗Нya, ko mс╗Н  pe ile aye ki i с╣гe awaa lс╗Н.Nijс╗Н kan, awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н orilс║╣-ede Naijiria yoo gbс╗Нn daadaa lati mс╗Н pe awс╗Нn eeyan ti wс╗Нn n rin kaakiri ti wс╗Нn n pe ara wс╗Нn ni oloс╣гelu yii, oniс╣гowo to n wa owo kiri nidii okoowo wс╗Нn ni gbogbo wс╗Нn. Bс║╣с║╣ ni ko si okoowo meji ti wс╗Нn n с╣гe ju oс╣гelu lс╗Н, owo araalu ni wс╗Нn fс║╣с║╣ gba, ki wс╗Нn maa jс║╣ ohun to jс║╣ ti gbogbo ilu nikan lo wa lс╗Нkan wс╗Нn. Ifс║╣ araalu, tabi ti idagbasoke ilu kan bayii ko si lс╗Нkan wс╗Нn, ibi ti awс╗Нn yoo ti ri jijс║╣-mimu tiwс╗Нn nikan ni wс╗Нn n wa, ki wс╗Нn si ri owo ti wс╗Нn yoo fi с╣гeranu gidi kiri. Ohun to с╣гe rс╗Нrun fun wс╗Нn lati kuro ninu с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu kan bс╗Н sinu omi-in ree, ti wс╗Нn yoo maa paarс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu bii с║╣ni to n paarс╗Н aс╣гс╗Н. Tabi с║╣ ko ri olori ile-igbimс╗Н aс╣гofin wa tс║╣lс║╣, Yakubu Dogara. с╗Мmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu PDP ni, inu с║╣gbс║╣ naa lo si wa to fi di ara ile-igbimс╗Н aс╣гofin ni 2007. Lс║╣yin to ti lo saa meji nile-igbimс╗Н yii, o kuro ninu с║╣gbс║╣ naa ni 2014, o dс╗Нmс╗Н APC. Ni 2018, Dogara kuro ni APC, o tun pada sinu PDP. Lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja yii, Dogara tun fi PDP silс║╣, o si pada sinu APC. с║╕ jс║╣ ka bi ara wa, iru anfaani wo ni iru eeyan jakujaku bayii yoo с╣гe fun ilu. Wс╗Нn yoo kan maa kowo ilu jс║╣ naa ni. Wс╗Нn ko ranti с╗Нjс╗Н iku tabi с╗Нjс╗Н с╗Нla, owo ati ipo nikan ni wс╗Нn n le kiri. Ole ni wс╗Нn o, awс╗Нn alaparutu eeyan, awс╗Нn oniranu gbogbo!с╗Мkunrin Adams Oshiomhole yii ni yoo jс║╣ ki wс╗Нn maa bu awс╗Нn eeyan kukuru. Bi wс╗Нn ba n sс╗Н pe eeyan kukuru biliisi, iru awс╗Нn Adams yii lo jс║╣ ki wс╗Нn maa wi bс║╣с║╣. Biliisi gan-an lс╗Нkunrin naa, ki i с╣гe с║╣ni to с╣гee duro ti rara. Oshiomhole lo ba aye Ize-Iyamu jс║╣ ni 2016, to sс╗Н pe ole ni, o kowo jс║╣, с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ okunkun si ni, to n sс╗Н pe ko si meji iru Godwin Obaseki, to ni oun fi с╗Мlс╗Нrun bura lori saare baba oun, Godwin lo dara ju ni с║╣ni to le с╣гe gomina Edo. Oshiomhole naa lo n fo soke bayii pe Godwin yii ko daa, Ize-Iyamu ti oun pe ni ole lс╗Нjс╗Нsi lo daa ju lс╗Н. Nigba  ti yoo ba с╗Нrс╗Н jс║╣, o ni nitori с╗Мbaseki ko ri gomina с╣гe lo с╣гe kuro ninu APC, pe eeyan gidi kan ki i fi с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu to wa silс║╣, ohun ti oun fi jс║╣ с╗Нga niyс║╣n, nitori oun ko jс║╣ fi с║╣gbс║╣ oс╣гelu oun silс║╣. с╗Мkunrin yii ti gbagbe pe inu с║╣gbс║╣ Labour loun wa tс║╣lс║╣ ki oun too sa lс╗Н sinu с║╣gbс║╣ AC, ki wс╗Нn too jс╗Н waa di с╗Нmс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ APC. Nigba ti eeyan ba ti le parс╗Н ju, iwa с╗Нmс╗Нluabi yoo jinna si i. Bс║╣ с║╣ ba ri Oshiomhole, с║╣ jinna si i o, eeyan kukuru biliisi ni."},{"question":"Dame un buen t├нtulo para el texto : Dos visitantes caminan sobre los pilares del monumento al Holocausto en Berl├нn.Un hombre hace malabarismo con seis bolas rosadas. Una posa en un movimiento de yoga, otra se para en una pierna, dos hombres saltan de un pilar a otro.Pero al escritor israel├н-alem├бn Shahak Shapira no le pareci├│ el monumento al Holocausto en Berl├нn. Shapira copi├│ 12 selfies tomadas en el monumento y subidas a redes sociales y las public├│ en un sitio web el jueves.Pero con un truco: quit├│ el fondo del monumento y lo reemplaz├│ con escenas de los campos de concentraci├│n, dejando a los j├│venes tomadores de selfies involuntariamente rodeados de cuerpos y cad├бveres.El sitio web se llama \\"Yolocaust\\", una combinaci├│n entre la popular etiqueta en ingl├йs \\"Yolo\\" (you only live once, o s├│lo se vive una vez) y \\"Holocausto\\". Fue un ├йxito en l├нnea y tomado por varios medios de comunicaci├│n que elogiaron la idea. Los protagonistas de las fotograf├нas fueron tratados de \\"tontos\\", \\"irrespetuosos\\", e \\"idiotas tomadores de selfies\\".Shapira pens├│ la la idea durante aproximadamente un a├▒o antes de comenzar el trabajo el mi├йrcoles, dijo.\\"Es un fen├│meno que hab├нa comenzado a notar en Berl├нn y luego empec├й a ver esas im├бgenes en todas partes. Sent├нa que la gente necesitaba saber lo que estaban haciendo realmente, o c├│mo otros podr├нan interpretar lo que estaban haciendo\\".As├н que revis├│ miles de selfies en Facebook, Instagram, Tinder y Grindr y eligi├│ una docena de los m├бs extremos.Las im├бgenes estaban todas en las cuentas p├║blicas de redes sociales y no pidi├│ permiso a ninguno de los titulares. En la parte inferior de su p├бgina web hay una direcci├│n de correo electr├│nico -\\"undouche.me@yolocaust.de\\"- para solicitar que se elimine una imagen. \\"Supongo que ese es mi compromiso\\", coment├│ Shapira.Lo que vuelve el proyecto provocativo es \\"la gente y la forma en que se representan a s├н mismos\\", en lugar de las escenas de muerte impactantes que ha superpuesto, dijo.\\"Si hubiese usado seres aut├│nomos normales, con gente parada all├н sin hacer.\\"","answer":"Yolocausto: ┬┐esta bien tomarse fotos en monumentos que recuerdan a las v├нctimas del Holocausto?. "},{"question":"\\"р╢╗р╖Ф р╢╗р╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Ер╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Ер╢нр╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╢╜ р╢пр╖Тр╢пр╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╢╜р╖Тр╢║ р╢┤р╢╢р╖П,р╢╗р╢▒р╖К р╢╗р╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒ р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╖Щ р╖Ар╖Щр╢л р╢▒р╖Пр╢п р╢▒р╖Фр╢┤р╖П р╢нр╢╢ р╢нр╢╢р╖П \\"р╢╕р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╢║р╖Т, р╢┤р╢пр╖КтАНр╢║ р╖Ар╢╜ р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╢Ер╢╗р╖Фр╢нр╢║р╖Т. р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Фр╢╜р╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢п ?","answer":"р╢▒р╖Фр╢┤р╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢│ р╖Ар╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╢╗р╖Цр╢┤ р╢╗р╖Пр╖Бр╖Тр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Ер╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╢Жр╢Ър╖Пр╢╗р╢║р╢з р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╢╜р╖Т р╢╗р╖Ър╢Ыр╖Пр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Ър╖Пр╢▒р╖Кр╢нр╖Тр╢║ р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ер╢нр╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╢╜р╢пр╖Ар╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К, р╢╗р╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╢╗р╖Гр╢пр╖Тр╢║ р╢Ср╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Пр╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Ур╢▒р╖П р╢▒р╖Пр╢пр╢║р╢з р╢Ер╢▒р╖Фр╖Ар╢╕ р╢┤р╖Пр╢пр╢║ р╢нр╢╢р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Ер╢▒р╢Вр╢Ьр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢╕р╢╜р╖Кр╖Др╖У р╢╢р╖Тр╢│р╖Тр╢▒р╖П р╖Гр╖Ъ р╢▒р╖Щр╢нр╖К р╢Ър╖Ьр╢▒р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Гр╢╢р╢║ р╢пр╖Щр╖Г р╢╢р╢╜р╢╕р╖Тр╢▒р╖К, р╢Т р╢Лр╢нр╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╢пр╖Щр╖Ар╢Яр╢▒р╖Фр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢зр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Тр╢╜р╖Пр╖Гр╢║ р╢╕р╢╕ р╢Ър╖Щр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Ар╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╢п?"},{"question":"ф╕Ах║зхдзце╝хПСчФЯчБлчБ╛,шАБщЩИщАГхИ░ф║Жце╝щб╢хРО,цЧаш╖пхПпш╡░,ф╛┐щАГхИ░ф║ЖщЪФхгБчЪДце╝щб╢ф╕К,ф╕дце╝хПкщЪФ10хЕмхИЖ,шАБщЩИхН┤цСФцн╗ф║Ж,ф╕║ф╗Аф╣И","answer":"чнФцбИя╝Ъф╕дх║зце╝ф╕Аф╕к30х▒В,ф╕Аф╕к3х▒В"},{"question":"Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├б ","answer":"Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├б jс║╣╠Б ├мl├║ k├йker├й kan n├н ├Мp├нnlс║╣╠А с╗М╠Ас╣гun ni N├а├мj├нr├н├а Gс║╣╠Бgс║╣╠Б b├н a sс╗Н с╣гa├бj├║, ├мw├бd├м├н l├│r├н iс╣гс║╣╠Б y├м├н d├й ├Мjс╗Нba ├Мb├нlс║╣╠А ├Аt├аk├║mс╗Н╠Аs├а t├н ├│ n├н ib├╣j├│k├▓├│ rс║╣╠А n├н ├Тс╣г├║. N├н ├мjс╗Нba ├мb├мlс║╣╠А y├м├н, gbogbo ├аwс╗Нn ├мl├║ ├аti ab├║l├иko t├н ├│ w├а n├н ibс║╣╠А l├│ jс║╣╠Б ti ├Мjс║╣╠Ас╣г├а. с║╕╠Аy├а с║╣╠Аka-├иd├и ├Мjс║╣╠Ас╣г├а ni wс╗Н╠Бn s├м ┼Д sс╗Н ├аfi Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а t├н ├│ jс║╣╠Б с║╣╠Аy├а с║╣╠Аk├а-├иd├и Ifс║╣╠А ni wс╗Н╠Бn ┼Д sс╗Н. Gс║╣╠Бgс║╣╠Б b├н ├мt├аn t├н gbс╗Н╠Б, Ifс║╣╠А ni ├аwс╗Нn ar├б Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а ti с╣г├н lс╗Н s├н ├мl├║ n├б├а l├бti agbool├й Ar├╣b├н├мd├м n├н ├▓k├и Mс╗Н╠Аr├мс╣г├а n├н Il├й-Ifс║╣╠А1 . ├Мw├бd├м├н fi h├аn p├й с╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠А oy├и l├│ d├б ├мj├а s├нlс║╣╠А n├н ├а├аrin tс║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бnt├аb├║r├▓. с║╕╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn fс║╣╠Б jс║╣ oy├и, ├аb├║r├▓ n├б├а s├м ┼Д fс║╣╠Б jс║╣ oy├и n├б├а. с╗М╠Аrс╗Н╠А y├м├н d├б y├бnpс╗Нn-y├бnrin s├нlс║╣╠А n├н ├а├аrin wс╗Нn. L├│r├н ├мj├а oy├и y├м├н ni wс╗Н╠Бn w\`at├н с║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn fi lс╗Н s├н oko. с╣в├╣gbс╗Н╠Бn k├н с║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn t├│ ti oko d├й, ip├и l├бti jс║╣ oy├и d├║n. ├Аb├║r├▓ t├н ├│ w├а n├н il├й n├н ├аs├мk├▓ n├б├а l├│ jс║╣╠Б1. ├Мfс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠Аw├бnilс║╣╠Бnuw├▓ pс║╣╠Аl├║ ar├бb├мnrin Julianah aya ni 17/6/92.2. ├Мfс╗Н╠Аrс╗Н╠Аw├бnilс║╣╠Бnuw├▓ pс║╣╠Аl├║ Ol├│y├и F├бk├│w├аjс╗Н ni 17/6/92. Ip├й n├б├а. Ip├и ti s├й с║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn mс╗Н╠Б oko. ├Иy├н b├н с║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn n├нn├║ n├нgb├а t├н ├│ gbс╗Н╠Б p├й ├аb├║r├▓ ├▓un ti jс║╣ ├▓y├й, ├│ s├м kс╗Н╠А l├бti pad├а w├б s├н il├й n├нtor├н p├й k├▓ l├и fi or├н balс║╣╠А f├║n ├аb├║r├▓ rс║╣╠А t├н ├│ ti jс║╣ oy├и. с╗М╠Аrс╗Н╠А y├м├н di ohun t├н wс╗Нn ┼Д gb├й ogun ja ara wс╗Нn s├н f├║n с╗Н╠Аpс╗Н╠Аlс╗Нpс╗Н╠А с╗Нd├║n. N├нgb├а t├н с║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn y├м├н w├б ┼Д gb├й ogun ja ├аb├║r├▓ rс║╣╠А n├н Ifс║╣╠А lemс╗Н╠Бlemс╗Н╠Б, ni ├аwс╗Нn Ifс║╣╠А b├б fi с║╣╠Аp├а с╣гe o├▓g├╣n s├н с║╣nu odi ├мl├║ n├н ├Мl├│d├и. Wс╗Н╠Бn s├м fi m├аr├мw├▓ с╣гe ├аm├м s├м с╗Н╠Аgangan ibi t├н wс╗Н╠Бn с╣гe o├▓g├╣n n├б├а s├н. L├бti ├мgb├а y├м├н ni ogun с║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn k├▓ ti l├и wс╗Н Ifс║╣╠А mс╗Н. ├Аwс╗Нn ├Мjс║╣╠Ас╣г├а n├н ├│ ni k├н с║╣╠Аgbс╗Н╠Бn t├н ├│ ┼Д b├нn├║ y├м├н lс╗Н tс║╣╠Аd├│ s├н ├Мw├аr├а. N├нgb├а t├н wс╗Н╠Бn d├й ├Мw├аr├а, wс╗Н╠Бn fi mс╗Н╠Аr├мw├▓ с╗Н╠Аpс║╣ g├║n ilс║╣╠А, k├н ilс║╣╠А t├│ mс╗Н╠Б mс╗Н╠Аr├мw├▓ kс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Аkan ti di igi с╗Н╠Аpс║╣ kс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Аkan.├Мс╣гс║╣╠Аlс║╣╠А tс║╣╠Аlс║╣╠А, wс╗Н╠Бn s├м pinnu p├й ├аwс╗Нn k├▓ n├н├н l├и b├б ├аwс╗Нn ├аlej├▓ n├б├а gb├й n├нtor├н p├й ol├│├▓g├╣n ni wс╗Нn. ├Иy├н l├│ m├║ k├н ├аwс╗Нn ara ├Мw├аr├а l├й ├аwс╗Нn ├аlej├▓ n├б├а s├н iw├бj├║. Ibi t├н ├аwс╗Нn ├аlej├▓ n├б├а tс║╣╠Аd├│ s├н lс║╣╠Бy├мn t├н wс╗Н╠Бn k├║r├▓ n├н ├Мw├аr├а ni a mс╗Н╠А s├н Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а l├│n├м├н. L├│├▓├│tс╗Н╠Б or├н ilс║╣╠А ├Мjс║╣╠Ас╣г├а ni Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а w├а с╣г├╣gbс╗Н╠Бn k├▓ s├н ├аjс╗Нс╣гepс╗Н╠А kan d├аb├н al├бr├а l├б├аrin Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а, Il├йс╣г├а ├аti ├Мw├аr├а t├нt├н di ├▓n├н p├а├бp├а├б n├нpa с║╣╠Аka-├иd├и t├н wс╗Нn ┼Д sс╗Н.├Аk├нy├иs├н fi h├аn p├й gbogbo or├║kс╗Н ├аd├║gb├▓ t├н ├│ w├а n├н Ifс║╣╠А n├б├а ni ├│ w├а n├н Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а. A r├н agbool├й b├н Ar├╣b├н├мd├м, Mс╗Н╠Ас╗Н╠Аrс║╣╠А, ├Тk├иr├иw├и, L├│k├▓rс║╣╠Б ├аti ├Иyindi n├н Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а.B├бkan n├б├а с║╣╠Аy├а с║╣╠Аka-├иd├и Ifс║╣╠А n├м wс╗Н╠Бn ┼Д sс╗Н n├н Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а. ├Аs├мk├▓ t├н wс╗Н╠Бn b├б s├м ┼Д с╣гe с╗Нd├║n ├мb├нlс║╣╠А n├н Ifс║╣╠А n├б├а ni ├аwс╗Нn ar├б Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а m├бa ┼Д с╣гe tiwс╗Нn.├Мw├бd├м├н n├нpa ├мt├аn ├мс╣гс║╣╠Аd├бlс║╣╠А ├аwс╗Нn ├мl├║ t├н iс╣гс║╣╠Б y├м├н d├й fi h├аn gbangba p├й mс╗Н╠Аlс║╣╠Бb├н ni Ifс║╣╠А, Ifс║╣╠Ас║╣╠Бtс║╣╠Аd├│ pс║╣╠Аl├║ ├Тk├и-Igbo, ├аti Ifс║╣╠Аw├аr├а. Wс╗Н╠Бn jс╗Нra n├нn├║ ├мс╣гes├н wс╗Нn. с║╕╠Аka-├иd├и wс╗Нn dс╗Н╠Бgba, or├║kс╗Н ├аd├║gb├▓ wс╗Нn t├║n b├бra mu, b├бkan n├б├а ni с║╣╠Аs├мn wс╗Нn t├║n dс╗Н╠Бgba. ├Аk├│k├│ t├н wс╗Н╠Бn ┼Д с╣гe с╗Нd├║n ├мb├нlс║╣╠А k├▓ y├аtс╗Н╠А s├н ara wс╗Нn. B├н с║╣r├║ b├б s├м jс╗Нra, ├│ d├бj├║ p├й il├й kan n├б├а ni wс╗Н╠Бn ti j├бde."},{"question":"р╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╢пр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Фр╖Ер╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Ьр╖Др╖Ьр╢╕р╢п?","answer":"р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╖Пр╢Вр╢Ър╖Тр╢Ър╢║р╢▒р╖К р╢╜р╢Ър╖Кр╖В 21р╢Ър╢з р╢Ер╢░р╖Тр╢Ъ р╢┤р╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╖Гр╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╢╗р╢лр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Гр╖Ф р╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╢пр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ур╢╕ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢║ р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ьр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢┤р╢пр╖Тр╢Вр╢ар╖Т р╖Ар╖У р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Тр╢пр╖Пр╢▒ р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ьр╢╕р╢║ р╢┤р╖Ар╖Гр╢║р╖Т.р╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╢пр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Ер╖Ар╖Бр╖КтАНр╢║ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢Ср╢║ р╢Ър╖Е р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕ р╢пр╖Щр╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Ар╢нр╖Тр╢▒ р╢╢р╖А р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Т р╢пр╖Пр╢▒ р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ьр╢╕р╢║р╖Ъ р╢вр╢▒р╢нр╖К р╖Гр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢╕р╖Пр╢нр╢╗р╢Жр╢╗р╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Т р╢╢р╖Ур╢╢р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╖Гр╖Тр╢Вр╖Др╢╜ р╖Гр╖Ър╖Ар╢║ р╖Ар╖Щр╢н р╢Ър╖Тр╢║р╖П р╖Гр╖Тр╢зр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╢Ьр╖Бр╖Ур╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢пр╖Рр╢▒ р╢Ьр╖Рр╢▒р╖Ур╢╕ р╢┤р╖Тр╢лр╖Тр╖Г р╢║.тАЬр╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╢пр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢╕ р╢пр╖Щр╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖Ар╖П. р╢Ср╢Ър╢Ър╖К р╢нр╢╕р╢║р╖Т р╢нр╢╕р╢▒р╖К р╢вр╖Ур╖Ар╢нр╖Кр╖А р╢Йр╢пр╖Кр╢пр╖Т р╢┤р╖Ьр╢╗р╖Ьр╢▒р╖Кр╢пр╖Ф р╢┤р╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢┤р╖Фр╢╗р╖Ар╢╜р╖П р╢Тр╢Ър╢з р╢пр╖Пр╢║р╢Ъ р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Фр╖Ер╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К. р╢Ер╢▒р╖Тр╢нр╖К р╢Ср╢Ъ р╢нр╢╕р╢║р╖Т р╢нр╢╕р╢▒р╖Кр╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢ер╖Пр╢нр╖Ур╢▒р╖Кр╢з р╢┤р╖Фр╖Ер╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Щр╢▒р╖Щр╢Ър╖К р╢╕р╖Рр╢╗р╖Фр╢лр╢з р╢┤р╖Гр╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╢Т р╖Ар╖Рр╢йр╖Ъ р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒. р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Т р╢пр╖Пр╢▒ р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ьр╢╕р╢║ р╢Ър╢нр╖П р╢Ър╢╗р╢╜р╖П р╢Ер╢┤р╖Тр╢з р╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╢пр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒ р╢┤р╖Фр╖Ер╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖К.тАЭр╢╕р╢╗р╢лр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╢║ 4 р╢Ър╖К р╢Йр╢Ър╖Кр╢╕ р╢║р╖Пр╢╕р╢з р╢┤р╖Щр╢╗ р╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╢╜р╢╢р╖П р╢Ьр╢н р╢║р╖Фр╢нр╖Ф р╢╢р╖А р╢п р╢Фр╖Др╖Ф р╢Ер╖Ар╢░р╖Пр╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╢Ър╖Е р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢╕р╖Тр╢║ р╢Ьр╖Ьр╖Гр╖К р╢┤р╖Рр╢║ 4р╢▒р╖К р╢┤р╖Гр╖Фр╖А р╖Гр╖Ыр╢╜ р╢╕р╖Тр╢║ р╢║р╖Пр╢╕ р╢Жр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╖ р╖Ар╖Ур╢╕ р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Фр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Зр╖Гр╖К р╢╜р╢╢р╖П р╢Ьр╢н р╢▒р╖Ьр╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Т р╢╢р╖А р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Ер╖Ър╢║.р╢Фр╢╢р╖Ър╢Ьр╖Ъ р╢пр╖Щр╢▒р╖Щр╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╢нр╖К р╢Ер╢║р╖Щр╢Ър╖Фр╢з р╢пр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Ър╖Рр╢╕р╢нр╖Кр╢нр╢Ър╖К р╢пр╢Ър╖Кр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢▒р╢╕р╖К р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╢нр╢▒ р╢Ер╢Вр╢Ъ 011 2692051 / 011 2696109 р╢Фр╖Гр╖Кр╖Гр╖Ъ р╖Бр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖У р╢╜р╢Вр╢Ър╖П р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Т р╢пр╖Пр╢▒ р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ьр╢╕р╢║ р╖Др╖П р╖Гр╢╕р╖Кр╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢░ р╖Ар╖У р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢┤р╢пр╖Тр╢Вр╢ар╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢║ р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║."},{"question":"inona no zom-pirenena zakain'ny mpikambana ao amin'ny \\"Daft Punk\\"?","answer":"ny mpikambana ao amin'ny \\"Daft Punk\\" dia mizaka ny zom-pirenena frantsay"},{"question":"SIDEE U HAQIIJIN KARTAA HADAFKAAGA AMA GANACSIGAAGA?","answer":"Guul┬а ganacsi inta badan waxaa lagu gaaraa goтАЩaan adag, geesinimo iyo in aad wax ka barato dadka waayo aragnimada buuxda u leh arirmaha ganacsiga, ┬аislamarkaana hirgaliyay ganacsiyada horumarka gaaray ama guuleystay . Haddaba, Haddii aad doonayso in aad ganacsi horumar leh samayso waa in aad tixgalisaa talooyinka dadka waayoaragnimada leh ee soo arkay loolanka ganacsiga iyo horumarkiisa. Halkaan waxaan idinkugu soo gudbin doonana qaar ka mid ah talooyinka ugu muhiimsan ee laga dhaxlay qaar ka mid ah ganacsatada ugu taajirsan dunida,Waxaana ka mid ah :Naftaada loolan gali┬атАУ┬аRichard Branson oo ah ninka aasaasay shirkada Virgin ee caanka ah ayaa ku talinaya in qofka doonaya in uu ganacsi abuuro uu diyaar u noqdo in uu loolan joogto ah galiyo naftiisa. Waxa uu aaminsanyahay in noloshu ay tahay waxbarasho joogto ah oo aad maalinkasta wax-cusub barato.Qabo shaqo aad jeceshahay┬атАУ ┬аSteve Jobs oo ahaa ninkii horumarka weyn gaarsiiyay shirkadda Apple ayaa ku talin jiray in dadka dhalinyarada ah ay sameeyaan ganacsiyo aysan lacag darteed keliya u abuurin balse ay sameeyaan ganacsi la xiriira waxyaabaha ay jecelyihiin si ay ugu raaxaystaan.U barrer Qatarta┬атАУ┬аJeямА Bezos oo ah agaasimaha Amazon waxa uu leeyahay in aadan waligaa ogaanayn qiimaha ямБkradaada ilaa aad tijaabiso. Waxa uu sheegay in aad ka shalaaynayso in aadan tijaabin , halkii aad ka shalaayi lahayd fashilka. Waayo fashilkaas cashar ayaad ka qaadanaysaa balse ямБkrad┬аaadan tijaabin waxba kama faaтАЩidaysid. Aragti lahoowтАУ Agaasimaha Tumblr oo lagu magacaabo┬аDavid Karp ayaa aaminsan in ganacsadaha halabuurka leh uu yahay mid aragti-dheer leh oo ay u caddahay waxyaabaha uu doonayo in uu sameeyo iyo sida uu ku gaarayo hadafkiisa.Naftaada aamin┬атАУ┬аHenry Ford oo ahaa ninkii aasaasay shirkada baabuurta ee Ford ayaa laga soo wariyay in uu yiri тАЭ Haddii aad aaminsantahay in aad wax samayn karto iyo haddii aad aamisantahay in aadan samayn Karin, Labadaba waa ku saxsantahayтАЭ Haddii aad aaminsantahay in aad guuleysanayo, waad helaysaa wadooyinkii aad ku guuleysan lahayd balse haddii ┬аaadan aaminsanayn waxaad helaysaa marmarsiiyo aad ku guuldaraysato."},{"question":"Dhaqtaradii ugu horeysay ee Islam-ka?","answer":"Rufeydah Bintu Sacad."},{"question":"римриЧри╝рижри╛риж рижри╛ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ : риЕри▓ри┐рилри╝ ри▓рйИри▓ри╛","answer":"римрйЬрйЗ риЪри┐ри░ри╛риВ рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╣рйИ риХри┐ риЕри░рим рижрйЗри╕ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЗриХ риЕриорйАри░ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╕рйА ред риЙри╣рижри╛ риЪрй░риЧри╛ ри╡рй▒рибри╛ рикри░ри╡ри╛ри░ ри╕рйА риЕридрйЗ риирйМриХри░ риЪри╛риХри░ ри╡рйА римри╣рйБридрйЗ ри╕рии ред риЙри╣ риЬрйАри╡рии рижрйЗ рижри┐рии римрйЬрйА риЦрйБри╕ри╝рйА ри╡ри┐риЪ римри┐ридри╛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйАредриЙри╣рижрйЗ риХрйЛри▓ римри╣рйБрид ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ рикри╕рйВ ри╡рйА ри╕рии ред риЙри╣риирйВрй░ ри░рим ри╡ри▓рйЛриВ рикри╕рйВриЖриВ риЕридрйЗ рикрй░риЫрйАриЖриВ рижрйА римрйЛри▓рйА ри╕риориЭриг рижрйА ри╕ри╝риХридрйА риори┐ри▓рйА ри╣рйЛриИ ри╕рйА ред рикри░ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ риЙри╣ риХри┐ри╕рйЗ риирйВрй░ рижрй▒ри╕ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйА ри╕риХрижри╛ риХри┐риЙриВриХри┐ риЗри╕ ринрйЗрид рижрйЗ риЦрйЛри▓рйНри╣риг рижрйА ри╕риЬри╝ри╛ риорйМрид ри╕рйАредрикри╕рйВриЖриВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЙри╣рижрйЗ риХрйЛри▓ риЗриХ риврй▒риЧри╛ риЕридрйЗ риЗриХ риЦрйЛридри╛ ри╡рйА ри╕рии ред рижрйЛри╣ри╛риВ рижрйА риЦрйБри░ри▓рйА риХрйЛри▓ риХрйЛри▓ ри╣рйА ри╕рйА ред риХриИ ри╡ри╛ри░ риЬрижрйЛриВ риЙри╣риири╛риВ риирйВрй░ риЗриХрй▒риари┐риЖриВ рикрй▒риарйЗ риЦри╛риг рижри╛ риорйМриХри╛ риори┐ри▓рижри╛ ридри╛риВ риЙри╣ риЗриХ рижрйВриЬрйЗ риири╛ри▓ риЖрикригрйЗ рижрйБриЦ ри╕рйБриЦ рилрйЛри▓ ри▓рйИриВрижрйЗредриЗриХ рижри┐рии ридри░риХри╛ри▓ри╛риВ ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риЖрикригрйЗ риирйМриХри░ри╛риВ риЕридрйЗ римри╛ри▓ римрй▒риЪри┐риЖриВ риири╛ри▓ римрйИриари╛ ри╣рй▒ри╕ риЦрйЗриб ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйА риХри┐ риЕриЪри╛риириХ риЙри╣риирйЗ риврй▒риЧрйЗ риЕридрйЗ риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйВрй░ риЖрикри╕ ри╡ри┐риЪ риШрйБри╕ри░ риорйБри╕ри░ риХри░рижри┐риЖриВ ри╕рйБригри┐риЖ редриврй▒риЧри╛ риХри╣ри┐ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйА, \\"ридрйВрй░ ридри╛риВ риорйЛридрйА риоригри╕ риХрйЗ риЗри╣ риЬриирио ри▓ри┐риЖ риЬри╛рикрижри╛ рижрйЗ ! римрйБрй▒ри▓рйЗ ри▓рйБриЯрижри╛ риПриВ, риори┐рй▒ридри░ри╛ ! ридрйЗри░рйАриЖриВ риЦри╝ри╛ридри░ри╛риВ рижрйАриЖриВ ри░рйАри╕ри╛риВ риири╣рйАриВред риЯри╣ри┐ри▓рйАриП ридрйЗри░рйЗ риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ рикри┐рй▒риЫрйЗ рикриП рилри┐ри░рижрйЗ риирйЗ ред риРрии ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ ри╕ри┐ри░ ридрйИриирйВрй░ ридри╛риЬри╝рйЗ рикрй▒риарйЗ рикри╛риЙриВрижрйЗ риирйЗ ред рикрйАриг риирйВрй░ риЪри╕ри╝риорйЗ рижри╛ риарй░рибри╛ риари╛ри░ рикри╛ригрйА ри▓ри┐риЖ рижри┐рй░рижрйЗ риирйЗ ридрйЗ ридрйЗри░рйА риери╛риВ ри╕ри╝рйАри╕ри╝рйЗ ри╡ри╛риВриЩ ри╕ри╛рилри╝ ри░риЦрижрйЗ риирйЗ ! рикри░, рипри╛ри░, ри░ридрйА риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╡рй▒ри▓ ри╡рйЗриЦ ред риЕрй▒ризрйА риЕрй▒ризрйА ри░ри╛рид ридриХ рикрй░риЬри╛ри▓рйА ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬриХрйЬрйА риорйЗри░рйА ризрйМриг ри╡рйА риЖриХрйЬ риЬри╛риВрижрйА риП ред ри╣ри▓ ри╡ри╛ри╣рйБрй░рижри┐риЖриВ риорйЗри░рйАриЖриВ риЦрйБрй▒риЪри╛риВ ри░ри╣ри┐ риЬри╛риВрижрйАриЖриВ риирйЗ ред риХриИ риХриИ рижри┐рии риорйЗри░рйЗ рикри┐рй░рибрйЗ ридрйЛриВ ри╕рйЛриЯрйА рижрйАриЖриВ ри▓ри╛ри╕ри╝ри╛риВ риири╣рйАриВ риЬри╛риВрижрйАриЖриВ редрижри┐рии риЪрйЬрйНри╣рии ридрйЛриВ ри░ри╛рид рикрйИриг ридриХ риЕрй░риирйНри╣рйЗ ри╡ри╛ри╣ риорйИриирйВрй░ ри░риЧрйЬри┐риЖ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ риПред риХрйЛриИ ри╡рйА риХрй░рио ри╣рйЛри╡рйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░ри┐риЖриВ рижрйЗ риорйВрй░ри╣ ридрйЗ риорйЗри░ри╛ риИ риири╛риВ риЪрйЬрйНри╣ри┐риЖ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ риП, риЬри┐рй▒рижри╛риВ ри╣рйЛри░ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ рикри╕рйВ риори░ риЧриП ри╣рйБрй░рижрйЗ риирйЗ ! ридрйЗ рилрйЗри░, риЬрижрйЛриВ риорйИриирйВрй░ риЯрйБрй▒риЯрйЗ ринрй▒риЬрйЗ риирйВрй░ ри░ри╛рид ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ риЦрйБри░ри▓рйА ри▓ри╛риЧ ри▓ри┐риЕ римрй░риирйНри╣рижрйЗ риирйЗ ридри╛риВ риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЦрйЬрйНри╣рии риЬрйЛриЧрйА ри╡рйА ри╣ри┐рй░риорид риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА ред рикрй▒риари┐риЖриВ ри╡ри▓ риорйВрй░ри╣ риХри░рижри╛ риЖриВ ридри╛риВ риири┐ри░рйА риЦрйЛри╣ риИ риЦрйЛри╣ ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА риП ! ридрйЗ риорйЗри░рйА риери╛риВ ри╡ри▓ ри╡рйЗриЦ ри▓рйИред ри╕ри╛ри░рйА ри╕ри╛ри░рйА ри░ри╛рид риЧрйЛри╣рйЗ ридрйЗ риЪри┐рй▒риХрйЬ риири╛ри▓ риИ ри▓ри┐римрйЬри┐риЖ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ риЖриВ ридрйЗ рижри┐риирйЗ ризрйБрик ри╡ри┐риЪ риЧрйЛри╣рйЗ рижрйЗ ри╕рйБрй▒риХриг риири╛ри▓ риорйЗри░ри╛ рикри┐рй░рибри╛ ри╣рйЛри░ риЖриХрйЬ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ риП ридрйЗ рибрй░рибри┐риЖриВ рижрйА риори╛ри░ риири╛ри▓ ри╕рйБрй▒риХрйАриЖриВ рикри╛риерйАриЖриВ ри╡ри╛риВриЭ риЭрйЬ риЭрйЬ рибри┐риЧрижри╛ риП редрикри░ ридрйВрй░ риПриВ ! риХрижрйА риХрй▒риЦ ринрй░рии риХрйЗ ри╡рйА рижрйВри╣ри░ри╛ риири╣рйАриВ риХрйАридри╛ ! ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ, риЬрйЛ риХрижрйА риори╛ри▓риХ риирйЗ ри╕ри╝ри╣ри┐ри░ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬри╛ригри╛ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ридри╛риВ ридрйЗри░рйА ри╡ри╛ри░рйА риЖ риЧриИ ред ридрйЗ риЙри╣ ри╡рйА ридрйЗри░рйА ри╕рйИри░ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижрйА ри╣рйИ ред ри░рйЗри╕ри╝риорйА ридрйЗри░рйЗ ридрйЗ риХри╛риарйА ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА риП, ри▓ри╛ри▓ рилрйБрй░риориг ридрйЗри░рйЗ риХрй░риири╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪриХри╛ри░ риХри▓риЧрйА ри╡ри╛риЩ ри╕рй▒риЬ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╣рйБрй░рижри╛ риП: риоригриХри┐риЖриВ ридрйЗ риШрйБрй░риЧри░рйВриЖриВ рижрйЗ ри╣ри╛ри░ ридрйЗри░рйЗ риЧри▓ ри╡ри┐риЪ, ри▓ри┐ри╕ри╝риХри╛риВ рикриП риори╛ри░рижрйЗ риирйЗред ридрйЗ рилрйЗри░, ри╕рйЛри╣ригри┐риЖриВ, риЬри┐ри╣рйЬри╛ ридрйВрй░ ри╡ри┐рй░риЧри╛ ри╣рйЛ ри╣рйЛ риХрйЗ ридрйБри░рижри╛ риПриВ! ридрйЗри░рйА риЯри╣рйБри░ ри╡рйЗриЦриг ри╡ри╛ри▓рйА ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА риП ! риЬрйЛ ридрйВрй░ риорйМриЬри╛риВ риори╛ригрижри╛ риПриВ ридрйЗ риорйИриВ рижри┐рии ри░ри╛рид ри╕рйЬри┐риЖ римри▓ри┐риЖ ри░ри╣ри┐рй░рижри╛ риЖриВ ред ридрйВрй░ риШри░ри╛рйЬрйЗ риори╛ри░рижри╛ риПриВ ридрйЗ риирйАриВриж риорйЗри░рйЗ ри▓ри╛риЧрйЗ риири╣рйАриВ рилрйЬриХрижрйА ред риорйИриВ ринрйБрй▒риЦри╛ ринри╛ригри╛ риЙримри╛ри╕рйАриЖриВ ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ риЖриВ ридрйЗ ридрйВрй░ риЧрйБри▓риЫрй▒ри░рйЗ риЙрибри╛риЙриВрижри╛ риПриВред ридрйЗри░рйАриЖриВ риЦри╝ри╛ридри░ри╛риВ ри╕ри╛ри╣ риири╣рйАриВ ри▓рйИриВрижрйАриЖриВ ридрйЗ риорйЗри░рйЗ ри╣рй▒риб ри╕рйБрй▒риХрйЗ риЬри╛риВрижрйЗ риирйЗ !\\"риЬрижрйЛриВ риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйЗ риврй▒риЧрйЗ рижрйАриЖриВ риЗри╣ риЧрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ ри╕рйБригрйАриЖриВ ридри╛риВ риЙри╣ римрйЬрйА риЙрй▒риЪрйА ри╕ри╛ри░рйА ри╣рй▒ри╕ри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ риЖриЦриг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, \\"рикри╛риЬрйАриЖ, ридрйЗри░рйАриЖриВ риЧрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ ри╕рйБриг риХрйЗ риорйЗри░ри╛ римрижрйЛримрижрйА ри╣ри╛ри╕ри╛ риири┐риХри▓рижри╛ риЬри╛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ риП ! ридрйВрй░ риири┐ри░ри╛ риЕриХри▓ рижри╛ риЕрй░риирйНри╣ри╛риВ риПриВ ! риорйВри░риЦри╛, ридрйЗ рижрйВриЬри┐риЖриВ ри▓риИ риЬрйБ риЬри╛рии риори╛ри░рижри╛ риПриВ, риЗри╣ риХри┐рй▒риерйЛриВ рижрйА риЕриХри▓ риП ! ри╕ри╡рйЗри░рйЗ риШри░рйЛриВ риири┐риХри▓ри┐риЖ ридрйЗ риириЦри┐рй▒ризри╛риВ ри╡ри╛риВриЭ ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ рижри┐рии ри╣рй▒риб риЧрйЛрибрйЗ ри░риЧрйЬрйЗ ридрйЗ риХри┐ризри░рйЗ риЬри╛ риХрйЗ ри░ри╛рид рикрйИриг ридрйЗ риорйБрйЬ риЖрикригрйА риЦрйБри░ри▓рйА рижри╛ риорйВрй░ри╣ ри╡рйЗриЦри┐риЖ !риириХри╛ри░ри┐риЖ, ри╕рйБриг ризри┐риЖрии риири╛ри▓ ! риХрижрйА риХрижрйА риерйЛрйЬрйА римри╣рйБрид риЪри▓ри╛риХрйА ри╡рйА ри╡ри░рид ри▓риИрижрйА риП ред риЬрижрйЛриВ риЙри╣ ридрйИриирйВрй░ риорйЗри░рйЗ ри▓ри╛риЧрйЗ риЖ римрй░риирйНри╣рижрйЗ риирйЗ, ридрйВрй░ риЪрйБрик риЪри╛рик риЖ риХрйЗ риЦрйЬрйНри╣ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ риПриВ ред риЙри╣ ри╕риориЭрижрйЗ риирйЗ риХри┐ ридрйВрй░ риЦри╝рйБри╕ри╝ риПриВ ред риЬрижрйЛриВ рикрй▒риарйЗ ридрйЗри░рйЗ риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ ри╕рйБриЯрижрйЗ риирйЗ ридри╛риВ ридрйВрй░ ри╣ри╛римрйЬри┐риЖриВ ри╡ри╛риВриЭ риЙри╣риири╛риВ ридрйЗ рикрйИриВрижри╛ риПриВ ридрйЗ риЙри╣ ри╕риориЭрижрйЗ риирйЗ риХри┐ ридрйВрй░ римрйЬри╛ рикрйНри░ри╕рй░рии риПриВ! рикри░ риЬрйЗ ридрйВрй░ риорйЗри░рйА риЧрй▒ри▓ риорй░риирйЗриВ ридри╛риВ риЬри┐рй▒рижри╛риВ риорйИриВ ридрйИриирйВрй░ рижрй▒ри╕рижри╛ риЖриВ, риЙрй▒рижри╛риВ риИ риХри░ редриЬрижрйЛриВ ридрйВрй░ ри╣ри▓ ри╡ри╛ри╣рйБриг ри▓риИ риЬри╛риПриВ, ридрйВрй░ риЦрйЗрид ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬри╛ риХрйЗ ри▓ри┐риЯриг ри▓риЧ риЬри╛риЗриЖ риХри░ ред ридрйЗ рилрйЗри░ ридрйИриирйВрй░ риЙри╣ ринри╛ри╡рйЗриВ риХрйБрй▒риЯ риХрйБрй▒риЯ риХрйЗ риЭрй░рим рижрйЗриг, ридрйВрй░ римри┐ри▓риХрйБри▓ риЙриаригри╛ риирйА ред риЬрйЗ риЙрй▒риа ри╡рйА риЦрйЬрйНри╣рйЗриВ ридри╛риВ рилрйЗри░ ри▓рйЗриЯ риЬри╛риИриВред''риЕрй░рид риирйВрй░ риЬрижрйЛриВ риЙри╣ ридрйИриирйВрй░ рикрй▒риарйЗ рикри╛риЙриг, ридрйВрй░ риЙри╣риири╛риВ риирйВрй░ риорйВрй░ри╣ ридриХ рии ри▓ри╛риИриВ ред рикрй▒риари┐риЖриВ ри╡ри▓ ри╡рйЗриЦ риХрйЗ рилрйВриХри╛риВ риори╛ри░рйА риЬри╛риИриВ ред риЙри╣ ри╕риориЭригриЧрйЗ риХри┐ ридрйВрй░ римри┐риори╛ри░ риПриВред рижрйЛ, риЪри╛ри░ рижри┐рии риЗри╕ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риХри░рйАриВ, рилрйЗри░ ри╡рйЗриЦрйА риХри┐рижри╛риВ ридрйЗри░рйЗ риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ рикри┐риЫрйЗ рилри┐ри░рижрйЗ риирйЗ !''риЬрижрйЛриВ риврй▒риЧрйЗ риирйЗ риЗри╣ ри╕рйБригри┐риЖ ридри╛риВ риЙри╣риирйЗ риЦрйЛридрйЗ рижри╛ рижри┐ри▓рйЛриВ ризрй░риири╡ри╛риж риХрйАридри╛ риЕридрйЗ риЦрйБри╕ри╝ ри╣рйЛ риХрйЗ риХри╣ри┐риг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, тАЬри╡ри╛ри╣, римриИ ри╡ри╛ри╣, риХрйА риХри╣ри┐ригрйЗ ридрйЗри░рйА риирйЗриХ ри╕ри▓ри╛ри╣ рижрйЗ ! риорйИриВ ридри╛риВ риПриири╛ риЪри┐ри░ риорйВри░риЦ риИ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ риЖриВ ! рикри░ ри╣рйБриг ридрйВрй░ риорйЗри░рйАриЖриВ риЕрй▒риЦри╛риВ риЦрйЛри▓ рижри┐рй▒ридрйАриЖриВ риирйЗ ридрйЗ риорйВри░риЦридри╛ рижрйЗ риШри░ ри╣риирйЗри░рйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪрйЛриВ риХрй▒рив ри▓ри┐риЖ риП ред\\"римрижриХри┐ри╕риоридрйА риири╛ри▓ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ ри▓ри╛риЧрйЗ рижрйЗ риХриори░рйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ римрйИриари╛ ри╕рйА ред риЙри╣риирйЗ риЗри╣риири╛риВ рижрйЛри╣ри╛риВ рижрйАриЖриВ ри╕рин риЧрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ ри╕рйБриг ри▓риИриЖриВ ред риЕриЧри▓рйЗ рижри┐рии ри╕ри╡рйЗри░рйЗ ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ ри╕ри┐ри░ риЖриЗриЖ риЕридрйЗ риврй▒риЧрйЗ риирйВрй░ риЦрйЗрид ри╡ри▓ ри▓рйИ риЧри┐риЖред риЙри╣риирйЗ ри╣ри░ ри░рйЛриЬри╝ ри╡ри╛риВриЭ риЙри╣рижрйА ризрйМриг ридрйЗ рикрй░риЬри╛ри▓рйА рикри╛риИ, рикри░ риврй▒риЧри╛ риЖрикригрйА риери╛риВ ридрйЗ риЕрйЬ риХрйЗ риЦрйЬрйНри╣ риЧри┐риЖред риЙри╣риирйВрй░ ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА риирйЗ римриерйЗри░рйА ри╣рй▒ри▓ри╛ри╕ри╝рйЗри░рйА рижри┐рй▒ридрйА, рикри░ риХри┐рй▒риерйЗ ! риврй▒риЧри╛ ри╣ри┐ри▓риг ридриХ рижри╛ риири╛риВ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйА ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ ред ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА римрйЬри╛ ридрй▒ридри╛ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ридрйЗ риЙри╣риирйВрй░ ри╕рйЛриЯрйЗ риири╛ри▓ рйЩрйВрим риЭрйБрй░римри┐риЖ ред риЗри╕рйЗ риори╛ри░ риХрйБриЯри╛риИ ри╡ри┐риЪ рикрй░риЬри╛ри▓рйА риерй▒ри▓рйЗ риЬри╛ рикриИ риЕридрйЗ риврй░риЧри╛ риЙрй▒риерйЛриВ риирй▒ри╕ риЙриари┐риЖ ред рикри░ ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА ри╡рйА риЙри╣рижри╛ рикри┐рй▒риЫри╛ риЫрй▒рибриг ри╡ри╛ри▓рйА римри▓ри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйА ред риЙри╣риирйЗ риврй▒риЧрйЗ риирйВрй░ риЬри╛ риШрйЗри░ри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ риРри╕ри╛ рилрйИриВриЯри╛ риЪри╛рйЬрйНри╣ри┐риЖ риХри┐ риврй▒риЧри╛ риЙрй▒риерйЗ ри╣рйА ри╡ри┐рй▒риЫ риЧри┐риЖ ред ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ рижри┐рии риврй▒риЧри╛ риЗри╕рйЗ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риЙриерйЗ рикри┐риЖ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ риЕридрйЗ риЙри╣риирйЗ риЬри╝ри░ри╛ риХрй░рио рии риХрйАридри╛ ред ри╕ри╝ри╛рио риирйВрй░ риЬрижрйЛриВ риЙри╣риирйВрй░ риШри░ ри▓ри┐риЖ риХрйЗ рикрй▒риарйЗ рикри╛риП риЧриП, риЙри╣риирйЗ риЙри╣риири╛риВ ри╡ри▓ риорйВрй░ри╣ ридриХ рии риХрйАридри╛ риЕридрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйА ри░ри╛рид ри╣риЙриХрйЗ ри▓рйИриВрижри╛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛редри╕ри╡рйЗри░ ри╕ри╡рйЗри░ риЬриж ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА риЙриерйЗ риЖриЗриЖ, риЙри╣риирйЗ ри╡рйЗриЦри┐риЖ риХри┐ риврй▒риЧрйЗ рижрйА риЦрйБри░ри▓рйА риЙрй▒ри╕рйЗ ридри░ри╛риВ рикрй▒риари┐риЖриВ риири╛ри▓ ринри░рйА рикриИ ри╣рйИ риЕридрйЗ риЙри╣ риЖрик риЪри┐рй▒риХрйЬ риЕридрйЗ риЧрйЛри╣рйЗ риири╛ри▓ ри▓ри┐римрйЬри┐риЖ рикри┐риЖ ри╣рйИред риЙри╣риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, риЙри╣ ри╣рйЛ ! риЗри╣ ридри╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪри╛ри░ри╛ римри┐риори╛ри░ риП ред риорйИриВ риРри╡рйЗриВ риИ риХрй▒ри▓рйНри╣ риЗри╣риирйВрй░ риЧри╝ри░рйАрим риори╛ри░ риХрйАридрйАред ри╡ри┐риЪри╛ри░рйЗ рижрйЗ рикрй▒риарйЗ ри╡рйА ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ рижрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░рйЗ риЙри╕рйЗ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ рикриП риирйЗ редри╕рйЛ риЙри╣ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риХрйЛри▓ риЧри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ риЙри╣риирйВрй░ ри╕ри╛ри░рйА риЧри▓ риЬри╛ ри╕рйБригри╛риИ ред рикри░ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риЬри╛ригрижри╛ ри╕рйА риХри┐ ри╡ри┐рй▒риЪрйЛриВ риЧрй▒ри▓ риХрйА ри╣рйИ ред риЙри╣риирйЗ ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА риирйВрй░ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЬриЬри╛ри╣, риЕрй▒риЬ риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйВрй░ ри▓рйИ риЬри╛ ридрйЗ - риЗри╣рижрйЗ риХрйЛри▓рйЛриВ риврй▒риЧрйЗ рижри╛ риХрй░рио ри▓рйИ ред\\"ри╕рйЛ ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйВрй░ ри▓рйИ риЧри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ рижри┐рии ри╣ри▓ риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ риЬрйЛриИ ри░рй▒риЦри┐риЖ ред риЦрйЛридри╛ риЗридриирйА риори┐ри╣риирид рижри╛ риЖрижрйА риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйА ред риЫрйЗридрйА ри╣рйА риерй▒риХ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ ри╕рйАред ри╣ри╛ри▓рйА риЙрй▒ри╕рйЗ ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡рй▒риЦрйА ри╡ри┐риЪ риЗриХ риЬрйЬ рижри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╕рйА риЕридрйЗ риЙри╣риирйВрй░ риЕриЧри╛риВри╣ ри╣ри┐риХ рижри┐рй░рижри╛ ри╕рйА редриЬрижрйЛриВ ри╕ри╝ри╛рио рикриИ ридри╛риВ риЦрйЗридрйЗ рижрйЗ риЧри▓рйЛриВ ри╣ри▓ ри▓ри╛ри╣ри┐риЖ риЧри┐риЖ ред риЙри╣рижрйАриЖриВ ри▓рй▒ридри╛риВ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЬри╝ри░ри╛ ри╡рйА ри╕ри╛ри╣ ри╕рй▒рид риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйА ред ри╡ри┐риЪри╛ри░ри╛ римрйБри░рйЗ ри╣ри╛ри▓рйАриВ ри╣рйМри▓рйА ри╣рйМри▓рйА ри▓рй░риЧрйЬри╛риЙриВрижри╛ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ риШри░ рикри╣рйБрй░риЪри┐риЖред риЙри╣рижрйАриЖриВ ри╡рй▒риЦрйАриЖриВ ри▓ри╛ри╕ри╝ри╛риВ риири╛ри▓ риирйАри▓рйАриЖриВ ри╣рйЛриИриЖриВ рикриИриЖриВ ри╕рии !риУризри░ риврй▒риЧри╛ ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ рижри┐рии римрйБрй▒ри▓рйЗ ри▓рйБрй▒риЯрижри╛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ред риХрижрйЗ рикрй▒риари┐риЖриВ риирйВрй░ риорйВрй░ри╣ риори╛ри░ ри▓ри╡рйЗ ред риХрижрйЗ риЬри╝ри░ри╛ рикрйВриЫ риири╛ри▓ риорй▒риЦрйАриЖриВ риЙрибри╛ ри▓ри╡рйЗ ред риХрижрйЗ риЖрикригрйЗ риХри┐рй▒ри▓рйЗ рижрйЗ риЧри┐ри░риж рижрйЛ риХрйБ ринрйБриЖриЯригрйАриЖриВ ри╣рйА ри▓рйИ ри▓ри╡рйЗ ред ри░ри╛рид рикрйИриг ридриХ риЙри╣рижри╛ риЪри┐ри╣ри░ри╛ риЦри┐рйЬ риЧри┐риЖ ред риЬрижрйЛриВ риЙри╣риирйЗ риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйВрй░ ри╡ри╛рикри╕ риЖриЙриВрижри┐риЖриВ ри╡рйЗриЦри┐риЖ ридри╛риВ риЙри╣ риХри╣ри┐риг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, тАЬри╣рйЗ риЕриХри▓ рижрйЗ ри╕ри╛риЧри░, ридрйЗри░рйА риИ риирйЗриХ ри╕ри▓ри╛ри╣ рижрйА римрижрйМри▓рид риорйЗри░ри╛ риЬрйАри╡рии ри╕рйМри░ри┐риЖ риП ред риЕриЬ рикри╣ри┐ри▓ри╛ рижри┐рии риП риХри┐ риорйИриВ ри╕рйБриЦ рижри╛ ри╕ри╛ри╣ ри▓ри┐риЖ риП ред риорйИриВ риХри┐ри╕ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ ридрйЗри░ри╛ риЬри╕ риЧри╛ри╡ри╛риВ !''рикри░ риЦрйЛридри╛ ри░рйЛригрйА римрйВриерйА римригри╛риИ риЪрйБрик риЪри╛рик риЦрйЬри╛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ред риЙри╣рижрйА риРри╕рйА рижрйБри░рижри╕ри╝ри╛ ри╕рйА риХри┐ риЙри╣рижрйЗ риорйВрй░ри╣рйЛриВ риЧрй▒ри▓ ридриХ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйА риири┐риХри▓рижрйА риХри┐риЙриВриХри┐ ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ рижри┐рии риЙри╣рижрйАриЖриВ ри╣рй▒рибрйАриЖриВ ри╕ри┐риХрижри┐риЖриВ ри░ри╣рйАриЖриВ ри╕рии ред риЙри╣ риЖрикригрйЗ риории ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╕рйЛриЪриг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, 'риЗри╣ ри╕ри╛ри░рйА риорйБри╕рйАримрид риорйЗри░рйА риЖрикригрйА риИ римрйЗри╡риХрйВрилри╝рйА рижри╛ рииридрйАриЬри╛ риП ред рижрйВриЬри┐риЖриВ рижрйА римри▓ри╛, риЦри╝ри╛ри╣ риориЦри╝ри╛ри╣ риЧри▓ ри╕ри╣рйЗрйЬ ри▓риИ риП ред риЦри╝рйИри░, риорйИриирйВрй░ риШримри░ри╛риЙригри╛ риири╣рйАриВ риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижри╛ ред ри░рй▒рим рижрйА римриЦри╝ри╕ри╝рйА ри╣рйЛриИ риЕриХри▓ риирйВрй░ ри╡ри░рид риХрйЗ риХрйЛриИ ри╣рйЛри░ риХри▓ри╛ риори░рйЛрйЬриирйА риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижрйА риП риЬри┐ри╕ риири╛ри▓ риврй▒риЧри╛ риорйБрйЬ риЖрикригрйЗ риЧрйЗрйЬ ри╡ри┐риЪ рикрйИ риЬри╛риПред риири╣рйАриВ ридри╛риВ риорйЗри░рйА римрйЬрйА ринрйБриЧрид ри╕рйМри░рйЗриЧрйА ридрйЗ риорйЗри░рйЗ ри▓риИ риЬрйАриКригри╛ риорйБри╣ри╛ри▓ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риПриЧри╛редтАЩриХрйБриЭ риЪри┐ри░ рикри┐рй▒риЫрйЛриВ риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйЗ рикрй▒риарйЗ риЦри╛ригрйЗ ри╢рйБри░рйВ риХри░ рижри┐ридрйЗ ред риврй▒риЧри╛ риХрйЛри▓ риЦрйЬри╛ риЙри╣риирйВрй░ ри╕ри▓ри╛ри╣рйБрй░рижри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕рйА риерй▒риХрижри╛редриЙри╕рйЗ ри░ри╛рид ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риЖрикригрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риЕридрйЗ римрй▒риЪри┐риЖриВ риири╛ри▓ риЪрй░рижри░риорйЗ рижрйА ри░рйЛри╕ри╝риирйА ри╡ри┐риЪ риШри░ рижрйА риЫрй▒рид ридрйЗ римрйИриари╛ риЧрй▒рикри╛риВ риори╛ри░ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйА' риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйЗ риврй▒риЧрйЗ риирйВрй░ риЖриЦри┐риЖ тАЬри╕рйБригри╛, римриИ ! рилрйЗри░ риХрй▒ри▓рйНри╣ ри▓риИ ридрйЗри░ри╛ риХрйА риЗри░ри╛рижри╛ риП ?\\"риврй▒риЧрйЗ риирйЗ риЙрй▒ридри░ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛, тАЬриЗри░ри╛рижри╛ риХрйА ри╣рйЛригри╛ риПред ридрйВрй░ риЬри┐ри╣рйЬрйА риорй▒рид рижри┐рй▒ридрйА риП риЙри╣рижрйА ри░рйАри╕ риири╣рйАриВ ред риорйЗри░рйА риЬри╛риЪрйЗ риЗри╣ риирйБри╕риЦри╛ ридри╛риВ ри╕ри╛ри░рйА риЙриори░ ри╡ри░ридригри╛ риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижри╛ риП ред ри╕ри╛ри░ри╛ рижри┐рии риорйМриЬ риХри░рижри╛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ риЖриВ ред риорйИриирйВрй░ ри╣рйЛри░ риХрйА риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижри╛ риП !тАЭрикри░ риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйЗ ри╕ри┐ри░ рилрйЗри░ри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ риЖриЦри┐риЖ, 'риири╛, риири╛ ! риХри┐ридрйЗ риЗри╕ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риири╛ риХри░ римрйИриарйА !\\"тАЬриХри┐риЙриВ ?\\" риврй▒риЧрйЗ риирйЗ ри╣рйИри░ри╛рии ри╣рйЛ риХрйЗ рикрйБрй▒риЫри┐риЖ редриЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЬриЗриХ риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╕рижри╛ ри▓риИ рикрй▒ри▓рйЗ риири╣рйАриВ римрй░риирйНри╣ риЫрй▒рибрйАрижрйА ред риХриИ ри╡ри╛ри░ риЙри╣ рикрйБрй▒риарйА ри╡рйА рикрйИ риЬри╛риВрижрйА риП ред риорйЗри░рйЗ риХрйЛри▓ риири╡рйАриЖриВ риири╡рйАриЖриВ риЧрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ рижри╛ риХрйЛриИ риШри╛риЯри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ред риЬри┐рй░риирйАриЖриВ ри╕ри▓ри╛ри╣ри╛риВ риХри╣рйЗриВ ридрйИриирйВрй░ рижрйЗ рижри╡ри╛риВред риорйИриВ риЕриЬ ри╣рйА риори╛ри▓риХ риирйВрй░ риЗри╣ риХри╣ри┐рй░рижри┐риЖриВ ри╕рйБригри┐риЖ риПриВ, 'риЬрйЗ римрйИри▓ риЗри╕рйЗ ридри░ри╛риВ риХри▓ ри╡рйА риХрй░рио риири╛риВ риХри░рйЗ, ридри╛риВ риЗри╣риирйВрй░ риХри╕ри╛риИ рижрйЗ ри╣ри╡ри╛ри▓рйЗ риХри░ рижри┐риУред риЗри╣ риЧри╝ри░рйАримри╛риВ рижрйЗ риЦри╛риг рижрйЗ риХрй░рио риИ риЖриК ридрйЗ риЕри╕рйАриВ риЗри╣рижрйА риЦрй▒ри▓ ри╡рйЗриЪ риХрйЗ риЪри╛ри░ рикрйИри╕рйЗ риИ ри╡риЯ ри▓ри╡ри╛риВриЧрйЗ ред' риЗри╣ ридрйВрй░ ри╣рйБриг ри╕рйЛриЪ ри▓рйИ ! риХри┐ридрйЗ ри╣ри╛ри╕рйЗ рижри╛ риорйЬри╛ри╕ри╛ риИ риири╛ римриг риЬри╛риПред риорйИриВ ридрйИриирйВрй░ риЦри╝римри░рижри╛ри░ риХри░ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛ риП ! ридрйВрй░ риЕрй▒риЧрйЗ риЖрикригри╛ рикрйЬрйНри╣ри┐риЖ ри╡ри┐риЪри╛ри░ред'' риЬрижрйЛриВ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риирйЗ риЗри╣ ри╕рйБригри┐риЖ, риЙри╣ риЦри┐рйЬ риЦри┐рйЬри╛ риХрйЗ ри╣ри╕ рикри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ риЗридриири╛ ри╣ри╕ри┐риЖ риХри┐ риЙриерйЗ ри▓рйЛриЯ рикрйЛриЯ ри╣рйЛ риЧри┐риЖ редриЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риЙри╣риирйВрй░ рикрйБрй▒риЫриг ри▓рй▒риЧрйА, тАЬриХрйЛриИ риРри╕рйА ри╡рйИри╕рйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ридри╛риВ ри╣рйЛриИ риири╣рйАриВред риЗри╣ ри╣ри╛ри╕ри╛ риХри╛ри╣рижри╛ риП ?''риЙри╣риирйЗ риЙрй▒ридри░ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛, тАЬриврй▒риЧрйЗ ридрйЗ риЦрйЛридрйЗ рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╕рйБриг риХрйЗ риорйЗри░ри╛ ри╣ри╛ри╕ри╛ риири╣рйАриВ ри░рйБриХрижри╛ред\\"риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риирйЗ рикрйБрй▒риЫри┐риЖ, тАЬриорйИриирйВрй░ ри╡рйА ридри╛риВ риХрйБриЭ рикридри╛ ри▓риЧрйЗ ред риЙри╣ риХрйА риХри╣ри┐ ри░ри╣рйЗ риирйЗ редтАЭри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риирйЗ риЙрй▒ридри░ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛, тАЬриЗри╣ риорйИриВ риири╣рйАриВ рижри╕ ри╕риХрижри╛ ! риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риирйЗ риЖриЦри┐риЖ, тАЬридрйБри╣ри╛риирйВрй░ риЬри╝ри░рйВри░ рижрй▒ри╕ригри╛ рикриПриЧри╛ред''ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риирйЗ рилрйЗри░ риЙрй▒ридри░ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛, тАЬриири╣рйАриВ, риорйИриВ ридрйИриирйВрй░ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ риЬрйБ риП риорйИриВ рижри╕ риири╣рйАриВ ри╕риХрижри╛ред ридрйИриирйВрй░ рикридри╛ риири╣рйАриВ риЗри╣ рижрй▒ри╕риг рижрйА ри╕риЬри╝ри╛ риорйМрид риП редтАЭрикри░ риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риирйЗ риЖриЦри┐риЖ, \\"риЗри╣ ридри╛риВ риири┐ри░ри╛ риЭрйВриа риП ред риорйИриирйВрй░ ринрйЛри▓рйА ринри╛ри▓рйА ри╕риориЭ риХрйЗ риариЧрижрйЗ риУ ! ри╣ри╕ риорйЗри░рйЗ ридрйЗ ри░ри╣рйЗ риУ ридрйЗ риири╛риВ рикри╢рйВриЖриВ рижри╛ ри▓ри╛ ри░ри╣рйЗ риУ ред риорйИриерйЛриВ риЬри╝ри░рйВри░ ридрйБри╕рйАриВ риХрйБриЭ ри▓рйБриХри╛ ри░ри╣рйЗ риУ ред рикри░ риЬрйЗ ридрйБри╕рйАриВ риорйИриирйВрй░ риири╣рйАриВ рижри╕рйЛриЧрйЗ ридри╛риВ риорйИриВ риЗриерйЛриВ риЪри▓рйА риЬри╛ригри╛ риП риорйБрйЬ риХрижрйЗ ри╡рйА риири╣рйАриВ риЖриЙригри╛ !\\"риЗри╣ риХри╣ри┐ риХрйЗ риЙри╣ римрйИриа риЧриИ риЕридрйЗ риЙрй▒риЪрйА риЙрй▒риЪрйА ри░рйЛриг ри▓риЧ рикриИ ред ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛, тАЬридрйВрй░ ри╢рйБрижрйИриг ридри╛риВ риири╣рйАриВ ри╣рйЛ риЧриИ? ри░рй▒рим ридрйЛриВ рибри░ ридрйЗ риЬри╛риг рижрйЗ риЗри╕ риЧри▓ риирйВрй░ ред риРри╡рйЗриВ риири┐рй▒риХрйА риЬри┐ри╣рйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ридрйЗ риХри▓рйЗри╕ри╝ риири╣рйАриВ риХри░рйАрижри╛ редтАЭрикри░ риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риЬри┐рй▒рижрйА рикрйИ риЧриИ риЕридрйЗ риХри╣ри┐риг ри▓рй▒риЧрйА, 'риири╣рйАриВ, риири╣рйАриВ, риорйИриирйВрй░ ри╕риЪ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ ридрйБри╕рйАриВ ри╣рй▒ри╕рйЗ риХри┐риЙриВ риУ !'ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риирйЗ риЙрй▒ридри░ рижри┐рй▒ридри╛, тАЬринри▓рйАриП ри▓рйЛриХрйЗ, ридрйИриирйВрй░ рикридри╛ риП риХри┐ риЬрижрйЛриВ ри░рй▒рим риирйЗ риорйИриирйВрй░ риЬри╛риири╡ри░ри╛риВ ридрйЗ рикрй░риЫрйАриЖриВ рижрйА римрйЛри▓рйА ри╕риориЭриг рижрйА ри╕ри╝риХридрйА рижри┐рй▒ридрйА ри╕рйА ридри╛риВ риири╛ри▓ риИ риЙри╣риирйЗ риХри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйА риХри┐ риЬрйЗ риорйИриВ риЗри╕ римри╛ри░рйЗ риХри┐ри╕рйЗ риирйВрй░ рижрй▒ри╕ри┐риЖ ридри╛риВ риорйИриВ риири╣рйАриВ римриЪригри╛ ! риЦри╛риориЦри╝ри╛ри╣ рижри╛ риЕрйЬримрикрйБригри╛ риЫрй▒риб рижрйЗ ред\\"тАЬрикри░ри╡ри╛ри╣ риири╣рйАриВ ! риорйИриирйВрй░ рйЫри░рйВри░ рижрй▒ри╕рйЛ риХри┐ риврй▒риЧрйЗ ридрйЗ риЦрйЛридрйЗ риирйЗ риЗриХ рижрйВриЬрйЗ риирйВрй░ риХрйА риХри┐ри╣ри╛ риП ред риПриерйЗ риХри┐ри╕рйЗ римри╣ри┐ ри░ри╣ри┐ригри╛ риП ред риЕрй░рид ри╡рйЗри▓ри╛ ридри╛риВ риЕрйЩрйАри░ ри╕рин рижри╛ риЖриЙригри╛ риИ риПриВредтАЭриЗри╕ ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риЙри╣рижрйЗ риЦри╣ри┐рйЬрйЗ рикрйИ риЧриИ риЕридрйЗ риЙри╣ римрйЬри╛ риЕри╡ри╛риЬри╝ри╛ри░ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ред рикри░ риЙри╣ риЖрикригрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риири╛ри▓ римрйЬри╛ рикри┐риЖри░ риХри░рижри╛ ри╕рйА ред риЗри╕ ри▓риИ риЗриХ рижри┐рии риЙри╣ ридрй░риЧ риЖ риХрйЗ риЖриЦриг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, ''риЕрй▒риЫри╛, ридри╛риВ римрйБри▓ри╛ ри▓ри┐риЖ риЖрикригрйЗ риори╛риВ рикри┐риУ ридрйЗ ри╣рйЛри░ ри╕ри╛риХ ри╕римрй░ризрйАриЖриВ риирйВрй░ ридри╛риВ риЬрйЛ риорйИриВ риори░рии ридрйЛриВ рикри╣ри┐ри▓ри╛риВ риЖрикригрйА ри╡ри╕рйАриЕрид риХри░ риЬри╛ри╡ри╛риВ редтАЭри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риХрйЛри▓ риЗриХ риХрйБрй▒ридри╛, риЗриХ риХрйБрй▒риХрйЬ риЕридрйЗ рикрй░риЬри╛ри╣ риХрйБ риХрйБриХрйЬрйАриЖриВ ри╡рйА ри╕рии ред риЬрижрйЛриВ риЙри╣ риЖрикригрйЗ риЕрй░рид ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ рижрйА ридри┐риЖри░рйА риХри░ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ ри╕рйА, ридри╛риВ риЙри╣риирйЗ риХрйБрй▒ридрйЗ риЕридрйЗ риХрйБрй▒риХрйЬ риирйВрй░ риЧрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ риХри░рижри┐риЖриВ ри╕рйБригри┐риЖ ред риХрйБрй▒ридрйЗ риирйЗ риХрйБрй▒риХрйЬ риирйВрй░ риЖриЦри┐риЖ, тАЬриХрйА ридрйИриирйВрй░ рикридри╛ риП риХри┐ ри╕ри╛рибри╛ риори╛ри▓риХ риори░рии ри▓риИ ридри┐риЖри░ ри╣рйЛ ри░ри┐ри╣ри╛ риП ред риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риЗри╕ риЧрй▒ри▓ ридрйЗ риЕрйЬрйА ри╣рйЛриИ риП риХри┐ риЙри╣риирйВрй░ ри╕ри╛рибрйАриЖриВ ри╕рйБригрйАриЖриВ ри╣рйЛриИриЖриВ риЧрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ рижри╕рйЗ ред риЙри╣рижрйЗ ри╕риориЭри╛риг римрйБриЭри╛риг ридрйЗ ри╡рйА риЙри╣ римри╛риЬ риири╣рйАриВ риЖ ри░ри╣рйА редриХрйБрй▒риХрйЬ риирйЗ риЖриЦри┐риЖ, тАЬри╕ри╛рибри╛ риори╛ри▓риХ риЖриЦрижри╛ ридри╛риВ риП риХри┐ риЙри╣риирйВрй░ риЧрйИрим рижрйАриЖриВ риЧрй▒ри▓ри╛риВ рижри╛ рикридри╛ риП, рикри░ риХрйА ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ риЬрйЗ риЙри╣ риЖрикригрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риирйВрй░ ри╡рйА риири╣рйАриВ риЪри╛ри░ ри╕риХрижри╛ !тАЭриХрйБрй▒ридрйЗ риирйЗ рикрйБрй▒риЫри┐риЖ, тАЬрилрйЗри░ ридрйЗри░рйЗ рйЩри┐риЖри▓ ри╡ри┐риЪ ри╕ри╛рибрйЗ риори╛ри▓риХ риирйВрй░ ри╣рйБриг риХрйА риХри░риири╛ риЪри╛ри╣рйАрижри╛ риП ?тАЭтАЬриХри┐риЙриВ, риЗри╣ ридри╛риВ риЧрй▒ри▓ риИ риХрйБриЭ риири╣рйАриВ ! риЖрикригрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риирйВрй░ риЗри╣ риХри╣ри┐ рижри╡рйЗ риХри┐ ри╕рйБригрии ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ ри╕рижри╛ ри▓риИ ри╢ри╝рйБрижри╛риИ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ риП ридрйЗ риЙри╣рижрйА риорйМрид римрйБри░рйА ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ ри╣рйБрй░рижрйА риП ред римри╕ риЗри╕рйЗ рибри░ риири╛ри▓ риИ риЙри╣ риЖрикригрйА риЬри┐рй▒риж риЫрй▒риб рижри╡рйЗриЧрйА редтАЭри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риХрйБрй▒риХрйЬ рижрйА риЧрй▒ри▓ ри╕рйБриг риХрйЗ римри╣рйБрид риЦрйБри╕ри╝ ри╣рйЛриЗриЖ ред риЙри╣ риЙри╕рйЗ ри╡рйЗри▓рйЗ риЖрикригрйЗ риХриори░рйЗ ри╡ри┐риЪ риЧри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ риЖрикригрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риирйВрй░ римрйБри▓ри╛ риХрйЗ риХри╣ри┐риг ри▓рй▒риЧри╛, 'ри╣ри╛риВ ри╕рй▒риЪ, риЗри╣ рижри╕ригри╛ ридри╛риВ риорйИриВ ринрйБри▓ риИ риЧри┐риЖ ри╕ри╛риВ риХри┐ ринрйЗрид ри╡ри╛ри▓рйА риЧрй▒ри▓ риирйВрй░ ри╕рйБригрии ри╡ри╛ри▓ри╛ ри╡рйА риири╛ри▓ риИ ри╢рйБрижри╛риИ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛риВрижри╛ риП ридрйЗ римрйБри░рйА ридри░рйНри╣ри╛риВ риори░рижри╛ риП ! ри╕рйЛ ридрйВрй░ ри╡рйА риори░рии ри▓риИ ридри┐риЖри░ ри╣рйЛ риЬри╛ред''риЗри╣ ри╕рйБригрижри┐риЖриВ ри╣рйА риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА рижрйЗ ри╣рйЛри╕ри╝ риЙрй▒риб риЧриП риЕридрйЗ риЙри╣ риШримри░ри╛ риХрйЗ римрйЛри▓рйА, тАЬриири╛, риири╛, риЗри╣рйЛ риЬри╣рйА риЧри▓ ри╕рйБригриирйЛриВ риХрйА риерйБрйЬрйНри╣ри┐риЖ риП ! риорйИриВ ри╕ри╝рйБрижрйИриг риерйЛрйЬрйНри╣рйА риЖриВ ред риорйИриВ ридри╛риВ риРри╡рйЗриВ ри╣рй▒ри╕ ри░ри╣рйА ри╕ри╛риВ !\\" ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риирйЗ риЖриЦри┐риЖ-''риЪрй░риЧри╛ ! рилрйЗри░ риири╛ риХрижрйА рикрйБрй▒риарйЗ ри╕ри┐рй▒ризрйЗ ри╕ри╡ри╛ри▓ риХри░рйАриВредтАЭриЗри╕ ридрйЛриВ рикри┐рй▒риЫрйЛриВ ри╕рйМрижри╛риЧри░ риЦри╝рйБри╕ри╝рйА риЦри╝рйБри╕ри╝рйА ри░ри╣ри┐риг ри▓риЧ рикри┐риЖ риЕридрйЗ риЙри╣рижрйА ри╡ри╣рйБриЯрйА риирйЗ рилрйЗри░ риХрижрйА риЕрйЬрйА риири╣рйАриВ риХрйАридрйА ред"},{"question":"Raha resaka sakafo, inona avy no afaka hanaovana ny voatabia?","answer":"Ny voatabia dia afaka hanaovana:- lasary na rogay- sosy miaraka amin'ny tongolo na sosy amin'izao - ranom-boankazo - fangaro-kanina ( mofo hamburger ... )"},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐:родроЮрпНроЪрпИропро┐ро▓рпН рокрпКро▒ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│ роЕро░роЪро╛рогрпИропро╛ро▓рпН роЕро▒ро┐ропрокрпНрокроЯрпБроорпН роЪрпЖропрпНродро┐ ропро╛родрпБ?","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН:родроЮрпНроЪро╛ро╡рпВро░ро┐ро▓рпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроирпНрод роЖроХроо роЪро╛ро╕рпНродро┐ро░ рокрогрпНроЯро┐родро░ро╛роХро┐роп роЪро░рпНро╡роЪро┐ро╡ рокрогрпНроЯро┐родро░ро┐роЯродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН рокро▓ роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпИроЪрпН  роЪро╛ро░рпНроирпНрод рооро╛рогро╛роХрпНроХро░рпНроХро│рпН роХро▓рпНро╡ро┐роХрпН роХро▒рпНроХ ро╡роирпНродро┐ро░рпБроирпНродро╛ро░рпНроХро│рпН роОройрпНро▒ роЪрпЖропрпНродро┐, роорпБродро▓рпН роЗро░ро╛роЬро░ро╛роЬ роЪрпЛро┤ройрпН роХро╛ро▓родрпНродро┐ро▓рпН родроЮрпНроЪрпИропро┐ро▓рпН рокрпКро▒ро┐роХрпНроХрокрпНрокроЯрпНроЯрпБро│рпНро│родрпБ."},{"question":"╪п ╪з┘Б╪║╪з┘Ж╪│╪к╪з┘Ж ╪к┘И┌й┘Е█М╪▓ ┘И█М╪┤ ╪п ╪к╪з╪▒█М╪о ┘╛┘З ╪з┘И┌Ц╪п┘И ┌й█Р ╪о┘╛┘Д ┘╝┘И┘Д┘Ж█М╪▓-╪│█М╪з╪│┘К ┘Е┘Ж╪╕╪▒┘З ┌Е┘Ж┌л┘З ╪и╪п┘Д┘З ┌й┌У█Р ╪п┘З╪Я","answer":"╪п ╪з┘Б╪║╪з┘Ж╪│╪к╪з┘Ж ╪к┘И┌й┘Е█М╪▓ ┘И█М╪┤╪М ┌Ж█Р ╪п ┘Д┘И█М┘И ┌Й┘Д┘И ┘Д┌й┘З ┘╛┌Ъ╪к┘И┘Ж╪М ╪к╪з╪м┌й╪М ┘З╪▓╪з╪▒┘З ╪з┘И ╪з╪▓╪и┌й┘И ┌Е╪о┘З ╪м┘И┌У ╪п█М╪М ╪п ┘З█М┘И╪з╪п ╪п ┘╛█М┌Ж┘Д█Р ┘╝┘И┘Д┘Ж█М╪▓-╪│█М╪з╪│┘К ┘Е┘Ж╪╕╪▒█Р ┘╛┘З ╪м┘И┌У┘И┘Д┘И ┌й█Р ┘Е┘З┘Е ╪▒┘И┘Д ┘Д┘И╪и┘И┘Д█М ╪п█М. ┘╛┘З ╪к╪з╪▒█М╪о┘К ╪к┘И┌л┘З╪М ╪п ┘И╪з┌й ┘Е╪и╪з╪▒╪▓█Р ╪з┘И ╪┤╪о┌У█Р ╪з┌й╪л╪▒╪з ┘╛┘З ┘В┘И┘Е┘К ╪к╪з┘И╪к╪▒█М╪о┘И╪з┘Д┘И ┌й█Р ╪▒█М┌Ъ█Р ┘Д╪▒┘К╪М ┌Ж█Р ┘Е╪о╪к┘Д┘Б ┌л╪▒┘И┘╛┘И┘Ж┘З ╪п ┘Ж┘Б┘И╪░ ╪з┘И ╪з╪│╪к╪з╪▓█М╪к┘И╪и ┘Д┘╛╪з╪▒┘З ╪│█М╪з┘Д┘К ┌й┘И┘К. ╪п ┘╛┌Ъ╪к┘Ж┘И ┘И╪з┌й┘Е┘Ж┘К╪М ┌Ж█Р ╪к╪▒ ┘╝┘И┘Д┘И ┘Д┘И█М┘З ╪к┘И┌й┘Е█М╪▓┘З ┌Й┘Д┘З ╪п┘З╪М █М┘И┘З ╪к┌й╪▒╪з╪▒┘К ┘Е┘И╪╢┘И╪╣ ╪п┘З╪М ┌Ж█Р ╪п ╪н┌й┘И┘Е╪к┘И╪з┘Д█Н ┘╛┘З ╪к╪н╪▒┌й╪з╪к┘И ╪з╪║█М╪▓┘З ┌й┘И┘К ╪з┘И ╪п ╪и█Р ╪л╪и╪з╪к█Н ┘╛┘З ╪п┘И╪▒┘З ┌й█Р ┘Е╪▒╪│╪к┘З ┌й┘И┘К. ╪п ┘Е╪о╪к┘Д┘Б┘И ┘В┘И┘Е┘И┘Ж┘И ╪к╪▒┘Е┘Ж┌Б ╪п ┘Е┘Ж╪з╪и╪╣┘И╪М ╪│█М╪з╪│┘К ┘И╪з┌й╪М ╪з┘И ┌й┘Д╪к┘И╪▒┘К ┘╛█М┌Ш┘Ж╪п┘Ж█Р ╪│█М╪з┘Д█Н ╪┤╪о┌У┘И ╪к┘З ┘Д╪з╪▒┘З ┘З┘И╪з╪▒┘З ┌й┌У█Р╪М ┌Ж█Р ╪п █М┘И ┘З┘Е╪║┌Ц┘К ┘Е┘Д┘К ┘З┘И█М╪к ╪п ┘╛╪▒╪з╪о╪к█М╪з ┘Е╪о┘З ┘Ж█М╪│┘К. ╪п █М┘И ┘╝┘И┘Д ╪┤┘Е┘И┘Д┘З ╪│█М╪з╪│┘К ╪│█М╪│┘╝┘Е ╪п ╪▒╪з┘Е█М┘Ж┌Б╪к┘З ┌й┘И┘Д┘И ┘З┌Е█Р ┌Ж█Р ╪п ┘╝┘И┘Д┘И ╪к┘И┌й┘Е┘И┘Ж┘И ┌л┘╝█Р ┘╛┌й█Р ┌Б╪з█М ┘╛┘З ┌Б╪з█М ╪┤┘И┘К ╪▒┘И╪з┘Ж█Р ╪п┘К╪М ┘╛┘З ╪з┘Б╪║╪з┘Ж ╪п┘И┘Д╪к ┌й█Р ╪п ╪к┘Ж┘И╪╣ ╪п ╪з┘Ж┌Й┘И┘Д ┌й┘И┘Д┘И ┘╛█М┌Ж┘Д█Р ┘Ж┘Ж┌л┘И┘Ж█Р ┘Е┘Ж╪╣┌й╪│ ┌й┘И┘К."},{"question":"Taiza no niandohan'ny kafe?","answer":"Avy any Etiopia ny kafe, izay nahitana ny hazo kafe voalohany. Niparitaka nanerana izao tontolo izao ny zava-pisotro avy eo taminтАЩny alalanтАЩny varotra."},{"question":"ркжрлВркз рккрлМрк╡рк╛ ркмркирк╛рк╡рк╡рк╛ркирлА рк╕рлНрккрлЗрк╢рлНркпрк▓ рк░рлЗрк╕рлАрккрлА ркЬркгрк╛рк╡рлЛ.","answer":"1. ркжрлВркзркирлЗ ркЙркХрк╛рк│рлА рк▓рлЛ, ркдрлЗркорк╛ ркЦрк╛ркВркб ркирк╛ркЦрлЛ ркЕркирлЗ ркЦрк╛ркВркб ркУркЧрк│рлЗ ркдрлНркпрк╛ркВ рк╕рлБркзрлА рк╣рк▓рк╛рк╡рлЛ. 2. ркжрлВркзркирлЗ ркаркВркбрлБ ркерк╡рк╛ ркжрлЛ. 3. рк╣рк╡рлЗ рккрлМркЖркирлЗ ркзрлЛркИ рк▓рлЛ. ркзрлЛркпрлЗрк▓рк╛ рккрлМркЖркирлЗ ркаркВркбрк╛ ркжрлВркзркорк╛ркВ ркирк╛ркЦрлЛ. 4. рк╣рк╡рлЗ ркжрлВркз-рккрлМркЖркирлЗ 4-5 ркХрк▓рк╛ркХ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ рклрлНрк░рлАркЬркорк╛ркВ ркорлБркХрлЛ. 5. рк╣рк╡рлЗ ркдрлЗркорк╛ркВ ркИрк▓рк╛ркпркЪрлА рккрк╛рк╡ркбрк░ ркирк╛ркЦрлА рк╣рк▓рк╛рк╡рлА рк▓рлЛ. 6. ркжрлВркз рккрлМркЖ ркдрлИркпрк╛рк░ ркЫрлЗ. ркЖ ркжрлВркз рккрлМркЖркирлЗ ркЪрк╛ркВркжркирлА рк░рк╛ркдркорк╛ркВ ркмрлЗрк╕рлАркирлЗ ркдрлЗркирлЛ ркЖркиркВркж ркЙркарк╛рк╡рлЛ."},{"question":"с╗Мlс╗Нpaa n wa mс╗Нlс║╣bi с╗Нmс╗Нbinrin ti wс╗Нn ba oku с║╣ lotс║╣с║╣li kan ni Kwara","answer":"с╗Мmс╗Нbinrin kan ti wс╗Нn ko ti i mс╗Н ibi to ti wa, ni wс╗Нn ba oku rс║╣ nileetura kan, Premium Diamond, to wa ni agbegbe Adewс╗Нle, nijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ Iwс╗Н Oorun Ilс╗Нrin (West)  nipinlс║╣ Kwara.Agbс║╣nusс╗Н ileeс╣гс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa, с║╣ka ti ipinlс║╣ Kwara, с╗Мgbс║╣ni с╗Мkasanmi Ajayi, lo fidi iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ naa mulс║╣ ninu atс║╣jade kan to fi lede lс╗Нjс╗Н Iс╣гс║╣gun, Tusidee, с╗Нс╣гс║╣ yii. O lobinrin ti wс╗Нn pa sileetura с╗Нhun ni wс╗Нn o ti ri с║╣nikс║╣ni ko waa beere rс║╣, ati pe awс╗Нn Dokita ti с╣гe ayс║╣wo oku naa ti gbogbo ara rс║╣ с╣гi pe pс║╣rс║╣pс║╣rс║╣.Ileeс╣гс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ipinlс║╣ Kwara ti waa kede pe gbogbo obi ati alagbatс╗Н ti wс╗Нn o ba ri с╗Нmс╗Нbinrin wс╗Нn bс║╣rс║╣ lati с╗Нjс╗Н kejidinlс╗Нgbс╗Нn, oс╣гu karun-un, с╗Нdun yii, ki wс╗Нn wa si с║╣ka to n ri si с╗Нrс╗Н oku, lolu ileeс╣гс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ipinlс║╣ Kwara, lati wo oku с╗Нmс╗Нbinrin с╗Нhun, ki wс╗Нn le gba oku wс╗Нn.Nigba ti с╗Мkasanmi n с╣гalaye lori iс╣гс║╣lс║╣ naa, o ni с╗Нjс╗Н kс║╣tadinlс╗Нgbс╗Нn, oс╣гu kс║╣fa yii, ni arakunrin kan torukс╗Н rс║╣ n jс║╣ с╗Мlamilekan Hanafi to jс║╣ alaamojuto ileetura Premium Diamond, to wa ni Adewс╗Нle, niluu Ilс╗Нrin, pe ileesс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa, to si salaye pe с╗Нkunrin kan torukс╗Н rс║╣ n jс║╣ Adegboyega James, (No 12, Okelewo Street, с║╕dс║╣) nipinlс║╣ с╗Мsun, waa gba yara, lс║╣yin to gba a tan lo jade lс╗Н, nigba to de pada loun pс║╣lu с╗Нmс╗Нbinrin kan jс╗Н pada de lalс║╣ с╗Нjс╗Н naa, с╣гugbс╗Нn nigba to di owurс╗Н с╗Нjс╗Н keji ti awс╗Нn ko gbс╗Н nnkan kan ninu yara naa lawс╗Нn lo kс╗Нkс╗Нrс╗Н miiran lati с╣гilс║╣kun, с╣гugbс╗Нn iyalс║╣nu lo jс║╣ pe oku obinrin yii nikan lawс╗Нn ri ninu yara, awс╗Нn o si mс╗Н igba ti с╗Нmс╗Нkunrin с╗Нhun sa lс╗Н. Lс║╣yin iwadii ni awс╗Нn too mс╗Н pe ayederu ni adirс║╣si to fi silс║╣.с╗Мkasanmi ni Kс╗Нmiс╣гanna с╗Нlс╗Нpaa, Mohammed Lawal Bagega, ti paс╣гс║╣ pe ki wс╗Нn mu awс╗Нn to n sakoso ileetura с╗Нhun fun с║╣kunrс║╣rс║╣ iwadii."},{"question":"Awс╗Нn с╗Нmo Oodua ni Kwara ati Kogi fс║╣с║╣ darapс╗Н mс╗Н awс╗Нn eeyan wс╗Нn nilс║╣ Yoruba","answer":"Awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н Yoruba ti wс╗Нn wa ni ipinlс║╣ Kwara ati Kogi ti kс╗Нwe si ile igbimс╗Н aс╣гofin agba lati beere fun с║╣tс╗Н didarapс╗Н mс╗Н awс╗Нn eeyan wс╗Нn nilс║╣ Yoruba yooku. Wс╗Нn ni ki wс╗Нn с╣гe atunс╣гe si aala ilс║╣ ni agbegbe mejeeji, ki awс╗Нn le bс╗Н si aarin awс╗Нn с╗Н╠Дo baba awс╗Нn.с║╕gbс║╣ awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н Yoruba to wa ijс╗Нba ibilс║╣ meje ni Kwara, ti marun-un wa ni Kogi, ni wс╗Нn panupс╗Н sс╗Нrс╗Н yii lс╗Нjс╗Н с║╕ti, Fraidee, to kс╗Нja pe awс╗Нn ti kс╗Нwe ranс╣гс║╣ s├н ile igbimс╗Н aс╣гofin agba, ti awс╗Нn si sс╗Н pe yoo wu awс╗Нn ti ijс╗Нba ba le с╣гe atunс╣гe si eto aala ilс║╣, eyi ti yoo fun awс╗Нn lanfaani lati wa lara awс╗Нn ilс║╣ Yoruba yooku ni Naijiria.Orukс╗Н с║╣gbс║╣ wс╗Нn naa ni Kwara South Consultative Forum.Ninu с╗Нrс╗Н Aarс║╣ с║╣gbс║╣ naa, Alagba Joseph Aderibigbe, с║╣ni to jс║╣ akс╗Нwe agba akс╗Нkс╗Н fun ijс╗Нba ipinlс║╣ Kwara lс╗Нdun 1967, o ni iwe awс╗Нn ti wa nile igbimс╗Н aс╣гofin agba, ohun tawс╗Нn si fс║╣ ni bi gbogbo aye yoo с╣гe maa ri awс╗Нn Yoruba t├│ w├а n├н Kwara ├аti Kogi bi Yoruba tootс╗Н, tawс╗Нn eeyan awс╗Нn ti wс╗Нn wa ni iha Iwс╗Н-oorun Naijiria yoo si mс╗Н pe с╗Нkan naa l├аwс╗Нn n с╣гe.Bс║╣с║╣ gс║╣gс║╣ ni won tun bс║╣bс║╣ pe inu awс╗Нn yoo dun ti awс╗Нn naa ba ni eto iс╣гakoso to dara bii tawon ilс║╣╠А Yor├╣b├б yooku lawс╗Нn agbegbe ti ori da wс╗Нn si. Ati pe yoo jс║╣ ohun idunnu ti awс╗Нn Yoruba to wa ni ├мjс╗Нba ibilс║╣ marun-un ni Kogi ba le wa labс║╣ akoso awс╗Нn Yoruba Kwara, eyi ti yoo f├н wс╗Нn han gс║╣gс║╣ с╗Нkan lara awс╗Нn с║╣ya Yoruba ti wс╗Нn n gbe nilс║╣ Yoruba."},{"question":"Mowduuc kusaaabsan Qodbada jimcaha maiqori kartaaa ?","answer":"Haa waan kuqori karaa isheeg Mowduuca ."},{"question":"Nork idatzi zuen \\"Moby Dick\\" liburua?","answer":"\\"Moby Dick\\" liburua Herman Melvillek idatzi zuen."},{"question":"Wat is een Trachysarus ovalipennis?","answer":"Een Trachysarus ovalipennis is een keversoort uit de familie van de loopkevers. De wetenschappelijke naam van de soort is voor het eerst geldig gepubliceerd in 1955 door Straneo en Jeannel. "},{"question":"Generate a headline for the following text: nTawagar kwallon kafa ta mata ta Afirka ta Kudu ta yi nasara a kan ta Najeriya da ci 2-1 a wasan farko a rukuni na uku a gasar cin kofin Afirka a Morocco. Banyana-Banyana ta ci kwallayen ta hannun Jermaine Seoposenwe da kuma Hildah Tholakele Magaia. Najeriya ta zare kwallo daya daf da za a tashi daga karawar ta hannun Rasheedat Ajibade. Super Falcons mai kofi uku a jere 11 jumulla a gasar kofin Afirka, za ta yi wasa na biyu a rukuni na uku da Bostwana ranar 7 ga watan Yuni. A kuma ranar Banyana-Banyana za ta kece raini da Burundi. A cikin watan Satumba tawagar Afirka ta Kudu ta doke Super Falcons da ci 4-2 a gasar Aisha Buhari Cup ta kuma lashe kofin a Najeriya. Ranar Talata Rukunin farko zai yi wasa na biyu, inda mai masaukin baki Morocco za ta fafata da Uganda, yayin da Senegal za ta yi gumurzu da Burkina Faso. Morocco tana da maki uku, bayan cin Burkina Faso 1-0 ranar Asabar, ita kuwa Senegal ta doke Uganda 2-0 ranar Lahadi.","answer":"Sure, here's a headline for the given text -kungiyar kwallon kafa ta Banyana-Banyana ta doke kungiyar Super Falcons a gasar kofin Afirka ta mata"},{"question":"Dhab ka hadal","answer":"#Dhab_ka_hadalKan Doonaya in uu Madaxwe noqdo oo dhawr kun ama dhawr Malyan ku bixinaya In uu Dowlad Islaam dhiso miyuu doonayaa?Qofka Soomaaliga ah ee Nairobi ka dhistay guri 6 ama 7 dabaq ah oo ay ugu taallo 50 Qol oo midkiiba loogu jiro kiro dhan 500 oo doollar oo haddii Soomaaliya xasilooni ka dhacdo gurigiisa laga guurayo nabad ma rabaa?!Qofka Furihii isgaarsiinta ku shaqeysta ee hawadii Soomaaliya heysta ee hadalka aad ku hadleysid mobile kaaga lacag u yahay ee ka baqaya in dawladdu kala wareegto nabad ma rabaa?Qofka badeeca canshuur la aan ama mid dhacday soo geliya dalka ee ku lacageystay dawlad la aanta, filayana in haddii dawlad Islaam dhalato oo sharciga Islaamka  shaqeynayo nabad ma rabaa?Shirkadaha diyaaradaha ee xujeyda ka qaada 4000 ilaa 5000 oo doollar ee dadkaas xujeyda xoolahooda sida jajuubka ah ku cuna ee sidaas ku hela lacagta xad dhaafkaa haddii xasilooni timaadana ay macquul tahay in lagu soo xajiyo 1000 ama ka yar, kuwaasi iyaguna nabad ma rabaan?Hoggaamiye goboleedka horjoogaha u ah dhawr gobol ee loogu wanqalay madaxweyne ayaad tahay ee u qaraab taga dawlaha carabta ee soo helo boorso doollar ah ee Dubai ama Nairibi gurya ka dhista ilmihiisuna dibadda wax ugu bartaan nabad ma rabaa?Inta gacan ku dhiigla ah inta takana qabto oo sharciga ka baqeysa inta guri dawlo ama mid dadweyne ku jirta inta beer islaameed heysata, inta xaaraan ku noolka ah nabad ma rabaan?Intaasi marka loo fiiriyo bulshada inteeda  kale ma dhama 20% ayagana waxa ay u Sacab tumayaan kuwa kor lagu soo xusay in yar oo uu Alle u naxariistay mooyaanee#Dadyahow Baraarugoo #Diinta Dhab u qaatoo#Dimuqraadiyada diidoo#Duulkaan doobinaayee(dhawaaqida) #Diiday Sharciga Islaamkiyo#Qiyamkii Wanaagsanaa#Intaad Alle ka baqataan#Doqon-nimada deysaan#Dib isu waaniyoo#Diida oo ku Kufriya#Daacada Allaah iyo#Rasuulkiisa raaca#Rafaad waad ka baxeysaan#Raxmad waad heleysane"},{"question":"Tulis satu karangan yang membincangkan langkah-langkah mengatasi masalah pencemaran alam sekitar. ","answer":"Fenomena pemanasan global semakin hari semakin menjadi realiti. Kenaikan suhu bumi yang kian terasa di setiap pelusuk dunia telah menjadi tajuk berita dan amaran yang diberikan oleh para saintis kini dialami sendiri oleh manusia. Salah satu punca berlakunya perubahan iklim yang ekstrim dan tidak menentu ini adalah disebabkan pencemaran terhadap alam sekitar. Tamadun manusia telah mengecapi suatu kejayaan apabila sektor perindustrian diperkenalkan. Namun disebalik kejayaan tersebut, pemeliharaan alam sekitar telah terabai dan meninggalkan kesan kepada kita generasi hari ini. Berbekalkan kemajuan sains dan teknologi ketika ini, kita masih berpeluang untuk memperbaiki kesilapan generasi terdahulu agar khazanah alam yang kita miliki dapat dinikmati selamanya. Oleh yang demikian, penting untuk kita mengetahui apakah langkah-langkah untuk mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar demi kemaslahatan manusia sejagat.Langkah pertama untuk mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar adalah dengan melaksanakan dasar kerajaan dan polisi pentadbiran yang mesra alam. Pihak kerajaan berperanan besar dalam membentuk undang-undang yang wajid dipatuhi oleh rakyat yang menetap di negara tersebut. Maka, penggubal polisi dan undang-undang negara bertanggungjawab untuk melaksanakan dasar yang mementingkan pemeliharaan alam sekitar. Sebagai contoh, dasar negara bebas karbon pada tahun 2050 perlu dilaksanakan dengan tepat dan menyeluruh. Perlepasan gas karbon ke udara perlu dikurangkan secara berperingkat bermula hari ini. Pihak kerajaan juga perlu menukarkan cara kita menjana kuasa elektrik pada hari ini iaitu dengan pembakaran arang batu dan menggantikannya dengan penjanaan kuasa yang boleh diperbaharui. Pelbagai alternatif dan teknologi yang telah dicipta supaya mesra alam tetapi memerlukan modifikasi dan kos untuk menggunakannya secara domestik. Ibarat peribahasa, dayung sudah di tangan, perahu di air. Tegasnya, Dengan melaksanakan dasar dan polisi yang mesra alam, pemeliharaan alam sekitar pasti dapat dicapai. Langkah seterusnya untuk mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar adalah dengan memperkasa pendidikan mengenai penjagaan alam sekitar. Pepatah melayu ada berkata, melentur buluh biarlah dari rebungnya. Begitu juga apabila kita ingin mendidik generasi muda supaya menghargai alam sekitar dan tidak melakukan pencemaran. Pendidikan mengenai kepentingan alam sekitar terhadap kehidupan manusia dan tahap kebergantungan kita kepada satu-satunya alam yang boleh kita diami ini adalah signifikan. Misalnya jika sungai-sungai dicemari dengan sisa toksik, mereka mungkin sukar untuk mendapat sumber air bersih untuk kegunaan harian. Pendidikan mengenai contoh-contoh tindakan yang mencemarkan alam sekitar juga penting untuk mereka mengetahui modus operandi pesalah laku terhadap alam sekitar. Apabila pendedahan seperti ini diberikan kepada mereka yang berusia setahun jagung, pastinya mereka akan melakukan perkara yang betul untuk memastikan kelangsungan generasi mereka kekal. Jelasnya, pencemaran terhadap alam sekitar dapat diatasi melalui pendidikan yang efektif dan berkesan.Di samping itu, kaedah untuk membendung pencemaran alam sekitar adalah dengan menyediakan pengurusan sisa yang terbaik. Secara konvensional, kita membuang sampah tanpa mengasingkan kategorinya dan akhirnya loggokan sampah tersebut akan dibiarkan lupus di tanah pelupusan sampah. Jika kaedah konvensional ini berterusan, jumlah tanah pelupusan sampah akan bertambah dan menyebabkan pencemaran berlaku. Justeru, sebagai individu kita perlu mengamalkan budaya kitar semula secara proaktif. Dengan melakukan kitar semula, kita dapat mengurangkan jumlah sisa sampah dan pencemaran dapat dikurangkan. Dari aspek masyarakat pula, kita hendaklah mengamalkan sikap bersederhana dalam kehidupan khususnya pemakanan. Malaysia mencatatkan lebih 17,000 tan sisa makanan pada setiap hari. Jika kita berhemah dalam kehidupan seperti memastikan makanan kita dimakan sehingga habis dan sisanya digunakan untuk membaja pastinya jumlah sisa sampah dapat dikurangkan. Intihannya, budaya pengurusan sisa sampah yang baik dapat membantu mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar.Akhir sekali, pencemaran alam sekitar dapat diatasi dengan menghukum pesalah laku terhadap dengan hukuman yang berat. Pihak berkuasa seperti Jabatan Alam Sekitar sewajarnya menguatkuasakan undang-undang dan menghukum pihak yang berkenaan. Jika kita lihat pada hari ini, hanya segelintir kilang industri yang dibina mengikut piawai yang ditetapkan oleh kerajaan. Dan juga terdapat berita mengenai kilang yang membuang sisa toksik terus ke sungai atau parit sebelum merawat sisa tersebut. Sikap pemain industri yang seperti enau dalam belukar, melepaskan pucuk masing-masing akan menyebabkan pencemaran untuk terus berlaku. Oleh sebab itu, apabila pesalah ditangkap dan dikenakan hukuman yang berat seperti menarik lesen perniagaan atau kilang mereka. Jika hukuman hanya sekadar bayaran denda, mereka pasti akan mengulangi kesalahan yang sama kerana hukuman tersebut tidak memberikan kesan kepada mereka. Izharnya, pencemaran alam sekitar boleh diatasi sekiranya pesalah yang membuat pencemaran dihukum dengan berat sebagai iktibar kepada masyarakat umum.Kesimpulannya, terdapat banyak langkah-langkah yang boleh dilakukan untuk mengatasi masalah pencemaran kepada alam sekitar. Tidak dinafikan masalah pencemaran alam sekitar merupakan satu isu yang tidak asing lagi di negara kita. Anggota masyarakat perlu memainkan peranan masing-masing untuk memastikan inisiatif-inisiatif mengatasi pencemaran alam sekitar dilaksanakn dengan efisien. Hari ini kita sendiri dapat mengalami kesan pencemaran seperti jerebu, banjir kita dan sebagainya. Cuba fikirkan apa yang bakal dihadapi oleh anak cucu kita nanti jika pencemaran terhadap alam sekitar ini tidak dibendung? Ibarat peribahasa melayu berkata, ingat antara belum kena, hemat antara belum habis. Semoga usaha yang kita lakukan hari ini memberikan hasil kepada generasi akan datang untuk manfaat mereka."},{"question":"Sommige autoтАЩs en vooral landbouwmachines zijn wel heel erg breed. Op smalle landweggetjes hebben ze de hele breedte van de weg nodig en soms zelfs de berm. Als ik daar wandel met mijn hond moet ik vaak uitwijken. Om nog maar niet te spreken van het moment dat ik daar met de auto rijd. Ik heb toch recht op de helft van de weg?","answer":"Het recht op de helft van de weg bestaat niet. Dat is echt niet wettelijk vastgelegd. Er zijn nu eenmaal smalle Nederlandse wegen waar zelfs twee autoтАЩs van gewoon formaat elkaar niet kunnen passeren. In dat geval gaat het erom elkaar de ruimte te geven door even bij een breder stuk te wachten tot de ander gepasseerd is, of van de berm gebruik te maken, als dat kan.Er geldt wel een maximumbreedte voor voertuigen. De wet schrijft voor dat vrachtautoтАЩs en de daaraan gekoppelde aanhangwagens en opleggers maximaal 2,55 meter breed mogen zijn. Voor koelwagens met de nodige, extra dikke wanden geldt zelfs 2,60 meter. Landbouwvoertuigen en andere zogenaamde rijdende werktuigen mogen inclusief de banden 3,00 meter breed zijn. Ook aanhangwagens hebben te maken met een breedtebeperking. Die mogen sinds 1 januari van dit jaar over de bak gemeten hooguit 2,55 meter breed zijn. Voorheen gold een maximumbreedte van 3,00 meter. Overigens kunnen voertuigen met een speciale ontheffing altijd toch nog breder zijn dan wat de wet voorschrijft."},{"question":"с╗Мkс╗Н mi k├м ├н с╣гe pid├бn-pid├бn, ├аmс╗Н╠Б N├а├мj├нr├н├а с╣г├м m├бa d├бra - Oluremi Tinubu","answer":"Aya aarс║╣ orilс║╣ ede Najiria Sс║╣nс║╣tс╗Н Olurс║╣mi Tinubu sс╗Н pe с╗Нkс╗Н oun Aarс║╣ Bс╗Нla Tinubu ki с╣гe pidan-pidan, с╣гugbon o n с╣гe iс╣гс║╣ rс║╣ bo с╣гe tс╗Н ati bo с╣гe yс║╣ lati jс║╣ ki orilс║╣ede Naijiria pada bс╗Н sipo.Nigba ti o n sс╗Нrс╗Н ni ile ijosin kan nibi ti wс╗Нn ti n с╣гe ayс║╣yс║╣ ayajс╗Н с╗Нdun ominira ni ilu Abuja lanaa с╗Нjс╗Н Aiku, Olurс║╣mi sс╗Н pe с╗Нkс╗Н oun ko ni dс║╣bi ohun to bajс║╣ ni Naijiria ru awс╗Нn to ti с╣гe ijс╗Нba sс║╣yin.Amс╗Нс╣гa, Oluremi ni ijс╗Нba Tinubu yoo tun gbogbo ohun to ti bajс║╣ с╣гe, ati pe yoo mu irс╗Нrun ba awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н orilс║╣ ede Najiria.O fikun с╗Нrс╗Н rс║╣ pe oun ni igbagbс╗Н ninu с╗Нkс╗Н oun pe o maa с╣гiс╣гс║╣ lati ri pe alaafia yoo fi jс╗Нba ni Naijiria.Sс║╣nс║╣tс╗Н Oluremi tun sс╗Н ninu с╗Нrс╗Н rс║╣ pe с╗Нjс╗Н ola si n bс╗Н wa dara lorilс║╣ ede Naijiria.Igba с╗Нpс╗Н ti de ni Naijiria, nitori naa, awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н Naijiria gbс╗Нdс╗Н ri ju ohun ti o n с╣гс║╣lс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н bayii lс╗Н ti wс╗Нn be fс║╣ jс║╣ alabapin ninu igbega orilс║╣ede wс╗Нn.O si tun rс╗Н awon с╗Нmс╗Н orilс║╣ ede Najiria lati с╣гe ajс╗Нyс╗Н ominira ni iс╣гс╗Нkan eyi to n gbe orilс║╣ ede leke.''Ko si idojukс╗Н ti a ko le bori ti a ba le tс║╣ le с╗Нrс╗Н ti с╗Мlс╗Нrun sс╗Н ninu iwe mimс╗Н pe с║╣ wa si с╗Нdс╗Н mi с║╣yin ti n с╣гiс╣гс║╣ ti a di с║╣ru wuwo le lori emi o si fi isinmi fun с╗Нkan yin.Ni iru asiko bayii, gbogbo ohun ti a le с╣гe ni lati di igbagbс╗Н wa mu sinsin ninu с╗Мlс╗Нrun.Aya aarс║╣ tun fi da awс╗Нn с╗Нmс╗Н orilс║╣ ede Najiria loju pe Tinubu ti ke si awon orilс║╣ ede lagbaye lati wa da ile iс╣гс║╣ silс║╣ fun irс╗Нrun gbogbo eeyan,'' Oluremi lo sс╗Н bс║╣с║╣."},{"question":"р░Чр▒Лр░зр▒Бр░ор░Хр▒Кр░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Б, р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░кр▒Бр░Хр▒Кр░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Бр░▓ р░ор░зр▒Нр░п р░др▒Зр░бр░╛р░▓р░ир▒Б р░др▒Жр░▓р░кр░Вр░бр░┐.","answer":"р░Чр▒Лр░зр▒Бр░о р░Хр▒Кр░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Б р░Чр░░р▒Нр░нр░╕р▒Нр░е р░кр░┐р░Вр░бр░╛р░▓р░▓р▒Лр░ир▒Б, р░╢р░┐р░╢р▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Лр░ир▒Б р░Ор░Хр▒Нр░Хр▒Бр░╡р░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐. р░жр▒Ар░ир░┐ р░Ор░бр░┐р░кр▒Лр░╕р▒Ир░Яр▒Н р░Хр░гр░╛р░▓р░▓р▒Л р░Ер░ир▒Зр░Х р░Ър░┐р░ир▒Нр░и р░Хр▒Кр░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Б р░мр░┐р░Вр░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р▒Б р░Йр░Вр░Яр░╛р░пр░┐. р░Зр░жр░┐ р░╢р░┐р░╢р▒Бр░╡р▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Л р░Йр░╖р▒Нр░гр░╛р░ир▒Нр░ир░┐ р░Йр░др▒Нр░кр░др▒Нр░др░┐р░Ър▒Зр░╕р░┐ р░жр▒Зр░╣ р░Йр░╖р▒Нр░гр▒Лр░Чр▒Нр░░р░др░ир▒Б р░Хр░╛р░кр░╛р░бр▒Бр░др▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐.р░др▒Жр░▓р▒Бр░кр▒Б р░Хр▒Кр░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Б р░кр▒Мр░в р░Ьр▒Ар░╡р▒Бр░▓р░▓р▒Л р░Ер░зр░┐р░Хр░ор▒Бр░Чр░╛ р░Йр░Вр░бр░┐ р░Ор░бр░┐р░кр▒Лр░╕р▒Ир░Яр▒Н р░Хр░гр░ор▒Бр░▓р▒Л р░Тр░Х р░кр▒Жр░жр▒Нр░ж р░Хр▒Кр░╡р▒Нр░╡р▒Б р░мр░┐р░Вр░жр▒Бр░╡р▒Б р░Йр░Вр░Яр▒Бр░Вр░жр░┐."},{"question":"шп╖ч╗Щф╗еф╕ЛчЪДцЦЗшиАцЦЗхоГчЪДшпСцЦЗя╝ЪхМбшббхнЧчиЪхЬня╝МхЛдхнжшАМцЧачГЫя╝МщВ╗х▒ЕцЬЙчГЫшАМф╕НщАоуАВшббф╣Гчй┐хгБх╝ХхЕ╢хЕЙя╝Мф╗еф╣жцШахЕЙшАМшп╗ф╣ЛуАВщВСф║║хдзхзУцЦЗф╕НшпЖя╝Мхо╢хпМхдЪф╣жя╝Мшббф╣Гф╕ОхЕ╢ф╜гф╜ЬшАМф╕Нц▒ВхБ┐уАВф╕╗ф║║цАкщЧошббя╝МшббцЫ░я╝ЪтАЬцД┐х╛Чф╕╗ф║║ф╣жщБНшп╗ф╣ЛуАВтАЭф╕╗ф║║цДЯхП╣я╝Мш╡Дч╗Щф╗еф╣жя╝МщБВцИРхдзхнжуАВ","answer":"хМбшббхнЧчиЪхЬня╝МхЛдхеЛхе╜хнжя╝Мф╜Жхо╢ф╕нц▓бцЬЙшЬбчГЫчЕзцШОуАВщВ╗х▒Ехо╢цЬЙшЬбчГЫя╝МхЕЙч║┐хН┤чЕзф╕НхИ░ф╗Цхо╢я╝МхМбшббх░▒хЗ┐чй┐хвЩхгБх╝ХцЭещВ╗х▒Ехо╢чЪДчГЫхЕЙя╝МцККф╣жцШачЕзчЭАхЕЙцЭешп╗уАВхРМф╣бцЬЙф╕кхдзцИ╖ф╕НшпЖхнЧя╝Мф╜Жхо╢ф╕нцЬЙх╛ИхдЪф╣жуАВф║ОцШпхМбшббх░▒хИ░ф╗Цхо╢хО╗хБЪф╗ЦчЪДф╜гф║║хН┤ф╕Нц▒Вх╛ЧхИ░цКещЕмуАВф╕╗ф║║хп╣хМбшббчЪДф╕╛хКицДЯхИ░хеЗцАкя╝МщЧоф╗Ця╝Мф╗Цшп┤я╝ЪтАЬцИСх╕МцЬЫшГ╜хдЯшп╗щБНф╕╗ф║║хо╢чЪДф╣жуАВтАЭцЦЗф╕НшпЖцДЯхИ░цГКхП╣я╝Мх░▒цККф╣жхАЯч╗Щф╗ЦуАВцЬАч╗И(хМбшбб)цИРф╕║ф║ЖхдзхнжщЧохо╢уАВ"},{"question":"Dime cu├бl es el tema principal o categor├нa de esta pregunta: ┬┐Cu├бntas expansiones hay de World of Warcraft?","answer":"La categor├нa de esta pregunta es videojuegos."},{"question":"роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роЙродро╡ро┐роХро│рпИ рокро┐ро▒ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроЪрпН роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роЙройродрпБ роХро░рпБродрпНродрпБ роОройрпНрой? ро╡роХрпБрокрпНрокро┐ро▓рпН роХро▓роирпНродрпБро░рпИропро╛роЯрпБроХ.","answer":"роХрооро▓ройрпН : ро░ро╛роорпБ! роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роЪро┐ро▒рпБ роЙродро╡ро┐роХро│рпИрокрпН рокро┐ро▒ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроЪрпН роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБ рокро▒рпНро▒ро┐ роирпА роОройрпНрой роиро┐ройрпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ропрпН?рооро╛ро▒ройрпН : роХроЯрпНроЯро╛ропроорпН роиро╛роорпН роЕро╡ро▒рпНро▒рпИ роиро╛роорпН роЪрпЖропрпНроп ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН. роирпА роОройрпНрой роиро┐ройрпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ропрпН?роХрооро▓ройрпН : роЪрпЖропрпНроп ро╡рпЗрогрпНроЯрпБроорпН роОройрпНро▒рпБ родро╛ройрпН роиро┐ройрпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒рпЗройрпН.рооро╛ро▒ройрпН : роЪро░ро┐, роЕрокрпНрокроЯро┐ роирпА роЪрпЖропрпНропрпБроорпН рокрпЛродрпБ роЙройрпН рооройроиро┐ро▓рпИ роОрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН?роХрооро▓ройрпН : роЕрокрпНрокроЯро┐ роЙродро╡ро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНропрпБроорпН рокрпЛродрпБ роороХро┐ро┤рпНроЪрпНроЪро┐ропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН, родро┐ро░рпБрокрпНродро┐ропро╛роХро╡рпБроорпН роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН. роПродрпЛ рокрпЖро░ро┐роп роЪро╛родройрпИ рокрпБро░ро┐роирпНродродрпБ рокрпЛро▓ рооройродро┐ро▓рпН родрпЛройрпНро▒рпБроорпН. роЙройроХрпНроХрпБ роОрокрпНрокроЯро┐ропро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН?рооро╛ро▒ройрпН : ро░ро╛роорпБ роОройроХрпНроХрпБроорпН роЕродрпЗ рооройроиро┐ро▓рпИродро╛ройрпН роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН. роироороХрпНроХрпБро│рпН рокро▓ роТро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпИ роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпЗ!роХрооро▓ройрпН : роироороХрпНроХрпБ роороЯрпНроЯрпБрооро▓рпНро▓, роироорпНроорпИрокрпНрокрпЛро▓ роЙродро╡ро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНроХро┐ройрпНро▒ роЕройрпИро╡ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБро│рпНро│рпБроорпН роЗродрпЗ роТро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпИропро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН. роЗрокрпНрокроЯро┐ роЙродро╡ро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╡ро░рпНроХро│ро╛ро▓рпНродро╛ройрпН роЗройрпНро▒ро│ро╡рпБроорпН роЙро▓роХроорпН роЗропроЩрпНроХро┐роХрпН роХрпКрогрпНроЯро┐ро░рпБроХрпНроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рооро╛ро▒ройрпН : роЖрооро╛роорпН, ро░ро╛роЬро╛! роЪро░ро┐ропро╛роХроЪрпН роЪрпКройрпНройро╛ропрпН. рооройро┐родро░рпНроХро│рпН рооройро┐родро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБ роЙродро╡ро┐ роЪрпЖропрпНро╡родрпБродро╛ройрпН рооро╛ройрпБроЯродрпНродро┐ройрпН рооро╛рогрпНрокрпБ. роЖройро╛ро▓рпН роЗродрпИрокрпН рокрпБро░ро┐роирпНродрпБ роОро▓рпНро▓рпЛро░рпБроорпН роироЯроирпНродро╛ро▓рпН роОро╡рпНро╡ро│ро╡рпБ роЪро┐ро▒рокрпНрокро╛роХ роЗро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБроорпН.роХрооро▓ройрпН : роЖрооро╛роорпНрокро╛ роЪро░ро┐ропро╛роХ роЪрпКро▓рпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ропрпН. роиро╛роорпН роЪрпЖропрпНроХро┐ро▒ роЪро┐ро▒ро┐роп роЙродро╡ро┐роХрпВроЯ рокро▓ро░рпБроХрпНроХрпБрокрпН рокрпЗро░рпБродро╡ро┐ропро╛роХ роЕроорпИроирпНродрпБ ро╡ро┐роЯрпБроХро┐ро▒родрпБ.рооро╛ро▒ройрпН : роиро╛роорпН роЗро░рпБро╡ро░рпБроорпН роЗрогрпИроирпНродрпБ роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокроЯ роиро╛ройрпН ро╡ро┐ро░рпБроорпНрокрпБроХро┐ро▒рпЗройрпН. роирпА роОройрпНрой роиро┐ройрпИроХрпНроХро┐ро▒ро╛ропрпН?роХрооро▓ройрпН : роиро▓рпНро▓родрпБ роЪрпЖропрпНроп роЗрогрпИро╡родрпБ родрокрпНрокрпЗропро┐ро▓рпНро▓рпИ роирогрпНрокро╛- роЗрогрпИро╡рпЛроорпН тАУ роЪрпЖропро▓рпНрокроЯрпБро╡рпЛроорпН тАУ роиройрпНро▒ро┐ роирогрпНрокро╛!"},{"question":"эЬ┤ыМАэП░ ыЛдэБмыкиыУЬъ░А ъ╖╝ьЛЬые╝ ьЬаы░ЬэХаъ╣М?","answer":"ьХДьзБ ъ╖╝ьЛЬьЭШ ьаХэЩХэХЬ ьЫРьЭ╕ьЭА ы░ЭэШАьзАьзА ьХКьХШьЬ╝ый░, ы│╡ьЮбэХЬ ьЪФьЭ╕ыУдьЭ┤ ъ▓░эХйэХШьЧм ы░Ьы│СэХа ьИШ ьЮИыКФ ъ▓ГьЬ╝ыбЬ ьХМыадьа╕ ьЮИьК╡ыЛИыЛд. ыЛдэБмыкиыУЬые╝ ьВмьЪйэХШыКФ ъ▓ГьЭ┤ ьзБьаСьаБьЬ╝ыбЬ ъ╖╝ьЛЬые╝ ьЬаы░ЬэХШыКФ ъ▓ГьЭА ьХДыЛИьзАызМ, ыФФьзАэД╕ ъ╕░ъ╕░ ьВмьЪй эМиэД┤ъ│╝ ыИИ ъ▒┤ъ░Х ьВмьЭ┤ьЧР ьЧ░ъ┤АьД▒ьЭ┤ ьЮИьЭД ьИШ ьЮИьК╡ыЛИыЛд.ыФФьзАэД╕ ъ╕░ъ╕░ые╝ ьШдыЮлыПЩьХИ ьВмьЪйэХШъ▒░ыВШ ьЮШык╗ыРЬ ьЮРьД╕ыбЬ ьВмьЪйэХа ъ▓╜ьЪ░ ыИИьЧР ы╢АыЛ┤ьЭ┤ ъ░Аый░, ыИИьЭ┤ эФ╝ыбЬэХШъ▓М ыКРъ╗┤ьзИ ьИШ ьЮИьК╡ыЛИыЛд. ьЭ┤ъ▓ГьЭ┤ ъ╖╝ьЛЬ ы░ЬьГЭъ│╝ ъ┤АыаиыРШьЦ┤ ьЮИьЭД ьИШ ьЮИьК╡ыЛИыЛд. ыШРэХЬ, ьЮеъ▒░ыжм ьЛЬьХ╝ьЭШ ы╢Аьб▒ъ│╝ ъ░Аъ╣МьЪ┤ ъ▒░ыжмьЧРьДЬьЭШ ъ│╝ыПДэХЬ эЩФый┤ ьЛЬь▓ньЭА ъ╖╝ьЛЬ ьЬДэЧШьЭД ьжЭъ░АьЛЬэВм ьИШ ьЮИьК╡ыЛИыЛд.ъ╖╝ьЛЬ ьШИы░йьЭД ьЬДэХ┤ьДЬыКФ ыФФьзАэД╕ ъ╕░ъ╕░ ьВмьЪй ьЛЬ ьаХъ╕░ьаБьЭ╕ эЬ┤ьЛЭьЭД ь╖иэХШъ│а, ыФФьзАэД╕ ьКдэБмыж░ьЧРьДЬ ыИИьЭД ьЙмъ▓М эХШыКФ эЩФый┤ ъ░БыПДыВШ ы░Эъ╕░ ьДдьаХ, ьХИый┤ ьЪ┤ыПЩ, ьаБьаИэХЬ ьб░ыкЕьЭД ьВмьЪйэХШыКФ ъ▓ГьЭ┤ ыПДьЫАьЭ┤ ыРа ьИШ ьЮИьК╡ыЛИыЛд. ыШРэХЬ, ъ╖╝ьЛЬьЩА ъ░ЩьЭА ыИИ ъ▒┤ъ░Х ым╕ьаЬъ░А ы░Ьъ▓мыРШый┤ ьХИъ│╝ ьЭШьВмьЩА ьГБыЛ┤эХШыКФ ъ▓ГьЭ┤ ьвЛьК╡ыЛИыЛд."},{"question":"┘Е╪з ┘Е╪п┘Й ╪з┘Ж╪к╪┤╪з╪▒ ╪з╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д╪╖╪и ╪з┘Д╪к┘В┘Д┘К╪п┘К╪Я","answer":"┘Г╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪╖╪и ╪з┘Д╪к┘В┘Д┘К╪п┘К ┘И╪з┘Д╪к┘Г┘Е┘К┘Д┘К ┘Е┘И╪▒╪п┘Л╪з ╪г╪│╪з╪│┘К┘Л╪з ┘Д┘Д╪╡╪н╪й ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪г╪│╪▒ ┘И╪з┘Д┘Е╪м╪к┘Е╪╣╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Е╪н┘Д┘К╪й ╪╣┘Д┘Й ┘Е╪п╪з╪▒ ╪╣╪п╪й ┘В╪▒┘И┘Ж. ┘И╪г╪и┘Д╪║╪к ┘Е╪з╪ж╪й ┘И╪│╪и╪╣┘И┘Ж ╪п┘И┘Д╪й ╪╣┘Ж ╪з╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ╪з┘Д╪╖╪и ╪з┘Д╪к┘В┘Д┘К╪п┘К╪М ┘И┘Г╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘И╪о╪▓ ╪и╪з┘Д╪е╪и╪▒ ┘З┘И ╪з┘Д╪┤┘Г┘Д ╪з┘Д╪г┘Г╪л╪▒ ╪┤┘К┘И╪╣┘Л╪з ┘Д┘Д┘Е┘Е╪з╪▒╪│╪й ┘Б┘К 113 ╪и┘Д╪п┘Л╪з. ┘И╪и╪п╪г╪к ╪з┘Д╪╣╪п┘К╪п ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪и┘Д╪п╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к┘В╪п┘Е╪й ╪г┘К╪╢┘Л╪з ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪з╪╣╪к╪▒╪з┘Б ╪и╪з┘Д╪╖╪и ╪з┘Д╪к┘В┘Д┘К╪п┘К ┘И╪п┘Е╪м┘З ┘Б┘К ┘Ж┘П╪╕┘П┘Е ╪з┘Д╪▒╪╣╪з┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪╡╪н┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪о╪з╪╡╪й ╪и┘З╪з.┘И┘И┘Б┘В┘Л╪з ┘Д╪и┘К╪з┘Ж╪з╪к ╪╣╪з┘Е 2012╪М ┘К╪│╪к╪о╪п┘Е ┘Е╪з ┘К┘В╪▒╪и ┘Е┘Ж ┘Ж╪╡┘Б ╪з┘Д╪│┘Г╪з┘Ж ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪╣╪п┘К╪п ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪и┘Д╪п╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪╡┘Ж╪з╪╣┘К╪й ╪з┘Д╪в┘Ж ╪и╪╣╪╢ ╪г╪┤┘Г╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д╪╖╪и ╪з┘Д╪к┘В┘Д┘К╪п┘К ┘И╪з┘Д╪к┘Г┘Е┘К┘Д┘К ╪и╪з┘Ж╪к╪╕╪з┘Е (╪з┘Д┘И┘Д╪з┘К╪з╪к ╪з┘Д┘Е╪к╪н╪п╪й╪М 42%╪Ы ╪г╪│╪к╪▒╪з┘Д┘К╪з╪М 48%╪Ы ┘Б╪▒┘Ж╪│╪з╪М 49%╪Ы ┘Г┘Ж╪п╪з╪М 70%)╪Ы ┘И┘К┘И╪м╪п ╪з╪│╪к╪о╪п╪з┘Е ┘Г╪и┘К╪▒ ┘Д╪и╪╣╪╢ ╪г╪┤┘Г╪з┘Д ╪з┘Д╪╖╪и ╪з┘Д╪к┘В┘Д┘К╪п┘К ┘И╪з┘Д╪к┘Г┘Е┘К┘Д┘К ┘Б┘К ╪з┘Д╪╣╪п┘К╪п ┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪и┘Д╪п╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪г╪о╪▒┘Й╪М ┘Е╪л┘Д ╪┤┘К┘Д┘К (71%) ┘И┘Г┘И┘Д┘И┘Е╪и┘К╪з (40%) ┘И╪и┘Ж╪│╪и╪й ╪к╪╡┘Д ╪е┘Д┘Й 80% ┘Б┘К ╪и╪╣╪╢ ╪з┘Д╪и┘Д╪п╪з┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪г┘Б╪▒┘К┘В┘К╪й."},{"question":"\\"T\\" р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╖Др╖Эр╢йр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢Ър╖У р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖Т р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗ р╢п?","answer":"\\"T\\" р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢╗р╢║ р╢▒р╖Цр╢нр╢▒ р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╖Др╖Эр╢йр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ 20 р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Кр╢ор╖Пр╢▒р╢║ р╖Др╖Тр╢╕р╖Т р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Гр╖Д р╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╖Ър╢нр╖КтАНр╢╗ р╖Др╢╗р╖Др╖П р╢┤р╖Ьр╖Др╖Ьр╖Гр╢нр╖К р╢Йр╢нр╖Тр╖Др╖Пр╖Гр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢н.р╢╕р╖Цр╢╜р╖Пр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╢║: \\"T\\" р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ р╢╕р╖Цр╢╜р╖Пр╢╗р╢╕р╖Кр╢╖р╢║ р╖Жр╖Ур╢▒р╖Ур╖Вр╖Тр╢║р╖Пр╢▒р╖Ф р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗ \\"Taw\\" р╢нр╖Фр╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ер╢нр╢╗, р╢Ср╢║ \\"Tau\\" р╢║р╢▒ р╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╢Ъ р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╢зр╢п р╖Др╖Ър╢нр╖Ф р╖Ар╖Тр╢║. р╢Ср╢║ /t/ р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╢┤р╢нр╖К р╢Ър╢╗ р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Ър╢зр╖Др╢мр╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Рр╢нр╖Т р╢Зр╢╜р╖Кр╖Ар╖Щр╢║р╖Эр╢╜р╢╗р╖К р╢┤р╖Кр╢╜р╖Эр╖Гр╖Тр╖Ар╖К р╖Бр╢╢р╖Кр╢пр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢╗р╖Цр╢┤р╢лр╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з р╢Ер╢Ыр╢лр╖Кр╢йр╖А р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╢Ър╢╗ р╢Зр╢н.р╢Лр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Пр╢╗р╢лр╢║: р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Тр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К, \\"T\\" р╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Лр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Пр╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒р╖Ф р╢╜р╢╢р╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Ъ р╢Ър╢зр╖Др╢м р╢╗р╖Др╖Тр╢н р╢Зр╢╜р╖Кр╖Ар╢╜р╖Щр╢║р╖Эр╢╜р╢╗р╖К р╢┤р╖Кр╢╜р╖Эр╖Гр╖Тр╖Ар╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Гр╢║, р╢Ср╢║ р╢Йр╖Др╖Е р╢Йр╢пр╖Тр╢╗р╖Тр╢┤р╖Г р╢пр╢нр╖К р╢┤р╖Тр╢зр╖Фр╢┤р╖Гр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢Зр╢╜р╖Кр╖Ар╢╜р╖Щр╢║р╖Эр╢╜р╢╗р╖К р╢Ър╢│р╖Ф р╢╕р╖Фр╢пр╖Фр╢▒р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Пр╢нр╢║ р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ар╖Пр╖Др╢║р╢з р╢╢р╖Пр╢░р╖П р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢┤р╢пр╖Ар╢▒ р╖Бр╢╢р╖Кр╢пр╢║р╢Ър╖Т.р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╢║: \\"T\\" р╢║р╢▒р╖Ф р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢┤р╖Ьр╢пр╖Ф р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ \\"р╢Ьр╖Г\\", \\"р╖Ар╢Ьр╖Фр╖А\\", \\"р╢Ър╖Пр╢╜р╢║\\" р╖Гр╖Д \\"р╢нр╖Пр╢Ър╖КтАНр╖Вр╢лр╢║\\" р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╖Ар╢ар╢▒ р╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╖Ъ.р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╢нр╖К р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╢╜р╖Тр╢▒р╖К: \\"T\\" р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢╗р╢║ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢░ р╢Лр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Пр╢╗р╢л р╖Гр╖Др╖Тр╢н р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖П р╖Гр╖Д р╖Др╖Эр╢йр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Ъ. р╢▒р╖Тр╢пр╖Гр╖Фр╢▒р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К, р╖Гр╖Кр╢┤р╖Пр╢др╖Кр╢д р╢╖р╖Пр╖Вр╖Пр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К, р╢Лр╢ар╖Кр╢ар╖Пр╢╗р╢лр╢║ р╢Йр╢Вр╢Ьр╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Ур╖Гр╖Т р╖Др╖П р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Ар╖Ъ, р╢▒р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╢Ср╢║ р╢пр╖Тр╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢пр╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Кр╢┤р╢╗р╖Кр╖Б р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢┤р╢пр╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ср╖Др╖Т р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╢нр╖Тр╢╡р╢╜р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╢╕р╖Шр╢пр╖Ф р╖Бр╢╢р╖Кр╢пр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╖Ар╖Ъ.р╢Ър╖Ър╢н р╖Гр╖Д р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ър╖Ър╢н р╢нр╖Фр╖Е: р╢Ьр╖Фр╖Ар╢▒р╖Кр╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖Фр╢╜р╖Тр╢║ р╖Гр╖Д р╢пр╖Фр╢╗р╢Ър╢ор╢▒р╢║ р╖Др╢╗р╖Др╖П р╢┤р╖Рр╖Др╖Рр╢пр╖Тр╢╜р╖Т р╖Гр╖Д р╢▒р╖Тр╢╗р╖Ар╢пр╖КтАНр╢║ р╖Гр╢▒р╖Кр╢▒р╖Тр╖Ар╖Ър╢пр╢▒р╢║ р╖Гр╢│р╖Др╖П р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢▒р╖Ър╢зр╖Э р╖Бр╢╢р╖Кр╢п р╖Др╖Эр╢йр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ, \\"T\\" р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢╗р╢║ \\"Tango\\" р╢║р╢▒ р╖Ар╢ар╢▒р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╖Эр╢вр╢▒р╢║ р╖Ар╖Ъ.р╢Ьр╢лр╖Тр╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Гр╖Д р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ: р╢╖р╖Юр╢нр╖Тр╢Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╢пр╖КтАНр╢║р╖Пр╖Ар╖Ъ р╢Лр╖Вр╖Кр╢лр╢нр╖Кр╖Ар╢║ р╖Др╖Э р╢Ьр╢лр╖Тр╢нр╢║р╖Ъ р╢┤р╢╗р╖Тр╖Ар╢╗р╖Кр╢нр╢▒р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╖Ар╖Тр╢ар╢╜р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖Э р╢▒р╖Тр╢║р╢нр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢▒р╖Тр╢╗р╖Цр╢┤р╢лр╢║ р╢Ър╖Тр╢╗р╖Ур╢╕р╢з \\"T\\" р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢╗р╢║ р╢╢р╖Ьр╖Др╖Э р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╖Ар╖Ъ.р╖Гр╖Пр╖Др╖Тр╢нр╖КтАНр╢║р╢║ р╖Гр╖Д р╢╕р╖Пр╢░р╖КтАНр╢║ р╢нр╖Фр╖Е: р╢вр╢▒р╢┤р╖КтАНр╢╗р╖Тр╢║ р╖Гр╢Вр╖Гр╖Кр╢Ър╖Шр╢нр╖Тр╢║р╖Ъ р╢ар╢╗р╖Тр╢нр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╖Ар╢▒ \\"р╢зр╖У-р╖Вр╢╗р╖Кр╢зр╖К\\" р╖Др╖Э \\"р╢╕р╖Тр╖Гр╖Кр╢зр╢╗р╖К р╢зр╖У\\" р╖Ар╖Рр╢▒р╖Т р╢Ър╖Щр╢зр╖Т р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Фр╢╕р╢Ър╖К р╖Др╖Э р╖Гр╢Вр╢Ър╖Ър╢нр╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г \\"р╢зр╖У\\" р╢╖р╖Пр╖Ар╖Тр╢нр╖П р╢Ър╖Е р╖Др╖Рр╢Ъ.р╢╕р╖Фр╢пр╖КтАНр╢╗р╢л р╖Бр╖Тр╢╜р╖Кр╢┤р╢║ р╖Гр╖Д р╢Ер╢нр╖К р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф: р╢Ер╢нр╖К р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф р╖Ар╢╜ \\"T\\" р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗ р╢╜р╖Тр╢║р╖П р╢Зр╢нр╖Кр╢нр╖Ъ р╢пр╖Е р╖Ар╖Бр╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢╕р╖Рр╢пр╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Ар╖Щр╢▒р╢нр╖К р╢╗р╖Ър╢Ыр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖Тр╢▒р╖К р╖Др╢╗р╖Гр╖К р╢Ър╢╗р╢▒ р╢╜р╢п р╖Гр╢╗р╢╜ р╢╗р╖Ър╢Ыр╖Пр╖Ар╢Ър╖К р╢╜р╖Щр╖Г р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╢Ър╖Фр╢йр╖П р╢Ер╢Ър╖Фр╢╗р╖Ф \\"t\\" р╢з р╖Гр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒ р╖Гр╖Кр╖Ар╢╗р╖Цр╢┤р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Т р╢▒р╢╕р╖Фр╢нр╖К р╖Гр╖Пр╢╕р╖Пр╢▒р╖КтАНр╢║р╢║р╖Щр╢▒р╖К р╢Ър╖Фр╢йр╖П р╖Ар╢▒ р╢Ер╢нр╢╗ р╖Гр╢╕р╖Др╢╗ р╖Ар╖Тр╢з р╢┤р╖Пр╢пр╢║р╖Ъ р╖Ар╢Ър╖КтАНр╢╗р╢║р╢Ър╖К р╢Зр╢нр╖Фр╖Ер╢нр╖К р╖Ар╖Ъ.р╢╕р╖Щр╢╕ р╢Ер╢Вр╖Б р╖Гр╢╜р╢Ър╖П р╢╢р╖Рр╢╜р╖Ур╢╕р╖Щр╢▒р╖К, р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢░ р╖Ар╖Гр╢╕р╖К р╖Др╢╗р╖Др╖П \\"T\\" р╢Ер╢Ър╖Кр╖Вр╢╗р╢║р╖Ъ р╖Ар╖Тр╖Ар╖Тр╢░ р╢║р╖Щр╢пр╖Фр╢╕р╖К р╖Гр╖Д р╖Ар╖Рр╢пр╢Ьр╢нр╖Кр╢Ър╢╕ р╢Ер╢┤р╢з р╢Ер╢Ьр╢║ р╢Ър╖Е р╖Др╖Рр╢Ър╖Тр╢║."},{"question":"Dukkanin su sun samu shahada a yakin Uhud, amma ban da","answer":" (a) Hamza bin Abdil Mudallib (b) Mus'ab bin Umair (c) Sa'ad bin Abi Waqqas"},{"question":"Manomeza lahatsoratra miresaka momba ny fitaovam-pitantanana noforonina ho anтАЩny mpiompy trondro.","answer":"Ny FeonтАЩny Mpiompy Trondro n┬░ 53Marsa 3, 2022LOHAHEVITRA : Atsaraina ny famokarana trondro tantanam-pianakavianaHafa ny fiompiana trondro ! Matetika mifandray aminтАЩny  fiompiana omby ohatra izy, vokatry ny fampiasana zezika. Tena miankina aminтАЩny tahirim-bola ihany koa ny fampiharana ny teknika : tsy azo ampiharina indraindray ny teknika nohatsaraina vokatry ny tsy fisianтАЩny vola. Afakamanatsara ny kalitaonтАЩny tohana entinтАЩny mpanentana (ACP) sy ny fitantananтАЩny mpiompy trondro ny famokarany ny TFT.Namorona sy nanandrana ny fomba fiasa TFT tao aminтАЩnyfaritra Itasy izahay ny taona 2019 hatraminтАЩny 2020.Nofantarinay taminтАЩizany aloha ireo olana eo aminтАЩny fitantanana ny famokarana trondro. Izany no nahafahanay nanamboatra fitaovana tsotra, mety aminтАЩny mpiompy trondro sy ny ACP, hanampiana azy ireo aminтАЩny fandalinana.Ankehitriny, ireo no fitaovana fototra ifampiresahanтАЩny ACP sy ny mpiompy trondro. Ampiasaina ireo aminтАЩny fanjohiana eny ifotony sy aminтАЩny fotoana manan-danja aminтАЩny taom-pamokarana. Mora ho anтАЩny mpiompy trondro ny mamantatrany fanatsarana entina aminтАЩny famokarana trondro vokatry ny fisianтАЩireo fitaovana ireo sy ny fiarahan-dianтАЩny ACP. Tsara kokoa anefa ny manontany mivantana ny hevitrтАЩizy ireo !Ho anareo mpiompy trondro na lehilahy na vehivavy izay mamaky ity lahatsoratra ity ary mampiasa ny fitaovanтАЩny TFT ihany koa dia aza misalasala mizara ny fahit├аnareo izany aoaminтАЩny laharana manaraka !FMT : Inona no fanambinareo taminтАЩny nametrahana ireo fitaovam-pitantanana ireo ?Chlo├й : Ny tarehimarika, ny kajy, ny firaiketana an-tsoratra, тАж mety ho vaovao sy sarotra ho anтАЩny mpiompy trondro ireo rehetra ireo ! Nisy ny ezaka fampiofananasy ┬л fanapariahana ┬╗ ireo voambolanтАЩny fitantanana tsy maintsy natao. VoarainтАЩny mpiompy trondro tsara anefa ireo fitaovana taorianтАЩny fiarahan-dia mifanaraka aminтАЩizany syny famerimberenana ny fiofanana natao. Nisy ihany koa ny fanamby ho anтАЩny ACP, fomba fiasa vaovao mantsy izy io : nasainay nampivelatra ny fomba fijeriny izy ireo fa tsyhifantoka aminтАЩny fiompiana trondro sy ny lafiny teknika fotsiny ihany. TaorianтАЩny fampiofanana vitsivitsy sy ny fampiharana ifotony dia nandeha tsara ny asa rehetra.FMT : Tena nila ireo fitaovam-pitantanana ireo ve ny mpiompy trondro ary inona no fiovana azonтАЩizy ireo taminтАЩizany ?Chlo├й : Malalaka ny mpiompy trondro na hampiasa na tsia ireo fitaovana ireo. Anjaranay kosa anefa ny manome azy ireo fahalalana sy fahaiza-manao mikasika ny fitantanana ny fiompiana trondro. Ny fanomezana azy ireo teknika tsy miaraka aminтАЩny fanalahidinтАЩny fitantanana dia tahaka ny manome boky tsy misy solomaso amakiana azy ! Araka ny efa nohazavaiko, niezaka namaly ny fil├аnтАЩny mpiompy trondro mikasika ny olanтАЩny fitantanana izahay. Ireo fitaovana izay mamaly tsara ny fangatahanтАЩizy ireo dia ampiasainy aminтАЩny ankapobeny. Manampy azy aminтАЩny fifampidinihana sy ny fanatsarana ny lamina aminтАЩny taom-pamokarana zana-trondro sy fanatavizana, ny ara-bola, ny famarotana sy ny fitantanana ny valam-pamokarana. Ankoatra izay, rehefa atao ny tombana ara-tekinika sy ara-toekarena (fa tsy ara-tekinika fotsiny) dia afaka manova ny safidiny eo aminтАЩny lafiny teknika sy ny fitantanana araka ny tanjona kendreny ny mpiompy trondro. Ny fitahirizany ireo fitaovana ireo ho anтАЩny taom-piompiana mifandimby dia ahafahanтАЩizy ireo manaraka akaiky ny fivoaranтАЩny famokarana ataony.Fitaovam-pitantanana maro no noforonina niaraka taminтАЩireo mpanentana sy ireo mpiompy trondro miara-miasa aminтАЩny APDRA mba hamahana ny olanтАЩny fitantanana sedrainтАЩireto farany.Ireto avy ny fitaovam-pitantanana nampiasaina :Peta-drindrina fandraiketana an-tsoratra ny teknika sy ny ekonomika : fitaovana mora ampiasaina kokoa mitaha aminтАЩny kahie firaiketana an-tsoratra ; natao hitahirizana ny zava-mitranga rehetra eo aminтАЩny famokarana mandritra ny taom-pamokarana iray izy ity, na eo aminтАЩny lafiny teknika (daty fampanatodizana, fandrotsahana trondro, fanajariana, famahanana, sns.) na ny lafiny toekarena (fidirana sy fivoaham-bola).Fisy fikajiana ireo tondro ara-teknika sy ara-ekonomika : natao hikajiana ireo mari-drefy manan-danja taminтАЩny taom-pamokarana teo aloha ity fitaovana ity ; mifototra aminтАЩny tarehimarika hita tao aminтАЩny peta-drindrina firaikena ara-teknika sy ara-toekarena ny kajy rehetra. Tanjona ny hamintina ny fotoam-pamokarana sy hanatsoaka lesona hampivoarana ny taom-pamokaranamanaraka.Fitantanana ny asa famokarana zana-trondro na ny ┬л 4 Fzana-trondro ┬╗ : izy no ahafahanтАЩny mpamokatra zana-trondro mandamina mialoha ny famokarany hifanaraka aminтАЩny zava-misy (tsy fisianтАЩny rano, tinadinтАЩny tsena, sns.) sy mamaly tsara ny fil├аnтАЩny mpanatavy zana-trondro. Tetiandro famatsiam-bola ny asa famokarana trondro : manampy ny mpiompy trondro tojo fahasahiranana ara-bola ary tsy afaka mamita tsara ny asany izy ity. Tanjona ny hahazoanтАЩizy ireo mitantana tsara ny famokarany araka ny vola misy eo am-pelatanana, aminтАЩny al├аlanтАЩio fitaovana io. Ankehitriny, mbola mamorona fitaovana hamaliana ireo fanontaniana vaovao sy olana hovahana ny mpanentana. Foronina miaraka aminтАЩny mpiompy trondro ary natao ho azy ireo izany fitaovana izany, lasa fampiasany ary ampifanarahany aminтАЩny fil├аny sy ny zava-misy iainany avy eo. Efa anaovana andrana ankehitriny ny fitaovana sasany mialoha ny hanapariahana azy.Fitaovam-pitantanana noforonina ho anтАЩny mpiompy trondro."},{"question":"Berikan judul yang tepat untuk artikel berita berikut.Artikel: Foto mengejutkan yang mengingatkan tentang pentingnya masalah sampah di laut. Kenapa tak ada tindakan untuk mengatasi masalah sampah? Seberapa gawatkah masalah sampah di laut Indonesia? Tulisan ini akan menjelaskannya.Beberapa waktu terakhir ini warganet kembali diingatkan pada masalah sampah plastik melalui video wisatawan Inggris yang menyelam di antara lautan sampah di Nusa Penida, Bali. Aneka sampah plastik mengapung di sekitar penyelam. Ditambah lagi, tumpukan sampah yang terhampar di sepanjang pantai di Bali beberapa bulan terakhir membuat persoalan plastik yang selama ini terpinggirkan, kembali menyita perhatian publik. Pria Inggris ini menyelam dengan banyak sampah plastik.Kementerian Pariwisata membantah video tersebut melalui akun Twitter resminya. \\"Siapa bilang laut Nusa Penida banyak sampah? Dikepung sampah plastik seperti yang diviralkan diver Inggris Rich Horner? Lautnya ternyata clear. Biota lautnya juga hidup sangat sehat,\\" kata akun @Kemenpar_RI pada 10 Maret 2018. Kementerian tersebut berusaha memberikan bukti dengan video laut yang bersih dan diberi tagar #IniLhoAslinyaNusaPenida #WonderfulNusaPenida. Pada 10 Maret 2018 ada sekitar 3.800 tagar #IniLhoAslinyaNusaPenida diikuti 2.882 tagar terkait, #WonderfulNusaPenida. Kedua tagar tersebut hanya muncul hingga 11 Maret dan pada 12 Maret, sudah hampir tidak ada lagi twit baru dengan tagar tersebut.Reaksi Kementerian ini disayangkan warganet, karena tidak memberikan solusi terhadap masalah sampah. Sebenarnya, benarkah soal sampah di laut ini adalah sebuah masalah yang besar? Seperti apa kondisi sampah di laut?Untuk melihat seberapa gawatnya kondisi sampah di laut, berikut ini fakta yang bisa disimak. Apa dampak sampah di laut hanya untuk manusia?Sampah plastik membunuh para penghuni laut, dari ikan, penyu, bahkan burung yang tinggal di sekitar pantai. Makhluk laut terbelit aneka sampah plastik. Dalam film dokumenter BBC, Blue Planet 2, penonton bisa melihat bagaimana seekor kura-kura penyu sisik terjerat kantong plastik.Jawaban:","answer":"Sampah di Laut Indonesia: Fakta atau Hoax?"},{"question":"р▓И р▓╡р▓╛р▓Хр│Нр▓пр▓ж р▓Тр▓Вр▓жр│Б р▓╣р│Жр▓Ър│Нр▓Ър│Б р▓╕р▓Вр▓Хр│Ар▓░р│Нр▓г р▓Жр▓╡р│Гр▓др│Нр▓др▓┐р▓пр▓ир│Нр▓ир│Б р▓░р▓Ър▓┐р▓╕р▓┐ р▓Ер▓╡р▓░р│Б р▓╕р│Кр▓Хр│Нр▓Хр▓┐р▓и р▓╣р│Ар▓▓р│Н р▓кр▓╛р▓др│Нр▓░р▓╡р▓ир│Нр▓ир│Б р▓кр▓░р▓┐р▓кр│Вр▓░р│Нр▓гр▓Чр│Кр▓│р▓┐р▓╕р▓┐р▓жр▓░р│Б.","answer":"\\"р▓Ер▓╡р▓░р│Б р▓Ер▓╣р▓Вр▓Хр▓╛р▓░р▓┐ р▓Ор▓жр│Бр▓░р▓╛р▓│р▓┐р▓п р▓Ър▓┐р▓др│Нр▓░р▓гр▓╡р▓ир│Нр▓ир│Б р▓╕р│Вр▓Хр│Нр▓╖р│Нр▓ор▓╡р▓╛р▓Чр▓┐ р▓Чр│Мр▓░р▓╡р▓┐р▓╕р▓┐р▓жр▓░р│Б, р▓Ер▓╕р▓╛р▓зр▓╛р▓░р▓г р▓Хр│Ир▓Ър▓│р▓Х р▓ор▓др│Нр▓др│Б р▓жр│Гр▓вр│Ар▓Хр▓░р▓гр▓жр│Кр▓Вр▓жр▓┐р▓Чр│Ж р▓╕р│Кр▓Хр│Нр▓Хр▓┐р▓и 'р▓╣р│Ар▓▓р│Н' р▓кр▓╛р▓др│Нр▓░р▓╡р▓ир│Нр▓ир│Б р▓╕р▓╛р▓Хр▓╛р▓░р▓Чр│Кр▓│р▓┐р▓╕р▓┐р▓жр▓░р│Б.\\""},{"question":"Complete o seguinte extrato: O terceiro ├бlbum de est├║dio da banda, \\"Midnight Memories,\\" foi lan├зado em 25 de novembro de 2013. Este foi o ├бlbum mais vendido em todo o mundo em 2013, com 4 milh├╡es de c├│pias vendidas. \\"Best Song Ever\\", o primeiro single do ├бlbum, se tornou a m├║sica de maior sucesso do One Direction nos Estados Unidos. Ap├│s o lan├зamento do ├бlbum, o grupo embarcou na turn├к","answer":"turn├к \\"Where We Are\\". A banda teve uma m├йdia de 49,848 f├гs por show, com ingressos esgotados no minuto em que as vendas come├зaram. A turn├к arrecadou mais de USD 290 milh├╡es e foi a turn├к com maior bilheteria de 2014."},{"question":"De qual categoria ├й essa pergunta: T├│quio fica na China?.","answer":"Geografia"},{"question":"Chii chinoitika panguva yechikamu chinonzi \\"Giggle Box\\"? Mutambo weTV wakaiswa nyeredzi uye wakagadzirwa naJustin Fletcher, uyo anotamba vatambi mune ese ezvikeche zvekomedhi uye akanyorawo mashoma mashoma mumutsara wayo wekutanga. Mamwe emifananidzo akatorwa mu studio, nepo mamwe mapikicha akatorwa kunze; semuenzaniso, imwe inotorwa paPortmeirion, inoshandiswa kudhorobha rengano reWiggyville uko mifananidzo yaKaputeni Adorable inoiswa kubva Series 1 kusvika 2. Chiratidziro chinopindirana nesarudzo yevana vanonzi maGigglekids, vanotaura majee kuna Justin pachake, mumutauro wavo. chikamu chako chinonzi 'Giggle Box'.","answer":"Vana vanonzi maGigglekids vanotaura majee kuna Justin."},{"question":"роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐ : роЗродрпНродро╛ро▓ро┐ропро┐ройрпН родро▓рпИ роироХро░рпН роОродрпБ ?","answer":"рокродро┐ро▓рпН : ро░рпЛроорпН."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo hita any an-tanindrazana?","answer":"Ireto avy no hita any an-tanindrazana:- ny trano nonenan'ny razana.- ny fasana nilevenan'ny razana.- ny tanimboly nambolen'ny razana."},{"question":"шп╖чФичоАц┤БчЪДшпншиАхЫЮчнФф╗еф╕ЛщЧощвШя╝ЪщЧощвШя╝Ъф║║ч▒╗хнжхжВф╜ХчаФчй╢ф╕НхРМцЦЗхМЦчЪДш║лф╗╜ф╕ОцЭГхКЫя╝Я","answer":"чнФцбИя╝Ъф║║ч▒╗хнжщАЪш┐ЗчаФчй╢ф╕НхРМцЦЗхМЦчЪДш║лф╗╜шодхРМуАБцЭГхКЫч╗УцЮДуАБчд╛ф╝ЪщШ╢х▒ВчнЙцЦ╣щЭвцЭеф║ЖшзгхЕ╢ш║лф╗╜ф╕ОцЭГхКЫчЪДцЦЗхМЦцЮДх╗║хТМчд╛ф╝ЪхЕ│ч│╗уАВ"},{"question":"In de Verenigde Staten heeft president Joe Biden het controversi├лle olieproject in Alaska goedgekeurd. Het bedrijf ConocoPhilips zou tot 180.000 olievaten per dag kunnen produceren. Wat is de naaam van dit omstreden olieproject?","answer":"Willow "},{"question":"╨в╨╛╨│╤Г╨╖ ","answer":"9 ╤Ж╨╕╤Д╤А╨░╤Б╤Л╨╜╤Л╨╜ ╨╢╨░╨╖╨╝╨░ ╤В╥п╤А╥п╨╜╨┤╙й ╨╢╨░╨╖╤Л╨╗╨│╨░╨╜╤Л"},{"question":"H├гy cung cс║еp c├бch l├аm Phс╗Я b├▓ sс╗Сt vang H├а Nс╗Щi.","answer":"C├бch l├аm Phс╗Я b├▓ sс╗Сt vang H├а Nс╗Щi:a. S╞б chс║┐, chuс║йn bс╗Л:Chс╗Нn b├▓ nс║еu sс╗Сt vang ngon nhс║еt l├а phс║зn dс║╗ s╞░с╗Эn c├│ cс║г g├вn khi ─Гn c├│ vс╗Л mс╗Бm b├йo, sс║зn sс║нt m├а kh├┤ng bс╗Л kh├┤. B├▓ mua vс╗Б b├│p ch├║t r╞░с╗гu trс║пng v├а gс╗лng ─Сс║нp dс║нp rс╗Уi rс╗нa sс║бch, th├бi miс║┐ng to h├мnh bao di├кm. C├бc gia vс╗Л ─Сс║╖c tr╞░ng gс╗Уm c├│ quс║┐, hс╗Уi, thс║гo quс║г v├а kh├┤ng thс╗Г thiс║┐u l├б nguyс╗Зt quс║┐. R╞░с╗гu vang ─Сс╗П vс╗лa gi├║p mс╗Бm thс╗Лt, vс╗лa t─Гng h╞░╞бng th╞бm ─Сс║╖c tr╞░ng. Gс╗лng, tс╗Пi gi├г hoс║╖c b─Гm nhс╗П. ─Рс╗Г tс║бo m├аu n├вu ─Сс╗П hс║еp dс║лn cho m├│n ─Гn n├кn sс╗н dс╗еng dс║зu m├аu ─Сiс╗Бu hoс║╖c bс╗Щt с╗Ыt paprika. C├а chua rс╗нa sс║бch, kh├нa h├мnh chс╗п thс║нp tr├кn quс║г, cho v├аo n╞░с╗Ыc s├┤i chс║зn 1 - 2 ph├║t cho vс╗П bong vс╗Ыt ra ng├вm v├аo n╞░с╗Ыc lс║бnh, b├│c t├бch bс╗П vс╗П, b─Гm nhuyс╗Еn. b. Tс║йm ╞░с╗Ыp:Cho thс╗Лt b├▓ v├аo ├вu lс╗Ыn rс╗Уi ╞░с╗Ыp vс╗Ыi 1/2 gс╗лng tс╗Пi gi├г, th├кm 3 th├мa canh dс║зu m├аu ─Сiс╗Бu, 2 th├мa canh n╞░с╗Ыc mс║пm, 1 th├мa c├а ph├к muс╗Сi (bс╗Щt canh), 1 th├мa c├а ph├к hс║бt n├кm, 1 th├мa c├а ph├к hс║бt ti├кu, 1/2 ch├йn r╞░с╗гu vang ─Сс╗П c├╣ng quс║┐, hс╗Уi, thс║гo quс║г ─С├г rang th╞бm. Trс╗Щn ─Сс╗Бu tс║еt cс║г v├а ╞░с╗Ыp tс╗Сi thiс╗Гu trong 1 giс╗Э. Nс║┐u c├│ thс╗Эi gian, bс╗Нc m├аng bс╗Нc thс╗▒c phс║йm ─Сс╗Г qua ─С├кm trong ng─Гn m├бt tс╗з lс║бnh. c. Nс║еu sс╗Сt vang:Phi th╞бm 1/2 tс╗Пi vс╗Ыi b╞б, tr├║t thс╗Лt b├▓ ─С├г ╞░с╗Ыp v├аo x├аo s─Гn. N├кm nс║┐m lс║бi gia vс╗Л cho vс╗лa miс╗Зng. Tiс║┐p tс╗еc phi th╞бm b╞б v├а tс╗Пi, cho c├а chua v├аo, n├кm ch├║t muс╗Сi.Nс║┐u c├│ ─Сiс╗Бu kiс╗Зn, n├кn nс║еu n╞░с╗Ыc d├╣ng ─Сс╗Г m├│n ─Гn c├│ vс╗Л ngс╗Нt tс╗▒ nhi├кn. X╞░╞бng b├▓ ng├вm vс╗Ыi n╞░с╗Ыc muс╗Сi lo├гng, th├кm ch├║t r╞░с╗гu trс║пng rс╗Уi ─Сem n╞░с╗Ыng, chс║зn rс╗нa sс║бch lс║бi. Ninh x╞░╞бng с╗Я lс╗нa nhс╗П, th├кm h├аnh t├вy, h├аnh kh├┤, gс╗лng n╞░с╗Ыng c├╣ng ch├║t muс╗Сi v├а ─С╞░с╗Эng ph├иn cho dс╗Лu vс╗Л. Thс╗Йnh thoс║гng hс╗Ыt bс╗П bс╗Нt. N├кn ninh x╞░╞бng tr╞░с╗Ыc ─Сс╗Г khi nс║еu sс║╜ tiс╗Зn h╞бn. N╞░с╗Ыc d├╣ng ─Сс║бt l├а c├│ m├аu v├аng c├бnh gi├бn ├│ng ├бnh mс╗б b├▓ m├а trong, c├│ m├╣i th╞бm ─Сс║╖c tr╞░ng. Mс╗Щt sс╗С h├аng qu├бn khi b├бn th╞░с╗Эng m├║c sс╗Сt vang nс║еu ri├кng cho v├аo, cuс╗Сi c├╣ng m├║c n╞░с╗Ыc d├╣ng phс╗Я. Tr├║t thс╗Лt b├▓ x├аo s─Гn, c├а chua x├аo mс╗Бm v├аo nс╗Уi, th├кm n╞░с╗Ыc, n╞░с╗Ыc d├╣ng b├▓ (c─Гn ─Сс╗з l╞░с╗гng ng╞░с╗Эi ─Гn), 1/2 ch├йn r╞░с╗гu vang ─Сс╗П c├▓n lс║бi v├аo. N├кm nс║┐m lс║бi gia vс╗Л cho vс╗лa miс╗Зng. Khi n╞░с╗Ыc s├┤i, hс║б nhс╗П lс╗нa v├а ninh tс╗Сi thiс╗Гu trong 1 giс╗Э hoс║╖c cho tс╗Ыi khi thс╗Лt mс╗Бm, n╞░с╗Ыc d├╣ng sс╗Сt s├бnh lс║бi. Vс╗Ыt bс╗П quс║┐, hс╗Уi, thс║гo quс║г v├а nh╞░ vс║нy l├а sс╗Сt vang ─С├г ho├аn th├аnh. B├бnh phс╗Я t╞░╞бi chс║зn qua n╞░с╗Ыc s├┤i rс╗Уi chia ─Сс╗Бu ra c├бc b├бt, rс║пc rau th╞бm (h├аnh, m├╣i t├аu, m├╣i ta), gс║пp mс╗Чi b├бt 5 - 6 miс║┐ng sс╗Сt vang rс╗Уi chan n╞░с╗Ыc sс╗Сt vang, th├кm n╞░с╗Ыc d├╣ng (nс║┐u th├нch) v├а th╞░с╗Яng thс╗йc. d. Y├кu cс║зu th├аnh phс║йm:B├бt phс╗Я sс╗Сt vang hс╗Щi tс╗е cс║г sс║пc, h╞░╞бng v├а vс╗Л vс╗Ыi thс╗Лt b├▓ ─Сс╗П n├вu, mс╗Бm ngс╗Нt, c├│ ch├║t sс║зn sс║нt tс╗л g├вn m├а kh├┤ng bс╗Л kh├┤ bс╗Я. N╞░с╗Ыc d├╣ng n├вu ─Сс╗П, h╞бi s├бnh, dс║нy m├╣i th╞бm cс╗зa quс║┐, hс╗Уi, thс║гo quс║г. Ch├║t h├аnh l├б, rau m├╣i xanh t╞░╞бi m├бt t─Гng th├кm phс║зn bс║пt mс║пt. M├│n n├аy ─Гn trong tiс║┐t trс╗Эi m├бt mс║╗ rс║еt hс╗гp."},{"question":"╪е╪░╪з ┘Г╪з┘Ж╪к '┘И┘Е┘Ж ╪з┘Д╪м┘Е┘К┘Д ╪з┘Д┘Г┘Д╪з┘Е ┘Е╪╣┘Г' ╪╡╪н┘К╪н╪й ┘Б╪е┘Ж┘К '╪з┘Ж╪з ╪з╪к╪н╪п╪л ╪з┘Д┘К┘Г ┘Г┘Д ┘К┘И┘Е .' ╪╡╪н┘К╪н╪й╪Я ╪╡╪н ╪г┘Е ╪о╪╖╪г╪Я","answer":"╪║╪з┘Д╪и╪з┘Л ╪╡╪н┘К╪н╪й."},{"question":"Meeqo sano ayuu  jiray  nabiga csw markuu dhimanaayay?","answer":"Nabiga csw wuxuu jiray 63 sano"},{"question":"Gс╗Лnс╗Л bс╗е azс╗Лza gwam gwam gwam(agwс╗еgwa) a?Gwa m с╗Нdara с╗Нbс╗е ereghi ure","answer":"с╗М bс╗е Nkume"},{"question":"с╗Мlс╗Нpaa ti mu Otubс╗Н, с╗Нkunrin с║╣gbс║╣ с║╣ lo ki mс╗Нlс║╣ laarin oru to fс║╣с║╣ maa с╣гe тАШkinniтАЩ fun lтАЩOс╣гodi","answer":"с╗Мkunrin kan, Jane Otubс╗Н, с║╣ni с╗Нdun mejidinlс╗Нgbс╗Нn, ti wa lakata awс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa с╗Нtс║╣lс║╣muyс║╣ ni Panti, lagbegbe Yaba, o ti n с╣гalaye ohun to ri lс╗Нbс║╣ to fi waro с╗Нwс╗Н, wс╗Нn lс╗Нkunrin с║╣gbс║╣ с║╣ lo fс║╣с║╣ fipa ba lo pс╗Н tс╗Нwс╗Н awс╗Нn agbofinro fi tс║╣ с║╣.Gс║╣gс║╣ bawс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa с╣гe sс╗Н, wс╗Нn ni ori ikanni atс║╣ ayelujara kan lafurasi с╗Нdaran ti wс╗Нn lo n gbe Ojule kс║╣ta, Opopona с║╕niс╗Нla, ni Mafoluku, lтАЩOс╣гodi, ti pade с╗Мgbс║╣ni Francis Azeez, agbegbe Gwagwalada, niluu Abuja, olu-ilu ilс║╣ wa, lawс╗Нn mejeeji jс╗Н n с╣гс╗Нrс║╣, wс╗Нn jс╗Н n с╣гaati (chat).Ibi ti wс╗Нn ti n sс╗Нrс╗Н loorekoore yii ni wс╗Нn ni Otubс╗Н ti с╣гeleri fun Francis pe oun aa da a lokoowo, oun aa si ran an lс╗Нwс╗Н, o ni ko waa ba oun lтАЩEkoo kawс╗Нn jс╗Н foju rinju, kawс╗Нn le jс╗Н sс╗Н bi bisinс║╣с║╣si naa aa с╣гe bс║╣rс║╣.Francis с╣гalaye fawс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa pe ohun ti ko jс║╣ koun fura si с╗Нkunrin ti wс╗Нn lс╗Нmс╗Н bibi ipinlс║╣ Enugu ni yii ni pe funra с║╣ lo fowo ti oun maa fi wс╗Нkс╗Н ofurufu wa sтАЩEkoo с╣гс╗Нwс╗Н sinu akaunti oun, lai mс╗Н oun ri, loun naa ba gbera, o mori le Eko lс╗Нsс║╣ to kс╗Нja, с╗Нdс╗Н с╗Нrс║╣ rс║╣ yii lo de si.Olumuyiwa Adejс╗Нbi, Alukoro ileeс╣гс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa Eko, sс╗Н pe ninu alaye ti Francis с╣гe ni teс╣гan с╗Нlс╗Нpaa Makinde, lтАЩOс╣гodi, nigba to waa fс║╣jс╗Н sun, o ni с╗Нrс╗Н bisinс║╣с║╣si lawс╗Нn kс╗Нkс╗Н n sс╗Н, afi bo с╣гe di oru с╗Мjс╗Нruu, Wс║╣sidee, ti olugbalejo oun bс║╣rс║╣ si i fс╗Нwс╗Н pa oun lara, to n fс╗Нwс╗Н pa oun labс║╣ nigba toun sun lс╗Н, titaji toun taji, o ni ihooho goloto lс╗Нkunrin naa wa, o si ti bu с╣гokoto oun so, o loun fс║╣ kawс╗Нn jс╗Н laс╣гepс╗Н, loun ba yari mс╗Н с╗Нn lс╗Нwс╗Н.Francis с╣гalaye siwaju si i pe ijakadi gidi lawс╗Нn ba ara awс╗Нn ja, tori с╗Нkunrin naa ni afi dandan ni koun с╣гe тАШkinniтАЩ foun lai ki i с╣гe obinrin, ariwo kitakita tawс╗Нn n с╣гe lo ji awс╗Нn araale silс║╣, eyi lo mu ki с╗Нkunrin kan ti wс╗Нn n pe ni aafaa tс║╣ ileeс╣гс║╣ с╗Нlс╗Нpaa laago  loru naa, n ni wс╗Нn ba waa fi pampс║╣ с╗Нba gbe afurasi с╗Нdaran с╗Нhun.Wс╗Нn ni lanlс╗Нс╗Нdu ile naa tun с╣гalaye fawс╗Нn с╗Нlс╗Нpaa pe с╗Нkunrin yii ko с╣гс║╣с╣гс║╣ maa huwa palapala с╗Нhun, lanlс╗Нс╗Нdu ni с╗Нpс╗Н igba loun ti pari aawс╗Н latari bawс╗Нn eeyan с╣гe n n fс║╣jс╗Н tс║╣nanti yii sun pe o n fi ilс╗Нkulс╗Н lс╗Н awс╗Нn.Bo tilс║╣ jс║╣ pe okoowo awс╗Нn nnkan jijс║╣ ni afurasi с╗Нdaran naa loun n с╣гe, awс╗Нn aladuugbo naa ni irin с║╣sс║╣ rс║╣ ko mс╗Н, wс╗Нn lс╗Нganjс╗Н oru lo maa n wс╗Нle lс╗Нpс╗Н igba, с║╣nu si ti n kun un laduugbo pe afaimс╗Н ni ko ma jс║╣ oniс╣гс║╣с║╣bi с║╣da kan ni, wс╗Нn ni boya tori с║╣ lс╗Нkunrin naa с╣гe n pe ara с║╣ ni Jane.с╣вa, с╗Нrс╗Н rс║╣ ti detiigbс╗Н kс╗Нmiс╣гanna с╗Нlс╗Нpaa ipinlс║╣ Eko, o si ti ni ki wс╗Нn fa a le с╗Нlс╗Нpaa с╗Нtс║╣lс║╣muyс║╣ lс╗Нwс╗Н fun iwadii gidi, lс║╣yin eyi lo maa lс╗Нс╗Н с╣гalaye ara с║╣ ni kootu laipс║╣"},{"question":"цмбуБоуВ┐уВдуГИуГлуБлхЯ║уБеуБДуБжуАБцЬАхдз500шкЮуБоцо╡шР╜уВТцЫ╕уБДуБжуБПуБауБХуБДя╝Ъ уАМхе│цАзуБМхГНуБНуВДуБЩуБДхЫ╜уАНцЧецЬмуБп29уБохЫ╜уБоф╕нуБз28чХк","answer":"3цЬИ8цЧеуБпхЫ╜щАгуБМц▒║уВБуБЯуАМхЫ╜щЪЫхе│цАзуГЗуГ╝уАНуБзуБЧуБЯуАВуВдуВоуГкуВ╣уБоч╡Мц╕ИуБощЫСшкМуБпуАБф╕ЦчХМуБо29уБохЫ╜уБочФ╖цАзуБихе│цАзуБоч╡жцЦЩуВДхГНуБПф║║уБоцХ░уБкуБйуВТшк┐уБ╣уБжуАБхе│цАзуБМхГНуБНуВДуБЩуБДхЫ╜уВТчЩ║шбиуБЧуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВ29уБохЫ╜уБоф╕нуБзуАБ1чХкуБпуВвуВдуВ╣уГйуГ│уГЙуБзуАБцЧецЬмуБп28чХкуБзуБЧуБЯуАВцЧецЬмуБпф╝Ъчд╛уБочобчРЖшБ╖уБишбЖшн░щЩвуБошн░хУбуБохе│цАзуБохЙ▓хРИуБМуБДуБбуБ░уВУф╜ОуБПуБкуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ29чХкуБпщЯУхЫ╜уБзуБЧуБЯуАВщЫСшкМуБпуАМцЧецЬмуБищЯУхЫ╜уБзуБпф╗КуБзуВВуАБхе│цАзуБМхо╢цЧПуБиф╗Хф║ЛуБоуБйуБбуВЙуБЛуВТщБ╕уБ░уБкуБСуВМуБ░уБкуВКуБ╛уБЫуВУуАНуБишиАуБгуБжуБДуБ╛уБЩуАВцФ┐х║ЬуБоцЭ╛щЗОхоШцИ┐щХ╖хоШуБпуАМчФ╖цАзуВВхе│цАзуВВуАБхГНуБНуБкуБМуВЙхнРуБйуВВуВТшВ▓уБжуВЛуБУуБиуБМуБзуБНуВЛуВИуБЖуБлуБЧуБжуАБуБ┐уВУуБкуБМц┤╗ш║НуБзуБНуВЛчд╛ф╝ЪуБлуБЧуБЯуБДуБзуБЩуАНуБишй▒уБЧуБ╛уБЧуБЯуАВ"},{"question":"рккрлЗрк░рк┐рк╕ркорк╛ркВ рклрк░рк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗркирк╛ рк╕рлБркВркжрк░ рк╕рлНркерк│рлЛ: ","answer":"рккрлЗрк░рк┐рк╕ ркП рккрлНрк░рлЗрко ркЕркирлЗ рк░рлЛркорк╛ркВрк╕ркирлБркВ рк╢рк╣рлЗрк░ ркЫрлЗ, ркЬрлЗркорк╛ркВ ркЗркдрк┐рк╣рк╛рк╕, рк╕ркВрк╕рлНркХрлГркдрк┐ ркЕркирлЗ ркЕркжркнрлВркд рк╕рлНркерк╛рккркдрлНркпркерлА ркнрк░рккрлВрк░ ркЫрлЗ. ркирлАркЪрлЗ рккрлЗрк░рк┐рк╕ркорк╛ркВ рклрк░рк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗркирк╛ ркХрлЗркЯрк▓рк╛ркХ рк╕рлБркВркжрк░ рк╕рлНркерк│рлЛ ркЖрккрлНркпрк╛ ркЫрлЗ:ркЖркЗркХрлЛркирк┐ркХ рк╕рлНркерк│рлЛ:ркПрклрк┐рк▓ ркЯрк╛рк╡рк░:  рккрлЗрк░рк┐рк╕ркирлБркВ рккрлНрк░ркдрлАркХ, ркЖ рк▓рлЛркЦркВркбркирлА ркЯрк╛рк╡рк░ рк╢рк╣рлЗрк░ркирк╛ ркЕркжркнрлВркд ркиркЬрк╛рк░рк╛ркУ рккрлНрк░ркжрк╛рки ркХрк░рлЗ ркЫрлЗ.рк▓рлБрк╡рлНрк░рлЗ ркорлНркпрлБркЭрк┐ркпрко:  рк╡рк┐рк╢рлНрк╡ркирк╛ рк╕рлМркерлА рккрлНрк░ркЦрлНркпрк╛ркд ркорлНркпрлБркЭрк┐ркпркорлЛркорк╛ркВркирлБркВ ркПркХ, рк▓рлБрк╡рлНрк░рлЗ ркорлЛркирк╛ рк▓рк┐рк╕рк╛, рк╡рк┐ркирк╕ ркбрлА ркорк┐рк▓рлЛ ркЕркирлЗ ркШркгрлА ркЕркирлНркп ркХрк▓рк╛ркХрлГркдрк┐ркУркирлБркВ ркШрк░ ркЫрлЗ.ркирлЛркЯрлНрк░рлЗ ркбрлЗрко:  12ркорлА рк╕ркжрлАркирлБркВ ркЧрлЛркерк┐ркХ ркХрлЕркерлЗркбрлНрк░рк▓, ркЬрлЗ ркдрлЗркирлА ркЕркжркнрлВркд рк╕рлНркерк╛рккркдрлНркп ркЕркирлЗ рк╕рлБркВркжрк░ ркЧрлБрк▓рк╛ркмрлА ркХрк╛ркЪркирлА ркмрк╛рк░рлАркУ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркЬрк╛ркгрлАркдрлБркВ ркЫрлЗ.ркЖрк░рлНркХ ркбрлА ркЯрлНрк░рк╛ркпркорлНркл:  ркирлЗрккрлЛрк▓рк┐ркпрки ркжрлНрк╡рк╛рк░рк╛ ркдрлЗркирк╛ рк╡рк┐ркЬркпрлЛркирлА ркЙркЬрк╡ркгрлА ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркмркирк╛рк╡рк╡рк╛ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлЗрк▓, ркЖ рк╡рк┐ркЬркп рк╕рлНркерк╛рккркдрлНркп рк╢рк╣рлЗрк░ркирк╛ ркХрлЗркирлНркжрлНрк░ркорк╛ркВ рк╕рлНркерк┐ркд ркЫрлЗ.рк╕рлБркВркжрк░ рккрк╛рк░рлНркХрлЛ ркЕркирлЗ ркмркЧрлАркЪрк╛ркУ:ркЬрк╛рк░рлНркбрк┐рки ркбрлБ рк▓ркХрлНрк╕рлЗркоркмрк░рлНркЧ:  25 рк╣рлЗркХрлНркЯрк░ркорк╛ркВ рклрлЗрк▓рк╛ркпрлЗрк▓рлЛ ркЖ рк╕рлБркВркжрк░ ркмркЧрлАркЪрлЛ рккрлЗрк░рк┐рк╕рк┐ркпркирлЛ ркЕркирлЗ рккрлНрк░рк╡рк╛рк╕рлАркУ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркПркХ рк▓рлЛркХрккрлНрк░рк┐ркп рк╕рлНркерк│ ркЫрлЗ.ркЪрлЗркорлНрккрлНрк╕-ркПрк▓рк┐рк╕рлАрк╕: ркЖ рк╡рк┐рк╢рк╛рк│ ркмрлБрк▓рлЗрк╡рк░рлНркб ркдрлЗркирлА рклрлВркЯрккрк╛рке, ркмркЧрлАркЪрк╛ркУ ркЕркирлЗ рк▓ркХрлНркЭрк░рлА ркжрлБркХрк╛ркирлЛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркЬрк╛ркгрлАркдрлБркВ ркЫрлЗ.ркмрлЛркЗрк╕ ркбрлА рк╡рк┐ркирлНрк╕рлЗркирлНрк╕:  рккрлЗрк░рк┐рк╕ркирк╛ рккрлВрк░рлНрк╡ркорк╛ркВ ркЖрк╡рлЗрк▓рлБркВ ркЖ рк╡рк┐рк╢рк╛рк│ ркЬркВркЧрк▓ ркмрк╛ркЗркХ ркЪрк▓рк╛рк╡рк╡рк╛, ркжрлЛркбрк╡рлБркВ, ркмрлЛркЯрк┐ркВркЧ ркХрк░рк╡рк╛ ркЕркирлЗ рккрлНрк░ркХрлГркдрк┐ркирлЛ ркЖркиркВркж ркорк╛ркгрк╡рк╛ ркорк╛ркЯрлЗ ркПркХ рк╢рк╛ркиркжрк╛рк░ рк╕рлНркерк│ ркЫрлЗ.ркЕркирлНркп рк░рк╕рккрлНрк░ркж рк╕рлНркерк│рлЛ:ркорлЛркирлНркЯркорк╛рк░рлНркЯрлНрк░рлЗ:  ркПркХ рк╕рлБркВркжрк░ ркШрк╛ркЯрлА ркЬрлЗркорк╛ркВ рк╕рлЗркХрлНрк░рлЗркб-ркХрлЛркпрк░ ркмрлЗрк╕рк┐рк▓рк┐ркХрк╛ ркЕркирлЗ ркШркгрк╛ ркЖрк░рлНркЯ ркЧрлЗрк▓рлЗрк░рлАркУ ркЕркирлЗ ркХрк▓рк╛ркХрк╛рк░рлЛркирк╛ рк╕рлНркЯрлБркбрк┐ркпрлЛ ркЖрк╡рлЗрк▓рк╛ ркЫрлЗ. ркорлНркпрлБркЭрлА ркбрлА'ркУрк░рк╕рлЗ:  19ркорлА рк╕ркжрлАркирлА ркХрк▓рк╛ркирлБркВ ркПркХ ркорк╣ркдрлНрк╡ркирлБркВ рк╕ркВркЧрлНрк░рк╣, ркЬрлЗркорк╛ркВ ркорлЛркирлЗркЯ, рк░рлЗркирлЛркЗрк░ ркЕркирлЗ ркбрлЗркЧрк╛рк╕ ркЬрлЗрк╡рк╛ ркХрк▓рк╛ркХрк╛рк░рлЛркирк╛ ркХрк╛рк░рлНркпрлЛ ркЫрлЗ.рккрлЗркирлНркерк┐ркУрки:  ркПркХ ркРркдрк┐рк╣рк╛рк╕рк┐ркХ рк╕рлНркорк╛рк░ркХ ркЬрлЗркорк╛ркВ рк╡рк┐ркХрлНркЯрк░ рк╣рлНркпрлБркЧрлЛ, ркПркорк┐рк▓ ркЭрлЛрк▓рк╛ ркЕркирлЗ ркорк╛рк░рлА ркХрлНркпрлБрк░рлА ркЬрлЗрк╡рк╛ рккрлНрк░ркЦрлНркпрк╛ркд рк▓рлЛркХрлЛркирк╛ ркЕрк╡рк╢рлЗрк╖рлЛ ркЫрлЗ.рккрлЗрк▓рлЗрк╕ ркЧрк╛рк░рлНркирк┐ркпрк░:  ркПркХ ркнрк╡рлНркп ркУрккрлЗрк░рк╛ рк╣"},{"question":"Which Dutch darts player became victorious at the Lakeside Country Club in Frimley Green on January 15, 2012, in the BDO World Championship?","answer":"On January 15, 2012, Christian Kist won the BDO World Championship at the Lakeside Country Club in Frimley Green."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai alah limau oleh benalu\\"?","answer":"Peribahasa ini bermaksud orang baik kalah kepada orang jahat."},{"question":"роЪро░ро┐ропро╛рой ро╡ро┐роЯрпИропрпИ родрпЗро░рпНроирпНродрпЖроЯрпБродрпНродрпБ роОро┤рпБродрпБроХ .роХрпЗро│рпНро╡ро┐: 1942 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╣роЬро┐ро░ро╛рокро╛роХрпН роородрпНродро┐роп роЪро┐ро▒рпИропро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНрод рокрпЛродрпБ тАШро╡ро╛ро▓рпНроХро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роХроЩрпНроХрпИ ро╡ро░рпИтАЩ роОройрпНро▒ роирпВро▓рпИ роЗроирпНродро┐ роорпКро┤ро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роОро┤рпБродро┐ропро╡ро░рпН тАжтАжтАжтАжтАжтАж..роЕ) ро░ро╛роХрпБро▓рпН роЪро╛роЩрпНроХро┐ро░рпБродрпНропро╛ропройрпНроЖ) роЪроЪро┐родрпЗро╡рпНроЗ) роХрогроорпБродрпНродрпИропро╛роИ) ро╡рпЖ. ро╕рпНро░рпАро░ро╛роорпН","answer":" рокродро┐ро▓рпН: 1942 роЖроорпН роЖрогрпНроЯрпБ ро╣роЬро┐ро░ро╛рокро╛роХрпН роородрпНродро┐роп роЪро┐ро▒рпИропро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНрод рокрпЛродрпБ тАШро╡ро╛ро▓рпНроХро╛ро╡ро┐ро▓ро┐ро░рпБроирпНродрпБ роХроЩрпНроХрпИ ро╡ро░рпИтАЩ роОройрпНро▒ роирпВро▓рпИ роЗроирпНродро┐ роорпКро┤ро┐ропро┐ро▓рпН роОро┤рпБродро┐ропро╡ро░рпН роЕ) ро░ро╛роХрпБро▓рпН роЪро╛роЩрпНроХро┐ро░рпБродрпНропро╛ропройрпН.роЗро░ро╛роХрпБро▓рпН роЪро╛роЩрпНроХро┐ро░рпБродрпНродро┐ропро╛ропройрпН (роПрокрпНро░ро▓рпН 9, 1893 - роПрокрпНро░ро▓рпН 14, 1963) роЗроирпНродро┐ рокропрог роЗро▓роХрпНроХро┐ропродрпНродро┐ройрпН родроирпНродрпИ роОрой роЕро▒ро┐ропрокрпНрокроЯрпБрокро╡ро░рпН; родройрпН ро╡ро╛ро┤рпНроиро╛ро│ро┐ро▓рпН 45 ро╡ро░рпБроЯ роХро╛ро▓родрпНродрпИ роЙро│рпНроиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБ рооро▒рпНро▒рпБроорпН ро╡рпЖро│ро┐роиро╛роЯрпНроЯрпБрокрпН рокропрогродрпНродро┐ро▓рпН роЪрпЖро▓ро╡ро┤ро┐родрпНродро╡ро░рпН; рокройрпНроорпКро┤ро┐рокрпНрокрпБро▓ро╡ро░рпН; рокро▓рпНродрпБро▒рпИ ро╡ро┐родрпНродроХро░рпН; рокрпБродрпНродродрпН родрпБро▒ро╡ро┐ропро╛роХро┐ рокро┐ройрпНройро░рпН рооро╛ро░рпНроХрпНроЪро┐ропро╡ро╛родро┐ропро╛ройро╡ро░рпН. роЕродрпБроороЯрпНроЯрпБрооройрпНро▒ро┐ роЖроЩрпНроХро┐ро▓рпЗропро░рпН роЖроЯрпНроЪро┐роХрпНроХрпЖродро┐ро░ро╛рой роХро░рпБродрпНродрпБроХро│рпИ роОро┤рпБродро┐ропродро▒рпНроХро╛роХ роорпВройрпНро▒ро╛рогрпНроЯрпБ роХро╛ро▓ роЪро┐ро▒рпИро╡ро╛роЪроорпН роЕройрпБрокро╡ро┐родрпНродро╡ро░рпН."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en est├б categor├нa : deporte. ","answer":"┬┐Qu├й golfista termin├│ subcampe├│n en el U. S. Abierto la mayor├нa de las veces sin ganar nunca? Phil Mickelson. "},{"question":"Nd├аx mbind mii jub na?Too├▒kat ya weccee baat ya Nu leen waxoon, ak yeneeni baat yu wuuteek yooya, Nu daldi w├аcce ca way-too├▒ ├▒a mbugal mu bawoo asamaan ngir la ├▒u nekkoon di saay-saay [su g├йnn diine].","answer":"D├йedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Too├▒kat ya weccee baat ya Nu l├йen w├аxoon, ak yeneen i baat yu w├╣utee'k yooya, Nu daldi w├аcce ca waytoo├▒ ├▒a mbugal mu bawoo ├аsamaan ng├мr la ├▒u nekkoon di saay-saay [su g├йnn diine]."},{"question":"Jawab soalan yang rumit ini: Apakah anugerah yang menamakan Anna Kendrick dalam filem muzikal?","answer":"Anugerah Tony"}]`),M={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:S},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:I,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},C={class:"search-container"},O={class:"card-container"},B=["disabled"],D={key:0},L={key:1};function K(e,a,s,g,t,u){const d=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"ЁЯдФ AI effective tips collection ЁЯза")])],-1)),n("div",C,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",O,[(i(!0),o(p,null,c(u.filteredPoems,(r,m)=>(i(),f(d,{key:m,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",L,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",D,"See more"))],8,B)):j("",!0)])}const P=k(M,[["render",K],["__scopeId","data-v-34f586a7"]]),F=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/26.md","filePath":"chatai/26.md"}'),H={name:"chatai/26.md"},E=Object.assign(H,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(P)]))}});export{F as __pageData,E as default};
